<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="210" order_by="210">STATE AND REGIONAL MENTAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>210.031</section_number><catch_line>Advisory committee on need for services for deaf or hard-of-hearing persons.   </catch_line><order_by>031</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet shall establish an advisory committee of sixteen (16) members to advise the Department for Behavioral Health, Developmental and Intellectual Disabilities of the need for particular services for persons who are deaf or hard-of-hearing. <section prefix="a">At least eight (8) members shall be deaf or hard-of-hearing and shall be appointed by the secretary. Four (4) deaf or hard-of-hearing members, representing one (1) of each of the following organizations, shall be appointed from a list of at least two (2) nominees submitted from each of the following organizations: <section prefix="1">The Kentucky Association of the Deaf; </section><section prefix="2">The A.G. Bell Association; </section><section prefix="3">The Kentucky School for the Deaf Alumni Association; and </section><section prefix="4">Self Help for the Hard of Hearing. </section></section> The remaining four (4) deaf or hard-of-hearing members shall be appointed by the secretary from a list of at least eight (8) nominees submitted by the Kentucky Commission on the Deaf and Hard of Hearing. <section prefix="b">One (1) member shall be a family member of a deaf or hard-of-hearing consumer of mental health services and shall be appointed by the secretary from a list of nominees accepted from any source. </section><section prefix="c">The head of each of the following entities shall appoint one (1) member to the advisory committee: <section prefix="1">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services, Department for Behavioral Health, Developmental and Intellectual Disabilities; </section><section prefix="2">The Education and Workforce Development Cabinet, Office of Vocational Rehabilitation; </section><section prefix="3">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services, Department for Aging and Independent Living; </section><section prefix="4">The Education and Workforce Development Cabinet, Commission on the Deaf and Hard of Hearing; </section><section prefix="5">The Kentucky Registry of Interpreters for the Deaf; and </section><section prefix="6">A Kentucky School for the Deaf staff person involved in education. </section></section><section prefix="d">The remaining member shall be a representative of a regional board for mental health or individuals with an intellectual disability, appointed by the commissioner of the Department for Behavioral Health, Developmental and Intellectual Disabilities from a list composed of two (2) names submitted by each regional board for mental health or individuals with an intellectual disability. </section></section><section prefix="2">Of the members defined in subsection (1)(a) and (b) of this section, three (3) shall be appointed for a one (1) year term, three (3) shall be appointed for a two (2) year term, and three (3) shall be appointed for a three (3) year term; thereafter, they shall be appointed for three (3) year terms. The members defined under subsection (1)(c) and (d) of this section shall serve with no fixed term of office. </section><section prefix="3">The members defined under subsection (1)(a) and (b) of this section shall serve without compensation but shall be reimbursed for actual and necessary expenses; the members defined under subsection (1)(c) and (d) of this section shall serve without compensation or reimbursement of any kind. </section><section prefix="4">The Department for Behavioral Health, Developmental and Intellectual Disabilities shall make available personnel to serve as staff to the advisory committee. </section><section prefix="5">The advisory committee shall meet quarterly at a location determined by the committee chair. </section><section prefix="6"><section prefix="a">The advisory committee shall prepare a biennial report which: <section prefix="1">Describes the accommodations and the mental health, intellectual disability, development disability, and substance abuse services made accessible to deaf and hard-of-hearing persons; </section><section prefix="2">Reports the number of deaf or hard-of-hearing persons served; </section><section prefix="3">Identifies additional service needs for the deaf and hard-of-hearing; and </section><section prefix="4">Identifies a plan to address unmet service needs. </section></section><section prefix="b">The report shall be submitted to the secretary, the commissioner of the Department for Behavioral Health, Developmental and Intellectual Disabilities, and the Interim Joint Committee on Health and Welfare by July 1 of every odd-numbered year. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 68, effective July 12, 2012; and ch. 158, sec. 35, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 63, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 18, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 123, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 300, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 28, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 245, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 209, sec. 19, effective July 15, 1994. – Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 340, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note>(7/12/2012). This statute was amended by 2012 Ky. Acts chs. 146 and 158, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40796</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>