<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="70" order_by="70">SHERIFFS, CONSTABLES, AND COUNTY POLICE FORCE </unit></structure><section_number>70.261</section_number><catch_line>Adoption of rules -- Certified copies -- Subjects addressed -- Issuance of additional rules -- Repeal or amendment of existing rules. </catch_line><order_by>261</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When a county creates a deputy sheriff merit board, the board shall issue, and publish within forty-eight (48) hours after their adoption, rules that are not inconsistent with the provisions of KRS 70.260 to 70.273. The board shall provide a certified copy of the rules to: <section prefix="a">The sheriff of the county who shall additionally post a copy in a conspicuous place in the main office and in any branch offices where deputies are regularly assigned to work from; </section><section prefix="b">The county judge/executive of the county; and </section><section prefix="c">The legislative body of the county. </section></section><section prefix="2">The board shall, at a minimum, adopt a body of rules that addresses the following subjects: <section prefix="a">For deputy sheriffs: <section prefix="1">Qualifications for initial and continued employment, which shall at a minimum include: citizenship, age, physical, mental, and educational requirements; </section><section prefix="2">Grounds for temporary appointments; </section><section prefix="3">Advancement requirements. Deputy sheriffs shall be employed for at least three (3) full years before being eligible for the rank of sergeant; </section><section prefix="4">Factors that shall, or may, result in demotion, the procedures for determining whether or not to demote a deputy, and the procedures for executing a demotion; </section><section prefix="5">Factors that shall, or may, result in fining, probation, suspension, or removal; and </section><section prefix="6">Administrative procedures for the deputies in the office such as transfer, lay-off, and reinstatement. </section></section><section prefix="b">For the general administration of the board itself: <section prefix="1">Organizational structure and conduct of meetings; </section><section prefix="2">Procedure and conduct of public hearings as a result of the board's actions; and </section><section prefix="3">Implementation and execution of written and oral examinations, and physical tests of fitness for appointment and promotion of deputies. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">The subsequent issuance of additional rules, or of the repeal or amendment of existing rules shall follow the provisions indicated in subsection (1) of this section. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 244, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 510, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/98).  This section was created by 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 244, sec. 10, and ch. 510, sec. 10, which are identical and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24217</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>