<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="151" order_by="151">B WORKFORCE EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>151B.133</section_number><catch_line>Duties of Office for Education and Workforce Statistics.   </catch_line><order_by>133</order_by><text>The duties of the Office for Education and Workforce Statistics shall be to: <section prefix="1">Oversee and maintain the warehouse of education data and workforce data in the Kentucky Longitudinal Data System; </section><section prefix="2">Develop de-identification standards and processes using modern statistical methods; </section><section prefix="3">Conduct research and evaluation regarding federal, state, and local education and training programs at all levels; </section><section prefix="4">Audit and ensure compliance of education and training programs with applicable federal and state requirements as authorized by federal and state law; </section><section prefix="5">Work with public agencies and other entities to define statewide education, workforce development, and employment metrics and ensure the integrity and quality of data being collected; </section><section prefix="6">Link education data and workforce data from multiple sources for consideration in developing broad public policy initiatives; </section><section prefix="7">Develop requirements and definitions for data to be provided by any public agency, private institution of higher education, private school, or parochial school, as directed by the Board of the Kentucky Center for Education and Workforce Statistics; </section><section prefix="8">Develop a reasonable fee schedule for services provided; </section><section prefix="9">Establish data quality standards; </section><section prefix="10">Promulgate administrative regulations necessary for the proper administration of the Kentucky Longitudinal Data System; </section><section prefix="11">Ensure compliance with the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act, 20 U.S.C. sec 1232g, and all other relevant federal and state privacy laws; </section><section prefix="12">Respond to approved research data requests in accordance with the data access and use policy established by the board; </section><section prefix="13">Develop and disseminate, in cooperation with the Council on Postsecondary Education and the Department of Education, information on the employment and earnings of the public postsecondary institution graduates in Kentucky. This information shall be updated at least every three (3) years and shall be: <section prefix="a">Posted on the Web site of the Office for Education and Workforce Statistics; </section><section prefix="b">Posted on the Web site of the Council on Postsecondary Education; </section><section prefix="c">Posted on the Web site of each public postsecondary institution, with the Web site address published in each institution's catalogue; and </section><section prefix="d">Made available to every high school guidance and career counselor, who shall be notified of its availability for the purpose of informing all high school students preparing for postsecondary education; and </section></section><section prefix="14">Enter into contracts or other agreements with appropriate entities, including but not limited to federal, state, and local agencies, to the extent necessary to carry out its duties and responsibilities only if such contracts or agreements incorporate adequate protections with respect to the confidentiality of any information to be shared. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 26, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. -- Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 3, effective June 25, 2013; and ch. 90, sec. 3, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><lrc-note>(6/25/2013). This statute was created with identical text in 2013 Ky. Acts chs. 18 and 90, which were companion bills. These Acts have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43215</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>