<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="344" order_by="344">CIVIL RIGHTS </unit></structure><section_number>344.385</section_number><catch_line>Notice of violation by real estate dealer to be given Real Estate Commission -- Notice of violation to state or federal licensing agency. </catch_line><order_by>385</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Where a real estate broker or a real estate salesman has failed to comply with an order issued by the commission or has been found to have committed an unfair housing practice in violation of KRS 344.380, the commission shall notify in writing the Real Estate Commission of the Commonwealth of Kentucky of the failure to comply or violation. </section><section prefix="2">In the case of an order with respect to a discriminatory housing practice that occurred in the course of a business subject to licensing or regulation by a state or federal government agency, the commission shall, not later than thirty (30) days after the date of the issuance of the order, or if the order is judicially reviewed, thirty (30) days after the order is in substance affirmed upon review: <section prefix="a">Send copies of the finding of fact, conclusions of law, and the order to that governmental agency; and </section><section prefix="b">Recommend to that governmental agency appropriate disciplinary action, including, where appropriate, the suspension or revocation of the license of the respondent. </section></section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 282, sec. 43, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 167, sec. 11. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32646</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>