<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.20-505</section_number><catch_line>Authorization to establish Small Business Stationary Source Technical and Environmental Compliance Assistance Program -- Functions. </catch_line><order_by>20-505</order_by><text>The cabinet is hereby authorized to establish the Small Business Stationary Source Technical and Environmental Compliance Assistance Program, referred to hereafter as "the program." The program shall perform the functions designated for it in the 1990 Federal Clean Air Act amendments and assist the small business stationary source compliance advisory panel in the development and dissemination of the panel's reports and advisory opinions. The cabinet may also, as funding allows, offer assistance in complying with other environmental protection regulatory programs. For the purposes of providing the assistance to small business stationary sources, "small business" shall have the meaning given it in the 1990 Federal Clean Air Act amendments. For the purposes of providing assistance with other environmental protection regulatory programs, "small business" shall also include entities owned or operated by a person that employs one hundred (100) or fewer individuals, is a small business concern as defined in the Small Business Act (15 U.S.C. secs. 631 et seq.), but which need not have air emissions subject to regulatory control. </text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 73, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 245, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:34</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10360</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>