<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="151" order_by="151">GEOLOGY AND WATER RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>151.625</section_number><catch_line>Establishment of long-term groundwater monitoring network -- Duties. </catch_line><order_by>625</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The KGS shall, in cooperation with the Interagency Technical Advisory Committee on Groundwater, establish a long-term groundwater monitoring network for the purpose of characterizing the quality, quantity, and distribution of Kentucky's groundwater resources. </section><section prefix="2">The monitoring network shall include: <section prefix="a">Representative sites sampled by various agencies; </section><section prefix="b">Water wells, springs, and surface water associated with wells and springs; and </section><section prefix="c">New monitoring wells installed in areas of demonstrated need. </section></section> This network shall collect information on a statewide basis and provide long-term data collection to determine the quality, quantity, and occurrence of groundwater throughout the Commonwealth. <section prefix="3">The KGS shall utilize collected data to support research efforts that develop models for groundwater systems, and to determine and monitor trends of groundwater movement, water quality, and quantity. </section><section prefix="4">The KGS shall provide data from the network to the Kentucky Groundwater Data Repository and make the data readily available to the public, government agencies, industry, and other entities that request access. Analyzed data may be made available in the form of maps, charts, bulletins, and reports. </section><section prefix="5">The KGS shall solicit input from federal, state, and local agencies, and industry, agriculture, universities, and the public to determine priority monitoring locations based on water quality and quantity concerns as the network is developed. </section><section prefix="6">Within ninety (90) days of the end of each state fiscal year, the KGS shall provide to the Governor and the Legislative Research Commission a summary of the groundwater monitoring network data collection and analysis activities. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 30, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2145</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>