<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.782</section_number><catch_line>Guidelines to provide highly skilled education assistance to schools and districts -- Professional leave for selected employee -- Appropriate training -- Review of paperwork requirements. </catch_line><order_by>782</order_by><text><section prefix="1">After receiving the advice of the Office of Education Accountability; the School Curriculum, Assessment, and Accountability Council; and the National Technical Advisory Panel on Assessment and Accountability, the Kentucky Board of Education shall promulgate administrative regulations in conformity with KRS 158.6471 and 158.6472 and KRS Chapter 13A, to set forth the guidelines for providing highly skilled education assistance to schools and school districts. The program shall be designed to support improved teaching and learning and may include, but not be limited to, establishing the following: <section prefix="a">Criteria for identifying successful strategies of assistance; </section><section prefix="b">Policies and procedures for providing education assistance, which may include training, making assignments, employing certified personnel, and setting salaries that may include supplements; and </section><section prefix="c">Duties of those providing education assistance, which may include personnel evaluation and recommendations concerning retention, dismissal, or transfer of personnel. </section></section><section prefix="2">A district employee selected to provide assistance shall be granted professional leave pursuant to KRS 161.770 though the time may exceed two (2) years if determined by the state board to be necessary. A certified employee shall not lose any employee benefits as a result of a special assignment. </section><section prefix="3">The Department of Education shall provide appropriate training for the persons selected to provide assistance that shall include but not be limited to training to strengthen the school-based decision making process. </section><section prefix="4">The Kentucky Board of Education shall annually review the paperwork required of schools receiving highly skilled certified education assistance. It shall assure that paperwork requirements are kept to a minimum, relevant to the needs of the school, and are directly related to improving teaching and learning. </section></text><history> Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 3, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 598, sec. 14, effective April 14, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 408, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. I, sec. 6, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3585</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>