<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="238" order_by="238">CHARITABLE GAMING </unit></structure><section_number>238.520</section_number><catch_line>Charitable Gaming Advisory Commission. </catch_line><order_by>520</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Charitable Gaming Advisory Commission is created to be composed of nine (9) members consisting of: <section prefix="a">The secretary of the Public Protection Cabinet or his designee; </section><section prefix="b">The Attorney General or his designee; </section><section prefix="c">One (1) representative from the Kentucky Commonwealth's Attorneys Association; </section><section prefix="d">One (1) representative from the Kentucky Charitable Gaming Association; </section><section prefix="e">One (1) certified public accountant; </section><section prefix="f">One (1) member selected from the public at large; </section><section prefix="g">One (1) representative selected from the Joint Executive Council of Veterans Organizations of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="h">One (1) representative from Catholic organizations; and </section><section prefix="i">One (1) representative from Kentucky's volunteer firefighter organizations. </section></section> The certified public accountant, the one (1) at-large member, and the representatives from the Kentucky Commonwealth's Attorneys Association and the Kentucky Charitable Gaming Association shall be appointed by the Governor. The representative from each of the two (2) associations, the one (1) representative from the Joint Executive Council of Veterans Organizations of Kentucky, the one (1) representative from the Catholic organizations, and the one (1) representative from the volunteer firefighter organizations shall be selected from a list of at least three (3) names submitted to the Governor by the respective association. <section prefix="2">Initial appointments to the commission shall be for staggered terms as follows: one (1) member for a term of one (1) year; two (2) members for a term of two (2) years; two (2) members for a term of three (3) years; and two (2) members for a term of four (4) years. Thereafter, each member shall be appointed for a term of four (4) years. No member from the public at large shall be appointed in the same year. Vacancies shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment for the unexpired portion of the term. No member of the commission may serve more than two (2) full terms. </section><section prefix="3">The Charitable Gaming Advisory Commission shall provide ongoing advice and input to the department and to the General Assembly but shall not become directly involved in the licensing and regulation of charitable gaming by the department. </section><section prefix="4">The commission shall meet quarterly, upon the request of the chair or four (4) of its members or as otherwise directed by the department. Five (5) members shall constitute a quorum for conducting business. The commission shall annually elect a chairman from its membership, and no person elected chairman shall serve more than two (2) consecutive terms of one (1) year each. Members shall receive no compensation for serving on the commission, but shall be reimbursed for travel expenses for attending meetings and performing other official functions, consistent with state reimbursement policy for state employees. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 536, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 5, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 374, sec. 5, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 232, sec. 3, effective April 1, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 331, sec. 15, effective April 10, 1996. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 66, sec. 5, effective March 16, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11195</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>