<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="75" order_by="75">FIRE PROTECTION DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>75.420</section_number><catch_line>Application for recognition of fire department -- Boundaries. </catch_line><order_by>420</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commission shall recognize all fire departments which comply with the provisions of KRS 75.410 and regulations promulgated in compliance therewith. Applications for recognition shall be made on forms provided by the commission. The department shall attach to the application an accurate map and a written description which delineates the boundaries of the area served by the department. The map and description shall also be filed with the county clerk of the county in which the department is located. If the boundaries extend into two (2) or more counties, the map and description shall be filed with the county clerk in each county in which a part of the department's service area is located. </section><section prefix="2">The boundaries between two (2) or more departments created pursuant to KRS Chapter 273 may be altered if the departments enter into a written agreement establishing the boundaries, and if a majority of the property owners in the affected area approve the new boundaries. A new map and written description of the altered boundaries shall be filed with the commission and with the county clerks in the affected counties. </section></text><history> Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 43, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24466</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>