<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">A EMERGENCY MEDICAL SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>311A.015</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Board of Emergency Medical Services -- Members -- Terms -- Quorum -- Procedure -- Removal of members -- Reimbursement -- Annual reports. </catch_line><order_by>015</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Board of Emergency Medical Services is created and shall be attached to the Kentucky Community and Technical College System. </section><section prefix="2">The board shall consist of eighteen (18) members who are residents of Kentucky appointed by the Governor in conjunction with recognized state emergency medical services related organizations. Membership shall be made up of the following: <section prefix="a">One (1) paramedic who works for a government agency but is not serving in an educational, management, or supervisory capacity; </section><section prefix="b">One (1) emergency medical technician-basic who works for a government agency but is not serving in an educational, management, or supervisory capacity; </section><section prefix="c">One (1) first responder who is not serving in an educational, management, or supervisory capacity; </section><section prefix="d">One (1) physician licensed in Kentucky having a primary practice in the delivery of emergency medical care selected from a list of three (3) physicians submitted by the Kentucky Medical Association; </section><section prefix="e">One (1) physician licensed in Kentucky serving as medical director of an advanced life support ambulance service selected from a list of three (3) physicians submitted by the Kentucky Medical Association; </section><section prefix="f">One (1) physician licensed in Kentucky who routinely is involved in the emergency care of ill and injured children selected from a list of three (3) physicians submitted by the Kentucky Medical Association; </section><section prefix="g">One (1) trauma surgeon licensed in Kentucky selected from a list of three (3) physicians submitted by the Kentucky Medical Association; </section><section prefix="h">One (1) citizen having no involvement in the delivery of medical or emergency services; </section><section prefix="i">One (1) emergency medical services educator certified by the board; </section><section prefix="j">One (1) mayor of a city that operates, either directly or through contract services, a licensed Class I ground ambulance service; </section><section prefix="k">One (1) county judge/executive from a county that operates, whether directly or through contract services, a licensed Class I ground ambulance service; </section><section prefix="l">One (1) volunteer-staffed, licensed Class I ground ambulance service administrator who is a certified emergency medical technician or a licensed paramedic; </section><section prefix="m">One (1) fire-service-based, licensed Class I ground ambulance service administrator who is a certified emergency medical technician or a licensed paramedic; </section><section prefix="n">One (1) licensed air ambulance service administrator or paramedic for a licensed air ambulance service headquartered in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="o">One (1) private licensed Class 1 ground ambulance service administrator who is a certified emergency medical technician or a licensed paramedic who is a resident of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="p">One (1) hospital administrator selected from a list of five (5) nominees submitted by the Kentucky Hospital Association; </section><section prefix="q">One (1) basic life support, licensed Class I government-operated ground ambulance service administrator who is a certified emergency medical technician or a licensed paramedic; and </section><section prefix="r">One (1) advanced life support, government-operated ambulance service administrator who is a certified emergency medical technician or a licensed paramedic. </section></section><section prefix="3">No board member shall serve more than two (2) consecutive terms. A member appointed to a partial term vacancy exceeding two (2) years shall be deemed to have served a full term. A former member may be reappointed following an absence of one (1) term. </section><section prefix="4">The board shall annually: <section prefix="a">Meet at least six (6) times a year; </section><section prefix="b">At the first meeting of the board after September 1, elect a chair and vice chair by majority vote of the members present; and </section><section prefix="c">Set a schedule of six (6) regular meetings for the next twelve (12) month period. </section></section><section prefix="5">The board shall adopt a quorum and rules of procedure by administrative regulation. </section><section prefix="6"><section prefix="a">A member of the board who misses three (3) regular meetings in one (1) year shall be deemed to have resigned from the board and his or her position shall be deemed vacant. </section><section prefix="b">The failure of a board member to attend a special or emergency meeting shall not result in any penalty. </section><section prefix="c">The year specified in this subsection shall begin with the first meeting missed and end three hundred sixty-five (365) days later or with the third meeting missed, whichever occurs earlier. </section><section prefix="d">The Governor shall appoint a person of the same class to fill the vacancy within ninety (90) days. </section><section prefix="e">The person removed under this subsection shall not be reappointed to the board for ten (10) years. </section></section><section prefix="7">Members of the board shall be entitled to reimbursement for actual and necessary expenses when carrying out official duties of the board in accordance with state administrative regulations relating to travel reimbursement. The board shall meet at least six (6) times each year. </section><section prefix="8">Annual reports and recommendations from the board shall be sent by September 1 each year to the Governor, the president of the Kentucky Community and Technical College System, and the General Assembly. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 243, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30718</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>