<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="327" order_by="327">PHYSICAL THERAPISTS </unit></structure><section_number>327.050</section_number><catch_line>Licensing provisions.   </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Before applying for licensure by the board as a physical therapist, a person shall have successfully completed an accredited program in physical therapy approved by the board. No school shall be approved by the board unless it has been approved for the educational preparation of physical therapists by the recognized national accrediting agency for physical therapy educational programs. </section><section prefix="2">Any person who possesses the qualifications required by this chapter and who desires to apply for licensure as a physical therapist in Kentucky shall make written application to the board, on forms to be provided by the board. The application shall be accompanied by a nonrefundable application fee in an amount to be determined by the board, but not to exceed two hundred fifty dollars ($250). </section><section prefix="3">If it appears from the application that the applicant possesses the qualifications required by this chapter and has not yet successfully completed the board-approved examination, the applicant shall be allowed to sit for the examination and tested in the subjects the board may determine to be necessary. </section><section prefix="4">Examinations shall be held within the state at least once a year at the time and place as the board shall determine. </section><section prefix="5">An applicant who is admitted to the examination or an applicant who has submitted satisfactory evidence that he has been accepted as a candidate for licensure by examination in a state which offers an examination approved by the board may be granted a temporary permit which shall be valid until his examination is graded and he is notified by the board of his score. The board may summarily withdraw a temporary permit upon determination that the person has made any false statement to the board on the application, or the person fails to pass an examination approved by the board. </section><section prefix="6">An applicant who receives a passing score as determined by the board and who meets the other qualifications required by this chapter shall be licensed as a physical therapist. </section><section prefix="7">An applicant who fails to receive a passing score on his examination shall not be licensed, but the board may, by administrative regulation, permit applicants to take the examination more than once. </section><section prefix="8">All licenses and certificates shall be renewed biennially, upon payment on or before March 31 of each uneven-numbered year of a renewal fee in an amount to be promulgated by the board by administrative regulations. </section><section prefix="9">Licenses and certificates which are not renewed by March 31 of each uneven-numbered year shall lapse. </section><section prefix="10">This chapter shall not be construed to affect or prevent: <section prefix="a">A student of physical therapy from engaging in clinical practice under the supervision of a licensed physical therapist, as part of the student's educational program; </section><section prefix="b">A physical therapist who is licensed to practice in another state or country from conducting or participating in a clinical residency under the supervision of a physical therapist licensed in Kentucky and for a period of not more than ninety (90) days; </section><section prefix="c">A physical therapist who is licensed to practice in another state or country from conducting or participating in the teaching of physical therapy in connection with an educational program and for a period of not more than ninety (90) days; </section><section prefix="d">A physical therapist licensed in another state or country from performing therapy on members of the out-of-state sports or entertainment group they accompany to Kentucky; or </section><section prefix="e">The practice of chiropractic as defined in KRS 312.015(3). </section></section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 21, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 61, sec. 13, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 313, sec. 5, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 160, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 443, secs. 12, 25, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 377, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 72, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 53, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 313, sec. 6, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 115, sec. 5. -- Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 27, sec. 5, effective June 19, 1958. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44624</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>