<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="160" order_by="160">SCHOOL DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>160.305</section_number><catch_line>Contracts for use of school buses to transport persons eligible for transportation services. </catch_line><order_by>305</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services may enter into a contract with the local board of education of any school district in the Commonwealth for the use of school buses to transport persons eligible for transportation services at times when the buses are not needed to transport students to or from school or school events. Persons eligible for these transportation services shall be: <section prefix="a">Sixty-two (62) years of age or older; </section><section prefix="b">Those with physical or mental disabilities; or </section><section prefix="c">Any other person designated by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services as appropriate for these transportation services. </section></section><section prefix="2">Before this contract is entered into, the Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall formulate a plan for the use of school buses for these purposes and shall submit it to the local board of education for its approval or disapproval. The plan for the use of school buses for these transportation purposes shall include routes, schedules, cost, and any other matters deemed necessary by both parties. </section><section prefix="3">The cost of transporting persons eligible under the provisions of subsection (1) of this section shall be borne by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 135, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 117, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 405, sec. 28, effective July 15, 1994. -- Repealed and reenacted 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 435, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 322, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3708</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>