<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.964</section_number><catch_line>Health care facility not to restrict use of laetrile -- Exception. </catch_line><order_by>964</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When amygdalin (laetrile) is prescribed or administered by a physician holding a regular license for the practice of medicine in the State of Kentucky and the patient has signed a written informed request form, except as provided in subsection (2) of this section, a hospital or other health care facility shall not restrict or forbid the use of amygdalin (laetrile) in the treatment of any malignancy, disease, illness or physical condition. </section><section prefix="2">If the federal government states that it will withdraw all federal funds from a health care facility for allowing amygdalin (laetrile) to be used within the facility, and if providing or allowing its use within the facility would jeopardize the receipt of federal funds for reimbursement for medicine or Medicaid for all persons within the facility, or any construction funds provided by the federal government under the Hill-Burton Hospital Construction Program or under Title XVI of the Public Health Services Act, the hospital or other health care facility may, notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (1) of this section, prohibit the use of amygdalin (laetrile) within its facility. </section></text><history>Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 354, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1980 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30703</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>