<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17B-001</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for subtitle. </catch_line><order_by>17B-001</order_by><text>As used in this subtitle, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Administrator" is defined in KRS 304.9-051(1); </section><section prefix="2">"Agent" is defined in KRS 304.9-020; </section><section prefix="3">"Assessment process" means the process of assessing and allocating guaranteed acceptance program losses or Kentucky Access funding as provided for in KRS 304.17B-021; </section><section prefix="4">"Authority" means the Kentucky Health Care Improvement Authority; </section><section prefix="5">"Case management" means a process for identifying an enrollee with specific health care needs and interacting with the enrollee and their respective health care providers in order to facilitate the development and implementation of a plan that efficiently uses health care resources to achieve optimum health outcome; </section><section prefix="6">"Commissioner" is defined in KRS 304.1-050(1); </section><section prefix="7">"Department" is defined in KRS 304.1-050(2); </section><section prefix="8">"Earned premium" means the portion of premium paid by an insured that has been allocated to the insurer’s loss experience, expenses, and profit year to date; </section><section prefix="9">"Enrollee" means a person who is enrolled in a health benefit plan offered under Kentucky Access; </section><section prefix="10">"Eligible individual" is defined in KRS 304.17A-005(11); </section><section prefix="11">"Guaranteed acceptance program" or "GAP" means the Kentucky Guaranteed Acceptance Program established and operated under KRS 304.17A-400 to 304.17A-480; </section><section prefix="12">"Guaranteed acceptance program participating insurer" means an insurer that offered health benefit plans through December 31, 2000, in the individual market to guaranteed acceptance program qualified individuals; </section><section prefix="13">"Health benefit plan" is defined in KRS 304.17A-005(22); </section><section prefix="14">"High-cost condition" means acquired immune deficiency syndrome (AIDS), angina pectoris, ascites, chemical dependency, cirrhosis of the liver, coronary insufficiency, coronary occlusion, cystic fibrosis, Friedreich's ataxia, hemophilia, Hodgkin's disease, Huntington's chorea, juvenile diabetes, leukemia, metastatic cancer, motor or sensory aphasia, multiple sclerosis, muscular dystrophy, myasthenia gravis, myotonia, open-heart surgery, Parkinson's disease, polycystic kidney, psychotic disorders, quadriplegia, stroke, syringomyelia, Wilson's disease, chronic renal failure, malignant neoplasm of the trachea, malignant neoplasm of the bronchus, malignant neoplasm of the lung, malignant neoplasm of the colon, short gestation period for a newborn child, and low birth weight of a newborn child; </section><section prefix="15">"Incurred losses" means for Kentucky Access the excess of claims paid over premiums received; </section><section prefix="16">"Insurer" is defined in KRS 304.17A-005(27); </section><section prefix="17">"Kentucky Access" means the program established in accordance with KRS 304.17B-001 to 304.17B-031; </section><section prefix="18">"Kentucky Access Fund" means the fund established in KRS 304.17B-021; </section><section prefix="19">"Kentucky Health Care Improvement Authority" means the board established to administer the program initiatives listed in KRS 304.17B-003(5); </section><section prefix="20">"Kentucky Health Care Improvement Fund" means the fund established for receipt of the Kentucky tobacco master settlement moneys for program initiatives listed in KRS 304.17B-003(5); </section><section prefix="21">"MARS" means the Management Administrative Reporting System administered by the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="22">"Medicaid" means coverage in accordance with Title XIX of the Social Security Act, 42 U.S.C. secs. 1396 et seq., as amended; </section><section prefix="23">"Medicare" means coverage under both Parts A and B of Title XVIII of the Social Security Act, 42 U.S.C. secs. 1395 et seq., as amended; </section><section prefix="24">"Pre-existing condition exclusion" is defined in KRS 304.17A-220(6); </section><section prefix="25">"Standard health benefit plan" means a health benefit plan that meets the requirements of KRS 304.17A-250; </section><section prefix="26">"Stop-loss carrier" means any person providing stop-loss health insurance coverage; </section><section prefix="27">"Supporting insurer" means all insurers, stop-loss carriers, and self-insured employer-controlled or bona fide associations; and </section><section prefix="28">"Utilization management" is defined in KRS 304.17A-500(12). </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1273, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 253, sec. 6, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 144, sec. 10, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 4, effective June 24, 2003. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 476, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29385</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>