<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="173" order_by="173">CITY, COUNTY, AND REGIONAL LIBRARIES </unit></structure><section_number>173.730</section_number><catch_line>Board members -- Terms -- Vacancies to be filled by persons recommended by the board -- Removal of members -- Advisory board. </catch_line><order_by>730</order_by><text><section prefix="1">One-third (1/3) of the persons first appointed to the board shall serve for a term of two (2) years, one-third (1/3) for a term of three (3) years and one-third (1/3) for a term of four (4) years. Where the board consists of a number of members not divisible by three (3), one-third (1/3) of the next higher number divisible by three (3), shall serve for a term of two (2) years, one-third (1/3) for a term of three (3) years and the remaining number shall serve for a term of four (4) years. Thereafter, as their terms expire, their successors shall be recommended by the board. The board shall recommend two (2) persons committed to the provision of library services to the Department for Libraries and Archives, for each vacancy. The state librarian and commissioner shall recommend those names to the county judge/executive. The county judge/executive shall immediately, with the approval of the fiscal court, make the selection from those recommended. Board members thus appointed shall serve a term of four (4) years each. Trustees may serve for two </section><section prefix="2">consecutive terms after which they shall not succeed themselves. They may be </section>reappointed no earlier than twelve (12) months following the end of their last service. The members shall hold office until their respective successors are appointed and qualified. After absence of a trustee from four (4) regular monthly meetings of the board during any one (1) year of the trustee's term, the trustee shall be considered to have automatically resigned from the board. An advisory board may be appointed and serve as specified in bylaws of the board of trustees. (2) Any vacancy occurring in the terms of office of members shall be filled for the unexpired term by the county judge/executive, with the approval of the fiscal court, by appointment on recommendation of the state librarian and commissioner of two (2) persons interested in the provision of library services and living in the county in which the vacancy occurred. <section prefix="3">A member of the board may be removed from office as provided by KRS 65.007. </section></text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 58, sec. 11, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 218, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 245, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 18, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 8, sec. 8; and ch. 74, Art. VIII, B, sec. 1. -- Created 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4973</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>