<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.603</section_number><catch_line>Rape crisis center trust fund.   </catch_line><order_by>603</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is created a trust fund to be known as the rape crisis center trust fund. The fund shall be administered by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. </section><section prefix="2">The trust fund shall be funded with moneys collected through the designation of a taxpayer's refund as provided by KRS 141.447 and any contributions, gifts, donations, or appropriations designated for the trust fund. Moneys in the fund shall be used to support the services listed in KRS 211.600(3). No moneys in the fund shall be used to support abortion services or abortion education. </section><section prefix="3">Notwithstanding KRS 45.229, any moneys remaining in the fund at the close of the fiscal year shall not lapse but shall be carried forward into the succeeding fiscal year to be used for the purposes set forth in subsection (2) of this section. </section><section prefix="4">Any interest earned upon moneys in the rape crisis center trust fund shall become a part of the fund and shall not lapse. </section><section prefix="5">Moneys deposited in the fund are appropriated for the purposes set forth in this section and shall not be appropriated or transferred by the General Assembly for any other purposes. </section></text><history> Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 108, sec. 6, effective June 24, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44600</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>