<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>355.7-304</section_number><catch_line>Tangible bills of lading in a set.   </catch_line><order_by>7-304</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as customary in international transportation, a tangible bill of lading may not be issued in a set of parts. The issuer is liable for damages caused by violation of this subsection. </section><section prefix="2">If a tangible bill of lading is lawfully issued in a set of parts, each of which contains an identification code and is expressed to be valid only if the goods have not been delivered against any other part, the whole of the parts constitutes one (1) bill. </section><section prefix="3">If a tangible negotiable bill of lading is lawfully issued in a set of parts and different parts are negotiated to different persons, the title of the holder to which the first due negotiation is made prevails as to both the document of title and the goods even if any later holder may have received the goods from the carrier in good faith and discharged the carrier's obligation by surrendering its part. </section><section prefix="4">A person that negotiates or transfers a single part of a tangible bill of lading issued in a set is liable to holders of that part as if it were the whole set. </section><section prefix="5">The bailee is obliged to deliver in accordance with Part 4 of this article against the first presented part of a tangible bill of lading lawfully issued in a set. Delivery in this manner discharges the bailee's obligation on the whole bill. </section></text><history>Repealed and reenacted 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 20, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 7-304, effective July 1, 1960. </history><metadata><effective>July 12, 2012</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40621</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>