<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="502" order_by="502">PARTIES TO OFFENSES: ACCOUNTABILITY </unit></structure><section_number>502.020</section_number><catch_line>Liability for conduct of another -- Complicity. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of an offense committed by another person when, with the intention of promoting or facilitating the commission of the offense, he:  <section prefix="a">Solicits, commands, or engages in a conspiracy with such other person to commit the offense; or  </section><section prefix="b">Aids, counsels, or attempts to aid such person in planning or committing the offense; or  </section><section prefix="c">Having a legal duty to prevent the commission of the offense, fails to make a proper effort to do so.  </section></section><section prefix="2">When causing a particular result is an element of an offense, a person who acts with the kind of culpability with respect to the result that is sufficient for the commission of the offense is guilty of that offense when he:  <section prefix="a">Solicits or engages in a conspiracy with another person to engage in the conduct causing such result; or  </section><section prefix="b">Aids, counsels, or attempts to aid another person in planning, or engaging in the conduct causing such result; or  </section><section prefix="c">Having a legal duty to prevent the conduct causing the result, fails to make a proper effort to do so.  </section></section></text><history>Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 21, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 1975</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19660</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>