<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.1-520</section_number><catch_line>Site characterization report -- Corrective action plan. </catch_line><order_by>1-520</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon execution of an agreed order, the applicant shall submit to the cabinet within the agreed timeframe a site characterization report and a corrective action plan. </section><section prefix="2">The corrective action plan for properties involving hazardous substances over which the Department for Public Health has regulatory authority shall, at the time of submittal to the cabinet, also be submitted to the commissioner of the Department for Public Health. </section><section prefix="3">A corrective action plan shall comply with KRS 224.1-400, 224.1-405, 224.1-510 to 224.1-532, and any administrative regulations promulgated under these statutes, and shall include: <section prefix="a">Detailed documentation of the characterization conducted by the applicant to determine the nature and extent of the release or threatened release as required under KRS 224.1-400 and 224.1-405 and a description of any remediation performed on the site; </section><section prefix="b">A description of any corrective action and additional characterization proposed to complete the remediation in accordance with KRS 224.1-400 and 224.1-405, together with a proposed schedule for implementation; </section><section prefix="c">Descriptions of sampling and analysis methods, techniques, and results, and quality assurance methods and controls used or proposed; </section><section prefix="d">A description of measures to protect human health and safety during the remediation; </section><section prefix="e">A plan of action to inform the public about the remediation and redevelopment of the property and to provide for meaningful public comment; </section><section prefix="f">Identification of any limitations on land use or activity proposed for the site; </section><section prefix="g">Identification of any petroleum storage tanks on the site and an outline of how the applicant intends to comply with Subchapter 60 of KRS Chapter 224 and 401 KAR Chapter 42; and </section><section prefix="h">A requirement to update the corrective action plan to characterize and remediate releases discovered or caused during characterization or corrective action. </section></section></text><history> Created 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 128, sec. 6, effective June 21, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> June 21, 2001 </effective><former-codification>KRS 224.01-520. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41610</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>