<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.26-115</section_number><catch_line>Options for companies with preliminary approval or final agreement before July 13, 2004. </catch_line><order_by>26-115</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If, prior to July 13, 2004, the authority has given its preliminary approval designating an eligible company as a preliminarily approved company and authorizing the undertaking of an economic revitalization project, but has not entered into a final agreement with the company, the company shall have the one-time option to: <section prefix="a">Operate under the existing agreement as preliminarily approved; or </section><section prefix="b">Request the authority to amend the agreement to comply with the amendments to KRS 154.26-090, 154.26-100, 136.0704, and 141.310 in 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 18, secs. 1, 2, 4, and 5. </section></section><section prefix="2">If, prior to July 13, 2004, the authority has entered into a final agreement with an eligible company, and if the final agreement is still in effect, the company shall have the one-time option to: <section prefix="a">Operate under the existing final agreement; or </section><section prefix="b">Request the authority to amend only the employee assessment portion of the final agreement to comply with the amendment to KRS 154.26-100 in 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 2. </section></section></text><history> Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 3, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><lrc-note> (7/13/2004).  This section, as enacted in 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 3, is substantially similar to KRS 154.26-085, as enacted in 2004Ky. Acts ch.105, sec.  15. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2809</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>