<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="313" order_by="313">DENTISTS AND DENTAL SPECIALISTS </unit></structure><section_number>313.060</section_number><catch_line>Administrative regulations governing minimal requirements for documentation, oath for disease control compliance, sedation of patients, and compliance with federal statutes and regulations -- Death or incapacity of dentist -- Telehealth -- Continuing education. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A relating to dental practices which shall include minimal requirements for documentation, Centers for Disease Control compliance, conscious sedation of patients, compliance with federal controlled substances regulations, and any applicable federal statute or regulation. </section><section prefix="2">Any person practicing or offering to practice dentistry or dental surgery shall practice under his or her own name or the name of a deceased or incapacitated dentist for whom the person practicing dentistry has contracted to perform continuing operations. </section><section prefix="3">No person shall conduct a dental office in his or her name nor advertise his or her name in connection with any dental office unless he or she personally performs services as a dentist or dental surgeon in such office or personally supervises such services as are performed in such office during a portion of the time such office is operated by him or her only, and shall not use his or her name in connection with that of any other dentist, except as provided for deceased or incapacitated dentists in subsection (4) of this section. </section><section prefix="4">The executor or administrator of a deceased dentist's estate, or the legal guardian or authorized representative of a dentist who has become incapacitated, may contract with another dentist or dentists to continue the operations of the deceased or incapacitated dentist's practice if the practice of the deceased or incapacitated dentist is a: <section prefix="a">Sole proprietorship; </section><section prefix="b">Corporation in which the deceased or incapacitated dentist is the sole shareholder; or </section><section prefix="c">Limited liability company in which the deceased or incapacitated dentist is the sole member. </section></section><section prefix="5">Contracts to continue the operations of a deceased or incapacitated dentist's practice may extend until the practice is sold. </section><section prefix="6">Prior to contracting with another dentist or dentists to continue operations of a deceased or incapacitated dentist's practice, the executor, administrator, guardian, or authorized representative shall file a notification of intent to contract for continuation of practice with the board on a form prescribed by the board. The notification shall include the following information: <section prefix="a">The name and license number of the deceased or incapacitated dentist; </section><section prefix="b">The name and address of the dental practice; </section><section prefix="c">The name, address, and tax identification number of the estate; </section><section prefix="d">The name and license number of each dentist who will provide services in the dental practice; </section><section prefix="e">An affirmation, under penalty of perjury, that the information provided is true and correct and that the executor, administrator, guardian, or authorized representative understands that any interference by the executor, administrator, guardian, or authorized representative, or any agent or assignee of the executor, administrator, guardian, or authorized representative, with the contracting dentist's or dentists' practice of dentistry or professional judgment or any other violation of this chapter is grounds for an immediate termination of the operations of the dental practice; and </section><section prefix="f">Any other information the board deems necessary for the administration of this chapter. </section></section><section prefix="7">Within thirty (30) days after the death or incapacitation of a dentist, the executor, administrator, guardian, or authorized representative shall send notification of the death or incapacitation by mail to the last known address of each patient of record that has received treatment by the deceased or incapacitated dentist within the previous twelve (12) months, with an explanation of how copies of the practitioner's records may be obtained. This notice may also contain any other relevant information concerning the continuation of dental practice. </section><section prefix="8">A treating dentist who provides or facilitates the use of telehealth shall ensure: <section prefix="a">That the informed consent of the patient, or another appropriate person with authority to make the health care treatment decision for the patient, is obtained before services are provided through telehealth; and </section><section prefix="b">That the confidentiality of the patient's medical information is maintained as required by this chapter and other applicable law. At a minimum, confidentiality shall be maintained through appropriate processes, practices, and technology as designated by the board and that conform to applicable federal law. </section></section><section prefix="9">The board shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to implement this section and as necessary to: <section prefix="a">Prevent abuse and fraud through the use of telehealth services; </section><section prefix="b">Prevent fee-splitting through the use of telehealth services; and </section><section prefix="c">Utilize telehealth in the provision of dental services and in the provision of continuing education. </section></section><section prefix="10">A licensed dentist may delegate to a licensed dental hygienist the administration of block and infiltration anesthesia and nitrous oxide analgesia under the direct supervision of a dentist if the dental hygienist completes the following requirements and receives a certificate of verification from the board: <section prefix="a">Formal training from a dental or dental hygiene school accredited by the Commission on Dental Accreditation; </section><section prefix="b">A minimum of thirty-two (32) hours covering all of the following topics, including but not limited to anatomical considerations, basic injunction technique, basic placement technique, nitrous oxide administration, recordkeeping, armamentarium exercise, local anesthesia and nitrous oxide, techniques of maxillary anesthesia, techniques of mandibular injections, partner injections and partner administration of nitrous oxide, neurophysiology, pharmacology of local anesthetics and nitrous oxide, pharmacology of vasoconstrictors, physical and psychological evaluation, local and systemic complications, and contraindications; </section><section prefix="c">A minimum of two (2) hours of clinical education for nitrous oxide administration with successful completion of administration, monitoring, and removal of nitrous oxide on at least two (2) patients; </section><section prefix="d">A minimum of twelve (12) hours demonstrating mastery of local anesthesia applications and successful completion of at least three (3) injections each of all maxillary and mandibular injection sites; and </section><section prefix="e">A score that exceeds seventy-four percent (74%) on a written examination administered after coursework and clinical training. </section></section><section prefix="11">The board shall approve all continuing education courses and require them for individuals holding anesthesia registration for over one (1) year without practical application. The courses shall be developed and implemented by dental education institutions accredited by the Commission on Dental Accreditation. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 10, effective July 15, 2010. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2636-10. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30815</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>