<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XLII" order_by="42">MISCELLANEOUS PRACTICE PROVISIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="456" order_by="456">CIVIL ORDERS OF PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>456.140</section_number><catch_line>Filing copy of foreign protective order -- Effect -- Required affidavit --Certification by issuing court -- Uncertified order.  (Effective January 1,2016)</catch_line><order_by>140</order_by><text>(1)A copy of a foreign protective order may be filed in the office of the clerk of anycourt of competent jurisdiction of this state. A foreign protective order so filedshall have the same effect and shall be enforced in the same manner as aninterpersonal protective order issued by a court of this state.(2)(a)At the time of the filing of the foreign protective order, the person filing theorder shall file with the clerk of the court an affidavit on a form prescribedand provided by the Administrative Office of the Courts. The affidavit shallset forth the name, city, county, and state or other jurisdiction of theissuing court. The person shall certify in the affidavit the validity andstatus of the foreign protective order, and attest to the person's belief thatthe order has not been amended, rescinded, or superseded by any ordersfrom a court of competent jurisdiction. All foreign protective orderspresented with a completed and signed affidavit shall be accepted andfiled.(b)The affidavit signed by the applicant shall have space where thereviewing judge shall place information necessary to allow the order'sentry into the Law Information Network of Kentucky in the same manneras a Kentucky order.(3)(a)If the person seeking to file the order presents a copy of the foreignprotective order which is current by the terms of the order and has beencertified by the clerk or other authorized officer of the court which issuedit, the circuit clerk shall present it to the District Judge or Circuit Judge,who shall read the order and enter on the affidavit the informationnecessary to allow the order's entry into the Law Information Network ofKentucky. The order shall not be subject to further verification and shallbe accepted as authentic, current, and subject to full faith and credit.(b)If the order presented is current by the terms of the order but is notcertified in the manner specified in paragraph (a) of this subsection, thecircuit clerk shall present the order and the affidavit to the District orCircuit Judge, who shall read the order and enter on the affidavit theinformation necessary to allow the order's entry into the Law InformationNetwork of Kentucky. The order shall be subject to full faith and credit inthe same manner as a Kentucky interpersonal protective order, but shallbe subject to verification by the circuit clerk. The order shall be valid for aperiod of fourteen (14) days and may be renewed once for a period offourteen (14) days if the circuit clerk has not received a certified copy ofthe order from the issuing jurisdiction. The clerk shall treat the foreignprotective order in the same manner as an interpersonal protective orderof this state issued pursuant to KRS 456.060, except that no service onthe adverse party shall be required pursuant to 18 U.S.C. sec. 2265.(c)Upon the filing of an uncertified foreign protective order, the circuit clerkshall, within two (2) business days, contact the issuing court to request acertified copy of the order. If the certified copy of the order is received bythe circuit clerk within the initial fourteen (14) day period, the clerk shallcause the information that certification has been received to be enteredinto the Law Information Network of Kentucky and shall notify theapplicant for the order of the fact of its certification. A facsimile copy of acertified foreign protective order shall be grounds for the issuance of aninterpersonal protective order.(d)If the clerk has not received a certified copy of the foreign protective orderwithin ten (10) days, the clerk shall notify the court and the applicant thatthe order has not been received. The notice to the applicant, on a formprepared by the Administrative Office of the Courts, shall state that theforeign protective order will be extended for another fourteen (14) days,but will be dismissed at the expiration of that time. If the clerk informs thejudge in writing that the certified foreign protective order has beenrequested but has not yet been received, the judge shall extend theforeign protective order for a period of fourteen (14) days. If certification ofthe foreign protective order is not received within twenty-eight (28) days,the foreign protective order shall expire and shall not be reissued. If theapplicant meets the qualifications for the issuance of a Kentuckyinterpersonal protective order, the court may, upon proper application andshowing of evidence, issue a Kentucky order in accordance with thischapter.(4)The right of a person filing a foreign protective order to bring an action toenforce the order instead of proceeding under this chapter remains unimpaired.</text><history>Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 32, effective January 1, 2016.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:24</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44780</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>