<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="281" order_by="281">MOTOR CARRIERS </unit></structure><section_number>281.631</section_number><catch_line>Motor carrier vehicle license -- Applications -- Fees -- Bulk application fees -- Requirements for license -- City and county license fees -- Exemption for nonresident motor carriers -- Partial fees for additional carriers -- Administrative regulations.   </catch_line><order_by>631</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall act as a motor carrier without first obtaining a motor carrier vehicle license from the department for each motor carrier vehicle. </section><section prefix="2">Application for and renewal of a motor carrier vehicle license shall be made in such form as the department may require. Every motor carrier vehicle license shall be renewed annually. </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">Except as permitted under paragraph (b) of this subsection, an applicant or license holder shall pay to the department the following annual license fees: <section prefix="1">Thirty dollars ($30) for each taxicab, limousine, TNC, or disabled persons vehicle; </section><section prefix="2">Ten dollars ($10) for each motor carrier vehicle transporting household goods for hire; </section><section prefix="3">One hundred dollars ($100) for each charter bus or bus; </section><section prefix="4">Fifteen dollars ($15) for each motor carrier vehicle operating as a U-Drive-It; </section><section prefix="5">Ten dollars ($10) for each motor carrier vehicle transporting property other than household goods and those exempt under KRS 281.605; </section><section prefix="6">Ten dollars ($10) for each motor carrier vehicle operating as a driveaway; and </section><section prefix="7">Ten dollars ($10) for each automobile utility trailer. </section></section><section prefix="b">The cabinet may promulgate administrative regulations to set forth an optional motor carrier vehicle license fee schedule under this subsection on a bulk basis for applicants who employ or contract with more than fifty (50) vehicles. Bulk application fees under these administrative regulations may use a tiered system based on the type of certificate and the number of vehicles. </section></section><section prefix="4">Before the department may issue or renew a motor carrier vehicle license, the applicant or license holder shall: <section prefix="a">Pay the fee established under subsection (3) of this section; </section><section prefix="b">For a taxicab, limousine, disabled persons vehicle, TNC vehicle, charter bus, and bus, provide a copy of the vehicle registration for each out-of-state registered motor carrier vehicle being licensed, and if necessary, a statement showing that the driver is an insured driver of the vehicle, and that the registered owner or lessee authorizes the use of the vehicle for TNC services; and </section><section prefix="c">For a taxicab, limousine, disabled persons vehicle, TNC vehicle, charter bus, and bus, obtain and retain for a period of at least three (3) years, an inspection of the motor vehicle in the manner and form as the department may require. </section></section><section prefix="5">No motor carrier vehicle shall be operated after the expiration of the motor carrier vehicle license under which it is operated. </section><section prefix="6">All cities or counties of the Commonwealth may impose an annual license fee on an intrastate taxicab, limousine, or disabled persons vehicle operated from said city or county. The annual license fee shall not exceed thirty dollars ($30) per vehicle. </section><section prefix="7">Notwithstanding any other provisions of this section, nonresident motor carriers engaged in transporting passengers for hire in irregular route interstate charter or special operations shall be exempt from all fees prescribed in this chapter, if reciprocal privileges are granted to similar nonresident carriers by the laws and regulations of his or her state. </section><section prefix="8">If any person required to pay a license fee under subsection (3) of this section begins the operation of an additional motor carrier vehicle after the date of its certificate or renewal, the fee shall be as many twelfths of the annual fee as there are unexpired months in the certificate or renewal year. </section><section prefix="9">The department may promulgate administrative regulations as it deems necessary to carry out. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 19, sec. 12, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 331, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1956 (2nd Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 2, effective March 29, 1956. -- Created 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 212, secs. 1 and 2. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44161</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>