<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="209" order_by="209">PROTECTION OF ADULTS </unit></structure><section_number>209.160</section_number><catch_line>Spouse abuse shelter fund -- Department of Revenue to administer -- Cabinet for Health and Family Services to use -- Primary service providers. </catch_line><order_by>160</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created a trust and agency account in the State Treasury to be known as the domestic violence shelter fund. Each county clerk shall remit to the fund, by the tenth of the month, ten dollars ($10) from each twenty-four dollars ($24) collected during the previous month from the issuance of marriage licenses. The fund shall be administered by the Department of Revenue. The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall use the funds for the purpose of providing protective shelter services for domestic violence victims. </section><section prefix="2">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall designate one (1) nonprofit corporation in each area development district to serve as the primary service provider and regional planning authority for domestic violence shelter, crisis, and advocacy services in the district in which the designated provider is located. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 624, effective June 20, 2005; ch. 99, sec. 295, effective June 20, 2005; and ch. 132, sec. 28, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 240, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 428, sec. 35, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 338, sec. 18. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 161, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><lrc-note> (6/20/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 95, 97, 98, 99, 123, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section.  (6/20/2005).  This section was amended by 2005 Ky. Acts chs. 85, 99 and 132, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8196</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>