<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">A DRIVING UNDER THE INFLUENCE </unit></structure><section_number>189A.020</section_number><catch_line>Community labor program -- Terms and conditions. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text>All community labor shall be under the supervision of the court and subject to the following: <section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">No period of labor shall be less than four (4) hours to qualify for satisfaction of </section>a sentence; <section prefix="b">A "day" shall mean eight (8) hours of labor; </section><section prefix="c">A "month" shall mean twenty (20) days of labor; </section><section prefix="d">Periods of labor four (4) hours or longer may be cumulated to meet the requirements under this section; </section></section><section prefix="2">Labor shall be done for public agencies, nonprofit corporations or eleemosynary institutions only; </section><section prefix="3">Any agency for whom a person works shall agree to supervise such person and report to the court: <section prefix="a">The hours worked, </section><section prefix="b">The quality of the work, </section><section prefix="c">The nature of the work; </section></section><section prefix="4">An agency may refuse to accept persons under this program or to accept any particular person or persons sent by the court; </section><section prefix="5">The court shall maintain a list of agencies willing to accept and supervise persons sentenced under this program; </section><section prefix="6">The court may contract, at no cost to the state or participant, with any public agency or nonprofit corporation or eleemosynary institution for the supervision of persons in the program; </section><section prefix="7">No work performed under this program shall be deemed employment for any purpose nor shall the person performing such work be considered an employee; </section><section prefix="8">Failure to complete the community labor ordered by the court, to perform diligently at that labor, or to pay the fee required shall constitute contempt of court and the court shall, in addition to any other remedy for contempt, reinstitute all penalties which were previously imposed but suspended or delayed pending completion of the community labor. </section></text><history>Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6485</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>