<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>355.3-411</section_number><catch_line>Refusal to pay cashier's checks, teller's checks, and certified checks. </catch_line><order_by>3-411</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In this section, "obligated bank" means the acceptor of a certified check or the issuer of a cashier's check or teller's check bought from the issuer. </section><section prefix="2">If the obligated bank wrongfully: <section prefix="a">Refuses to pay a cashier's check or certified check; </section><section prefix="b">Stops payment of a teller's check; or </section><section prefix="c">Refuses to pay a dishonored teller's check, </section></section> the person asserting the right to enforce the check is entitled to compensation for expenses and loss of interest resulting from the nonpayment and may recover consequential damages if the obligated bank refuses to pay after receiving notice of particular circumstances giving rise to the damages. <section prefix="3">Expenses or consequential damages under subsection (2) of this section are not recoverable if the refusal of the obligated bank to pay occurs because: <section prefix="a">The bank suspends payments; </section><section prefix="b">The obligated bank asserts a claim or defense of the bank that it has reasonable grounds to believe is available against the person entitled to enforce the instrument; </section><section prefix="c">The obligated bank has a reasonable doubt whether the person demanding payment is the person entitled to enforce the instrument; or </section><section prefix="d">Payment is prohibited by law. </section></section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 49, effective January 1, 1997. -- Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 3-411, effective July 1, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 1997 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33481</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>