<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="514" order_by="514">THEFT AND RELATED OFFENSES </unit></structure><section_number>514.090</section_number><catch_line>Theft of labor already rendered. </catch_line><order_by>090</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of theft of labor already rendered when, in payment of labor already rendered by another, he intentionally issues or passes a check or similar sight order for the payment of money, knowing that it will not be honored by the drawee. </section><section prefix="2">For purposes of subsection (1) of this section, an issuer of a check or similar sight order for the payment of money is presumed to know that the check or order, other than a postdated check or order, would not be paid, if: <section prefix="a">The issuer had no account with the drawee at the time the check or order was issued; or </section><section prefix="b">Payment was refused by the drawee for lack of funds, upon presentation within thirty days (30) after issue, and the issuer failed to make good within ten (10) days after receiving notice of that refusal. </section></section><section prefix="3">Theft of labor already rendered is a Class A misdemeanor unless the value of the labor rendered is: <section prefix="a">Five hundred dollars ($500) or more but less than ten thousand dollars ($10,000), in which case it is a Class D felony; or </section><section prefix="b">Ten thousand dollars ($10,000) or more, in which case it is a Class C felony. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 12, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 451, sec. 7, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 125, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19811</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>