<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.2226</section_number><catch_line>Definitions -- Vehicles hauling building materials. </catch_line><order_by>2226</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Bill of lading" means a document evidencing the purchase of, or delivery order for, building materials issued by a person engaged in a business that sold or leased the building materials; </section><section prefix="b">"Building materials" means equipment or materials associated with new home construction, home remodeling, or home maintenance, including but not limited to: <section prefix="1">Agriculture products; </section><section prefix="2">Asphalt; </section><section prefix="3">Concrete; </section><section prefix="4">Crushed stone; </section><section prefix="5">Excavation equipment; </section><section prefix="6">Fill dirt and rock; </section><section prefix="7">Glass; </section><section prefix="8">Landscaping materials; </section><section prefix="9">Lumber or other wood products; </section><section prefix="10">Minerals; </section><section prefix="11">Roofing materials; and </section><section prefix="12">Steel products; </section></section><section prefix="c">"Home" means: <section prefix="1">A site where a single or multi-family housing unit is being initially constructed; and </section><section prefix="2">A site where construction of a single or multi-family housing unit is complete and persons inhabit the housing unit; and </section></section><section prefix="d">"State road" means a state or federal highway but does not mean an interstate or county road. </section></section><section prefix="2">Other statutes to the contrary in this chapter notwithstanding, any vehicle hauling building materials to a home shall be allowed, subject to the provisions of this section, to travel on any state road without a permit and without being subject to a fine, if the weight of the vehicle is within the limits of the registration issued to the vehicle and within the axle limits for the vehicle, even if the vehicle's gross weight or length, including vehicle and load, exceed the limits prescribed by this chapter or in other aspects fail to comply with this chapter. </section><section prefix="3">A vehicle hauling building materials under this section shall be allowed to travel the most direct route, in the opinion of the operator, to the vehicle's point of destination, provided any road traveled as the most direct route shall not be further than fifteen (15) miles from a state road that is classified to carry the registered weight of the vehicle. If a vehicle is traveling a road classified by the cabinet as a single "A" highway, the vehicle or its load cannot exceed ninety-six (96) inches in width. If a vehicle or its load exceed ninety-six (96) inches in width, the operator shall be required to obtain the appropriate overdimensional permit required by this chapter to travel the proposed route. The operator of a vehicle hauling building materials under this section shall have in his or her possession a bill of lading. </section><section prefix="4">All vehicles hauling building materials under this section shall be prohibited from exceeding the established width and posted bridge weight limits for any route the vehicle travels. A vehicle that exceeds the width or bridge limits for its posted routes shall be required to obtain the appropriate overdimensional or overweight permit required by this chapter. </section></text><history> Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 34, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6329</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>