<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="190" order_by="190">MOTOR VEHICLE SALES </unit></structure><section_number>190.031</section_number><catch_line>Automotive mobility dealers -- License and regulation requirements. </catch_line><order_by>031</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person, prior to engaging or continuing in the business of an automotive mobility dealer after June 26, 2007, shall obtain an automotive mobility dealer license from the commission. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">An automotive mobility dealer shall be licensed and regulated by the commission under the provisions of this chapter. </section><section prefix="b">The commission shall, by administrative regulations promulgated under KRS Chapter 13A, establish requirements for initial application for and renewal of a license to be an automotive mobility dealer. The commission's regulations establishing requirements for automotive mobility dealers shall include provisions for automotive mobility dealers to meet reasonable and appropriate quality assurance requirements. These requirements may include: <section prefix="1">Appropriate training by automotive mobility dealers regarding adapted vehicle usage; </section><section prefix="2">Driver evaluation by automotive mobility dealers; and </section><section prefix="3">A requirement that automotive mobility dealers obtain and maintain insurance in an amount to be established by the commission. </section></section> The commission shall have the power to promulgate any other regulations that are necessary to implement this section. <section prefix="c">The commission shall immediately suspend the license of an automotive mobility dealer if it determines that the dealer has sold or modified a vehicle that does not comply with this section or any administrative regulations promulgated thereunder. A dealer whose license is suspended under this paragraph shall be permitted to appeal the suspension in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section></section><section prefix="3">A licensed automotive mobility dealer shall have the right to display, inventory, advertise, and offer for sale any adapted vehicle. </section></text><history> Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 125, sec. 2, effective June 26, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6526</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>