<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="217" order_by="217">B FERTILIZER AND PESTICIDE USE AND APPLICATION </unit></structure><section_number>217B.545</section_number><catch_line>Suspension, revocation, or modification of applicator's or manager's license -- Procedure -- Waiting period for eligibility for reapplication. </catch_line><order_by>545</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The department may suspend, revoke, or modify the provision of any applicator's or manager's license issued under KRS 217B.515 to 217B.520 if it finds that the licensee has committed any of the acts set forth in KRS 217B.550. </section><section prefix="2">The license holder shall have ten (10) days upon the receipt of the notification of a proposed suspension, revocation, or modification of license to request a hearing. The hearing shall be conducted in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section><section prefix="3">If a hearing is not requested as provided for in subsection (2) of this section, the department may suspend, revoke, or modify the license once the ten (10) day hearing request filing period has passed. </section><section prefix="4">Any licensee whose license is revoked under the provisions of this section shall not be eligible to apply for a new license until time has elapsed from the date of the final order revoking the license as established by the department, not to exceed two (2) years, or if an appeal is taken from the final order or revocation, not to exceed two (2) years from the date of the final order or final judgment sustaining the revocation. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 127, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 250, sec. 6, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 10, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9570</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>