<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="244" order_by="244">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- PROHIBITIONS, RESTRICTIONS, AND REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>244.590</section_number><catch_line>Brewer or distributor prohibited from offering certain inducements to retailers -- Brewer or distributor may furnish advertising matter or cleaning service to retailer.   </catch_line><order_by>590</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No brewer or distributor shall induce through any of the following means any retailer selling malt beverages by the package or drink to purchase any malt beverages from him or her to the exclusion in whole or in part of malt beverages sold or offered for sale by other persons, if the brewer or distributor engages in the practice of using such means, or any of them, to such an extent as substantially to restrain or prevent transactions in commerce in malt beverages: <section prefix="a">By acquiring or holding, after the expiration of any existing license, any interest in any license with respect to the premises of the retailer; </section><section prefix="b">By acquiring any interest in real or personal property owned, occupied, or used by the retailer in the conduct of his or her business; </section><section prefix="c">By furnishing, giving, renting, lending, or selling to the retailer, any equipment, fixtures, signs, supplies, money, services, or other things of value, except as the director of the Division of Malt Beverages, having regard for the public health, the quantity and value of the articles involved, the prevention of monopoly, and the practice of deception, may by administrative regulation otherwise prescribe; </section><section prefix="d">By paying or crediting the retailer for any advertising, display, or distribution service subject to the exceptions which the director may by administrative regulation prescribe; </section><section prefix="e">By guaranteeing any loan or the repayment of any financial obligation of the retailer; or </section><section prefix="f">By requiring the retailer to take and dispose of a certain quota of any malt beverages. </section></section><section prefix="2">Notwithstanding any provisions in KRS Chapter 244 and this section, a brewer or distributor may: <section prefix="a">Give, rent, loan, or sell to any retailer selling malt beverages by the package or drink signs, posters, placards, designs, devices, decorations, or graphic displays bearing advertising matter and for use in windows or elsewhere in the interior of a retail malt beverage establishment; and </section><section prefix="b">Provide or furnish draught-line cleaning or coil-cleaning service to a nonquota retail malt beverage package licensee either directly or indirectly with the consent of the distributor. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 97, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 4, effective July 13, 2004. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2554b-213. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><lrc-note> (6/20/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 95, 97, 98, 99, 123, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42532</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>