<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>355.9-304</section_number><catch_line>Law governing perfection and priority of security interests in deposit accounts. </catch_line><order_by>9-304</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The local law of a bank’s jurisdiction governs perfection, the effect of perfection or nonperfection, and the priority of a security interest in a deposit account maintained with that bank. </section><section prefix="2">The following rules determine a bank’s jurisdiction for purposes of this part of this article: <section prefix="a">If an agreement between the bank and its customer governing the deposit account expressly provides that a particular jurisdiction is the bank’s jurisdiction for purposes of this part of this article, this article, or this chapter, that jurisdiction is the bank’s jurisdiction. </section><section prefix="b">If paragraph (a) of this subsection does not apply and an agreement between the bank and its customer governing the deposit account expressly provides that the agreement is governed by the law of a particular jurisdiction, that jurisdiction is the bank’s jurisdiction. </section><section prefix="c">If neither paragraph (a) nor (b) of this subsection applies and an agreement between the bank and its customer governing the deposit account expressly provides that the deposit account is maintained at an office in a particular jurisdiction, that jurisdiction is the bank’s jurisdiction. </section><section prefix="d">If none of the preceding paragraphs applies, the bank’s jurisdiction is the jurisdiction in which the office identified in an account statement as the office serving the customer’s account is located. </section><section prefix="e">If none of the preceding paragraphs applies, the bank’s jurisdiction is the jurisdiction in which the chief executive office of the bank is located. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 242, sec. 58, effective July 12, 2006. -- Repealed and reenacted 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 408, sec. 44, effective July 1, 2001. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 174, effective January 1, 1997. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 65, effective July 1, 1987. -- Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 9-304, effective July 1, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33757</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>