<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.812</section_number><catch_line>Employee benefits.   </catch_line><order_by>812</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All certified, equivalent, and unclassified employees in the Office of Career and Technical Education shall be: <section prefix="a">Provided the same health insurance coverage as all other state government employees provided in KRS 18A.225; </section><section prefix="b">Eligible to participate in the deferred compensation system provided for all state government employees by KRS 18A.250 to 18A.265; </section><section prefix="c">Provided the same life insurance coverage provided all state employees pursuant to KRS 18A.205 to 18A.215; </section><section prefix="d">Reimbursed for all reasonable and necessary travel expenses and disbursements incurred or made pursuant to KRS 45.101 in the performance of their official duties; no part of the reimbursement shall be included in or accounted as a part of their salaries; </section><section prefix="e">Ensured equal employment opportunity regardless of race, color, religion, national origin, disability, sex, or age; and </section><section prefix="f">Given those holidays and rights granted state employees pursuant to KRS 18A.190. </section></section><section prefix="2">Employees under the jurisdiction of the former Department for Technical Education who are members of a state retirement system as of June 30, 1990, shall remain in their respective retirement systems. All new certified and equivalent employees hired by the office shall be placed in the Kentucky Teachers' Retirement System. </section></text><history> Repealed, reenacted, and renumbered 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 9, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 25, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 526, sec. 19, effective August 15, 2000. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 405, sec. 17, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 469, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 470, sec. 6, effective July 1, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, C, 3, (17) at 631. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><former-codification>KRS 151B.040. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42163</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>