<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="220" order_by="220">SANITATION DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>220.322</section_number><catch_line>Disconnections, reconnections, and relocations of water inflows -- Powers of board -- Use of funds -- Fees -- Responsibility of property owner. </catch_line><order_by>322</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, the board of directors of the district may adopt rules requiring owners of property within the district whose property is served by a connection of sewers maintained and operated by the district or whose sewers are connected to interceptor sewers maintained and operated by the district to: <section prefix="a">Disconnect storm water inflows to sanitary sewers maintained and operated by the district and not operated as a combined sewer, or to connections with these sewers; </section><section prefix="b">Disconnect nonstorm water inflows to storm water sewers to the extent the sewers are maintained and operated by the district and not operated as a combined sewer, or to connections with these sewers; </section><section prefix="c">Reconnect or relocate any disconnected inflows in compliance with rules and regulations of the district and applicable building codes, health codes, or other relevant law or administrative regulation. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any inflow required to be disconnected under a rule adopted pursuant to this chapter shall constitute a nuisance subject to injunctive relief and abatement pursuant to this chapter, or as otherwise permitted by law. </section><section prefix="3">The board of directors of a district may expend district funds, and other moneys from state or federal sources to the extent permitted by their terms, loans, or grants, for either of the following: <section prefix="a">The cost of disconnections, reconnections, or relocations required by rules adopted pursuant to this chapter, performed by district personnel or persons under contract with the district; </section><section prefix="b">Payments to the property owner or a contractor hired by the property owner pursuant to a competitive process for the cost of disconnections, reconnections, or relocations required by rules adopted pursuant to this chapter after the board of directors has approved the work to be performed and after the district has received from the property owner a statement releasing the district from all liability in connection with the disconnections, reconnections, or relocations. </section></section><section prefix="4">Except as provided in subsection (6) of this section, the board of directors of the district shall require in its rules regarding disconnections, reconnections, or relocations of sewers the reimbursement of moneys expended pursuant to subsection (3) of this section. This shall be done by the district assessing a charge to the property owner in the amount of the payment made pursuant to subsection (3) of this section for immediate payment or payments in installment with interest as determined by the board of directors not to exceed ten percent (10%). The payments may be billed as a separate item and in addition to any other fees charged to that owner for the usage of the sewers as may be required by the district. The board of directors may approve installment payments for a period of not more than fifteen (15) years. Charges not paid when due may cause the board of directors to compel payment in the manner authorized in this chapter and the rules and regulations of the district. </section><section prefix="5">The district may specify the maximum amount of the cost of any disconnection, reconnection, or relocation required pursuant to subsection (1) of this section that may be paid by the district for each affected parcel of property without requiring reimbursement. The board of directors shall determine the maximum amount for each qualifying parcel that does not need to be reimbursed. </section><section prefix="6">Disconnections, reconnections, or relocations required under this section performed by a contractor under contract with the property owner shall not be subject to competitive bidding laws of the Commonwealth of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="7">Property owners shall be responsible for maintaining any improvements made to private property to reconnect or relocate disconnected inflows pursuant to this section unless a recorded public easement, dated prior to January 1, 1994, exists requiring maintenance by a city, county or sanitation district. </section><section prefix="8">No provisions of this section shall apply to any municipal customer of the district which as of January 1, 1998, owns, operates, and maintains a separate storm sewer utility, provided the utility is adequately funded and performs at a level that is equal to or greater than the storm water facilities of the district capitalized. All these municipal customers shall only be responsible for the cost of that municipal facility. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 234, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9804</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>