<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IV" order_by="4">JUDICIAL BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="27" order_by="27">A JUDICIAL SUPPORT AGENCIES AND PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>27A.600</section_number><catch_line>Designation of nonprofit legal services agencies -- Funding -- Promotion of pro bono legal assistance. </catch_line><order_by>600</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For each judicial district, the Chief Justice of the Commonwealth of Kentucky shall designate a nonprofit agency to operate and administer programs for the provision of legal services to indigent clients involved in civil matters within the judicial district. <section prefix="a">This agency shall be the nonprofit legal services organization designated as eligible to receive funds from the federal Legal Services Corporation for the provision of civil legal services to the indigent, if one exists. The nonprofit legal services organization shall receive supplemental funds provided by this section for each county in the district in which it provides service. </section><section prefix="b">At least twelve and one-half percent (12.5%) of any funds appropriated pursuant to subsection (1)(a) shall be used to promote increased participation by the private bar in the delivery of legal services to the indigent through pro bono efforts, which may include the operation of intake and referral systems; the provision of professional education regarding legal matters peculiar to the indigent; the provision of technical co-counselling assistance to private attorneys engaged in representing indigent clients in civil matters; and reimbursement of reasonable costs and expenses incurred by private attorneys in delivering pro bono legal assistance. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed as limiting the maximum amount of funds appropriated under this section which may be used for promotion of pro bono efforts by the private bar, where the local legal services organization's board of directors deems that an effective and efficient system of delivering legal assistance to the local indigent population would require the allocation of a sum in excess of twelve and one-half percent (12.5%) of the funds disbursed pursuant to this section. The local organization's board of directors shall annually review the appropriate allocation of funds from this section for the promotion of pro bono services by the private bar. </section><section prefix="c">If any county in the Commonwealth is not currently served by a nonprofit agency eligible to receive funds from the federal Legal Services Corporation, the Chief Justice shall designate a nonprofit agency to provide legal services to indigent clients in civil matters within that county. </section></section><section prefix="2">In designating an agency pursuant to subsection (1) of this section, the Chief Justice shall consult with the Chief Circuit Judge of the judicial district, the president of the local bar association within the county or the judicial district, and agencies providing legal services to indigent clients in civil matters within the judicial district. The designated agency may serve one (1) or more counties within the judicial district, and designation of a multicounty agency shall be undertaken if consultations indicate that it would promote efficient use of funds. To receive designation, an agency shall certify to the Chief Justice that: <section prefix="a">It is incorporated under the laws of the Commonwealth of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="b">It is an organization within the meaning of Section 501 (c) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986; and </section><section prefix="c">All persons participating in delivery of legal services to agency clients provide the service without any fee to the client for these services. </section></section></text><history> Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 338, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20969</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>