<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="309" order_by="309">MISCELLANEOUS OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS </unit></structure><section_number>309.325</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 309.325  to 309.339.     </catch_line><order_by>325</order_by><text>As used in KRS 309.325 to 309.339, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Board" means the Kentucky Board of Licensed Diabetes Educators; </section><section prefix="2">"Diabetes education" means a comprehensive collaborative process through which people with or at risk for diabetes gain the knowledge and skills needed to modify behavior and successfully self-manage the disease and its related conditions; </section><section prefix="3">"Licensed diabetes educator" means a health care professional who has met the requirements of KRS 309.335, 309.337, and 309.339 and who focuses on training or educating people with or at risk for diabetes and related conditions to change their behavior to achieve better clinical outcomes and improved health status. The nondiabetes educator health professional and the nonhealth-care professional who provide or support health care services to individuals with diabetes as defined by the American Association of Diabetes Educators, Competencies for Diabetes Educators, shall work under the direction of a qualified diabetes care provider; </section><section prefix="4">"Practice of diabetes education" means assessing and developing a plan of care for a person with or at risk of diabetes, identifying self-management goals for the person, providing self-management training according to the plan, evaluating the individual's outcome and recording a complete record of the individual's experience and follow-ups; </section><section prefix="5">"Apprentice diabetes educator" means a person who holds a permit issued by the board to practice diabetes education who meets the requirements of KRS 309.334 and the corresponding administrative regulations promulgated by the board; and </section><section prefix="6">"Master licensed diabetes educator" means a licensed diabetes educator who has successfully completed the credentialing program of the American Association of Diabetes Educators or the National Certification Board for Diabetes Educators as a certified diabetes educator or a board-certified advanced diabetes manager. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 142, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch.  87, sec.  1, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42413</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>