<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="36" order_by="36">DEPARTMENT OF MILITARY AFFAIRS </unit></structure><section_number>36.260</section_number><catch_line>Duties of board. </catch_line><order_by>260</order_by><text>The board shall: <section prefix="1">Establish and maintain necessary offices, appoint an executive director, and hire other employees as necessary and prescribe their duties and compensation; </section><section prefix="2">Recruit and train volunteer members who shall comprise the community crisis response team; </section><section prefix="3">Maintain a team of volunteer members to provide crisis response services statewide; </section><section prefix="4">Provide technical assistance for the development of local community crisis response teams; </section><section prefix="5">Promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A relating to the operation of crisis response services; </section><section prefix="6">Provide training programs on the operation of the crisis response teams and the provision of crisis response services; </section><section prefix="7">Develop agreements with agencies in both the public and private sectors; </section><section prefix="8">Promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A as necessary to execute the duties of the board; </section><section prefix="9">Make recommendations to the Governor and to the General Assembly related to the planning and provision of crisis response services; and </section><section prefix="10">Receive funding from any source and apply for public and private grants as it deems necessary. </section></text><history> Repealed, reenacted, and amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 316, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><former-codification> KRS 42.670. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21462</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>