<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>272A.12-050</section_number><catch_line>Voluntary dissolution by board of directors and members.   </catch_line><order_by>12-050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as otherwise provided in KRS 272A.12-040, for a limited cooperative association to voluntarily dissolve: <section prefix="a">A resolution to dissolve shall be approved by a majority vote of the board of directors unless a greater percentage is required by the organic rules; </section><section prefix="b">The board of directors shall call a members meeting to consider the resolution, to be held not later than ninety (90) days after adoption of the resolution; and </section><section prefix="c">The board of directors shall mail or otherwise transmit or deliver to each member in a record that complies with KRS 272A.5-070: <section prefix="1">The resolution required by paragraph (a) of this subsection; </section><section prefix="2">A recommendation that the members vote in favor of the resolution or, if the board determines that because of conflict of interest or other special circumstances it should not make a favorable recommendation, the basis of that determination; and </section><section prefix="3">Notice of the members meeting, which shall be given in the same manner as notice of a special meeting of members. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">Subject to subsection (3) of this section, a resolution to dissolve shall be approved by: <section prefix="a">At least two-thirds (2/3) of the voting power of members present at a members meeting called under subsection (1)(b) of this section; and </section><section prefix="b">If the limited cooperative association has investor members, at least a majority of the votes cast by patron members, unless the organic rules require a greater percentage. </section></section><section prefix="3">The organic rules may require that the percentage of votes under subsection (2)(b) of this section is: <section prefix="a">A different percentage that is not less than a majority of members voting at the meeting; or </section><section prefix="b">Measured against the voting power of all members; or </section><section prefix="c">A combination of paragraphs (a) and (b) of this subsection. </section></section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 160, sec. 92, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41068</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>