<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="117" order_by="117">A UNIFORM MILITARY AND OVERSEAS VOTERS ACT </unit></structure><section_number>117A.060</section_number><catch_line>Application by covered voter -- Declaration -- Informing election official that voter is covered.   </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A covered voter who is registered to vote in the Commonwealth of Kentucky may apply for a military-overseas ballot using either the regular absentee ballot application in use in the voter’s jurisdiction under KRS 117.085 or the federal postcard application or the application’s electronic equivalent. </section><section prefix="2">A covered voter who is not registered to vote in the Commonwealth of Kentucky may use a federal postcard application or the application’s electronic equivalent to apply simultaneously to register to vote under KRS 117A.050 and for a military-overseas ballot. </section><section prefix="3">The Secretary of State shall ensure that the electronic transmission system described in KRS 117A.030(4) is capable of accepting the submission of both a federal postcard application and any other approved electronic military-overseas ballot application sent to the appropriate election official. The covered voter may use the electronic transmission system or any other approved method to apply for a military-overseas ballot. </section><section prefix="4">A covered voter may use the declaration accompanying a federal write-in absentee ballot as an application for a military-overseas ballot simultaneously with the submission of the federal write-in absentee ballot, if the declaration is received by the appropriate election official by the close of business hours seven (7) days before the election. </section><section prefix="5">To receive the benefits of this chapter, a covered voter shall inform the appropriate election official that the voter is a covered voter. Methods of informing the appropriate election official that a voter is a covered voter include: <section prefix="a">The use of a federal postcard application or federal write-in absentee ballot; and </section><section prefix="b">The use of the electronic transmission system established under KRS 117A.030(4). </section></section><section prefix="6">This chapter does not preclude a covered voter from voting using the regular absentee ballot provisions under KRS 117.075, 117.077, 117.085, and 117.086. </section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 131, sec. 7, effective July 1, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42727</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>