<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="42" order_by="42">FINANCE AND ADMINISTRATION CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>42.742</section_number><catch_line>Duties of Geographic Information Advisory Council.   </catch_line><order_by>742</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Geographic Information Advisory Council's duties shall include the following: <section prefix="a">Recommending the development and adoption of policies and procedures related to geographic information and geographic information systems; </section><section prefix="b">Providing input and recommendations for the development of a strategy for the maintenance and funding of a statewide base map and geographic information system; </section><section prefix="c">Recommending standards on geographic information and geographic information systems for inclusion in the statewide architecture; </section><section prefix="d">Contributing to the development and delivery of a statewide geographic information plan; </section><section prefix="e">Overseeing the development of operating policies and procedures for the management of the council and any standing or ad hoc committees and associated advisory groups; and </section><section prefix="f">Promoting collaboration and the sharing of data and data development, as well as other aspects of geographic information systems. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Division of Geographic Information Systems shall provide necessary staff support services to the council. All cabinets, departments, divisions, agencies, and officers of the Commonwealth shall furnish the council necessary assistance, resources, information, records, or advice as it may require to fulfill its duties. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 11, effective July 12, 2012. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 13, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 36, effective June 20, 2005. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 506, sec. 9, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 536, sec. 9, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 327, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><former-codification> KRS 11.517 and 61.959. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40266</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>