<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6">THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY </unit></structure><section_number>6.711</section_number><catch_line>Orientation courses for legislators. </catch_line><order_by>711</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commission shall design the general curriculum of orientation courses, which shall include but not be limited to explanations and discussions of the ethics laws, administrative regulations, relevant internal policies, specific technical and legal requirements, summaries of advisory opinions, underlying purposes and principles of ethics laws, examples of practical application of the laws and principles, and a question-and-answer participatory segment regarding common problems and situations. The commission shall prepare the methods and materials necessary to implement the curriculum. </section><section prefix="2">The commission shall: <section prefix="a">Administer the orientation courses for legislators; </section><section prefix="b">Designate instructors to conduct their courses who shall be trained by the commission; and </section><section prefix="c">Notify legislators regarding attendance in these courses. </section></section><section prefix="3">The orientation courses shall be conducted for new legislators in December of each even-numbered year. Each course shall be at least two (2) hours in length and shall be designed for approval by the Kentucky Bar Association for continuing legal education ethics credits which the bar association may require. </section><section prefix="4">To facilitate participant interaction, those portions of the courses dedicated to group participation may be closed to the public. </section><section prefix="5">Each legislator shall complete the initial orientation course offered under this section. Each legislator elected after the initial orientation course shall complete the next orientation course conducted. The commission may grant permission for a legislator to attend a later course for good cause shown. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 75, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 493, sec. 4, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1993 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 35, effective September 16, 1993. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43303</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>