<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="439" order_by="439">PROBATION AND PAROLE </unit></structure><section_number>439.600</section_number><catch_line>Extension of limits of place of confinement -- Conditions. </catch_line><order_by>600</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commissioner, or a person he delegates, may extend the limits of the place of confinement of a prisoner if there is reasonable cause to believe the prisoner will honor his trust, by authorizing him, under prescribed conditions, to: <section prefix="a">Visit specifically designated places within the boundaries of Kentucky for a period not to exceed seven (7) days and return to the same institution or facility. An extension of limits may be granted only to permit a visit to a dying relative, attendance at the funeral of a relative, the contacting of prospective employers, or for any other compelling reason consistent with the public interest, or to promote the welfare and rehabilitation of the inmate; or </section><section prefix="b">Be transferred to a medical facility outside the correctional facility for a period of time as required to receive necessary medical services not available in the institution; or </section><section prefix="c">Participate in an educational training program in the community on a voluntary basis while continuing as a prisoner of the institution or facility to which he is committed or confined; or </section><section prefix="d">To do work at paid employment in the community on a voluntary basis returning to the institution or to the facility at night. </section></section><section prefix="2">A prisoner authorized to work at paid employment in the community under the provision of this subsection shall surrender to the commissioner of the department, or his designate, his earnings, less standard payroll deductions required by law. After deducting from the earning of each prisoner an amount determined to be the cost of the prisoner's keep and confinement, which sum shall be deposited in the Kentucky State Treasury as trust and agency receipts at the place of confinement of the inmate, the commissioner of the department, or his designate shall: <section prefix="a">Allow the prisoner to draw from the balance a reasonable sum to cover his incidental expenses; </section><section prefix="b">Retain to the prisoner's credit an amount deemed necessary to accumulate a reasonable sum to be paid to him on his release from prison; </section><section prefix="c">Cause to be paid any additional balance as is needed for the support of the prisoner's dependents. </section></section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 103, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 344, sec. 55, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 293, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19215</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>