<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>362.1-504</section_number><catch_line>Partner's transferable interest subject to charging order. </catch_line><order_by>1-504</order_by><text><section prefix="1">This section provides the exclusive remedy by which the judgment creditor of a partner or the transferee of a partner may satisfy a judgment out of the judgment debtor’s transferable interest. </section><section prefix="2">On application to a court of competent jurisdiction by a judgment creditor of a partner or a partner's transferee, a court may charge the transferable interest of the judgment debtor with payment of the unsatisfied amount of the judgment. To the extent so charged, the judgment creditor has only the rights of a transferee and shall have no right to participate in the management of or to cause the dissolution of the partnership. The court may appoint a receiver of the share of the distributions due or to become due to the judgment debtor in respect of the partnership and make all other orders, directions, accounts, and inquiries the judgment debtor might have made or which the circumstances of the case may require to give effect to the charging order. </section><section prefix="3">A charging order constitutes a lien on and the right to receive distributions made with respect to the judgment debtor's transferable interest in the partnership. </section><section prefix="4">The court may order a foreclosure of the interest subject to the charging order at any time. The purchaser at the foreclosure sale has the rights of a transferee. A charging order does not of itself constitute an assignment of the transferable interest. </section><section prefix="5">At any time before foreclosure, an interest charged may be redeemed: <section prefix="a">By the judgment debtor; </section><section prefix="b">With property other than partnership property, by one (1) or more of the other partners; or </section><section prefix="c">With partnership property, by one (1) or more of the other partners with the consent of all of the partners whose interests are not so charged. </section></section><section prefix="6">This subchapter does not deprive a partner or a partner's transferee of a right under exemption laws with respect to the partner's or transferee's interest in the partnership. </section><section prefix="7">The partnership is not a necessary party to an application for a charging order. Service of the charging order on a partnership may be made by the court granting the charging order or as the court may otherwise direct. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 149, effective July 15, 2010; and amended ch. 133, sec. 56, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 149, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 45, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 183, provides, "The specific textual provisions of Sections 1 to 178 of this Act which reflect amendments made to those sections by 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137 shall be deemed effective as of June 26, 2007, and those provisions are hereby made expressly retroactive to that date, with the remainder of the text of those sections being unaffected by the provisions of this section."  (7/15/2010).  This section was amended by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 133, and repealed and reenacted by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51. Pursuant to Section 184 of Acts ch. 51, it was the intent of the General Assembly that the repeal and reenactment not serve to void the amendment, and these Acts do not appear to be in conflict; therefore, they have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34494</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>