<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.360</section_number><catch_line>Notice of intention to apply for license -- Protest. </catch_line><order_by>360</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person, corporation, partnership, or any other entity, except an applicant for the same license for the same premises, or an applicant for an out-of-state malt beverage supplier's license, limited out-of-state malt beverage supplier's license, out-of-state distilled spirits and wine supplier's license, limited out-of-state distilled spirits and wine supplier's license, micro out-of-state distilled spirits and wine supplier's license, supplemental bar license, extended hours supplemental license, a special agent or solicitor's license, a special nonbeverage alcohol license, a transporter's license, a special Sunday drink license, or a special temporary drink license shall, before applying for a license under KRS 243.030 and 243.040, advertise by publication under KRS 424.130(1)(b) his or her intention to apply for a license. </section><section prefix="2">The notice shall conform in all material respects to the following requirements: <section prefix="a">The notice shall state: the name and address of the applicant if the applicant is an individual, the name and address of each partner and the name of the business and its address if the applicant is a partnership, and the name and address of each principal officer and director and the name and business address of the corporation if the applicant is a corporation; </section><section prefix="b">The notice shall specifically state the location of the premises for which the license is sought and the type of license being requested; and </section><section prefix="c">The notice shall state the date the application will be filed and shall contain the following statement: "Any person, association, corporation, or body politic may protest the granting of the license by writing the Department of Alcoholic Beverage Control, 1003 Twilight Trail, Frankfort, Kentucky 40601, within thirty (30) days of the date of legal publication." </section></section><section prefix="3">Any protest received after the thirty (30) day period has expired shall not be considered a valid legal protest by the board. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 19, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 74, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 572, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 435, sec. 12, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 34, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 522, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 29, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 94, sec. 3. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 175. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2554b-133. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43041</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>