<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.450</section_number><catch_line>Fund administered by secretary -- Administrative regulations -- Reimbursement of administrative costs -- Reports. </catch_line><order_by>450</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The secretary or his or her designated representative shall administer the Law Enforcement Foundation Program fund pursuant to the provisions of KRS 15.410 to 15.510 and may promulgate any administrative regulations as, in his or her judgment, are necessary to carry out his responsibilities under KRS 15.410 to 15.510. Administrative hearings promulgated by administrative regulation under authority of this section shall be conducted in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section><section prefix="2">The secretary or his designated representative shall determine which local units of government are eligible to share in the Law Enforcement Foundation Program fund and may withhold or terminate payments to any local unit that does not comply with the requirements of KRS 15.410 to 15.510 or the administrative regulations issued by the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet under KRS 15.410 to 15.510. </section><section prefix="3">The Justice and Public Safety Cabinet shall, from moneys appropriated and accruing to the fund as provided under KRS 15.430, receive reimbursement for the salaries and other costs of administering the fund, including, but not limited to, council operations and expenses. The amount to be reimbursed for any given year shall be determined by the council and shall not exceed five percent (5%) of the total amount of funds for that year. </section><section prefix="4">The Justice and Public Safety Cabinet shall furnish periodically to the council any reports as may be deemed reasonably necessary. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 24, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 16, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 300, sec. 6, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. V, sec. 34. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=958</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>