<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.32-030</section_number><catch_line>Application of subtitle. </catch_line><order_by>32-030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any nonprofit corporation organized under the laws of this state for the purpose of establishing, maintaining, and operating a nonprofit plan, whereby hospital care, medical-surgical care, dental care, and other health services are made available to persons who become subscribers to such plan or plans under a contract with the corporation, shall be subject to and be governed by the provisions of this subtitle, and shall be exempt from all other provisions of this code, except as expressly provided in this subtitle, and no insurance law hereafter enacted shall be deemed to apply to these corporations unless they be specifically referred to therein. </section><section prefix="2">Except as provided in KRS 304.32-300 to 304.32-320, the provisions of this subtitle shall not apply to any employer's self-insured health plan or service established and maintained solely for its members and their immediate families, or to any self-insured health plan or service established, maintained, and insured jointly by any employer and any labor organization or organizations. </section></text><history> Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 37, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 158, sec. 3, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 32, sec. 3, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:06</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29760</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>