<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.175</section_number><catch_line>Recitation of Lord's prayer and pledge of allegiance -- Instruction in proper respect for and display of the flag -- Observation of moment of silence or reflection. </catch_line><order_by>175</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As a continuation of the policy of teaching our country's history and as an affirmation of the freedom of religion in this country, the board of education of a local school district may authorize the recitation of the traditional Lord's prayer and the pledge of allegiance to the flag in public elementary schools. Pupil participation in the recitation of the prayer and pledge of allegiance shall be voluntary. Pupils shall be reminded that this Lord's prayer is the prayer our pilgrim fathers recited when they came to this country in their search for freedom. Pupils shall be informed that these exercises are not meant to influence an individual's personal religious beliefs in any manner. The exercises shall be conducted so that pupils shall learn of our great freedoms, including the freedom of religion symbolized by the recitation of the Lord's prayer. </section><section prefix="2">The board of education of each school district shall establish a policy and develop procedures whereby the pupils in each elementary and secondary school may participate in the pledge of allegiance to the flag of the United States at the commencement of each school day. </section><section prefix="3">The Kentucky Board of Education shall develop a program of instruction relating to the flag of the United States of America, including instruction in etiquette, the correct use and display of the flag, and other patriotic exercises as may be related. This program of instruction shall be provided to each public school for use in its course of instruction. The program of instruction, at a minimum, shall include the provisions of 4 U.S.C. secs. 1 to 3 and 4 U.S.C. secs. 5 to 9. </section><section prefix="4">The board of education of each local school district may purchase or otherwise acquire and provide for display in each classroom copies of the Declaration of Independence, the Gettysburg Address, and other documents the local board deems significant to the history of Kentucky and the United States. </section><section prefix="5">At the commencement of the first class of each day in all public schools, the teacher in charge of the room may announce that a moment of silence or reflection not to exceed one (1) minute in duration shall be observed. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 235, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. IV, sec. 205, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 435, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 339, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 304, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 145, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3461</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>