<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.664</section_number><catch_line>Renewal and restoration of license -- Grace period -- Inactive status -- Reactivation. </catch_line><order_by>664</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every license issued by the board may be renewed annually, on or before the last day of the licensee's birth month, upon payment of a renewal fee as established in administrative regulations promulgated by the board. Failure to renew shall cause the license to expire. </section><section prefix="2">A sixty (60) day grace period shall be allowed after the expiration of the license during which time the licensee may continue to practice and may apply to restore his or her license upon payment of the renewal fee plus a restoration fee as established in administrative regulations promulgated by the board, and upon the provision of applicable proof of insurance as required by KRS 198B.668. </section><section prefix="3">A license that is not restored before the end of the sixty (60) day grace period shall immediately terminate. Upon termination of the license, the former licensee shall be ineligible to practice in the Commonwealth until he or she thereafter satisfies all applicable licensing requirements in accordance with this chapter. </section><section prefix="4">After the sixty (60) day grace period, a former licensee with a terminated license may apply to have the license reinstated upon payment of the renewal fee plus a reinstatement fee as established in administrative regulations promulgated by the board. An applicant for reinstatement shall not be required to submit to any examination as a condition of reinstatement if the reinstatement application is made within three (3) years from the date of termination. </section><section prefix="5">Notwithstanding the requirements of this section, an applicant for renewal, restoration, or reinstatement shall satisfy all other applicable qualifications for licensure as required by this chapter and the administrative regulations promulgated hereunder. </section><section prefix="6">Those persons licensed by the board and not engaged in the practice of heating, ventilating, and air conditioning in the Commonwealth may apply for and be granted inactive status by the board in accordance with administrative regulations promulgated by the board. A licensee granted inactive status shall not retain the right to statewide practice of heating, ventilation, and air conditioning. An inactive license shall not be a valid license. A licensee on inactive status may petition the board for restoration of a license to practice actively. The petitioner shall pay a reactivation fee, satisfy all other requirements as established in administrative regulations promulgated by the board, and, if applicable, obtain the insurance as required by KRS 198B.668. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 93, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 386, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43374</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>