<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.658</section_number><catch_line>Qualifications for licensure and certification. </catch_line><order_by>658</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An applicant for a master heating, ventilation, and air conditioning contractor's license shall: <section prefix="a">Be at least eighteen (18) years of age; </section><section prefix="b">Be a citizen of the United States or be a resident alien who is authorized to do work in the United States; </section><section prefix="c"><section prefix="1">Have been regularly and principally employed or engaged in heating, ventilation, and air conditioning trades as a journeyman heating, ventilation, and air conditioning mechanic for not less than two (2) years under the direction and supervision of a master heating, ventilation, and air conditioning contractor; or </section><section prefix="2">Have been regularly and principally employed or engaged in the practice of heating, ventilation, and air conditioning contracting as a master heating, ventilation, and air conditioning contractor, or equivalent thereof, for not less than five (5) years in a jurisdiction other than Kentucky, as demonstrated by verifiable documentation; </section></section><section prefix="d">Have passed an examination prescribed by the board to determine the applicant's competency to practice heating, ventilation, and air conditioning contracting; and </section><section prefix="e">Have paid a fee as established in administrative regulations promulgated by the board. </section></section><section prefix="2">An applicant for a journeyman heating, ventilation, and air conditioning mechanic's license shall: <section prefix="a">Be at least eighteen (18) years of age; </section><section prefix="b">Be a citizen of the United States or be a resident alien who is authorized to do work in the United States; </section><section prefix="c"><section prefix="1">Have been regularly and principally employed or engaged in heating, ventilation, and air conditioning trades for not less than two (2) years under the direction and supervision of a master heating, ventilation, and air conditioning contractor; or </section><section prefix="2">Have been regularly and principally employed or engaged in the performance of heating, ventilation, and air conditioning work for not less than four (4) years in a jurisdiction other than Kentucky, as demonstrated by verifiable documentation; </section></section><section prefix="d">Have passed an examination prescribed by the board to determine the applicant's competency to install, maintain, and repair heating and cooling systems, heating and cooling service, burner service, and hydronic systems; and </section><section prefix="e">Have paid a fee as established in administrative regulations promulgated by the board. </section></section><section prefix="3">If an applicant has obtained, while exempt from licensure under 198B.674(2), (7), (8), (10), (13), or (14), work experience that the board determines to be equivalent to the requirements of subsection (1)(c) or (2)(c) of this section, such experience may be considered as equivalent to one (1) year of employment toward the licensure requirements for a master heating, ventilation, and air conditioning contractor or journeyman heating, ventilation, and air conditioning mechanic, as applicable, not to exceed one (1) year. </section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">The board shall issue an apprentice heating, ventilation, and air conditioning mechanic's certificate to any person who is registered with the board. </section><section prefix="b">The board shall establish by administrative regulation the minimum number of hours of experience required by apprentices and shall maintain an apprentice register to credit an apprentice for hours worked under the supervision of a master heating, ventilation, and air conditioning contractor and journeyman heating, ventilation, and air conditioning mechanic. Experience gained under the supervision of a Kentucky licensed master heating, ventilation, and air conditioning contractor while registered as an apprentice with the Kentucky Labor Cabinet, Department of Workplace Standards, in cooperation with the United States Department of Labor, Bureau of Apprenticeship and Training shall be accepted toward the two (2) year experience requirement for a journeyman heating, ventilation, and air conditioning mechanic license. </section><section prefix="c">The apprentice register shall include the name, address, Social Security number, employer, and dates of employment of the apprentice. </section><section prefix="d">The apprentice shall notify the board in writing of any change in address or employer. </section><section prefix="e">Apprentices and pre-apprentices shall not be required to pay fees for a certificate of registration or a registration renewal fee. </section></section><section prefix="5">The satisfactory completion of one (1) academic year of a board-approved curriculum or one (1) year of professional training in heating, ventilation, and air conditioning work may be considered as equivalent to one (1) year of employment toward the licensure requirements for a journeyman heating, ventilation, and air conditioning mechanic, not to exceed one (1) year. </section><section prefix="6">The satisfactory completion of one (1) academic year of teaching experience in a board-approved or state-approved technical education program in heating, ventilation, and air conditioning shall be considered as equivalent to one (1) year of employment, as required by subsection (1)(c) or (2)(c) of this section. No more than one (1) year of approved teaching experience may be used in meeting the requirements of subsection (1)(c) or (2)(c) of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 93, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 289, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 579, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2014). In codification, the Reviser of Statutes has altered the internal numbering of subsection (4) of this statute from the way it appeared in 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 93, sec. 3 under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(a). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43375</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>