<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="216" order_by="216">B LICENSURE AND REGULATION OF HEALTH FACILITIES AND SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>216B.0435</section_number><catch_line>Requirement of written agreements between abortion facility and acute-care hospital and ambulance service. </catch_line><order_by>0435</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each abortion facility shall enter into a written agreement with a licensed acute-care hospital capable of treating patients with unforeseen complications related to an abortion facility procedure by which agreement the hospital agrees to accept and treat these patients. </section><section prefix="2">If unforeseen complications arise prior to or during an abortion facility procedure, the patient shall be transferred to the licensed acute-care hospital with which the abortion facility has a written agreement as provided under subsection (1) of this section or to the hospital selected by the patient, if the patient so chooses. </section><section prefix="3">Each abortion facility shall enter into a written agreement with a licensed local ambulance service for the transport of any emergency patient within the scope of subsection (1) of this section to the licensed acute-care hospital. </section><section prefix="4">The written agreements of an abortion facility with an acute-care hospital and with a local ambulance service shall be filed by the abortion facility with the cabinet. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 582, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:37</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9193</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>