<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.867</section_number><catch_line>Minimum requirements for summer learning camps at schools with certain Title I programs -- Mandatory reports -- Student participation guidelines -- Teacher compensation -- Summary annual reports.   </catch_line><order_by>867</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Schools that have schoolwide Title I programs or Targeted Assistance Title I programs are encouraged to establish summer learning camps that meet the following minimum requirements: <section prefix="a">Three (3) hours of daily innovative instruction in the core academic areas for students eligible for Title I services; </section><section prefix="b">Three (3) hours of planned enrichment activities that are available to students eligible for Title I services as well as to other students. The activities shall be determined by the designated administrators and staff of the summer camp. Enrichment may include music and dance, arts and crafts, sports, technology, and other enrichment activities that are deemed appropriate; </section><section prefix="c">Twenty (20) to twenty-five (25) days of planned programming; </section><section prefix="d">Involvement of community partners in the planning and implementation process through advisory committees and other activities; </section><section prefix="e">An organized marketing and notification process to parents of eligible children; </section><section prefix="f">Employment of highly qualified teachers for the core academic subjects; </section><section prefix="g">Employment of appropriately prepared teachers to conduct the enrichment activities, which may include noncertified teachers; </section><section prefix="h">Documentation that all summer school personnel and volunteers have completed background checks under KRS 160.380 and 161.148; </section><section prefix="i">Clearly defined administrative duties and responsibilities for operating the summer learning camp under the authority of the local superintendent and local board of education; </section><section prefix="j">Innovative professional development for the staff with opportunity for piloting and assessing innovative models of instruction; </section><section prefix="k">Provisions for transporting full-day participants residing in the host school's attendance area and one (1) way transportation for students participating only in the enrichment programs who reside in the host school's attendance area. Title I funds shall not be used for transporting students to and from school; </section><section prefix="l">Adherence to the same health, safety, civil rights, and disability requirements as are applied to public schools during the regular academic year; and </section><section prefix="m">Evaluation procedures. </section></section><section prefix="2">Prior to the commencement of the camps, a local district offering one (1) or more summer learning camps shall report to the Kentucky Department of Education its intention, the projected membership for the camps, and the estimated number of students that will be transported. Within one (1) month following the ending date of the camps, a district shall file a membership and transportation report to receive its allotment for state supplemental funding and transportation pursuant to KRS 157.077. The department shall specify the procedures for reporting. </section><section prefix="3">The department shall provide technical assistance upon request by a local school or school district in developing summer learning camps, except the department shall not impose additional curriculum requirements beyond what is provided in this section. </section><section prefix="4">Local districts may contract with private providers to offer the enrichment programs. </section><section prefix="5">Student participation in summer camps shall be permitted as follows: <section prefix="a">A summer camp to be conducted in a school that has a schoolwide Title I program shall admit children who have attended the host public school the previous year, subject to space limitations. Children residing outside the school's attendance area, but within the school district, who attended another schoolwide Title I public school or students who were identified for Title I services in a Targeted Assistance School the previous year may be admitted if space is available. Priority shall be given to children who are the lowest-achieving, most economically disadvantaged, disabled, migrant, homeless, or limited-English proficient; </section><section prefix="b">Two (2) or more schools that have schoolwide Title I programs may establish one (1) summer learning camp and admit children who have attended those schools, subject to space limitations. Priority shall be given to children who are the lowest-achieving, most economically disadvantaged, disabled, migrant, homeless, or limited-English proficient; </section><section prefix="c">A summer learning camp in a school that has a Targeted Assistance Title I program shall admit children who are identified based on the federal requirements in Title I, Part A, Section 1115; </section><section prefix="d">A summer learning camp may admit children who are not identified for Title I services to the enrichment programs in any of the summer camps without charging tuition as long as funds other than Title I funds are used for that purpose on a space-available basis; and </section><section prefix="e">Local districts that do not contain a Title I school may establish summer learning camps as described in this section and compensate highly qualified teachers from available state and local funds. </section></section><section prefix="6">Compensation for highly qualified teachers who serve Title I-identified students in the core academic areas may be paid from Title I funds or Individuals with Disabilities Education Act funds, if appropriate. Compensation for enrichment instructors may be from extended school services funds, state general fund appropriations designated for summer learning camps, local public funds, private funds, grants, and receipts from fundraising activities. </section><section prefix="7">Compensation for summer learning camp teachers shall be considered extra services, and highly qualified teachers shall make contributions to the Kentucky Teachers' Retirement System. </section><section prefix="8">Each local school district shall submit a summary annual report for each summer learning camp in the district to the Kentucky Department of Education based on the timelines, processes, and reporting form developed by the department. The report shall include at least the following: <section prefix="a">Students' demographic data, including grade level, gender, economic disadvantage, race, and where applicable, disabilities; </section><section prefix="b">Membership and average daily attendance; </section><section prefix="c">Programs provided; </section><section prefix="d">Description of enrichment activities, including field trips; </section><section prefix="e">Credentials of staff; </section><section prefix="f">Summary of activities to engage parents; and </section><section prefix="g">Summary of partnerships established and description of shared activities. </section></section><section prefix="9">The department shall annually summarize the reports required in subsection (8) of this section and electronically publish a statewide report, highlighting best practices and success stories. The department shall also provide state academic assessment data disaggregated by those attending summer learning camps. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 131, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40600</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>