<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="12" order_by="12">ADMINISTRATIVE ORGANIZATION </unit></structure><section_number>12.260</section_number><catch_line>Deputy secretaries in offices of secretary for public protection, for energy and environment, and for labor. </catch_line><order_by>260</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby established in the Office of the Secretary of the Public Protection Cabinet a deputy secretary, appointed by the secretary pursuant to KRS 12.050, who shall be responsible for and engaged in operations of the cabinet and any other duties as assigned by the secretary and, in the absence of the secretary, have authority over cabinet affairs. </section><section prefix="2">There is hereby established in the Office of the Secretary of the Energy and Environment Cabinet a deputy secretary, appointed by the secretary pursuant to KRS 12.050, who shall be responsible for and engaged in operations of the cabinet and any other duties as assigned by the secretary and, in the absence of the secretary, have authority over cabinet affairs. </section><section prefix="3">There is hereby established in the Office of the Secretary of the Labor Cabinet a deputy secretary, appointed by the secretary pursuant to KRS 12.050, who shall be responsible for and engaged in operations of the cabinet and any other duties as assigned by the secretary and, in the absence of the secretary, have authority over cabinet affairs. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 10, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 13, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 4, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VII, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:13</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=662</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>