<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="147" order_by="147">A PROGRAM DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>147A.325</section_number><catch_line>Certification of qualified community foundation, county-specific component, or affiliate community foundation -- Commission to maintain and publish list of certified entities -- Biennial review -- Administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>325</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In order to receive grants from the fund under KRS 147A.320, a qualified community foundation, county-specific component fund, or affiliate community foundation shall substantially comply with the national standards for community foundations established by the National Council on Foundations, and be certified by the commission. The commission may charge a nonrefundable administrative fee to cover the costs associated with the certification process, not to exceed one thousand dollars ($1,000) per certification application. </section><section prefix="2">The commission shall: <section prefix="a">Maintain a current list of all qualified community foundations, county-specific component funds, and affiliate community foundations which are certified. This list shall be: <section prefix="1">Published on a Web site which is accessible to the general public; and </section><section prefix="2">Provided to the Department for Local Government and the Department of Revenue; and </section></section><section prefix="b">Perform a biennial review of each qualified community foundation, county-specific component fund, and affiliate community foundation which has been certified to ensure that it remains in compliance with all requirements mandated by this section or by administrative regulation. </section></section><section prefix="3">The commission may promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to administer this section. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  A reference to the "Governor's Office for Local Development" in subsection (2) of this section, as created by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 6, has been changed in codification to the "Department for Local Government" to reflect the renaming of that agency in Executive Order 2009-540, which was confirmed by the General Assembly in 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 117. This change was made by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 90. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1670</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>