<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.43-070</section_number><catch_line>Solid Waste Management Legislative Task Force -- Composition -- Duties. </catch_line><order_by>43-070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is created a Solid Waste Management Legislative Task Force. </section><section prefix="2">The Solid Waste Management Legislative Task Force shall be appointed by the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives. </section><section prefix="3">Vacancies on the task force shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment occurred. </section><section prefix="4">Members of the task force shall serve with pay and shall receive their reasonable and necessary expenses in connection with the performance of their duties. </section><section prefix="5">The legislative task force shall meet monthly and at other times with the prior approval of the Legislative Research Commission. The legislative task force may hold public hearings or make site visits from time to time on matters within its purview. The legislative task force may organize itself into smaller groups, if the task force deems it appropriate. A quorum of its members is necessary to take action on any matter. A majority vote of the total members is required to approve any action. </section><section prefix="6">The legislative task force shall: <section prefix="a">Monitor the implementation of solid waste legislation enacted by the First 1991 Extraordinary Session of the General Assembly; </section><section prefix="b">Possess the power to subpoena records which may be necessary for the execution of its duties; </section><section prefix="c">Make recommendations to the 1992 General Assembly for enacting revenue measures to fund the clean-up and closure of abandoned solid waste facilities in the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="d">Make recommendations to the 1992 General Assembly for enacting legislation concerning minimum bonding requirements for solid waste management facilities; </section><section prefix="e">Make recommendations to the 1992 General Assembly concerning the economic and technical feasibility of establishing mandatory requirements that all waste disposed of within the Commonwealth be processed through a program for source reduction, recycling, or beneficial reuse before being placed in a landfill for final disposal. The recommendations shall address the feasibility of requiring that by the year 2000, one hundred percent (100%) of all waste placed in a landfill shall first be processed through a mandatory program; and the feasibility of establishing the following implementation schedule: twenty-five percent (25%) processed by 1994; fifty percent (50%) processed by 1996; and seventy-five percent (75%) processed by 1998. The recommendations of the legislative task force shall consider and evaluate as many options as possible to achieve the implementation of a mandatory program, including, but not limited to, a cooperative effort among state and local governments, industry, citizens' groups, and the public to implement recycling programs for the separation and collection of recoverable materials generated at single-family and multifamily residences. In developing any recommendations, the task force shall evaluate the economic and practical feasibility of source separation and collection and the availability of markets for recovered products; </section><section prefix="f">Make recommendations to the 1992 General Assembly to consider the necessity for establishing a waste generator certification program for generators and transporters, including but not limited to municipalities, businesses, and industries, to indicate that they have implemented a waste reduction and recycling program substantially meeting or exceeding any recommendation for the Commonwealth's waste reduction and recycling goals if they are established by the task force; and </section><section prefix="g">Make recommendations to the 1992 General Assembly for any additional action regarding solid waste management in the Commonwealth. Such recommendations shall be coordinated with any reports and findings issued by the local government task force created by Senate Concurrent Resolution 97 of the 1990 General Assembly and the Kentucky Recycling Brokerage Authority. </section></section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 486, sec. 30, effective July 15, 1994. – Created 1991 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 43, effective February 26, 1991. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><former-codification> KRS 224.885. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10411</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>