<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.990</section_number><catch_line>Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>990</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person who violates KRS 311.250 shall be guilty of a violation. </section><section prefix="2">Any college or professor thereof violating the provisions of KRS 311.300 to 311.350 shall be civilly liable on his bond for a sum not less than one hundred dollars ($100) nor more than one thousand dollars ($1,000) for each violation, which may be recovered by an action in the name of the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="3">Any person who presents to the county clerk for the purpose of registration any license which has been fraudulently obtained, or obtains any license under KRS 311.380 to 311.510 by false or fraudulent statement or representation, or practices podiatry under a false or assumed name or falsely impersonates another practitioner or former practitioner of a like or different name, or aids and abets any person in the practice of podiatry within the state without conforming to the requirements of KRS 311.380 to 311.510, or otherwise violates or neglects to comply with any of the provisions of KRS 311.380 to 311.510, shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. Each case of practicing podiatry in violation of the provisions of KRS 311.380 to 311.510 shall be considered a separate offense. </section><section prefix="4">Each violation of KRS 311.560 shall constitute a Class D felony. </section><section prefix="5">Each violation of KRS 311.590 shall constitute a Class D felony. Conviction under this subsection of a holder of a license or permit shall result automatically in permanent revocation of such license or permit. </section><section prefix="6">Conviction of willfully resisting, preventing, impeding, obstructing, threatening, or interfering with the board or any of its members, or of any officer, agent, inspector, or investigator of the board or the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, in the administration of any of the provisions of KRS 311.550 to 311.620 shall be a Class A misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="7">Each violation of subsection (1) of KRS 311.375 shall, for the first offense, be a Class B misdemeanor, and, for each subsequent offense shall be a Class A misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="8">Each violation of subsection (2) of KRS 311.375 shall, for the first offense, be a violation, and, for each subsequent offense, be a Class B misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="9">Each day of violation of either subsection of KRS 311.375 shall constitute a separate offense. </section><section prefix="10"><section prefix="a">Any person who intentionally or knowingly performs an abortion contrary to the requirements of KRS 311.723(1) shall be guilty of a Class D felony; and </section><section prefix="b">Any person who intentionally, knowingly, or recklessly violates the requirements of KRS 311.723(2) shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. </section></section><section prefix="11"><section prefix="a"><section prefix="1">Any physician who performs a partial-birth abortion in violation of KRS 311.765 shall be guilty of a Class D felony. However, a physician shall not be guilty of the criminal offense if the partial-birth abortion was necessary to save the life of the mother whose life was endangered by a physical disorder, illness, or injury. </section><section prefix="2">A physician may seek a hearing before the State Board of Medical Licensure on whether the physician's conduct was necessary to save the life of the mother whose life was endangered by a physical disorder, illness, or injury. The board's findings, decided by majority vote of a quorum, shall be admissible at the trial of the physician. The board shall promulgate administrative regulations to carry out the provisions of this subparagraph. </section><section prefix="3">Upon a motion of the physician, the court shall delay the beginning of the trial for not more than thirty (30) days to permit the hearing, referred to in subparagraph 2. of this paragraph, to occur. </section></section><section prefix="b">Any person other than a physician who performs a partial-birth abortion shall not be prosecuted under this subsection but shall be prosecuted under provisions of law which prohibit any person other than a physician from performing any abortion. </section><section prefix="c">No penalty shall be assessed against the woman upon whom the partial-birth abortion is performed or attempted to be performed. </section></section><section prefix="12">Any person who intentionally performs an abortion with knowledge that, or with reckless disregard as to whether, the person upon whom the abortion is to be performed is an unemancipated minor, and who intentionally or knowingly fails to conform to any requirement of KRS 311.732 is guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="13">Any person who negligently releases information or documents which are confidential under KRS 311.732 is guilty of a Class B misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="14">Any person who performs an abortion upon a married woman either with knowledge or in reckless disregard of whether KRS 311.735 applies to her and who intentionally, knowingly, or recklessly fails to conform to the requirements of KRS 311.735 shall be guilty of a Class D felony. </section><section prefix="15">Any person convicted of violating KRS 311.750 shall be guilty of a Class B felony. </section><section prefix="16">Any person who violates KRS 311.760(2) shall be guilty of a Class D felony. </section><section prefix="17">Any person who violates KRS 311.770 or 311.780 shall be guilty of a Class D felony. </section><section prefix="18">A person convicted of violating KRS 311.780 shall be guilty of a Class C felony. </section><section prefix="19">Any person who violates KRS 311.810 shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="20">Any professional medical association or society, licensed physician, or hospital or hospital medical staff who shall have violated the provisions of KRS 311.606 shall be guilty of a Class B misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="21">Any administrator, officer, or employee of a publicly owned hospital or publicly owned health care facility who performs or permits the performance of abortions in violation of KRS 311.800(1) shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="22">Any person who violates KRS 311.905(3) shall be guilty of a violation. </section><section prefix="23">Any person who violates the provisions of KRS 311.820 shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="24"><section prefix="a">Any person who fails to test organs, skin, or other human tissue which is to be transplanted, or violates the confidentiality provisions required by KRS 311.281, shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor; </section><section prefix="b">Any person who has human immunodeficiency virus infection, who knows he is infected with human immunodeficiency virus, and who has been informed that he may communicate the infection by donating organs, skin, or other human tissue who donates organs, skin, or other human tissue shall be guilty of a Class D felony. </section></section><section prefix="25">Any person who sells or makes a charge for any transplantable organ shall be guilty of a Class D felony. </section><section prefix="26">Any person who offers remuneration for any transplantable organ for use in transplantation into himself shall be fined not less than five thousand dollars ($5,000) nor more than fifty thousand dollars ($50,000). </section><section prefix="27">Any person brokering the sale or transfer of any transplantable organ shall be guilty of a Class C felony. </section><section prefix="28">Any person charging a fee associated with the transplantation of a transplantable organ in excess of the direct and indirect costs of procuring, distributing, or transplanting the transplantable organ shall be fined not less than fifty thousand dollars ($50,000) nor more than five hundred thousand dollars ($500,000). </section><section prefix="29">Any hospital performing transplantable organ transplants which knowingly fails to report the possible sale, purchase, or brokering of a transplantable organ shall be fined not less than ten thousand dollars ($10,000) or more than fifty thousand dollars ($50,000). </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 175, sec. 6, effective July 12, 2006; and ch. 248, sec. 9, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 590, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 42, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 262, sec. 34, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 343, sec. 25, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 545, effective July 15, 1998; ch. 578, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 614, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 447 sec. 6, effective July 14, 1992; and ch. 463, sec. 35, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 443, sec. 63, effective July 13, 1990; and ch. 495, sec. 10, effective January 1, 1991. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 375, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 342, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 64, sec. 2, effective June 1, 1980; ch. 188, sec. 258, effective July 15, 1980; and ch. 225, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 107, sec. 12; ch. 205, sec. 14; and ch. 211, sec. 12. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(1); and ch. 255, sec. 17(1) to (6). -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 218, sec. 18. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 244. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 150, secs. 17 and 18; ch. 197, sec. 8; and ch. 198, sec. 3. -- Amended 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 24. -- Amended 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 176, sec. 15. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2615, 2615-3, 2618, 2618a-4, 2618a-12, 2618b-2, 2618b-4, 2651. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><lrc-note>(7/23/06).  This section was amended by 2000 Ky. Acts chs. 175 and 248, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30714</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>