<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="200" order_by="200">ASSISTANCE TO CHILDREN </unit></structure><section_number>200.666</section_number><catch_line>Cabinet's monitoring of personnel standards for service providers - Personnel development. </catch_line><order_by>666</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet shall monitor personnel standards for service providers to ensure the qualified service providers necessary to carry out the provisions of KRS 200.650 to 200.676 are appropriately and adequately prepared and trained in order to comply with the requirements of federal law and regulations. </section><section prefix="2">The cabinet shall provide the components of a comprehensive system of personnel development which shall include: <section prefix="a">Preservice and inservice training conducted on an interdisciplinary basis to the extent appropriate; and </section><section prefix="b">Training provided for a variety of entities, including but not limited to, public and private providers, primary referral sources, parents, paraprofessionals, and persons who serve as professional service coordinators or case managers. </section></section><section prefix="3">Training may include: <section prefix="a">Implementing innovative strategies and activities for the recruitment and retention of early intervention service providers; </section><section prefix="b">Promoting the preparation of early intervention providers who are fully and appropriately qualified to provide early intervention; </section><section prefix="c">Training personnel to work in rural areas; and </section><section prefix="d">Recruiting and training personnel to coordinate transition services for infants and toddlers with disabilities from an early intervention program to a preschool program. </section></section><section prefix="4">The cabinet shall coordinate with other agencies in the provision of the comprehensive system of personnel development activities. </section></text><history> Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 313, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7329</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>