<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="367" order_by="367">CONSUMER PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>367.656</section_number><catch_line>Nonacceptance, revocation, suspension, or refusal to renew registration -- Judicial review -- Civil action. </catch_line><order_by>656</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">A filing pursuant to KRS 367.653 and this section shall be accepted unless the Attorney General notifies the professional solicitor or fundraising consultant otherwise, within fourteen (14) calendar days of the receipt of filing. If a filing is not accepted, the Attorney General shall notify the affected charity at the time of rejection. Within seven (7) calendar days after receiving a notice that the filing requirements are not satisfied, the professional solicitor or fundraising consultant may request a hearing. The hearing shall be held in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section><section prefix="b">A professional solicitor or fundraising consultant may submit an amended filing upon receiving notice that his prior filing has not been accepted. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Attorney General may revoke, suspend, or refuse to renew the registration of a professional solicitor or fundraising consultant if: <section prefix="a">He has violated any provision of KRS 367.650 to 367.670 or any administrative regulations promulgated by the Attorney General pursuant to those sections; </section><section prefix="b">He or any of his principal officers have refused or failed, after notice, to produce any records or disclose any information required pursuant to KRS 367.650 to 367.670, or any administrative regulations promulgated by the Attorney General pursuant to those sections. </section><section prefix="c">He has made a material false statement in an application, statement, or report required to be filed under KRS 367.650 to 367.670. </section></section><section prefix="3">Any party to a hearing who is aggrieved by the final order may seek judicial review by filing an appeal in the Franklin Circuit Court in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section><section prefix="4">The Attorney General may bring a civil action directly in the Franklin Circuit Court or in the Circuit Court of any county in which the fundraising campaign involving the professional solicitor or fundraising consultant is being conducted to revoke or suspend the registration statement for any of the grounds set forth in this section. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 349, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35029</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>