<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="70" order_by="70">SHERIFFS, CONSTABLES, AND COUNTY POLICE FORCE </unit></structure><section_number>70.270</section_number><catch_line>Disciplinary and removal procedures by sheriff -- Charges by citizen. </catch_line><order_by>270</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any deputy sheriff may be removed, suspended, or laid-off by the sheriff for any cause which will promote the efficiency of the department. Except when an appointment is revoked during the probationary period described in KRS 70.267(5), the sheriff shall furnish a covered deputy with a written statement of the reason why the action was taken. </section><section prefix="2">Except for the revocation of an appointment pursuant to KRS 70.267(5), every action in the nature of a dismissal, suspension, or reduction made by the sheriff shall be subject to review by the board at the request of any deputy sheriff affected by the provisions of KRS 70.260 to 70.273. </section><section prefix="3">Any citizen who makes written charges of misconduct, under oath, concerning the actions of any deputy sheriff covered by the provisions of KRS 70.260 to 70.273 shall present the charges to the sheriff, who shall investigate the charges. The sheriff shall determine what action, if any, shall be taken against the deputy, subject to the limitations set out in KRS 70.260 to 70.273. The citizen may appeal the determination of the sheriff to the board. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 438, sec. 4, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24222</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>