<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="532" order_by="532">CLASSIFICATION AND DESIGNATION OF OFFENSES -- AUTHORIZED DISPOSITION </unit></structure><section_number>532.160</section_number><catch_line>Criminal garnishment. </catch_line><order_by>160</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If a convicted person is unable to pay all court costs, fees, fines, and other monetary penalties at the time of sentencing, then the sentencing court may, consistent with KRS 23A.205, 24A.175, 534.020, and KRS 534.060, issue a criminal garnishment order for all fines under KRS Chapter 534 or KRS 346.185 and for court costs, restitution, and reimbursement charges in this chapter. </section><section prefix="2">A criminal garnishment applies to any of the following: <section prefix="a">A convicted person's earnings as defined in KRS 427.005; </section><section prefix="b">Indebtedness that is owed to a convicted person by a garnishee for amounts that are not earnings; </section><section prefix="c">Money that is held by a garnishee on behalf of a convicted person; </section><section prefix="d">The convicted person's personal property that is in the possession of a garnishee; or </section><section prefix="e">If the garnishee is a corporation, shares or securities of a corporation or a proprietary interest in a corporation that belongs to a convicted person. </section></section><section prefix="3">The debt associated with a criminal garnishment shall constitute a charge against the estate of any decedent owing moneys under this chapter. </section><section prefix="4">The sentencing court shall combine all fines, court costs, restitution, and reimbursement charges in a single order of garnishment. </section><section prefix="5">The sentencing court shall require payment of restitution to the victim of the offense before payments of any moneys to the government or a government agency. </section><section prefix="6">The court shall order payments made under this section to be paid by the defendant directly to the person or organization specified by written order of the court. The court shall not order payments of an order of criminal garnishment to be made through the circuit clerk, except for those payments due from a person under the supervision of the Department of Corrections. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 183, sec. 31, effective August 1, 2002. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 606, sec. 172, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> August 1, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20054</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>