<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>355.9-328</section_number><catch_line>Priority of security interests in investment property. </catch_line><order_by>9-328</order_by><text>The following rules govern priority among conflicting security interests in the same investment property: <section prefix="1">A security interest held by a secured party having control of investment property under KRS 355.9-106 has priority over a security interest held by a secured party that does not have control of the investment property. </section><section prefix="2">Except as otherwise provided in subsections (3) and (4) of this section, conflicting security interests held by secured parties each of which has control under KRS 355.9-106 rank according to priority in time of: <section prefix="a">If the collateral is a security, obtaining control; </section><section prefix="b">If the collateral is a security entitlement carried in a securities account and: <section prefix="1">If the secured party obtained control under KRS 355.8-106(4)(a), the secured party’s becoming the person for which the securities account is maintained; </section><section prefix="2">If the secured party obtained control under KRS 355.8-106(4)(b), the securities intermediary’s agreement to comply with the secured party’s entitlement orders with respect to security entitlements carried or to be carried in the securities account; or </section><section prefix="3">If the secured party obtained control through another person under KRS 355.8-106(4)(c), the time on which priority would be based under this paragraph if the other person were the secured party; or </section></section><section prefix="c">If the collateral is a commodity contract carried with a commodity intermediary, the satisfaction of the requirement for control specified in KRS 355.9-106(2)(b) with respect to commodity contracts carried or to be carried with the commodity intermediary. </section></section><section prefix="3">A security interest held by a securities intermediary in a security entitlement or a securities account maintained with the securities intermediary has priority over a conflicting security interest held by another secured party. </section><section prefix="4">A security interest held by a commodity intermediary in a commodity contract or a commodity account maintained with the commodity intermediary has priority over a conflicting security interest held by another secured party. </section><section prefix="5">A security interest in a certificated security in registered form which is perfected by taking delivery under KRS 355.9-313(1) and not by control under KRS 355.9-314 has priority over a conflicting security interest perfected by a method other than control. </section><section prefix="6">Conflicting security interests created by a broker, securities intermediary, or commodity intermediary which are perfected without control under KRS 355.9-106 rank equally. </section><section prefix="7">In all other cases, priority among conflicting security interests in investment property is governed by KRS 355.9-322 and 355.9-323. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 10, effective July 1, 2001. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 408, sec. 68, effective July 1, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33781</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>