<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>14A.2-010</section_number><catch_line>Filing requirements -- Authority for redaction of information.   </catch_line><order_by>2-010</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A document shall satisfy the requirements of this section, and of any other section that adds to or varies these requirements, to be entitled to filing by the Secretary of State. </section><section prefix="2">This chapter shall require or permit filing a document in the office of the Secretary of State. </section><section prefix="3">A document shall contain the information required by the organic law or by this chapter, and may contain other information if permitted by the organic law. </section><section prefix="4">A document shall be typewritten, printed, or electronically transmitted. If a document is electronically transmitted, the document shall be in a format that can be retrieved or reproduced in typewritten or printed form. </section><section prefix="5">A document shall be in the English language. A name may be in a language other than English if written in English letters or Arabic or Roman numerals. A document not in English shall be accompanied by an English translation reasonably authenticated to the satisfaction of the Secretary of State. </section><section prefix="6">A document shall be executed in the manner set forth in KRS 14A.2-020. </section><section prefix="7">The person executing the document shall sign it and state beneath or opposite the signature the person's name and the capacity in which the document is signed. The document may but need not contain: <section prefix="a">A seal of the entity or foreign entity; </section><section prefix="b">An attestation, acknowledgment, or verification; or </section><section prefix="c">A statement regarding the preparer of the document which complies with KRS 382.335(1). </section></section><section prefix="8">If the Secretary of State has prescribed a mandatory form for a document, it shall be in or on the prescribed form. </section><section prefix="9">A document shall be delivered to the office of the Secretary of State for filing. Delivery may be made by electronic transmission, if and to the extent permitted by the Secretary of State. If the document is filed in typewritten or printed form and not transmitted electronically, the Secretary of State may require that up to two (2) exact or conformed copies be delivered with the document. </section><section prefix="10">When the document is delivered to the office of the Secretary of State for filing, the correct filing fee, the organization tax, and any penalty required by this chapter or other law to be collected by the office of the Secretary of State with the document shall be paid or provision for payment shall be made in a manner permitted by the Secretary of State. The Secretary of State may accept payment of the correct amount due by check, credit card, charge card, or similar method. However, if the amount due is tendered by any method other than cash, the liability shall not be finally discharged until the Secretary of State receives final payment or credit of collectible funds. If, after five (5) days' prior written notice to the entity, foreign entity, or person who delivered a document for filing for which the filing fee was not collectible, payment of the filing fee in full is not made in immediately available funds, the Secretary of State may declare the document filed to be null and void and of no legal effect and may remove the document from the records of the Secretary of State. Written notice given pursuant to this subsection may be given by electronic communication. </section><section prefix="11">A document is delivered to the office of the Secretary of State for filing upon actual receipt. A document delivered electronically that is self-operative will be treated as received on the date of receipt. A document that is not self-operative delivered electronically or otherwise will be treated as received on the date of delivery if delivery is accomplished not later than 4:30 p.m. prevailing time in Frankfort, Kentucky or otherwise on the next business day. </section><section prefix="12">Any communication from the Secretary of State to an entity or foreign entity may be accomplished electronically. Communications to an entity may be mailed to the entity by first-class mail at its principal office address. </section><section prefix="13">If any law prohibits the disclosure by the Secretary of State of information contained in a record delivered for filing, the Secretary of State shall file the record if it otherwise complies with the applicable law, but the Secretary of State may redact such information so that it is not available to the public. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 34, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2015. -- Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 8, effective January 1, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44315</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>