<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="323" order_by="323">ARCHITECTS </unit></structure><section_number>323.414</section_number><catch_line>Unauthorized use of certificate number and signature -- Surrender of revoked or suspended certificate. </catch_line><order_by>414</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No certified interior designer shall knowingly: <section prefix="a">Affix, or permit to be affixed, the certified interior designer's certificate number and signature to any document, plan, report, drawing, or specification that depicts work that requires the seal of a registered architect or professional engineer; </section><section prefix="b">Affix, or permit to be affixed, the certified interior designer's certificate number and signature to any document, plan, report, drawing, or specification that depicts work that the certified interior designer is not competent or qualified to perform; or </section><section prefix="c">Affix the certified interior designer's signature and certificate number to any document, plan, report, drawing, or specification that was not prepared: <section prefix="1">By the certified interior designer; or </section><section prefix="2">Under the certified interior designer's supervision. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">When the certificate of a certified interior designer has been revoked or suspended, the certified interior designer shall surrender his or her certificate to the board within thirty (30) days after the revocation or suspension has become effective. If the certificate of the interior designer has been suspended or revoked, the certificate shall be returned to the certified interior designer upon the expiration of the period of suspension or reinstatement of the certificate. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 55, sec. 8, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31517</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>