<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="441" order_by="441">JAILS AND COUNTY PRISONERS </unit></structure><section_number>441.620</section_number><catch_line>Valid signatures or facsimiles on bonds -- Quorum -- Meetings -- Bylaws -- Regulations. </catch_line><order_by>620</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If any of the officers of the authority whose signatures or facsimiles thereof appear on any bonds of the authority or on any other instruments or documents pertaining to the functions of the authority, shall cease to be such officers before delivery of the bonds, or before the effective date or occasion of such instruments or documents, the signatures, and facsimiles thereof, shall nevertheless be valid for all purposes the same as if the officers had remained in office until such delivery or effective date or occasion. </section><section prefix="2">Any six (6) members of the authority shall constitute a quorum. </section><section prefix="3">The authority shall meet not less than every six (6) months and as often as necessary to comply with the provisions of KRS 441.420 to 441.450 when called as provided in this section. Special meetings of the authority may be called by the chairman, and upon written request of two (2) members the chairman shall call a special meeting of the authority to be held not later than twenty (20) days following receipt of the written request. The chairman shall give notice through the secretary by certified mail, return receipt requested, to each member of the authority at least ten (10) days prior to the time of any meeting, unless all members of the authority waive notice in writing. The offices of the authority shall be at the seat of state government. </section><section prefix="4">The authority may adopt bylaws relating to its organization and internal management, and may alter the same at will. Through its bylaws, or by resolution, it shall establish stated times and places for regular meetings; and may adjourn the same from time to time. If a quorum be present at any special meeting, and it shall appear from the minutes that reasonable notice was given to absent members, or waived by them, or the minutes subsequently consented to by them, any business transacted or action taken thereat shall be as fully regular and official as if transacted or taken at a regular meeting or an adjournment thereof. </section><section prefix="5">The authority may adopt rules and regulations for the conducting of its business and affairs, subject to the provisions of KRS Chapter 13A. </section></text><history>Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch.2, sec.82, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 415, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 235, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective>June 8, 2011 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, H, 5, c, (2) at 651. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39597</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>