<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="620" order_by="620">DEPENDENCY, NEGLECT, AND ABUSE </unit></structure><section_number>620.360</section_number><catch_line>Rights and responsibilities of foster parents -- Training of person investigating abuse or neglect in foster homes -- Nonliability of cabinet. </catch_line><order_by>360</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Persons who provide foster care services to children who have been committed to the custody of the state shall be considered a primary partner and member of a professional team caring for foster children. Foster parents who contract directly with the cabinet shall have the following rights: <section prefix="a">To be treated with respect, consideration, and dignity; </section><section prefix="b">To fully understand the role of the cabinet and the role of other members of the child's professional team; </section><section prefix="c">To receive information and training about foster parents' rights, responsibilities, and access to local and statewide support groups, including but not limited to the Kentucky Foster/Adoptive Care Association, the Kentucky Foster and Adoptive Parent Network, and Adoption Support of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="d">To receive information and training to improve skills in the daily care and in meeting the special needs of foster children; </section><section prefix="e">To receive timely and adequate financial reimbursement for knowledgeable and quality care of a child in foster care within budgetary limitations; </section><section prefix="f">To maintain the foster family's own routines and values while respecting the rights and confidentiality of each foster child placed in their home; </section><section prefix="g">To receive a period of respite from providing foster care, pursuant to cabinet policies; </section><section prefix="h">To receive, upon an open records request, a copy of all information contained in the cabinet's records about the family's foster home and the foster care services provided by the family consistent with KRS 605.160; </section><section prefix="i">To access cabinet support and assistance as necessary twenty-four (24) hours per day, seven (7) days per week; </section><section prefix="j">To receive, prior to a child being placed in the foster home pursuant to KRS 605.090, information relating to the child's behavior, family background, or health history that may jeopardize the health or safety of any member of the foster family's household, including other foster children, and similar information that may affect the manner in which foster care services are provided, consistent with KRS 605.160. In an emergency situation, the cabinet shall provide information as soon as it is available; </section><section prefix="k">To refuse placement of a child within the foster home and to request, with reasonable notice to the cabinet, the removal of a child from the foster home without fear of reprisal; </section><section prefix="l">To communicate, with an appropriate release of information consistent with KRS 605.160, with other professionals who work directly with the foster child, including but not limited to teachers, therapists, and health care practitioners and to notify the cabinet within twenty-four (24) hours of the communication; </section><section prefix="m">To assist the cabinet in the development of the child's plan of care; </section><section prefix="n">To receive an explanatory notice from the cabinet, consistent with KRS 620.130 and when it is in the best interest of the child, when a foster child's case plan has changed and, except in an immediate response to a child protective services investigation involving the foster home, an explanatory notice of termination or change in placement affecting the foster home within fourteen (14) days of the change or termination in placement; </section><section prefix="o">To have priority consideration for placement if a child who has previously been placed in the foster home reenters foster care, consistent with KRS 605.130 and 620.130 and to the extent it is in the best interest of the child; </section><section prefix="p">To have priority consideration for adoption if a foster child who has been placed in the foster home for a period of at least twelve (12) consecutive months becomes eligible for adoption consistent with KRS 605.130 and 620.130 and to the extent it is in the best interest of the child; and </section><section prefix="q">To maintain contact with the foster child after the child leaves the foster home, unless the child, a biological parent, the cabinet when the cabinet retains custody of the child, or other foster or adoptive parent refuses such contact. </section></section><section prefix="2">The responsibilities of foster parents that contract directly with the cabinet shall include but not be limited to the following: <section prefix="a">To maintain an orderly and clean home; </section><section prefix="b">To ensure that the child has adequate resources for personal hygiene and clothing; </section><section prefix="c">To provide recreational and spiritual opportunities for the child, in accordance with cabinet policies; </section><section prefix="d">To attend all school and case planning meetings involving a foster child placed in their home whenever possible, subject to KRS 620.130 and the confidentiality requirements of 42 U.S.C. sec. 671; </section><section prefix="e">To abide by cabinet policies relating to discipline of a foster child; and </section><section prefix="f">To support the involvement of a foster child's biological family whenever possible and in accordance with cabinet policies. </section></section><section prefix="3">The cabinet shall provide specific training on investigations of alleged child abuse or neglect in a foster home to a person appointed by the Kentucky Foster/Adoptive Care Association. The training shall include the rights of a foster parent during an investigation. Training shall be consistent with 42 U.S.C. sec. 5106(a). </section><section prefix="4">Nothing in this section shall be construed to establish monetary liability of or cause of action against the cabinet. </section></text><history> Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 45, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20226</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>