<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.232</section_number><catch_line>Registration not transferable until taxes paid, lien released, and proof of insurance and notarized affidavit presented.   </catch_line><order_by>232</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The county clerk shall not transfer the registration on any motor vehicle or trailer against which a tax lien has been filed until the taxes have been paid and the lien has been released. </section><section prefix="2">The county clerk shall not transfer the registration of any motor vehicle unless the transferee presents proof of insurance in compliance with KRS 304.39-080 and KRS 186.190. </section><section prefix="3">If a notarized affidavit is required and available under KRS 138.450, the county clerk shall not transfer the registration of a motor vehicle unless the notarized affidavit attesting to the total and actual consideration paid or to be paid for the motor vehicle is presented to the clerk at the time of the transfer. If a notarized affidavit is required but is not available, the county clerk shall contact the Department of Revenue to determine the "retail price" of the vehicle and any taxes due prior to transferring the vehicle. </section><section prefix="4">The county clerk shall not transfer title on a motor vehicle if there are delinquent ad valorem taxes on the motor vehicle. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 4, effective January 1, 2013. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 606, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 600, sec. 7, effective April 14, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 504, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 240, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2014 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2012).The amendment of this statute in 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 5 was to be effective January 1, 2013, pursuant to Section 7 of that Act. However, in 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 1, 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 7, was repealed, and a new effective date of January 1, 2014, was established for the 2011 amendment of this statute, pursuant to 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 2. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39945</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>