<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.0282</section_number><catch_line>Duties of Council on Postsecondary Education as to professional education preparation programs. </catch_line><order_by>0282</order_by><text>The Council on Postsecondary Education shall: <section prefix="1">Employ a director and sufficient staff to administer the professional education preparation programs; </section><section prefix="2">Formulate guidelines and policies governing program activities and fund expenditures; </section><section prefix="3">Allocate funds to appropriate agencies, organizations, and institutions for the purpose of conducting activities approved in accordance with guidelines and policies; </section><section prefix="4">Recognize regional groups made up of professionals, educators, and consumers, which shall serve in an advisory capacity to the council in accordance with guidelines and policies; </section><section prefix="5">Recognize a group made up of professionals, educators, and consumers which shall serve in an advisory capacity to the council on all program matters; </section><section prefix="6">Develop and maintain a mechanism for evaluating the impact of the program activities on admissions to, and graduation from, professional schools, and on professional manpower distribution; </section><section prefix="7">Conduct specific program activities which are beyond the capability of a single institution, agency, or organization, or when it is determined that it would be inappropriate for such institutions, agencies, or organizations to conduct the activity; </section><section prefix="8">Establish liaison with and provide assistance to the Kentucky Board of Education in developing counseling and other related programs to encourage students from shortage areas to prepare for professional careers; </section><section prefix="9">Coordinate the development of a financial support system to enable potential professional students in underserved areas which will enhance their ability to apply for, be admitted to, and graduate from professional education programs; </section><section prefix="10">Report at least annually to the appropriate committees and interim committees of the General Assembly on the operation of the program. </section></text><history> Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 79, effective May 30, 1997. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> May 30, 1997 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4182</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>