<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.174</section_number><catch_line>Personalized license plates. </catch_line><order_by>174</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For purposes of this section, "personalized license plate" means a license plate issued with personal letters or numbers significant to the applicant and it also means a license plate that is issued under this section and has been combined with a special license plate. </section><section prefix="2">Any owner or lessee of a motor vehicle that is required to be registered under the provisions of KRS 186.050(1), (3)(a), or (4)(a), or any owner or lessee of a motorcycle required to be registered under the provisions of KRS 186.050(2) may obtain a personalized license plate by applying for a personalized license plate in the office of the county clerk and upon payment of the fee required in KRS 186.162. A person initially applying for a personalized license plate shall submit the application and appropriate SF fee in person to the county clerk, but may submit the annual application to renew the personalized license plate and entire fee required in KRS 186.162 by mail to the county clerk. Applications and fees for personalized license plates pursuant to this section must be received by the Transportation Cabinet on or before September 1 preceding the year that the plate or renewal is to be issued. A personalized license plate shall be replaced annually unless the applicant chooses to receive a renewal registration decal. A county clerk shall immediately forward the application and the fee required in KRS 186.162 for a personalized license plate to the Transportation Cabinet. Personalized plates issued under this section expire December 31 each year. The initial fee for a personalized license plate that has been combined with special license plate shall be as established in KRS 186.162(3). </section><section prefix="3">A personalized plate shall not be issued that would conflict with or duplicate the alphabetical-numerical system used for regular license plates or any other license plates issued in the Commonwealth, and shall not contain a combination of more than six (6) letters of the alphabet and Arabic numerals, including spaces. A personalized plate shall not be issued if the cabinet determines the request fails to comply with the conditions specified in KRS 186.164(9)(c) to (g). The owner or lessee shall submit an application and fee to renew a personalized license plate pursuant to the provisions of subsection (2) of this section. Once an applicant obtains a personalized plate, he or she will have first priority on that plate for each of the following years that he or she makes timely and proper application. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 133, sec. 8, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 347, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 543, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 200, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 428, sec. 22, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 296, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1990; and ch. 498, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 143, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988; ch. 150, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1988; and ch. 241, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 203, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 335, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 9, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 153, sec. 3, effective January 1, 1977. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5985</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>