<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="177" order_by="177">STATE AND FEDERAL HIGHWAYS -- LIMITED ACCESS FACILITIES -- TURNPIKES -- ROAD BONDS -- BILLBOARDS -- RECYCLERS </unit></structure><section_number>177.078</section_number><catch_line>Application -- Fees -- Reimbursement. </catch_line><order_by>078</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An application from an historical site or from a tourist area or attraction for the erection of a limited supplemental guide sign shall be made to the commissioner of the Department of Highways. The application shall include, but not be limited to: <section prefix="a">Evidence that demonstrates the average annual attendance; </section><section prefix="b">Evidence that the tourist area or attraction is established as a permanent business; and </section><section prefix="c">Evidence that the tourist area or attraction has all necessary and proper licenses, that normal business hours shall be maintained, that it is open to the traveling public, and that it provides recreational or educational opportunities. </section></section><section prefix="2">An application fee of two hundred dollars ($200) shall be paid to the Department of Highways by each applicant. </section><section prefix="3">Upon approval of the application, the applicant shall reimburse the Transportation Cabinet for the total cost of the sign and its installation. The applicant shall have the option to pay the reimbursement cost in full or amortize the reimbursement cost for a period not to exceed ten (10) years. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 30, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 353, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 526, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5265</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>