<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>271B.7-050</section_number><catch_line>Notice of meeting. </catch_line><order_by>7-050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A corporation shall notify shareholders of the date, time, and place of each annual and special shareholders' meeting no fewer than ten (10) nor more than sixty (60) days before the meeting date. Unless this chapter or the articles of incorporation require otherwise, the corporation shall be required to give notice only to shareholders entitled to vote at the meeting. </section><section prefix="2">Unless this chapter or the articles of incorporation require otherwise, notice of an annual meeting shall not be required to include a description of the purpose or purposes for which the meeting is called. </section><section prefix="3">Notice of a special meeting shall include a description of the purpose or purposes for which the meeting is called. </section><section prefix="4">If not otherwise fixed under KRS 271B.7-030 or 271B.7-070, the record date for determining shareholders entitled to notice of and to vote at an annual or special shareholders' meeting shall be the day before the first notice is delivered to shareholders. </section><section prefix="5">Unless the bylaws require otherwise, if an annual or special shareholders' meeting is adjourned to a different date, time, or place, notice shall not be required to be given of the new date, time, or place if the new date, time, or place is announced at the meeting before adjournment. If a new record date for the adjourned meeting is or must be fixed under KRS 271B.7-070, however, notice of the adjourned meeting shall be given under this section to persons who are shareholders as of the new record date. </section></text><history>Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 53, effective January 1, 1989. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 1989 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13356</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>