<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXI" order_by="31">DEBTOR-CREDITOR RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="376" order_by="376">STATUTORY LIENS </unit></structure><section_number>376.400</section_number><catch_line>Lien of keeper of livery stable or agister for care of livestock -- Sale of livestock cared for -- Conditions. </catch_line><order_by>400</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any owner or keeper of a livery stable or other business providing for the care of animals, and a person feeding, grazing, or caring for any animal for compensation, shall, except as provided in subsection (2) of this section, have a lien for one (1) year upon the animal placed in the stable, kennel, or similar facility, or put out to be fed or grazed by the owner, for his or her reasonable charges for keeping, caring for, feeding, and grazing the animal. The lien shall attach whether the animal is merely temporarily lodged, fed, grazed, and cared for, or is placed at the stable or other place or pasture for regular board. The lien shall take priority over a lien created pursuant to KRS 376.420(1). </section><section prefix="2">Any person who has agreed to provide feed or care for an animal for compensation may, in lieu of the lien provided for in subsection (1) of this section, cause the animal to be sold if: <section prefix="a">The owner of the animal is at least forty-five (45) days in arrears on his or her payment for the care and feeding of the animal, and the animal is in the possession of the person or business providing for the care of the animal; </section><section prefix="b">The proposed sale is published in one (1) or more newspapers and qualified pursuant to KRS Chapter 424, with a publication area in the locale where the person providing care for the animal is located and the locale where the owner of the animal was last known to reside; and </section><section prefix="c">Written notice of the sale is sent by certified mail, return receipt requested, or registered mail, to the owner of the animal, addressed to such person at his or her last known address, and to all lien holders of record with the Kentucky Secretary of State and the local county clerk's office, at least ten (10) days before the sale is conducted. The written notice shall include: <section prefix="1">The amount due the person or business providing care for the animal; </section><section prefix="2">The date, time, and location of the sale; and </section><section prefix="3">A statement that the sale proceeds shall be disbursed as provided in subsection (3) of this section. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">If a sale is conducted as provided in subsection (2) of this section, the proceeds of the sale shall be disbursed in the following order: <section prefix="a">Payment for costs associated with the sale; </section><section prefix="b">Payment of amounts due to the person or business providing for the care and feeding of the animal; </section><section prefix="c">Payment to lien holders and creditors pursuant to a court order; and </section><section prefix="d">The remainder, if any, held for the owner for a period of twelve (12) months and, if not claimed at that time, then paid into the district school fund. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 91, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 28, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 231, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2500. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><lrc-note>(6/25/2009).  The Reviser of Statutes has corrected a manifest clerical or typographical error in subsection (1) of this statute under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(h). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35329</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>