<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="367" order_by="367">CONSUMER PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>367.932</section_number><catch_line>Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>932</order_by><text>As used in KRS 367.934 to 367.974 and 367.991, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Attorney General" means Division of Consumer Protection in the office of the Attorney General. </section><section prefix="2">"Financial institution" means a bank, trust company, federally chartered credit union, or savings and loan association authorized by law to do business in this state. </section><section prefix="3">"Preneed burial contract" means a contract, which has for a purpose the furnishing or performance of funeral services, or the furnishing or delivery of personal property, merchandise, or services of any nature in connection with the final disposition of a dead human body, for future use at a time determinable by the death of the person whose body is to be disposed of; but does not mean the furnishing of a cemetery lot or mausoleum. </section><section prefix="4">"Agent" means the licensee who is the person, partnership, association or corporation receiving any payments on a preneed funeral contract. </section><section prefix="5">"Trustee" means the financial institution. </section><section prefix="6">"Person" means an individual, corporation, partnership, joint venture, association, business trust, or any other form of business organization; provided, however, that an individual employee of an entity registered pursuant to KRS 367.934 to 367.974 and 367.991 shall not be required to comply with the registration requirement herein. </section><section prefix="7">"Remains" means the bodies of deceased persons, in whatever stage of decomposition, and cremated remains. </section><section prefix="8">"Cemetery" means any one (1) or combination of more than one (1) of the following in a place used or to be used and dedicated or designated for such purposes: <section prefix="a">A burial park, for earth interment. </section><section prefix="b">A mausoleum, for entombment. </section><section prefix="c">A columbarium, for inurnment. </section></section><section prefix="9">"Mausoleum" means a building or structure substantially exposed above ground used or intended to be used for the entombment of human remains, which is sold or offered for sale to the public. </section><section prefix="10">"Columbarium" means a structure or building substantially exposed above ground intended to be used for the inurnment of cremated remains and sold or offered for sale to the public. </section><section prefix="11">"Columbarium niche" means an inurnment space in a columbarium as defined herein. </section><section prefix="12">"Cemetery company" means any person who conducts the business of a cemetery. Excepted are small community cemeteries, their agents, lessees and otherwise that operate nonprofit; have no salaried employees, directors, officers or managers other than maintenance caretakers; are owned, controlled by lot owners; and do not sell any preneed merchandise or services. </section><section prefix="13">"Grave space" means a space of ground in a cemetery intended to  be used for the interment in the ground of the remains of one (1) human being. </section><section prefix="14">"Underground crypt" means a single unit entombment space in preplaced chambers below ground and also known as lawn crypt, westminister turftop mausoleum or below ground crypt. </section><section prefix="15">"Bank of underground crypts" means any construction unit of twenty (20) or more underground crypts designed as a part of a below ground crypt program, whether physically connected or not, having a common drainage system. </section><section prefix="16">"Mausoleum crypt" means an entombment space in a mausoleum as defined herein. </section><section prefix="17">"Cemetery merchandise" means urns, memorials, monuments, markers, vases, foundations, memorial bases, and other similar personal property commonly sold by or used in cemeteries. </section><section prefix="18">"Preneed cemetery merchandise contract" means any agreement or contract, or any series or combination of agreements or contracts, which has for a purpose the furnishing or delivery of cemetery merchandise, which within six (6) months of the date of the contract is not attached to the realty and permanently installed or which is not stored in a bonded warehouse with the receipt of ownership issued by the manufacturer in the name of the purchaser and transmitted to the purchaser. </section></text><history>Repealed, reenacted, and amended as KRS 367.932, 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 116, secs. 1, and 9, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created in part 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 294, sec. 2. -- Created in part 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984 </effective><former-codification> KRS 307.100 and 316.310. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-16</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35112</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>