<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>355.8-509</section_number><catch_line>Specification of duties of securities intermediary by other statute or regulation -- Manner of performance of duties of securities intermediary and exercise of rights of entitlement holder. </catch_line><order_by>8-509</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If the substance of a duty imposed upon a securities intermediary by KRS 355.8-504 to 355.8-508 is the subject of other statute, regulation, or rule, compliance with that statute, regulation, or rule satisfies the duty. </section><section prefix="2">To the extent that specific standards for the performance of the duties of a securities intermediary or the exercise of the rights of an entitlement holder are not specified by other statute, regulation, or rule or by agreement between the securities intermediary and entitlement holder, the securities intermediary shall perform its duties and the entitlement holder shall exercise its rights in a commercially reasonable manner. </section><section prefix="3">The obligation of a securities intermediary to perform the duties imposed by KRS 355.8-504 to 355.8-508 is subject to: <section prefix="a">Rights of the securities intermediary arising out of a security interest under a security agreement with the entitlement holder or otherwise; and </section><section prefix="b">Rights of the securities intermediary under other law, regulation, rule, or agreement to withhold performance of its duties as a result of unfulfilled obligations of the entitlement holder to the securities intermediary. </section></section><section prefix="4">KRS 355.8-504 to 355.8-508 do not require a securities intermediary to take any action that is prohibited by other statute, regulation, or rule. </section></text><history> Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 162, effective January 1, 1997. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 1997 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33725</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>