<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="216" order_by="216">B LICENSURE AND REGULATION OF HEALTH FACILITIES AND SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>216B.0425</section_number><catch_line>Certification designations for stroke care for acute care hospitals.   </catch_line><order_by>0425</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as otherwise provided, for purposes of this section: <section prefix="a">"Acute care hospital" means a licensed facility providing inpatient and outpatient medical or surgical services to an individual that seeks care and treatment, regardless of the individual's ability to pay for services, on an immediate and emergent basis through an established emergency department and a continuous treatment basis on its premises for more than twenty-four (24) hours; and <section prefix="1">Complies with census-based national standards and safety goals; </section><section prefix="2">Effectively uses evidence-based clinical practice guidelines to manage </section><section prefix="3">Uses an organized approach to measure performance. </section></section>(b)"Primary stroke center certification," "acute stroke ready hospital certification," and "comprehensive stroke center certification" mean certification for acute care hospitals issued by the Joint Commission, the American Heart Association, or another cabinet-approved nationally recognized organization that provides disease-specific certification for stroke care, that: and optimize care; and </section><section prefix="2">The secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall designate as a primary stroke center any acute care hospital which has received an acute stroke ready hospital certification, a comprehensive stroke center certification, or a primary stroke center certification. </section><section prefix="3">The secretary shall suspend or revoke an acute care hospital's designation as an acute stroke ready hospital, a comprehensive stroke center, or a primary stroke center if certification is withdrawn by the Joint Commission, the American Heart Association, or another cabinet-approved certifying organization. </section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">The cabinet shall maintain a list of certified acute stroke ready hospitals, comprehensive stroke centers, and primary stroke centers and post the list on its Web site. The cabinet shall provide the list and periodic updates to the Kentucky Board of Emergency Medical Services. </section><section prefix="b">The Kentucky Board of Emergency Medical Services shall share the list with each local emergency medical services provider at least annually, and as new centers and hospitals are designated and certified. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 9, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2015. -- Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 67, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:37</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44043</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>