<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.10-670</section_number><catch_line>Administrative regulations -- Standards and certification program for analysis of wastewater pollution -- Data submitted by uncertified laboratory invalid. </catch_line><order_by>10-670</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet may promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A establishing: <section prefix="a">Standards for the operation of laboratories relating to analyses and laboratory tests for wastewater pollution, on behalf of activities subject to 33 U.S.C. sec. 1342, fees for certification and competency evaluations of those laboratories, and issuance of certificates of competency to persons and laboratories meeting the standards established by the agency; and </section><section prefix="b">A certification program for laboratories that submit environmental data as it relates to analyses and laboratory tests for activities subject to 33 U.S.C. sec. 1342. In developing the certification program, the cabinet shall consider, among other things, nationally recognized certification programs and those tailored for individual states. </section></section><section prefix="2">After one (1) year from the effective date of the administrative regulations described in subsection (1)(a) and (b) of this section, all environmental samples collected pursuant to an approved permit under 33 U.S.C. sec. 1342 shall be submitted to a laboratory that is certified by the cabinet. After that date, any data submitted on behalf of activities subject to 33 U.S.C. sec. 1342 to any agencies of the cabinet, that are generated by an uncertified laboratory, shall be deemed invalid. </section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 2, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:34</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39921</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>