<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.863</section_number><catch_line>Control of commerce of low-level radioactive waste in and out of Kentucky -- Prohibitions -- Exemption. </catch_line><order_by>863</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Unless otherwise authorized by the commission: <section prefix="a">After July 15, 1998, no person shall deposit at a facility in Kentucky any low-level radioactive waste not generated within the region. </section><section prefix="b">After July 15, 1998, no person shall accept at a facility in Kentucky low-level radioactive waste not generated within the region. </section><section prefix="c">No person shall deposit at any regional facility in Kentucky any low-level radioactive waste that is owned or generated by the United States Department of Energy, owned or generated by the United States Navy as a result of decommissioning of vessels of the United States Navy, or owned or generated as the result of any research, development, testing, or production of any atomic weapon. </section><section prefix="d">No person shall accept at any regional facility in Kentucky any low-level radioactive waste that is owned or generated by the United States Department of Energy, owned or generated by the United States Navy as a result of decommissioning of vessels of the United States Navy, or owned or generated as the result of any research, development, testing, or production of any atomic weapon. </section><section prefix="e">No person shall export from the region low-level radioactive waste that is generated in Kentucky, other than low-level radioactive waste that is owned or generated by the United States Department of Energy, owned or generated by the United States Navy as a result of decommissioning of vessels of the United States Navy, or owned or generated as the result of any research, development, testing, or production of any atomic weapon. </section><section prefix="f">No person shall dispose of low-level radioactive waste in Kentucky except at a regional disposal facility. </section><section prefix="g">No person who provides a service by arranging for the collection, transportation, treatment, storage, or disposal of low-level radioactive waste from outside the region shall dispose of any low-level radioactive waste, regardless of origin, at a facility in Kentucky without prior specific approval by the commission. </section></section><section prefix="2">No person shall treat or store low-level radioactive waste at a facility other than a regional facility, if the treatment or storage is prohibited by the commission. </section><section prefix="3">Naturally-occurring radioactive material (NORM) as defined in KRS 211.862(8) shall be the exclusive regulatory responsibility of the states, except that no person shall import naturally occurring radioactive material (NORM) from outside the region for disposal in Kentucky, or dispose of such imported material in Kentucky, if the imports or disposal are inconsistent with polices of the commission. </section><section prefix="4">Any low-level radioactive waste which is not the responsibility of the Commonwealth of Kentucky or the Central Midwest Interstate Low-Level Radioactive Waste Commission pursuant to 42 U.S.C. sec. 2297h-11 shall be exempt from the provisions of KRS 211.861 to 211.869 and from the provisions of KRS 211.859. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 46, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8502</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>