<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="97" order_by="97">PARKS, PLAYGROUNDS, AND RECREATION </unit></structure><section_number>97.700</section_number><catch_line>Appropriation or tax levy to maintain memorial.   </catch_line><order_by>700</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In order to provide sufficient funds for maintaining the memorial and for carrying on the work of the commission the city legislative body in cities of the first class shall annually appropriate from the general fund of the city such sums as in the judgment of the legislative body shall, when supplemented by any funds received by the commission from gifts or earnings of the memorial, be reasonably necessary for such purposes. All moneys so appropriated may be paid over to the commission by the director of finance of such city in regular monthly installments. If it appears from the report or statement of the commission that funds received by gift or from earnings of the memorial, available for maintenance of the memorial for any fiscal year, are fully adequate for the purpose, the appropriation for such year may be withheld by the legislative body. </section><section prefix="2">For the purpose of providing necessary funds for maintaining such memorial and for carrying on the work of the commission a city legislative body of cities of the home rule class may annually appropriate from the general fund of the city or annually levy and collect a tax not exceeding five cents ($0.05) on each one hundred dollars ($100) worth of taxable property in such city as determined by the last regular assessment of such city, and the taxes so levied shall be collected in the customary way and shall be paid over to said commission for the purpose named in this section; provided, however, that if it shall appear from the report or statement of the commission that funds received by gift or from earnings of the memorial, available for maintenance of the memorial for any fiscal year, are fully adequate therefor after deductions therefrom are made as herein provided, the said tax levy for such year may be withheld by the city legislative body. </section></text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 184, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 363, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 4, effective June 17, 1954. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 3037i-10, 3037i-11. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:13</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43769</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>