<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="334" order_by="334">SPECIALISTS IN HEARING INSTRUMENTS </unit></structure><section_number>334.090</section_number><catch_line>Apprentice permit -- Training stages -- Renewal of permit -- Sponsorship of apprentices. </catch_line><order_by>090</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An applicant who fulfills the requirements of KRS 334.050 may apply to the board for an apprentice permit as provided by the board by the promulgation of an administrative regulation. The fee shall be established by the board by the promulgation of an administrative regulation. </section><section prefix="2">The apprenticeship period shall be for twelve (12) months as follows: <section prefix="a">Stage I -- The apprentice shall work for thirty (30) days under the direct control of a sponsor. The apprentice shall not in any way fit or test the client for the purpose of selling hearing instruments. </section><section prefix="b">Stage II -- This training stage shall last for one hundred fifty (150) days. During this period the apprentice may conduct testing necessary for the proper selection and fitting of a hearing instrument, and make ear impressions. During this period the apprentice shall be under the direct supervision of his sponsor or a licensed specialist in hearing instruments who shall also qualify as a sponsor as defined in subsection (8) of this section. During this period the apprentice shall not make delivery or final fitting without direct personal supervision during the actual delivery. </section><section prefix="c">Stage III -- This training stage shall last for one hundred eighty (180) days. The apprentice may engage in all activities of a licensed person. He shall, however, work under and be responsible to a licensed sponsor for the remainder of the apprentice period. </section></section><section prefix="3">The stages provided in subsection (2) of this section shall be completed with no interim time lapse between stages. If the apprentice leaves his place of training without approval of his employer, he shall forfeit seniority, and revert to stage I, subject to appeal to the board. </section><section prefix="4">After completion of the stages provided in subsection (2) of this section, the apprentice shall take the qualifying examination given by the board for a license and upon successfully passing the examination and paying the appropriate fee, may obtain a license. </section><section prefix="5">If a person who holds an apprentice permit issued under this section takes and fails to pass the qualifying examination, the board may renew the apprentice permit as provided by the board by the promulgation of an administrative regulation. A fee established by the board by the promulgation of an administrative regulation shall be paid prior to reexamination. </section><section prefix="6">Apprentice permit holders shall be governed by all administrative regulations and standards of ethical conduct pertaining to regular licensees. </section><section prefix="7">The satisfactory completion of a course in the selling or fitting of hearing instruments approved by the board may be considered equivalent to stages I and II of the apprenticeship period. </section><section prefix="8">No person shall sponsor an apprentice unless he is a licensed specialist in hearing instruments with a minimum of three (3) years' experience, has obtained NBC-HIS board certification, or has a current license issued pursuant to this chapter on or before December 31, 1992. No sponsor may have more than two (2) apprentices at one (1) time. The sponsor shall be responsible for all sales and service of the apprentices and all monetary reimbursements. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 272, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 460, sec. 9, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 9. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31875</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>