<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17A-623</section_number><catch_line>External review of adverse determination -- Who may request -- Criteria for review -- Fee -- Conditions under which covered person not entitled to review -- Resolution of disputes -- Confidentiality -- Expedited external review. </catch_line><order_by>17A-623</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every insurer shall have an external review process to be utilized by the insurer or its designee, consistent with this section and which shall be disclosed to covered persons in accordance with KRS 304.17A-505(1)(g). An insurer, its designee, or agent shall disclose the availability of the external review process to the covered person in the insured's timely notice of an adverse determination or notice of a coverage denial as set forth in KRS 304.17A-607(1)(j) and in the denial letter required in KRS 304.17A-617(1) and (2)(e). For purposes of this section "coverage denial" means an insurer's determination that a service, treatment, drug, or device is specifically limited or excluded under the covered person's health benefit plan. </section><section prefix="2">A covered person, an authorized person, or a provider acting on behalf of and with the consent of the covered person, may request an external review of an adverse determination rendered by an insurer, its designee, or agent. </section><section prefix="3">The insurer shall provide for an external review of an adverse determination if the following criteria are met: <section prefix="a">The insurer, its designee, or agent has rendered an adverse determination; </section><section prefix="b">The covered person has completed the insurer's internal appeal process, or the insurer has failed to make a timely determination or notification as set forth in KRS 304.17A-619(2). The insurer and the covered person may however, jointly agree to waive the internal appeal requirement; </section><section prefix="c">The covered person was enrolled in the health benefit plan on the date of service or, if a prospective denial, the covered person was enrolled and eligible to receive covered benefits under the health benefit plan on the date the proposed service was requested; and </section><section prefix="d">The entire course of treatment or service will cost the covered person at least one hundred dollars ($100) if the covered person had no insurance. </section></section><section prefix="4">The covered person, an authorized person, or a provider with consent of the covered person shall submit a request for external review to the insurer within sixty (60) days, except as set forth in KRS 304.17A-619(1), of receiving notice that an adverse determination has been timely rendered under the insurer's internal appeal process. As part of the request, the covered person shall provide to the insurer or its designee written consent authorizing the independent review entity to obtain all necessary medical records from both the insurer and any provider utilized for review purposes regarding the decision to deny, limit, reduce or terminate coverage. </section><section prefix="5">The covered person shall be assessed a one (1) time filing fee of twenty-five dollars ($25) to be paid to the independent review entity and which may be waived if the independent review entity determines that the fee creates a financial hardship on the covered person. The fee shall be refunded if the independent review entity finds in favor of the covered person. </section><section prefix="6">A covered person shall not be afforded an external review of an adverse determination if: <section prefix="a">The subject of the covered person's adverse determination has previously gone through the external review process and the independent review entity found in favor of the insurer; and </section><section prefix="b">No relevant new clinical information has been submitted to the insurer since the independent review entity found in favor of the insurer. </section></section><section prefix="7">The department shall establish a system for each insurer to be assigned an independent review entity for external reviews. The system established by the department shall be prospective and shall require insurers to utilize independent review entities on a rotating basis so that an insurer does not have the same independent review entity for two (2) consecutive external reviews. The department shall contract with no less than two (2) independent review entities. </section><section prefix="8"><section prefix="a">If a dispute arises between an insurer and a covered person regarding the covered person's right to an external review, the covered person may file a complaint with the department. Within five (5) days of receipt of the complaint, the department shall render a decision and may direct the insurer to submit the dispute to an independent review entity for an external review if it finds: <section prefix="1">The dispute involves denial of coverage based on medical necessity or the service being experimental or investigational; and </section><section prefix="2">All of the requirements of subsection (3) of this section have been met. </section></section><section prefix="b">The complaint process established in this section shall be separate and distinct from, and shall in no way limit other grievance or complaint processes available to consumers under other provisions of the KRS or duly promulgated administrative regulations. This complaint process shall not limit, alter, or supplant the mechanisms for appealing coverage denials established in KRS 304.17A-617. </section></section><section prefix="9">The external review process shall be confidential and shall not be subject to KRS 61.805 to 61.850 and KRS 61.870 to 61.884. </section><section prefix="10">External reviews shall be conducted in an expedited manner by the independent review entity if the covered person is hospitalized, or if, in the opinion of the treating provider, review under the standard time frame could, in the absence of immediate medical attention, result in any of the following: <section prefix="a">Placing the health of the covered person or, with respect to a pregnant woman, the health of the covered person or her unborn child in serious jeopardy; </section><section prefix="b">Serious impairment to bodily functions; or </section><section prefix="c">Serious dysfunction of a bodily organ or part. </section></section><section prefix="11">Requests for expedited external review, shall be forwarded by the insurer to the independent review entity within twenty-four (24) hours of receipt by the insurer. </section><section prefix="12">For expedited external review, a determination shall be made by the independent review entity within twenty-four (24) hours from the receipt of all information required from the insurer. An extension of up to twenty-four (24) hours may be allowed if the covered person and the insurer or its designee agree. The insurer or its designee shall provide notice to the independent review entity and to the covered person, by same-day communication, that the adverse determination has been assigned to an independent review entity for expedited review. </section><section prefix="13">External reviews which are not expedited shall be conducted by the independent review entity and a determination made within twenty-one (21) calendar days from the receipt of all information required from the insurer. An extension of up to fourteen (14) calendar days may be allowed if the covered person and the insurer are in agreement. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1241, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 14, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 181, sec. 9, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 262, sec. 12, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29312</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>