<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="439" order_by="439">PROBATION AND PAROLE </unit></structure><section_number>439.3405</section_number><catch_line>Parole of prisoners with documented terminal medical conditions -- Hearing. </catch_line><order_by>3405</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding any statute eliminating parole or establishing minimum time for parole eligibility for a certain class or status of offender, including KRS 439.340(11), 439.3401, 532.080(7), and 533.060, the board, with the written consent of a majority of the full board, may review the case of any prisoner and release that prisoner on parole despite any elimination of or minimum time for parole eligibility, when the prisoner has a documented terminal medical condition likely to result in death within one (1) year or severe chronic lung disease, end-stage heart disease, severe neuro-muscular disease such as multiple sclerosis; or has severely limited mobility as a result of stroke, disease, or trauma; or is dependent on external life support systems and would not pose a threat to society if paroled. </section><section prefix="2">Medical information considered under this section shall be limited to the medical findings supplied by Department of Corrections medical staff. The medical staff shall provide in writing the prisoner's diagnosis and prognosis in support of the conclusion that the prisoner suffers from a terminal medical condition likely to result in death within one (1) year or because of the conditions set forth in subsection (1) of this section he or she is substantially dependent on others for the activities of daily living. </section><section prefix="3">The medical information prepared by the Department of Corrections medical staff under this section shall be forwarded to the medical director of the Department of Corrections who shall submit that information and a recommendation for or against parole review under this section to the commissioner of the Department of Corrections or his or her designee. With the approval of the commissioner of the Department of Corrections, a request for parole review under this section, along with the medical information and medical director's recommendation, shall be submitted to the board. </section><section prefix="4">Medical information presented under this section shall be considered along with other information relevant to a decision regarding the granting of parole and shall not constitute the only reason for granting parole. </section><section prefix="5">Notwithstanding KRS 439.340(5), in addition to or in conjunction with each review conducted under subsection (1) of this section for any prisoner convicted of a Class A or B felony, or of a Class C felony involving violence or a sexual offense and prior to the granting of parole to any such prisoner, the Parole Board shall conduct a hearing of which the following persons shall receive not less than fifteen (15) nor more than thirty (30) days' notice: <section prefix="a">The Commonwealth's attorney, who shall notify the sheriff of every county and the chief of police of every city and county in which the prisoner committed any Class A, B, or C felony for which he or she is imprisoned; and </section><section prefix="b">All identified victims of the crimes or the next of kin of any victim who is deceased. </section></section> Notice to the Commonwealth's attorney shall be by mail, fax, or electronic means, at the discretion of the board, and shall be in a manner that ensures receipt at the Commonwealth attorney's business office. Notices received by chiefs of police and sheriffs shall be posted in a conspicuous location where police employed by the department may see it. Notices shall be posted in a manner and at a time that will allow officers to make comment thereon to the Parole Board. Notice to victims or their next of kin shall be made by mail, fax, or electronic means, at the discretion of the board, to their last known address or telephone number as provided by the Commonwealth's attorney to the Parole Board at the time of incarceration of the prisoner. Notice to the victim or the next of kin of subsequent considerations for parole after the initial consideration shall not be sent if the victim or the next of kin gives notice to the board that he or she no longer wants to receive such notices. The notice shall include the time, date, and place of the hearing provided for in this subsection, and the name and address of a person to write if the recipient of the notice desires to attend the hearing or to submit written comments. </text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 28, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 128, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 606, sec. 78, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 179, sec. 5, effective April 4, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39548</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>