<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="I" order_by="1">SOVEREIGNTY AND JURISDICTION OF THE COMMONWEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="2" order_by="2">CITIZENSHIP, EMBLEMS, HOLIDAYS, AND TIME </unit></structure><section_number>2.110</section_number><catch_line>Public holidays. </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The first day of January (New Year's Day), the third Monday of January (Birthday of Martin Luther King, Jr.), the nineteenth day of January (Robert E. Lee Day), the thirtieth day of January (Franklin D. Roosevelt Day), the twelfth day of February (Lincoln's Birthday), the third Monday in February (Washington's Birthday), the last Monday in May (Memorial Day), the third day of June (Confederate Memorial Day, and Jefferson Davis Day), the fourth day of July (Independence Day), the first Monday in September (Labor Day), the second Monday in October (Columbus Day), the eleventh day of November (Veterans Day), the twenty-fifth day of December (Christmas Day) of each year, and all days appointed by the President of the United States or by the Governor as days of thanksgiving, are holidays, on which all the public offices of this Commonwealth may be closed. </section><section prefix="2">No person shall be compelled to labor on the first Monday in September (Labor Day) by any person. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 17, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 88, sec. 1, effective January 1, 1986. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 1, effective June 21, 1974; and ch. 176, sec. 1, effective June 21, 1974. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 50, sec. 1, effective January 1, 1971. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 73, sec. 1, effective June 19, 1958. -- Amended 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 73, sec. 1, effective March 13, 1948. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2089b to 2089g, 2089j. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=46</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>