<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.7630</section_number><catch_line>Gathering and reporting information regarding 911 emergency communications funding and costs – Administrative regulations – Information subject to disclosure under Open Records Act and information subject to confidentiality – Report to Legislative Research Commission. </catch_line><order_by>7630</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The CMRS Board shall gather and report data and information regarding 911 emergency communications funding procedures and costs on or before August 1, 2011, and each August 1 thereafter. </section><section prefix="2">The CMRS Board shall determine the information it needs to evaluate 911 funding, CMRS service charge collections, and expenditures, and each local governmental agency, state governmental agency, wireless or wireline provider of technology capable of transmitting voice traffic for an emergency 911 request to a PSAP, and/or private citizen in possession of that information shall provide the information to the board within the time frames established by the board. The board may hire a consultant to gather and analyze the information required by this section. </section><section prefix="3">Each local governmental agency and state governmental agency having jurisdiction over one (1) or more public safety answering points (PSAPs) shall provide at least the following information to the board: <section prefix="a">For each PSAP for fiscal years 2007-2008, 2008-2009, 2009-2010, and 2010-2011: <section prefix="1">Wireline 911 fees; </section><section prefix="2">CMRS Board fund money dispersed to the PSAP; </section><section prefix="3">Direct grants or state matches for federal, state, or private grants; and </section><section prefix="4">Gifts or other amounts not otherwise reported in this paragraph; and </section></section><section prefix="b">How the revenue described in this paragraph was spent by the PSAPs. </section></section><section prefix="4">Each wireless or wireline provider of technology capable of transmitting voice traffic for an emergency 911 request to a PSAP shall report to the board the amount of reimbursements received in fiscal years 2007-2008, 2008-2009, 2009-2010, and 2010-2011. </section><section prefix="5">Each local governmental agency, state governmental agency, or wireless or wireline provider of technology capable of transmitting voice traffic for an emergency 911 request to a PSAP that fails to provide the information required by this section shall not be eligible to receive distributions of state funds from the CMRS Board. </section><section prefix="6">The CMRS Board shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to establish annual reporting requirements so that the board has the information needed to monitor the use of 911 funds and the rate of the 911 service charge. </section><section prefix="7">All information received by the CMRS Board pursuant to this section shall be subject to disclosure under KRS 61.870 to 61.884. Proprietary information given to the board by any wireless or wireline provider of technology capable of transmitting voice traffic for an emergency 911 request to a PSAP pursuant to this section shall be subject to the same confidentiality as provided for proprietary information under KRS 65.7639. </section><section prefix="8">The CMRS Board shall ensure that the Legislative Research Commission has access to all data collected under this section and shall report this information to the Legislative Research Commission's Interim Joint Committee on Veterans, Military Affairs, and Public Protection by August 1 of each year. </section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 1, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39928</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>