<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.20-320</section_number><catch_line>Declinations -- Cancellations -- Nonrenewals -- Terminations -- Notice of premium required. </catch_line><order_by>20-320</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Declinations. An applicant may request in writing an explanation of a declination. The insurer shall provide a prompt written response to such inquiries. </section><section prefix="2">Cancellations. <section prefix="a">A notice of cancellation of insurance subject to KRS 304.20-300 to 304.20-350 by an insurer shall be in writing, shall be delivered to the named insured or mailed to the named insured at the last known address of the named insured, shall state the effective date of the cancellation, and shall be accompanied by a written explanation of the specific reason or reasons for the cancellation. </section><section prefix="b">The notice of cancellation referred to in paragraph (a) of this subsection shall be mailed or delivered by the insurer to the named insured at least fourteen (14) days prior to the effective date of the cancellation if the cancellation is for nonpayment of premium or occurs within sixty (60) days of the date of issuance of the policy. Such notice of cancellation shall be mailed or delivered by the insurer to the named insured at least seventy-five (75) days prior to the effective date of the cancellation if the policy has been in effect more than sixty (60) days. </section><section prefix="c">Proof of mailing of notice of cancellation or of reasons for cancellation to the named insured at the address shown in the policy shall be sufficient proof of notice. </section></section><section prefix="3">Nonrenewals. <section prefix="a">No insurer shall refuse to renew a property or casualty insurance policy subject to KRS 304.20-300 to 304.20-350 unless at least seventy-five (75) days before the end of the policy period as described in KRS 304.20-310(1), the insurer shall mail or deliver to the named insured, at the last known address of the named insured, written notice of the insurer's intention not to renew the policy upon expiration of the current policy period with a written explanation of the specific reason or reasons for the nonrenewal. </section><section prefix="b">If notice is not provided pursuant to paragraphs (a) and (b) of this subsection, coverage shall be deemed to be renewed for the ensuing policy period upon payment of the appropriate premium under the same terms and conditions, and subject to the provisions of KRS 304.20-330, until the named insured has accepted replacement coverage with another insurer, or until the named insured has agreed to the nonrenewal. </section><section prefix="c">If the insurer has manifested its willingness to renew by mailing or delivering of a renewal notice, bill, certificate, or policy to the first named insured at his last known address at least thirty (30) days before the end of the current policy period with the amount of the renewal premium charge and its due date clearly set forth therein, then the policy shall expire and terminate without further notice to the insured on the due date unless the renewal premium is received by the insurer or its authorized agent on or before that date. When any policy terminates pursuant to this subsection because the renewal premium was not received on or before the due date, the insurer shall, within fifteen (15) days, deliver or mail to the first named insured at his last known address a notice that the policy was not renewed and the date on which the coverage under it ceased to exist. </section><section prefix="d">Proof of mailing of renewal premium to the insurer or its agent, when authorized, on or before the due date shall constitute a presumption of receipt pursuant to paragraph (c) of this subsection. </section><section prefix="e">Proof of mailing of notice of intention not to renew or of reasons for nonrenewal to the named insured at the address shown in the policy shall be sufficient proof of notice. </section></section><section prefix="4">No insurer shall increase the premium for a property or casualty insurance policy subject to KRS 304.20-300 to 304.20-350 more than twenty-five percent (25%) of the premium for the preceding policy term for like coverage and like risks unless at least seventy-five (75) days before the end of the policy period as described in KRS 304.20-310(1), the insurer shall mail or deliver to the named insured, at the last known address of the named insured, a notice for the renewal premium amount and the insurer shall mail or deliver to its agent, if any, a duplicate notice of the premium amount. In order to comply with this requirement, the insurer may extend the period of coverage of the current policy at the expiring premium. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 540, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 97, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1988; and ch. 225, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><lrc-note>.The amendment in 1988 Acts Chapter 225 conflicts with that in 1988 Acts Chapter 97 in that Chapter 97 removes subsection (4), while chapter 225 adds new language in subsection (4). Pursuant to KRS 446.250, the later enactment in chapter 225 prevails. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:04</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29503</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>