<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="281" order_by="281">MOTOR CARRIERS </unit></structure><section_number>281.990</section_number><catch_line>Penalties.   </catch_line><order_by>990</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided in subsection (5) of this section, a person shall be fined not less than twenty-five dollars ($25) and no more than two hundred dollars ($200), if the person: <section prefix="a">Violates, causes, aids, or abets any violation of the provisions of this chapter, or any order, rule, or administrative regulation lawfully issued pursuant to authority granted by this chapter; </section><section prefix="b">Knowingly makes any false or erroneous statement, report, or representation to the Department of Vehicle Regulation with respect to any matter placed under the jurisdiction of the department by this chapter; </section><section prefix="c">Knowingly makes any false entry in the accounts or records required to be kept pursuant to the authority granted by this chapter; or </section><section prefix="d">Knowingly fails to keep, or knowingly destroys or mutilates, any accounts or records. </section></section> Every device to evade or to prevent the application of any provision of this chapter, or any lawful order, rule or administrative regulation of the department issued pursuant thereto, shall constitute a violation thereof. <section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Any person who violates KRS 281.630(1) or 281.631(1) shall be fined not less than five hundred dollars ($500) nor more than three thousand five hundred dollars ($3,500). </section><section prefix="b">Any person who operates as a motor carrier in violation of the terms of his or her certificate or motor carrier vehicle license shall be fined not less than five hundred dollars ($500) nor more than three thousand five hundred dollars ($3,500). </section></section><section prefix="3">A person who violates KRS 281.630(9) shall not be subject to a penalty under this section. </section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">Except as provided in this subsection, any person who violates KRS 281.757 shall be fined two hundred fifty dollars ($250) for each offense. </section><section prefix="b">A person who is cited for a violation of KRS 281.757 in which the lights were inoperable or the reflectors were missing may, within thirty (30) days from the date of the citation, provide proof to the county attorney of the county in which the offense occurred that the mechanical problem has been repaired and that the lights are in working order or that the required reflectors have been placed on the vehicle. If such proof is shown, the citation shall be dismissed. </section><section prefix="c">A law enforcement officer and the department shall not issue a citation to a person as violating KRS 281.757 if the atmospheric conditions all motorists were subjected to at the time the person is stopped reasonably limit the ability of a person to keep the vehicle's lights or reflectors from being obscured by dirt, mud, or debris. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 19, sec. 33, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 159, sec. 2, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 512, sec. 9, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 331, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1979 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 7, effective July 1, 1979. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 6, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. IV, sec. 20(2). -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 139, sec. 10, effective June 16, 1960. -- Created 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 63, sec. 56, effective June 15, 1950. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><former-history>Repealed 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 63, sec. 57, effective June 15, 1950. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 185, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2739j-39, 2739j-90, 2739j-91, 27391-14. </former-history><former-history-former-name>KRS 281.990: </former-history-former-name><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44182</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>