<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.478</section_number><catch_line>Support services for deaf and hard of hearing students -- Funding. </catch_line><order_by>478</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It is the intent of the General Assembly to increase the educational level of deaf and hard of hearing persons by assuring them an equal opportunity to obtain an education in the public postsecondary institutions. </section><section prefix="2">The public postsecondary institutions shall make their programs accessible to deaf and hard of hearing students by providing support services necessary for such students to fully participate in the programs. The support services shall include but not be limited to interpreters and notetakers in the classroom and equal access to all support services available to those who are not deaf or hard of hearing. Appropriate assistive listening devices and alerting devices shall be available in dormitories housing deaf or hard of hearing students. </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">The General Assembly shall appropriate funds to the Office of Vocational Rehabilitation excluding costs of capital equipment or modifications for installation of assistive listening or alerting devices to cover the costs of support services at the institutions for students who are deaf or hard of hearing. </section><section prefix="b">The Office of Vocational Rehabilitation shall administer funding of support services at institutions for students who are deaf or hard of hearing contingent on General Assembly funding. The postsecondary institutions and the Office of Vocational Rehabilitation shall cooperate to assure that funds are used to effectively provide support services to students who are deaf and hard of hearing. </section><section prefix="c">The funds shall be distributed to institutions based upon actual costs or established fees for service of providing support services to individual students. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 106, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 448, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 292, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 144, sec. 9, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 470, sec. 65, effective July 1, 1990. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 75, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4298</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>