<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="237" order_by="237">FIREARMS AND DESTRUCTIVE DEVICES </unit></structure><section_number>237.100</section_number><catch_line>Notification of purchase of firearm or attempt to purchase firearm --Immunity.  </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text>(1)Upon receipt of notice that a person barred from purchasing a firearm under 18U.S.C. sec. 922(g)(8) has purchased or attempted to purchase a firearm, theJustice and Public Safety Cabinet shall make a reasonable effort to providenotice to the petitioner who obtained the domestic violence order issued underKRS 403.740 that the respondent to the order has attempted to purchase afirearm. The Justice and Public Safety Cabinet may contract with a privateentity in order to provide notification.(2)The notification shall be limited to a petitioner who has:(a)Received a domestic violence protective order issued or reissued underKRS 403.740 on or after July 15, 2002;(b)Received a domestic violence protective order that involves a respondentwho is prohibited by 18 U.S.C. sec. 922(g)(8) from possessing a firearm;and(c)Provided the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet or the entity with arequest for notification.(3)Any person carrying out responsibilities under this section shall be immunefrom civil liability for good faith conduct in carrying out those responsibilities.Nothing in this subsection shall limit liability for negligence.</text><history>Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 41, effective January 1, 2016. --Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 265, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created2002 Ky. Acts ch. 70, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44789</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>