<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="209" order_by="209">A SPOUSAL ABUSE OR NEGLECT </unit></structure><section_number>209A.020</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Secretary" means the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="2">"Cabinet" means the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="3">"Department" means the Department for Community Based Services of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="4">"Adult" means a person without regard to age who is the victim of abuse or neglect inflicted by a spouse; </section><section prefix="5">"Protective services" means agency services undertaken with or on behalf of an adult in need of protective services who is being abused or neglected. These services may include but are not limited to conducting investigations of complaints of possible abuse or neglect to ascertain whether or not the situation and condition of the adult in need of protective services warrants further action, including action under KRS Chapter 209, and social services aimed at preventing and remedying abuse or neglect; </section><section prefix="6">"Abuse" means the infliction of injury, unreasonable confinement, intimidation, or punishment resulting in physical harm or pain, including mental injury; </section><section prefix="7">"Investigation" shall include but is not limited to a personal interview with the individual reported to be abused or neglected. When abuse or neglect is allegedly the cause of death, a coroner's or doctor's report shall be examined as part of the investigation; </section><section prefix="8">"Records" means the medical or mental health records of the adult that are in the possession of any individual, hospital, firm, corporation, or other facility if necessary to complete the investigation mandated in KRS 209.030(5); </section><section prefix="9">"Neglect" means a situation in which a person deprives his or her spouse of reasonable services to maintain health and welfare; and </section><section prefix="10">"Authorized agency" means: <section prefix="a">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="b">A local law enforcement agency or the Department of Kentucky State Police; or </section><section prefix="c">The office of a Commonwealth's attorney or county attorney. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 243, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 21, effective June 20, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><lrc-note> (6/20/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 95, 97, 98, 99, 123, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8211</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>