<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">B MEDICAL IMAGING, RADIATION THERAPY, AND RELATED OCCUPATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>311B.150</section_number><catch_line>Prohibited activities.   </catch_line><order_by>150</order_by><text>It shall be unlawful for any person to: <section prefix="1">Claim to be a licensee or perform medical imaging or therapeutic procedures unless licensed under this chapter; </section><section prefix="2">Manipulate equipment that produces ionizing radiation or administer radiopharmaceuticals unless licensed under this chapter; </section><section prefix="3">Knowingly employ an advanced imaging professional, medical imaging technologist, radiographer, radiation therapist, nuclear medicine technologist, or limited X-ray machine operator unless that individual is licensed under the provisions of this chapter; or </section><section prefix="4">Be an advanced imaging professional, medical imaging technologist, radiographer, radiation therapist, nuclear medicine technologist, limited X-ray machine operator, employer of one (1) of these individuals, or any other person who, having knowledge of a situation listed in paragraphs (a) to (j) of this subsection, refrains from reporting to the board a licensee who: <section prefix="a">Has been convicted of any felony or a misdemeanor involving drugs, alcohol, fraud, deceit, falsification of records, a breach of trust, physical harm or endangerment to others, or dishonesty under the laws of any state or of the United States; </section><section prefix="b">Is suspected of fraud or deceit in procuring or attempting to procure a license or credential to practice in his or her discipline; </section><section prefix="c">Is suspected of negligently or willfully acting in a manner inconsistent with professional practice relative to his or her discipline; </section><section prefix="d">Is suspected of being unfit or incompetent to practice by reason of negligence or other causes, including but not limited to being unable to practice with reasonable skill or safety; </section><section prefix="e">Has a license or credential to practice medical imaging or radiation therapy denied, suspended, revoked, or otherwise disciplined in another jurisdiction on grounds sufficient to cause a license or credential to be denied, suspended, revoked, or otherwise disciplined in this Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="f">Is practicing medical imaging or radiation therapy, as it pertains to this chapter, without a current active license or valid temporary license issued by the board; </section><section prefix="g">Is suspected of misusing or misappropriating any drugs placed in the licensee’s custody to be administered to or used by others; </section><section prefix="h">Is suspected of falsely or negligently making incorrect entries or failing to make essential entries on essential records; </section><section prefix="i">Is suspected of abusing controlled substances, prescription medications, illegal substances, or alcohol; or </section><section prefix="j">Is suspected of violating any provision of this chapter. </section></section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 50, sec. 15, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40209</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>