<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="349" order_by="349">COALBED METHANE DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>349.060</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of Coalbed Methane Well Review Board -- Promulgation of administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The review board shall rule upon: <section prefix="a">Objections to proposed coalbed methane wells, their locations, the proposed stimulation, or the proposed completion pursuant to KRS 349.020; </section><section prefix="b">Appeals of permit denials arising under KRS 349.020(5); </section><section prefix="c">Requests for a hearing arising under KRS 349.025(3); </section><section prefix="d">Requests for pooling orders pursuant to KRS 349.080(1); </section><section prefix="e">Requests for the establishment or modification of drilling units for coalbed methane wells; </section><section prefix="f">Requests for the creation or modification of field rules relating to the drilling, completion, and production of coalbed methane wells; and </section><section prefix="g">Requests for the unitization of coalbed methane wells, pools, or fields. </section></section><section prefix="2">The review board shall meet, hold conferences, and hold hearings at a time and place as designated by the chairman. The chairman may call a meeting of the review board at any time. A majority of the members of the review board shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of any business to come before the review board. All determinations of the review board shall be by majority vote of the quorum present. The commissioner, or his or her designee within the department, shall be the chairman of the review board. The review board shall hold a regular monthly meeting. Notice of all meetings of the review board shall be given to each member by the chairman at least ten (10) days in advance of each meeting, unless otherwise agreed by the members. </section><section prefix="3">The review board shall execute, carry out, administer, and enforce the provisions of this chapter in the manner provided in this section. </section><section prefix="4">The review board may: <section prefix="a">Take evidence and issue orders concerning the permitting of a coalbed methane well, its location, stimulation, and the completion pursuant to KRS 349.015; issue pooling orders in accordance with KRS 349.080(1); issue orders regarding the establishment or modification of drilling units for coalbed methane wells, field rules relating to the drilling, completion, and production of coalbed methane wells; and requests for the unitization of coalbed methane wells, pools, and fields; </section><section prefix="b">Promulgate and enforce administrative regulations and rules necessary to govern the practice and procedure before the review board; </section><section prefix="c">Make relevant investigations of records and facilities as it deems proper in connection with ruling on any objections to a proposed coalbed methane well, its location, the proposed stimulation, or the proposed completion; and </section><section prefix="d">Issue subpoenas for the attendance and sworn testimony from witnesses and subpoenas duces tecum for the production of any books, records, maps, charts, diagrams, electronic data, and other pertinent documents or data in the review board's own name or at the request of any party. </section></section></text><history> Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 12, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32735</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>