<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIII" order_by="33">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS AND ESTATES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="387" order_by="387">GUARDIANS -- CONSERVATORS -- CURATORS OF CONVICTS </unit></structure><section_number>387.500</section_number><catch_line>Declaration of legislative purpose. </catch_line><order_by>500</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It is the intent and purpose of the General Assembly to recognize that disabled persons have varying degrees of disability. </section><section prefix="2">Persons who are only partially disabled must be legally protected without a determination of total incompetency and without the attendant deprivation of civil and legal rights that such a determination requires. </section><section prefix="3">To this end, guardianship and conservatorship for disabled persons shall be utilized only as is necessary to promote their well-being, including protection from neglect, exploitation, and abuse; shall be designed to encourage the development of maximum self-reliance and independence in each person; and shall be ordered only to the extent necessitated by each person's actual mental and adaptive limitations. </section><section prefix="4">If the court determines that some form of guardianship or conservatorship is necessary, partial guardianship or partial conservatorship shall be the preferred form of protection and assistance for a disabled person. </section></text><history>Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 1, effective July 1, 1982. </history><metadata><effective>July 1, 1982 </effective><lrc-note>.  The chairman of the guardianship subcommittee of the 1980-82 Interim Joint Committee on Judiciary Statutes, in a letter to the Deputy Director and Reviser of Statutes, dated 2-7-86, has stated as follows: "As indicated in Senate Bill 35, in Section 1, 'Guardianship and conservatorship for disabled persons shall be utilized only as is necessary to promote their well-being, including protection from neglect, exploitation and abuse.' </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36039</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>