<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="210" order_by="210">STATE AND REGIONAL MENTAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>210.470</section_number><catch_line>Taxing district for mental health or individuals with an intellectual disability -- Governing board.   </catch_line><order_by>470</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It is the intent of this section to create a taxing district for mental health or individuals with an intellectual disability by operation of law in each county coming under the provisions of KRS 210.370 to 210.460, in order to implement KRS 210.460. </section><section prefix="2">In all counties which have participated in the establishment of a regional community services program for mental health or individuals with an intellectual disability under KRS 210.380, a taxing district for mental health or individuals with an intellectual disability is hereby declared to be created. </section><section prefix="3">The members of the community board for mental health or individuals with an intellectual disability recognized by the secretary for health and family services pursuant to KRS 210.380 shall, by virtue of their office, constitute and be the governing board of the taxing district for mental health or individuals with an intellectual disability and shall perform the duties attendant thereto in addition to their duties as members of the community board for mental health or individuals with an intellectual disability. Officers of the community board for mental health or individuals with an intellectual disability shall be the officers of the taxing district for mental health or individuals with an intellectual disability. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 86, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 335, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 279, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 12, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(1) and (8). -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 278, sec. 8. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40814</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>