<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="202" order_by="202">A HOSPITALIZATION OF THE MENTALLY ILL </unit></structure><section_number>202A.021</section_number><catch_line>Hospitalization of minors -- Admission or discharge of voluntary patients. </catch_line><order_by>021</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The hospitalization of minors alleged to be mentally ill, except those provided for in KRS Chapter 640, shall be governed by KRS Chapter 645. </section><section prefix="2">An authorized staff physician of a hospital may admit for observation, diagnosis, care and treatment any person who is mentally ill or who has symptoms of mental illness and who applies voluntarily therefor. </section><section prefix="3">An authorized staff physician of a hospital shall discharge any voluntary patient who has recovered or whose hospitalization the staff physician determines to be no longer necessary or advisable. </section><section prefix="4">A voluntary patient shall be released upon the patient's written request unless further detained under the applicable provisions of this chapter. </section></text><history>Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 139, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 423, sec. 195, effective July 1, 1987. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 445, sec. 2, effective July 1, 1982.</history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1988 </effective><lrc-note>.  This section was enacted in 1982 Acts, Chapter 445, which contains the following language in Section 45 of that Act: "This Act shall become effective on July 1, 1982." The Ky. Constitution, in Section 55, requires that a reason be set forth for the emergency. However, no reason is set forth in this Act. The effective date for 1982 Acts with no emergency provision is July 15, 1982. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7442</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>