<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="244" order_by="244">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- PROHIBITIONS, RESTRICTIONS, AND REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>244.992</section_number><catch_line>Medical amnesty for persons reporting an alcohol overdose.   </catch_line><order_by>992</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person shall be immune from prosecution for the criminal offenses identified in subsection (2) of this section if: <section prefix="a">A law enforcement officer has contact with the person because the person: <section prefix="1">Requests emergency medical assistance for himself or herself or another person; </section><section prefix="2">Acts in concert with another person who requests emergency medical assistance; or </section><section prefix="3">Appears to be in need of emergency medical assistance and is the individual for whom the request is made; </section></section><section prefix="b">The request is made for an individual who reasonably appears to be in need of medical assistance due to alcohol consumption; and </section><section prefix="c">The person described in paragraph (a) of this subsection, if physically capable: <section prefix="1">Provides his or her own full name if requested by emergency medical assistance personnel or law enforcement officers; </section><section prefix="2">Provides any other relevant information requested by the law enforcement officer that is known to such person; </section><section prefix="3">Remains with, or is, the individual who reasonably appears to be in need of medical assistance due to alcohol consumption until professional emergency medical assistance is provided; and </section><section prefix="4">Cooperates with emergency medical assistance personnel and law enforcement officers. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">A person who meets the qualifications set forth in subsection (1) of this section shall be immune from criminal prosecution for the following offenses: <section prefix="a">Alcohol intoxication under KRS 222.202(1); </section><section prefix="b">Drinking alcoholic beverages in a public place under KRS 222.202(2); </section><section prefix="c">Offenses related to possession of alcoholic beverages by a minor under twenty-one (21) years of age under KRS 244.085; and </section><section prefix="d">Providing alcohol to minors under twenty-one (21) years of age or assisting minors under twenty-one (21) years of age to purchase alcohol under KRS 244.085 or 530.070. </section></section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 81, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42516</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>