<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.380</section_number><catch_line>Officers required to be certified -- Officers permitted to be certified -- Exemptions.   </catch_line><order_by>380</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The following officers employed or appointed as full-time, part-time, or auxiliary officers, whether paid or unpaid, shall be certified: <section prefix="a">Department of Kentucky State Police officers, but for the commissioner of the Department of Kentucky State Police; </section><section prefix="b">City, county, and urban-county police officers; </section><section prefix="c">Court security officers and deputy sheriffs, except those identified in KRS 70.045 and 70.263(3); </section><section prefix="d">State or public university police officers appointed pursuant to KRS 164.950; </section><section prefix="e">School security officers employed by local boards of education who are special law enforcement officers appointed under KRS 61.902; </section><section prefix="f">Airport safety and security officers appointed under KRS 183.880; </section><section prefix="g">Department of Alcoholic Beverage Control field representatives and investigators appointed under KRS 241.090; </section><section prefix="h">Division of Insurance Fraud Investigation investigators appointed under KRS 304.47-040; and </section><section prefix="i">County detectives appointed in a county containing a consolidated local government with the power of arrest in the county and the right to execute process statewide in accordance with KRS 69.360. </section></section><section prefix="2">The requirements of KRS 15.380 to 15.404 for certification may apply to all state peace officers employed pursuant to KRS Chapter 18A and shall, if adopted, be incorporated by the Personnel Cabinet for job specifications. </section><section prefix="3">Additional training in excess of the standards set forth in KRS 15.380 to 15.404 for all peace officers possessing arrest powers who have specialized law enforcement responsibilities shall be the responsibility of the employing agency. </section><section prefix="4">The following officers may, upon request of the employing agency, be certified by the council: <section prefix="a">Deputy coroners; </section><section prefix="b">Deputy constables; </section><section prefix="c">Deputy jailers; </section><section prefix="d">Deputy sheriffs under KRS 70.045 and 70.263(3); </section><section prefix="e">Officers appointed under KRS 61.360; </section><section prefix="f">Officers appointed under KRS 61.902, except those who are school security officers employed by local boards of education; </section><section prefix="g">Private security officers; </section><section prefix="h">Employees of a correctional services division created pursuant to KRS 67A.028 and employees of a metropolitan correctional services department created pursuant to KRS 67B.010 to 67B.080; and </section><section prefix="i">Investigators employed by the Department of Charitable Gaming in accordance with KRS 238.510; and </section><section prefix="j">Commonwealth detectives employed under KRS 69.110 and county detectives employed under KRS 69.360. </section></section><section prefix="5">The following officers shall be exempted from the certification requirements but may upon their request be certified by the council: <section prefix="a">Sheriffs; </section><section prefix="b">Coroners; </section><section prefix="c">Constables; </section><section prefix="d">Jailers; </section><section prefix="e">Kentucky Horse Racing Commission security officers employed under KRS 230.240; and </section><section prefix="f">Commissioner of the State Police. </section></section><section prefix="6">Federal peace officers cannot be certified under KRS 15.380 to 15.404. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 10, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 16, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 54, sec. 7, effective June 26, 2007; ch. 76, sec. 4, effective June 26, 2007; and ch. 85, sec. 20, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 2; and Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 53, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 374, sec. 18, effective July 14, 2000; ch. 447, sec. 7, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 480, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 606, sec. 99, effective December 1, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><lrc-note>(6/26/2007).  The amendment to this section in 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 4, effective June 26, 2007, is retroactive to July 1, 2004. See 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 5. (6/26/2007).  This section was amended by 2007 Ky. Acts chs. 54, 76, and 85. There is no conflict with Acts ch. 85. Where Acts chs. 54 and 76 are not in conflict, they have been codified together. Where a conflict exists, Acts ch. 76, which was last enacted by the General Assembly, prevails under KRS 446.250. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41831</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>