<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="210" order_by="210">STATE AND REGIONAL MENTAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>210.047</section_number><catch_line>Facility closure hearing -- Required considerations. </catch_line><order_by>047</order_by><text>A court hearing as provided under KRS 210.045(6) shall consider each of the following items relevant to the closure of the facility: <section prefix="1">Estimated timelines for the implementation of the closure of the facility; </section><section prefix="2">The types and array of available and accessible community-based services for individuals with an intellectual disability and other developmental disabilities and their families; </section><section prefix="3">The rights of individuals with an intellectual disability and other developmental disabilities; </section><section prefix="4">The process used to develop a community living plan; </section><section prefix="5">Individual and community monitoring and safeguards to protect health and safety; </section><section prefix="6">The responsibilities of state and local governments; </section><section prefix="7">The process used to transfer ownership or the state's plan to reuse the property; and </section><section prefix="8">Other issues identified by the cabinet, the resident, family member or guardian, or other interested party with standing to act on behalf of the resident that may affect the residents, their families, employees, and the community. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 16, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 2, effective April 5, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8227</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>