<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">A KENTUCKY MODEL PROCUREMENT CODE </unit></structure><section_number>45A.500</section_number><catch_line>Legislative findings. </catch_line><order_by>500</order_by><text>It is the finding of the General Assembly that a necessary component of waste management must be to reduce the quantity of waste; that recycling reduces the quantity of solid waste and reduces the costs to the state and local governments for collecting, transporting, landfilling, or incinerating solid waste, reduces litter on roadsides and waterways, creates income producing opportunities, and conserves energy and raw materials. It is also the finding of the General Assembly that government makes purchases in large volumes which significantly affects the availability, variety, price, and consumer acceptance of the products and services purchased by government. The General Assembly further finds that by eliminating policies and practices which discriminate against government procuring recycled material content products as well as products and services compatible with recycled material content goods, and that by requiring government purchases of products which contain the maximum possible amount of recycled materials, the availability and variety of recycled material content products will increase and removal and recycling of materials from the solid waste stream will grow. Finally, the General Assembly finds that instituting policies and practices to stimulate the availability and use of recycled material content products will help educate business and individual consumers about the value of recycling as a component of a waste management policy. </text><history>Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 367, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22435</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>