<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>271B.7-200</section_number><catch_line>Shareholders' list for meeting. </catch_line><order_by>7-200</order_by><text><section prefix="1">After fixing a record date for a meeting, a corporation shall prepare a list of the names of all its shareholders who are entitled to notice of a shareholders' meeting. The list shall be arranged by voting group (and within each voting group by class or series of shares) and show the address of and number of shares held by each shareholder. </section><section prefix="2">The shareholders' list shall be available for inspection by any shareholder, beginning five (5) business days before the meeting for which the list was prepared and continuing through the meeting, at the corporation's principal office or at a place identified in the meeting notice in the city where the meeting will be held. A shareholder, his agent, or attorney shall be entitled on written demand to inspect and, subject to the requirements of subsection (3) of KRS 271B.16-020, to copy the list, during regular business hours and at his expense, during the period it is available for inspection. </section><section prefix="3">The corporation shall make the shareholders' list available at the meeting, and any shareholder, his agent, or attorney shall be entitled to inspect the list at any time during the meeting or any adjournment. </section><section prefix="4">Refusal or failure to prepare or make available the shareholders' list shall not affect the validity of action taken at the meeting. </section></text><history>Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 56, effective January 1, 1989. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 1989 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13360</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>