<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.7912</section_number><catch_line>Commissioner to determine date, hours, polling places for voting, and details of assessment -- Uses and limitations of assessment. </catch_line><order_by>7912</order_by><text><section prefix="1">With respect to any referendum conducted under the provisions of KRS 247.7900 to 247.7928, the Commissioner shall, before calling and announcing the referendum, fix, determine, and publicly announce at least thirty (30) days before the date determined for the referendum, the date, hours, and polling places for voting in the referendum, the effective date of the assessment, if adopted, the amount and basis of the assessment proposed to be collected, the means by which the assessment shall be collected if authorized by the producers, and the general purposes to which any amount collected shall be applied. </section><section prefix="2">Any assessment levied by any referendum conducted under the provisions of KRS 247.7900 to 247.7928 shall be used for the purpose of financing or contributing towards the financing of a program of research, market development, and education to increase the domestic and foreign consumption, use, sale, and markets for porcine animals and porcine animal products. </section><section prefix="3">No assessment levied by any referendum conducted under the provisions of KRS 247.7900 to 247.7928 shall exceed fifty cents ($0.50) per hundred dollars ($100) worth of sales on porcine animals marketed in the state by any producer included in the group to which the referendum was submitted or by any person subsequently becoming a new producer in the area in which the referendum was held. </section></text><history> Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 7, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11820</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>