<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="635" order_by="635">PUBLIC OFFENDERS </unit></structure><section_number>635.545</section_number><catch_line>File of participants to be maintained -- Biennial report on whether participants later committed sex-related or other criminal offenses. </catch_line><order_by>545</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department of Juvenile Justice shall maintain on file the names and identities of program participants for a period of fifteen (15) years following their participation in the program. The names and identities shall not be disclosed except for the purposes allowed in this section. </section><section prefix="2">On a biennial basis, the Department of Juvenile Justice shall request from the Administrative Office of the Courts and the Department of Kentucky State Police information concerning whether any of the individuals who participated in the program have been arrested, tried, convicted, or incarcerated for any offense under KRS Chapter 510, KRS 530.020, 530.064(1)(a), or 531.310, or any other criminal offense. </section><section prefix="3">Each two (2) years, the Department of Juvenile Justice shall compile the information obtained and present it to the Governor, the Legislative Research Commission, and the Supreme Court. The report shall not contain the names of any of the individual participants but shall contain identifying information which may assist in the evaluation of the program and in determination of whether participants have engaged in further criminal behavior as juveniles or adults. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 333, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 67, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 358, sec. 54, effective July 1, 1997. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 94, sec. 14, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/96).  Under 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 358, sec. 67(3), the amendment of this statute by Section 54 of that Act becomes effective July 1, 1997, in that it deals with functions of the Department of Juvenile Justice. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20308</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>