<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.738</section_number><catch_line>Application and review of proposed research projects. </catch_line><order_by>738</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A proposed research project shall be submitted to the board on an application developed by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services in consultation with the board. The submission deadline for the application shall be determined by the board. </section><section prefix="2">The board shall review the project proposal for scientific merit and adherence to the research priority established in this section. After reviewing the project proposal's scientific merit and adherence to the research priority, the board shall determine whether a project proposal shall or shall not be funded. An applicant shall be notified of the board's decision by a date determined by the board. </section><section prefix="3">A project proposal shall be reviewed for scientific merit as follows: <section prefix="a">Adequacy of prior research and theory in providing a basis for the research; </section><section prefix="b">Adequacy of methods; </section><section prefix="c">Adequacy of environment, facilities, equipment, available equipment, and research atmosphere; </section><section prefix="d">Qualifications and productivity of the PI and key staff; </section><section prefix="e">Time commitments of the PI and key staff; </section><section prefix="f">Availability of subjects or patients where relevant; </section><section prefix="g">Adequacy of procedures for assessing the effect of interventions on recovery; and </section><section prefix="h">Other factors that affect the potential of the applicants to successfully address the research objectives. </section></section><section prefix="4">A project shall be reviewed by the board for adherence to research priorities relating to experimental, clinical, or population-based studies that may: <section prefix="a">Prevent or delay the development of diabetic disease; </section><section prefix="b">Predict the development of diabetic vascular, neuronal, or musculo-skeletal complications; </section><section prefix="c">Define the response of diabetic vascular, neuronal, or musculo-skeletal complications to existing therapies; </section><section prefix="d">Reverse diabetic vascular, neuronal, or musculo-skeletal complications; or </section><section prefix="e">Cure diabetic disease. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 72, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 370, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 171, sec. 4, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8476</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>