<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="324" order_by="324">REAL ESTATE BROKERS AND SALESMEN </unit></structure><section_number>324.330</section_number><catch_line>Notice of change of location, firm name, surname, or associate -- New license. </catch_line><order_by>330</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notice in writing shall be given to the commission by each licensee of any change of principal business location, a change of firm name, sales associate's transfer from one (1) principal broker to another, or a change of surname. The commission shall issue a new license for the unexpired period and shall charge the fee as provided in KRS 324.287(6) for effecting the change on its records. This section shall apply to both brokers and sales associates. </section><section prefix="2">The commission shall be notified in writing of a change of a residence address within ten (10) days. </section><section prefix="3">A fee shall be assessed for certification of a licensee's status with the commission. </section><section prefix="4">The commission shall, by the promulgation of administrative regulations, require all licensees to file with the commission, at annual renewal, their telephone numbers and, if applicable, their electronic mail addresses. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 45, sec. 8, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 448, sec. 27, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 196, sec. 30, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 215, sec. 5, effective June 16, 1960. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 184, secs. 3 and 11. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 3990e-5. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31612</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>