<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.47-060</section_number><catch_line>Quicksand Wood Utilization Center as hub for industry expansion -- Demonstration projects.   </catch_line><order_by>47-060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The University of Kentucky College of Agriculture may operate the Quicksand Wood Utilization Center, which is located in Breathitt County at the Quicksand Substation of the College of Agriculture of the University of Kentucky, as a hub for the expansion of the secondary wood products industry. The center shall, if utilized as a secondary wood products training center, develop and further workforce training, management skills, technology transfer, and collaborative design and product development mechanisms and processes associated with the secondary wood products industry. </section><section prefix="2">The Quicksand Wood Utilization Center shall serve as a model for the development of additional hubs in other parts of the state. </section><section prefix="3">The cabinet, utilizing facilities of the Quicksand Wood Utilization Center, may conduct demonstration projects at the center, and may provide assistance to rural development organizations by producing building materials, furniture, and other wood products for display and sale at area showrooms and for use by rural development organizations in carrying out approved demonstration projects. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 49, sec. 7, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 145, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 224, sec. 12, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42114</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>