<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.450</section_number><catch_line>Expiration date of licenses -- Renewal -- Delinquent licensees -- Penalty -- Deposit and use of fees.   </catch_line><order_by>450</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every license issued for the practice of podiatry shall expire on June 30 following the date of issuance unless sooner revoked and canceled. </section><section prefix="2">On or before June 1 of each year, the board shall send notices to all licensed podiatrists in this state, at their last known addresses, advising them that the annual license renewal fee is due on July 1 of each year. Every registered podiatrist shall renew his license on or before July 1 of each year by the payment to the board of an annual license renewal fee which shall be a reasonable fee set by regulation of the board and upon submission of a statement of compliance with the continuing education regulations of the board. If such renewal fee is not paid or such statement of compliance is not submitted on or before July 1, the board shall notify the delinquent licensee by mail at his last known address that such fee and statement are past due and that a delinquent penalty fee is assessed, in addition to the renewal fee and that the renewal fee and penalty must be paid and the statement of compliance submitted on or before January 1. If such fees, penalties and statement are not submitted by January 1, it shall be the duty of the board to suspend or revoke the license for nonpayment of the annual renewal and delinquent fees or for failure to submit the statement of compliance for the current year. </section><section prefix="3">All fees collected under the provisions of KRS 311.380 to 311.510, or the rules and regulations adopted pursuant thereto, shall be paid into the State Treasury, and credited to a trust and agency fund to be used in defraying the costs and expenses in the administration of KRS 311.380 to 311.510 including, but not limited to, salaries and necessary travel expenses. No part of this fund shall revert to the general funds of this Commonwealth. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 3, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 61, sec. 4, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 443, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 225, sec. 13. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 93, sec. 1. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 289, sec. 7. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 197, sec. 4. -- Created 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 176, sec. 8. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44608</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>