<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="121" order_by="121">CAMPAIGN FINANCE REGULATION </unit></structure><section_number>121.220</section_number><catch_line>Primary campaign depository -- Secondary depository -- Deposits -- Statements. </catch_line><order_by>220</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each candidate, slate of candidates, and each committee shall, before receiving any contributions or expending any money, designate one (1) primary campaign depository for the purpose of depositing all contributions received and disbursing all expenditures made by the candidate, slate of candidates, or committee. The candidate, slate of candidates, or committee may also designate one (1) secondary depository in each county in which an election is held and in which the candidate, slate of candidates, or committee participates. Deputy campaign treasurers may make expenditures from secondary depositories but only from moneys which first have been deposited in the primary campaign depository. Only a financial institution authorized to transact business in Kentucky may be designated as a campaign depository. The candidate, slate of candidates, or committee shall file the name and address of each primary and secondary depository so designated at the same time the candidate, slate of candidates, or committee files the name of his or its campaign treasurer. </section><section prefix="2">All funds received by the campaign treasurer or any deputy campaign treasurer of any candidate, slate of candidates, or committee shall be deposited in a campaign depository in an account designated "Campaign Fund of (name of candidate or committee)." For each deposit, the campaign treasurer or deputy campaign treasurer shall retain a statement showing the name and business address of the permanent committee, the amount contributed, and a description of the major business, social, or political interest represented by the permanent committee for each contribution of any amount made by a permanent committee, and the full name, address, employer of each other contributor and the spouse of the contributor or, if the contributor or spouse of the contributor is self-employed, the name under which he is doing business, and occupation of each contributor of more than one hundred dollars ($100) and the amount contributed. Cash contributions shall be accompanied by the same receipt form. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 9, effective March 16, 2005. -- Amended 1993 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 61, effective November 3, 1993. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 288, sec. 29, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 341, sec. 47, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 292, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 3, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 253, sec. 8. </history><metadata><effective> March 16, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:04</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27873</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>