<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="281" order_by="281">A COMMERCIAL DRIVER'S LICENSES </unit></structure><section_number>281A.240</section_number><catch_line>Recognition of commercial driver's license or permit of foreign jurisdiction -- Effect of foreign convictions. </catch_line><order_by>240</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding any law to the contrary, a person may drive a commercial motor vehicle in this state if the person has a valid commercial driver's license or commercial driver's license instruction permit issued by any state, Canada, or Mexico in accordance with the minimum federal standards for the issuance of commercial motor vehicle driver's license, if the person's driving privilege is not suspended, revoked, or canceled; and if the person is not disqualified from driving a commercial motor vehicle or subject to an out-of-service order. </section><section prefix="2">The Commonwealth of Kentucky shall give all out-of-state convictions full faith and credit and treat them for sanctioning purposes under this chapter as if they occurred in this state. Except as otherwise provided, when in this chapter reference is made to an offense which is a violation of a provision of this chapter or other Kentucky state law, the reference shall be deemed to include offenses under any local ordinance, any federal law, any law or local ordinance of another state substantially similar to any provision of the Kentucky Revised Statutes. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 28, sec. 8, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 455, sec. 24, effective July 1, 1991. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14486</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>