<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="64" order_by="64">FEES AND COMPENSATION OF PUBLIC OFFICERS AND EMPLOYEES </unit></structure><section_number>64.060</section_number><catch_line>Peace officers generally. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Sheriffs, constables, coroners, marshals, and policemen shall be paid out of the State Treasury for the following services the following fees: <section prefix="a">Apprehending a person on charge of felony, or a fugitive </section>  from justice charged with a felony in this state .............................. $10.00 <section prefix="b">Executing a process of contempt in a criminal </section>  case when the court excuses the contempt  ........................................ 1.60 <section prefix="c">Executing a summons upon a witness in behalf </section>  of the Commonwealth in a felony case  .............................................. 3.00 <section prefix="d">Summoning a jury, on order of a court, in a county other than that in which the action is pending, a reasonable allowance to be fixed by the court. </section><section prefix="e">Summoning and attending a jury in a case of felony  .................................. 2.50 </section></section><section prefix="2">No claim for services incidental to examining courts shall be allowed to any sheriff, deputy sheriff, constable, marshal, policeman, or other officer authorized to execute process in felony cases until the grand jury has returned an indictment for a felony. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 248, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 366, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 254, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 353, 354, 4586. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23189</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>