<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">COUNTY GOVERNMENT (FISCAL COURTS AND COUNTY COMMISSIONERS) </unit></structure><section_number>67.712</section_number><catch_line>Powers and immunities common to all county judges/executive and county governments, including urban-county governments and consolidated local governments. </catch_line><order_by>712</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Whenever rights, powers, privileges, immunities, and responsibilities are granted to the county judge/executive in general statutes, the same shall be considered a grant in those counties in which a consolidated local government has been adopted pursuant to KRS Chapter 67C to the mayor of the consolidated local government, and shall be considered a grant in those counties in which an urban-county government has been adopted pursuant to KRS Chapter 67A to the officer in whom such functions are vested under the applicable provision of the comprehensive plan of an urban-county government, if any, and otherwise to the chief executive officer of an urban-county government. </section><section prefix="2">Whenever rights, powers, privileges, immunities, and responsibilities are granted to the fiscal court in general statutes, the same shall be considered a grant in those counties in which a consolidated local government has been adopted pursuant to KRS Chapter 67C to the officer or officers in whom such functions are vested pursuant to KRS 67C.103(1) and 67C.105(1), respectively, of the consolidated local government, and shall be considered a grant in those counties in which an urban-county government has been adopted pursuant to KRS Chapter 67A to the legislative body of the urban-county government. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 42, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 16, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><lrc-note>.  See following KRS 67.705. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23772</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>