<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="319" order_by="319">B PROSTHETISTS, ORTHOTISTS, AND PEDORTHISTS </unit></structure><section_number>319B.030</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of board -- Administrative regulations -- Licensure and exemptions from licensure -- Examinations -- Fees -- Continuing education -- Enforcement -- Evaluation of applicants. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text>The board shall: <section prefix="1">Promulgate administrative regulations to: <section prefix="a">Establish licensure categories and issue licenses for orthotists, prosthetists, pedorthists, and orthotic fitters; </section><section prefix="b">Establish the qualifications, educational courses, curriculum, hours, and standards that are prerequisite to issuance of all levels and types of licensure established pursuant to paragraph (a) of this subsection. Any qualifications established by the board shall include the following: <section prefix="1">To qualify for a license to practice orthotics or prosthetics, a person shall: <section prefix="a">Possess a minimum of a baccalaureate degree from an accredited college or university; </section><section prefix="b">Complete a CAAHEP accredited education program in orthotics, prosthetics, or both; </section><section prefix="c">Complete a residency as defined in this chapter in the discipline for which a license is sought; </section><section prefix="d">Pass all written and practical examinations in any combination that is required and approved by the board; and </section><section prefix="e">Be qualified to practice in accordance with internationally accepted standards of orthotic and prosthetic care; </section></section><section prefix="2">To qualify for a license to practice pedorthics, a person shall: <section prefix="a">Possess a minimum of a high school diploma or comparable credential approved by the board; </section><section prefix="b">Complete an NCOPE-approved pedorthic education program; </section><section prefix="c">Pass all written and practical examinations that are required and approved by the board; </section><section prefix="d">Have a minimum of one thousand (1,000) hours of pedorthic patient care experience as approved by the board; </section><section prefix="e">Be qualified to practice in accordance with nationally accepted standards of pedorthic care; </section></section><section prefix="3">To qualify for a license to practice as an orthotic fitter, a person shall: <section prefix="a">Possess a minimum of a high school diploma or comparable credential approved by the board; </section><section prefix="b">Complete an NCOPE-approved orthotic fitter course; </section><section prefix="c">Pass all examinations that are required and approved by the board; </section><section prefix="d">Complete a minimum of one thousand (1,000) hours of experience in orthotic fitting as approved by the board; </section><section prefix="e">Be qualified to practice in accordance with nationally accepted standards of care acceptable to the board; </section></section><section prefix="4">Provisions that a person may be licensed in more than one (1) discipline; </section></section><section prefix="c">Establish the circumstances or conditions, if any, under which persons may be exempt from licensure after completion of training, while waiting to take or receive the results of any required examination, or upon meeting specified minimum educational and clinical qualifications; </section><section prefix="d">Select the examination or examinations to be utilized as the board's licensure examination or examinations and the prerequisites for admission to the examination or examinations. The board may enter into a contract or agreement with the chosen examination service or services, or select an intermediary between the board and the examination service or services, to process applicants for the examination or examinations; </section><section prefix="e">Establish any other criteria for licensure that are reasonably related to the safe and competent performance of prosthetics, orthotics, and pedorthics; </section><section prefix="f"><section prefix="1">Establish the fees to be paid for each of the following: <section prefix="a">Application for licensure; </section><section prefix="b">Renewal or reinstatement of licensure; </section><section prefix="c">Late renewal of licensure; </section><section prefix="d">Application for continuing education course approval; and </section><section prefix="e">Duplicate or replacement license. </section></section><section prefix="2">The fees shall be set at a level that is adequate to pay all of the expenses of implementing and administering licensure under this chapter; </section></section><section prefix="g">Establish the continuing education requirements for licensees, which shall include the frequency of reporting, number of hours, types of courses, approval of courses, methods of proving compliance, penalties for violation, and all fees necessary for implementing the continuing education process; and </section><section prefix="h">Delineate the standards of practice for persons licensed under this chapter; and </section></section><section prefix="2">Administer and enforce the provisions of this chapter and evaluate the qualifications of applicants for licensure. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31279</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>