<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.705</section_number><catch_line>Prosecutors Advisory Council.   </catch_line><order_by>705</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For the purpose of administration of the unified prosecutorial system, there is hereby created the Prosecutors Advisory Council, hereafter referred to as the council. </section><section prefix="2">The council shall consist of nine (9) members who shall be residents of Kentucky and shall include the Attorney General; three (3) Commonwealth's attorneys, one (1) from counties containing a consolidated local government, a city with a population of twenty thousand (20,000) or more based on the most recent federal decennial census, or an urban-county government, one (1) from counties containing a city with a population equal to or greater than eight thousand (8,000) but less than twenty thousand (20,000) based on the most recent federal decennial census, and one (1) from the other counties, each of whom shall be appointed by the Governor from a list of three (3) names for each Commonwealth's attorney position submitted by the Commonwealth's Attorneys Association; and three (3) county attorneys, one (1) from counties containing a consolidated local government, a city with a population equal to or greater than twenty thousand (20,000) based on the most recent federal decennial census, or an urban-county government, one (1) from counties containing a city with a population equal to or greater than eight thousand (8,000) but less than twenty thousand (20,000) based on the most recent federal decennial census, and one (1) from the other counties, each of whom shall be appointed by the Governor from a list of three (3) names for each county attorney position submitted by the County Attorneys Association; and two (2) nonattorney citizen members. The Attorney General shall serve during his term of office and the other members shall serve at the pleasure of the Governor. </section><section prefix="3">The Attorney General shall be the chairman of the council. Five (5) members shall constitute a quorum for the conduct of business. The council shall promulgate annually a schedule of meetings. Special meetings may be called by the chairman or five (5) members of the council. A minimum of ten (10) days' notice must be given prior to the call of a special meeting. Such a notice may be waived by a majority of the council. </section><section prefix="4">The council shall be responsible for, but not limited to, the preparation of the budget of the unified prosecutorial system of the Commonwealth of Kentucky and the continuing legal education and program development of the unified prosecutorial system of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="5">Each nonattorney citizen member of the council shall receive twenty-five dollars ($25) per day for attending each meeting. All council members shall be reimbursed for actual expenses incurred in the performance of their duties. </section></text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 21, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 17, sec. 2, effective January 1, 1977. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43606</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>