<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.935</section_number><catch_line>Physician recruitment and placement services for underserved geographic areas. </catch_line><order_by>935</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Physician" means a medical doctor practicing full-time family medicine, general obstetrics and gynecology, general pediatrics, or general internal medicine; and </section><section prefix="b">"Underserved geographic area" means a county in which the ratio between physicians practicing full-time in that county and the county's population results in each physician serving two thousand five hundred (2,500) or more residents, based on population data acceptable to either the University of Kentucky or the University of Louisville. </section></section><section prefix="2">The University of Kentucky and University of Louisville shall establish and maintain physician recruitment and placement services, the principal function of which shall be to recruit or place family or general practice physicians in underserved geographic areas. The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall pay each university fifty thousand dollars ($50,000) annually for basic administrative costs in addition to the fees enumerated in subsection (4) of this section. </section><section prefix="3">Physician recruitment and placement services may be contracted by licensed health-care facilities or services to assist in recruiting physicians in underserved geographic areas. Fees shall be charged by the University of Kentucky or the University of Louisville to the contracting party in an amount not to exceed ten thousand dollars ($10,000) per physician. </section><section prefix="4">If no licensed health-care facility or service has contracted for recruitment services, when the University of Kentucky or the University of Louisville places a physician in an underserved geographic area or a psychiatrist in a state mental health facility, the following fees shall be paid to the university by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, the total of which shall not exceed fifty thousand dollars ($50,000) per university in addition to the fifty thousand dollars ($50,000) per university enumerated in subsection (2) of this section: <section prefix="a">Ten thousand dollars ($10,000) for a family practice physician entering permanent, full-time practice; </section><section prefix="b">Ten thousand dollars ($10,000) for a psychiatrist entering full-time permanent employment in a state mental health facility; </section><section prefix="c">Eight thousand dollars ($8,000) for a general obstetrician-gynecologist entering permanent, full-time practice; </section><section prefix="d">Two thousand dollars ($2,000) for a general pediatrician or general internal medicine practitioner entering permanent, full-time practice; and </section><section prefix="e">One thousand dollars ($1,000) for any other licensed medical practitioner entering permanent, full-time practice. </section></section><section prefix="5">Fees paid to the universities under the provisions of subsection (3) of this section shall be made only after sufficient proof has been presented documenting the university's principal role in influencing the physician's practice location. Correspondence from physicians placed, as well as all other parties directly involved, shall state that the university substantially influenced the physician's choice of practice location and describe in detail the services provided by the university. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 141, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 120, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 482, sec. 14, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4491</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>