<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXVI" order_by="36">STATUTORY ACTIONS AND LIMITATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="413" order_by="413">LIMITATION OF ACTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>413.249</section_number><catch_line>Action relating to childhood sexual abuse or childhood sexual assault.   </catch_line><order_by>249</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Childhood sexual assault" means an act or series of acts against a person less than eighteen (18) years old and which meets the criteria defining a felony in KRS 510.040, 510.050, 510.060, 510.070, 510.080, 510.090, 510.110, 529.100 where the offense involves commercial sexual activity, 529.110 where the offense involves commercial sexual activity, 530.020, 530.064, 531.310, or 531.320. No prior criminal prosecution or conviction of the civil defendant for the act or series of acts shall be required to bring a civil action for redress of childhood sexual assault; </section><section prefix="b">"Childhood sexual abuse" means an act or series of acts against a person less than eighteen (18) years old and which meets the criteria defining a misdemeanor in KRS 510.120, KRS 510.130, KRS 510.140, or KRS 510.150. No prior criminal prosecution or conviction of the civil defendant for the act or series of acts shall be required to bring a civil action for redress of childhood sexual abuse; </section><section prefix="c">"Child" means a person less than eighteen (18) years old; and </section><section prefix="d">"Injury or illness" means either a physical or psychological injury or illness. </section></section><section prefix="2">A civil action for recovery of damages for injury or illness suffered as a result of childhood sexual abuse or childhood sexual assault shall be brought before whichever of the following periods last expires: <section prefix="a">Within five (5) years of the commission of the act or the last of a series of acts by the same perpetrator; </section><section prefix="b">Within five (5) years of the date the victim knew, or should have known, of the act; or </section><section prefix="c">Within five (5) years after the victim attains the age of eighteen (18) years. </section></section><section prefix="3">If a complaint is filed alleging that an act of childhood sexual assault or childhood sexual abuse occurred more than five (5) years prior to the date that the action is commenced, the complaint shall be accompanied by a motion to seal the record and the complaint shall immediately be sealed by the clerk of the court. The complaint shall remain sealed until: <section prefix="a">The court rules upon the motion to seal; </section><section prefix="b">Any motion to dismiss under CR 12.02 is ruled upon, and if the complaint is dismissed, the complaint and any related papers or pleadings shall remain sealed unless opened by a higher court; or </section><section prefix="c">The defendant files an answer and a motion to seal the record upon grounds that a valid factual defense exists, to be raised in a motion for summary judgment pursuant to CR 56. The record shall remain sealed by the clerk until the court rules upon the defendant's motion to close the record. If the court grants the motion to close, the record shall remain sealed until the defendant's motion for summary judgment is granted. The complaint, motions, and other related papers or pleadings shall remain sealed unless opened by a higher court. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 25, sec. 20, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 19, sec. 9, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 577, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41851</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>