<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXII" order_by="32">OWNERSHIP AND CONVEYANCE OF PROPERTY</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="382" order_by="382">CONVEYANCES AND ENCUMBRANCES </unit></structure><section_number>382.135</section_number><catch_line>Statement of consideration or market value and mailing and in-care-of addresses required in deed to real property -- Exceptions -- Affidavit of personal representative -- Clerk prohibited from filing noncompliant deed. </catch_line><order_by>135</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In addition to any other requirement imposed by law, a deed to real property shall contain the following: <section prefix="a">The mailing addresses of the grantor and grantee; </section><section prefix="b">A statement of the full consideration; </section><section prefix="c">A statement indicating the in-care-of address to which the property tax bill for the year in which the property is transferred may be sent; and </section><section prefix="d"><section prefix="1">In the case of a transfer other than by gift, or with nominal or no consideration a sworn, notarized certificate signed by the grantor or his agent and the grantee or his agent, or the parent or guardian of a person under eighteen (18) years old, that the consideration reflected in the deed is the full consideration paid for the property; or </section><section prefix="2">In the case of a transfer either by gift or with nominal or no consideration, a sworn, notarized certificate signed by the grantor or his agent and the grantee or his agent, or the parent or guardian of a person under eighteen (18) years old, stating that the transfer is by gift and setting forth the estimated fair cash value of the property. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">The deed filing requirements listed in subsection (1)(b), (c), and (d) of this section shall not apply to: <section prefix="a">Deeds which only convey utility easements; </section><section prefix="b">Deeds which transfer property through a court action pursuant to a divorce proceeding; </section><section prefix="c">Deeds which convey rights-of-way that involve governmental agencies; </section><section prefix="d">Deeds which convey cemetery lots; </section><section prefix="e">Deeds which correct errors in previous deeds conveying the same property from the same grantor to the same grantee; or </section><section prefix="f">Deeds which convey real property to a local airport board. </section></section><section prefix="3">In the case of an exchange of properties, the fair cash value of the property being exchanged shall be stated in the body of the deed. </section><section prefix="4">In the event of a transfer of property by will or under the laws of intestate succession, the personal representative of the estate, prior to closing out the estate, shall file an affidavit with the county clerk of each county in which any of the property is located, which shall contain the following: <section prefix="a">The names and addresses of the persons receiving each property passing by will or intestate succession; and </section><section prefix="b">The full or fair market value of each property as estimated or established for any purpose in the handling of the estate, or a statement that no such values were estimated or established. </section></section><section prefix="5">No county clerk or deputy clerk shall lodge for record, and no county clerk or deputy shall receive and permit to be lodged for record, any deed that does not comply with the provisions of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 143, sec. 3, effective August 1, 2008. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 171, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 263, sec. 8, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 411, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35593</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>