<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">BUDGET AND FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION </unit></structure><section_number>45.251</section_number><catch_line>Expenditures -- Scope -- Methodology -- Recordkeeping. </catch_line><order_by>251</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Expenditures shall be limited to the amounts and purposes for which appropriations are made. All expenditures shall be reflected in the unified and integrated system of accounts as provided by KRS 45.305. </section><section prefix="2">The Finance and Administration Cabinet shall prescribe all information technology standards, system attributes, and components to be used in, or in conjunction with, the unified accounting system. The components must be consistent with Commonwealth standards contained within the information technology architecture, as provided by the Commonwealth Office of Technology. </section><section prefix="3">The Governor, the Chief Justice, and the Legislative Research Commission shall designate the officer or employee authorized to approve advices of employment, purchase orders and contracts, and requisitions for reservation of funds, and no advice, order, contract, or requisition shall be honored as a commitment statement unless the designation has been conveyed to the Finance and Administration Cabinet. </section><section prefix="4">The Finance and Administration Cabinet may approve for payment any expenditure presented by a budget unit, provided that the Finance and Administration Cabinet is able to determine that the expenditure is to satisfy a liability of the Commonwealth of Kentucky created on behalf of that budget unit in fulfilling the governmental function assigned to that budget unit and that the expenditure is being made from the unexpended balance of a proper allotment. </section><section prefix="5">Subsidiary records shall be maintained to report the financial operation and condition of each budget unit. These subsidiary records shall be compatible with the unified accounting system prescribed by subsection (1) of this section and by KRS 45.305, and may be on the accrual basis or cash basis. Expenditures may be by prior encumbrances or by straight disbursements. The subsidiary records may be maintained by the Finance and Administration Cabinet and by the budget unit involved. When a budget unit is authorized to maintain subsidiary records, the Finance and Administration Cabinet shall have authority to prescribe the accounting and preauditing procedures. The unified system of accounts shall conform to accepted management and accounting principles. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 65, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 506, sec. 14, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 536, sec. 14, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 17, effective May 30, 1997. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 450, sec. 34, effective July 1, 1983. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22220</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>