<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="42" order_by="42">FINANCE AND ADMINISTRATION CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>42.017</section_number><catch_line>Office of General Counsel. </catch_line><order_by>017</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Office of General Counsel established within the Office of the Secretary by KRS 42.0145 shall be responsible for the coordination and provision of legal services for the cabinet and for other functions and duties as the secretary may assign relating to the performance of the cabinet's legal services. </section><section prefix="2">The Office of General Counsel shall be headed by an executive director who shall function as the general counsel. The executive director shall be appointed in accordance with KRS 12.210 and shall report to the secretary. The Attorney General, on request of the secretary, may designate attorneys in the Office of General Counsel as assistant attorneys general as provided in KRS 15.105. </section><section prefix="3">The Office of General Counsel shall consist of two (2) offices, each of which shall provide legal services for its respective offices and departments, as follows: <section prefix="a">Office of Legal Services for Finance and Technology, headed by an executive director and composed of organizational entities deemed appropriate by the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet; and </section><section prefix="b">Office of Legal Services for Revenue, headed by an executive director, including organizational entities deemed appropriate by the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 21, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 8, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 340, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21950</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>