<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="150" order_by="150">FISH AND WILDLIFE RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>150.025</section_number><catch_line>Power of department to make administrative regulations as to game and fish, including seasons and limits -- Inclusion of administrative regulations on department's Web site. </catch_line><order_by>025</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In carrying out the provisions of this chapter the department may, by administrative regulations promulgated under the provisions of KRS Chapter 13A: <section prefix="a">Fix, close, terminate, shorten, or divide open season, or make open seasons conditional; </section><section prefix="b">Regulate bag or creel limits and possession limits; </section><section prefix="c">Regulate buying, selling, or transporting; </section><section prefix="d">Regulate the size or type of any device used for taking, and regulate any method of taking; </section><section prefix="e">Regulate or restrict the places where taking is permitted; </section><section prefix="f">Regulate taking, or the opening or closing of seasons, in waters in which the department is conducting experiments or making improvements for the purpose of promoting the conservation of wildlife and increasing the supply thereof; </section><section prefix="g">Make administrative regulations apply to a limited area or to the entire state; and </section><section prefix="h">Promulgate any other administrative regulations reasonably necessary to implement or carry out the purposes of this chapter. </section></section><section prefix="2">The commissioner shall cause the text of every administrative regulation to be made available electronically on the department's Web site within five (5) working days of filing. The commissioner shall also cause to be prepared news releases concerning all new or amended administrative regulations for distribution to radio, television, and newspaper media. </section><section prefix="3">This section shall apply to KRS Chapter 150 and no other KRS chapter pertaining to this subject shall apply to KRS Chapter 150. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 127, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 83, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384 Ky. Acts ch. 288, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 38, sec. 2 -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 144 -- Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1 -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 200, sec. 7 -- Created 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 4. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1935</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>