<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="281" order_by="281">MOTOR CARRIERS </unit></structure><section_number>281.880</section_number><catch_line>Motor carrier safety management audit program -- Safety inspections and ratings. </catch_line><order_by>880</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">The Department of Kentucky State Police shall establish a motor carrier safety management audit program applicable to private or for-hire, intrastate or interstate motor carriers. </section><section prefix="b">The Department of Kentucky State Police may perform safety inspections on vehicles operated by a motor carrier on public highways and may enter onto property owned, leased, controlled, or operated by a motor carrier to inspect any of its vehicles or inspect or copy records relating to vehicle safety, maintenance, or financial responsibility. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Department of Kentucky State Police may issue motor carrier safety ratings to any private or for-hire motor carrier which is based in Kentucky, has a terminal in Kentucky, or operates consistently in Kentucky. The safety rating scale and factors determining a carrier's safety rating shall be established by administrative regulation and shall be compatible with the scale and factors established by the Federal Highway Administration in Title 49 of the United States Code of Federal Regulations, Part 385, relating to safety ratings, in effect as of July 13, 1990, or as amended after that date. </section><section prefix="3">The Department of Kentucky State Police may determine the safety fitness of a motor carrier and may require the maintenance of or upgrade to a satisfactory safety rating. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 75, sec. 18, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 284, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 466, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14449</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>