<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="403" order_by="403">DISSOLUTION OF MARRIAGE -- CHILD CUSTODY </unit></structure><section_number>403.761</section_number><catch_line>Amendment of domestic violence order to require participation inglobal positioning monitoring system -- Cost to be paid by respondentand system operator -- Shortening or vacating of order -- Penalty forviolation.  </catch_line><order_by>761</order_by><text>(1)Upon a petitioner's request and after an evidentiary hearing, a court mayamend a domestic violence order to require a respondent to participate in aglobal positioning monitoring system if:(a)The respondent has committed a substantial violation of a previouslyentered domestic violence order;(b)The court has reviewed an updated history of the respondent's Kentuckycriminal and protective order history; and(c)The court makes a factual determination that the use of a globalpositioning monitoring system would increase the petitioner's safety.(2)An order requiring participation in a global positioning monitoring system shall:(a)Require the respondent to pay the cost of participation up to therespondent's ability to pay, with the system operator bearing anyuncovered costs for indigent respondents;(b)State with specificity the locations or areas where the respondent isprohibited from being located or persons with whom the respondent shallhave no contact;(c)Include the date that the order expires, which shall be no longer than theexpiration date of the domestic violence order, although participation maybe extended if the underlying order is extended;(d)Require the entity that operates the monitoring system to immediatelynotify the petitioner, the local law enforcement agency named in theorder, and the court if a respondent violates the order; and(e)Include any other information as the court deems appropriate.(3)The Administrative Office of the Courts shall prepare a publicly availableinformational pamphlet containing information on the method of applying for,hearing, amending, and terminating an order requiring participation in a globalpositioning monitoring system.(4)(a)The Supreme Court may establish by rule a sliding scale of paymentresponsibility for indigent defendants for use in establishing requiredpayments under subsection (2) of this section.(b)A person, county, or other organization may voluntarily agree to pay all ora portion of a respondent's monitoring costs specified in this section.(5)An order requiring participation in a global positioning monitoring system maybe shortened or vacated by the court either:(a)Upon request of the petitioner; or(b)Upon request of the respondent after an evidentiary hearing, if therespondent has not violated the order and:1.Three (3) months have elapsed since the entry of the order; and2.No previous request has been made by the respondent in theprevious six (6) months.(6)A respondent who fails to wear, removes, tampers with, or destroys a globalpositioning monitoring system device in contravention of an order enteredunder this section shall be guilty of a Class D felony.</text><history>Repealed and reenacted 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 16, effective January1, 2016. -- Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2014. --Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 170, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2010.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:32</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44764</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>