<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171">STATE LIBRARIES -- LIBRARIANS -- STATE ARCHIVES AND RECORDS </unit></structure><section_number>171.347Commonwealth</section_number><catch_line>of Kentucky Abraham Lincoln Bicentennial Commission -- Membership.   </catch_line><order_by>347Commonwealth</order_by><text>There is created the Commonwealth of Kentucky Abraham Lincoln Bicentennial Commission, which shall be attached to the Kentucky Historical Society for administrative purposes. The commission shall be composed of twenty (20) members, as follows: <section prefix="1">Two (2) members of the House of Representatives, appointed by the Speaker of the House; </section><section prefix="2">Two (2) members of the Senate, appointed by the President of the Senate; </section><section prefix="3">The secretary of the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet, or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="4">One (1) member from the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet, appointed by the secretary of that cabinet; </section><section prefix="5">One (1) member from the Kentucky Historical Society, appointed by the executive director of that agency; </section><section prefix="6">One (1) member from the Kentucky Heritage Council, appointed by the executive director of that agency; </section><section prefix="7">One (1) member from the Kentucky African-American Heritage Commission, appointed by the head of that agency; </section><section prefix="8">One (1) member from the Kentucky Humanities Council, appointed by the executive director of that agency; </section><section prefix="9">One (1) member from the Abraham Lincoln Bicentennial Commission established by the United States Congress, appointed by the concurrence of the chairs of that agency; </section><section prefix="10">The Larue County judge/executive, or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="11">One (1) member from the Abraham Lincoln Birthplace, appointed by the superintendent of that national historic site; </section><section prefix="12">One (1) member from the Lincoln Museum in Hodgenville, appointed by the president of that agency; </section><section prefix="13">One (1) member from the Mary Todd Lincoln House in Lexington, appointed by the head of that agency; </section><section prefix="14">One (1) member from the Farmington Historic Home museum in Louisville, appointed by the head of that agency; and </section><section prefix="15">Four (4) citizen members from the state at large with a demonstrated interest in history and substantial knowledge and appreciation of Abraham Lincoln, appointed by the Governor. </section>The chair of the commission shall be elected from among the membership by the commission members. </text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 9, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 55, effective June 25, 2009; and ch. 16, sec. 44, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 109, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 96, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44495</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>