<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VII" order_by="7">PUBLIC PROPERTY AND PUBLIC PRINTING</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="56" order_by="56">STATE LANDS AND BUILDINGS </unit></structure><section_number>56.783</section_number><catch_line>Energy efficiency in state government buildings revolving loan fund. </catch_line><order_by>783</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A special fund in the State Treasury is hereby created which shall be known as the energy efficiency in state government buildings revolving loan fund. The fund shall be used to provide financial assistance to state government agencies for the purposes of KRS 56.770 to 56.784. </section><section prefix="2">The fund may receive state appropriations, gifts, grants, and federal funds and shall include earnings from the investment of moneys in the fund. Any fund balance at the close of the fiscal year shall not lapse but shall carry forward to the next fiscal year and shall remain available solely for the purposes of this section. </section><section prefix="3">Administration of this fund shall be the responsibility of the cabinet. The cabinet shall establish terms and conditions for loans from the fund including the application and repayment process. The cabinet shall establish and implement fiscal controls and accounting periods for payments received and disbursements made by the fund and for fund balances at the beginning and end of each accounting period. </section><section prefix="4">All repayments of loans made under this section shall be paid into the fund. Balances, or portions thereof, in the fund shall not revert to the general fund. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 9, effective February 25, 2010. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 139, sec. 9, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 35, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> February 25, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (2/25/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 28, provides that the repeal and reenactment of this section in that Act "shall apply retroactively to July 15, 2008." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22693</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>