<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="117" order_by="117">REGULATION OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>117.381</section_number><catch_line>Requirements for approval. </catch_line><order_by>381</order_by><text>No electronic voting system shall, upon any examination or reexamination, be approved by the State Board of Elections unless it shall be established that such system, at the time of examination or reexamination: <section prefix="1">Provides for voting in secrecy; </section><section prefix="2">Permits each voter to vote at any election for all candidates and questions for which he is lawfully entitled to vote, and no others; </section><section prefix="3">Permits each voter, at the general election to vote a straight political party ticket by one (1) or more marks or acts; </section><section prefix="4">Provides a method for write-in voting; </section><section prefix="5">Provides for a nonpartisan ballot; </section><section prefix="6">If it is of a type that registers the vote electronically, the voting system shall preclude each voter from voting for more persons for any office than he is entitled to vote for or upon any question more than once; </section><section prefix="7">Permits each voter at a primary election to vote only for the candidates seeking nomination by a political party in which such voter is registered, and for any candidate for nonpartisan nomination, and for any question upon which he is entitled to vote; </section><section prefix="8">If it is of a type that registers the vote electronically, the voting system shall permit each voter to change his vote for any candidate or upon any question appearing on the official ballot up to the time that he takes the final step to register his vote and to have his vote computed.  If it is of a type that uses paper ballots or ballot cards to register the vote and automatic tabulating equipment to compute such votes, the system shall provide that a voter who spoils his ballot may obtain another ballot; </section><section prefix="9">Is suitably designed for the purpose used, is constructed of a durable material, and is safely transportable; </section><section prefix="10">Is so constructed that a voter may readily learn the method of operating it; and </section><section prefix="11">Meets or exceeds the standards for electronic voting equipment established by the Federal Election Commission; and </section><section prefix="12">Provides for tabulating votes at the precinct in accordance with the requirements of KRS 117.275. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 195, sec. 12, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 421, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 360, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:10</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27446</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>