<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="216" order_by="216">B LICENSURE AND REGULATION OF HEALTH FACILITIES AND SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>216B.402</section_number><catch_line>Protocol for treatment of drug overdose. </catch_line><order_by>402</order_by><text>When a person is admitted to a hospital emergency department or hospital emergency room for treatment of a drug overdose: <section prefix="1">The person shall be informed of available substance use disorder treatment services known to the hospital that are provided by that hospital, other local hospitals, the local community mental health center, and any other local treatment programs licensed pursuant to KRS 222.231; </section><section prefix="2">The hospital may obtain permission from the person when stabilized, or the person's legal representative, to contact any available substance use disorder treatment programs offered by that hospital, other local hospitals, the local community mental health center, or any other local treatment programs licensed pursuant to KRS 222.231, on behalf of the person to connect him or her to treatment; and </section><section prefix="3">The local community mental health center may provide an on-call service in the hospital emergency department or hospital emergency room for the person who was treated for a drug overdose to provide information about services and connect the person to substance use disorder treatment, as funds are available. These services, when provided on the grounds of a hospital, shall be coordinated with appropriate hospital staff. </section></text><history> Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 66, sec. 7, effective March 25, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> March 25, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:37</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44003</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>