<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.055</section_number><catch_line>Hotel in-room service license. </catch_line><order_by>055</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, the following definitions shall apply: <section prefix="a">"Hotel" means any hotel, motel, inn, or other establishment which offers overnight accommodations to the public for hire; </section><section prefix="b">"In-room service" means the delivery of alcoholic beverages in unbroken packages by an employee of the hotel to a registered guest's room when the alcoholic beverages have been ordered by a guest and when the guest shall be billed for the cost of the alcoholic beverages at the time of delivery, with all sales of the alcoholic beverages being completed upon delivery; and, additionally, the provision of a cabinet or other facility located in a hotel guest's room which contains alcoholic beverages and which is provided upon written request of the guest and which is accessible by lock and key or remote control device only to the guest, with the sale of the alcoholic beverages contained therein being final at the time requested, except for a credit which may be given to the guest for any unused portion. The licensee may stock a cabinet or other facility located in a hotel guest's room pursuant to this section, with fifty (50) milliliter containers of distilled spirits. </section></section><section prefix="2">The department may issue a hotel in-room service license to any hotel which is licensed to sell distilled spirits, wine, and malt beverages upon the payment of the fee set forth in KRS 243.030. The license shall authorize the licensee to sell distilled spirits, wine, and malt beverages by in-room service. The sale of alcoholic beverages by in-room service shall be subject to all restrictions and limitations contained in KRS Chapters 241 to 244, and the administrative regulations issued under those chapters, and shall be authorized only on the days and only during the hours as the sale of alcoholic beverages is otherwise authorized in the county or municipality. All alcoholic beverages sold pursuant to this section shall be considered by the drink sales and shall be subject to all state and local taxes imposed on alcoholic beverages and shall be purchased from a licensed wholesaler and distributor. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 567, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 518, sec. 9, effective April 13, 1998. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 228, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11317</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>