<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.648</section_number><catch_line>State Advisory Council for Gifted and Talented Education -- Purpose -- Duties. </catch_line><order_by>648</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The State Advisory Council for Gifted and Talented Education is hereby created and attached to the Kentucky Department of Education. The council's purpose is to make recommendations regarding the provisions of services for gifted and talented students in Kentucky's education system. <section prefix="a">The council shall be composed of nineteen (19) voting members who shall be appointed by the Governor and three (3) nonvoting, ex officio members. The members shall be appointed representing various constituencies as follows: <section prefix="1">Four (4) members shall be teachers within local school districts representing elementary, middle, and high school levels with at least one (1) full-time teacher of gifted and talented students and one (1) full-time teacher who teaches in a regular classroom; </section><section prefix="2">Four (4) members shall be parents of students in local school districts, including two (2) parents of students identified as gifted and talented and at least one (1) who serves or has served on a school council; </section><section prefix="3">Three (3) members shall be from postsecondary education institutions, including one (1) from an independent college or university; </section><section prefix="4">One (1) member shall be a superintendent of a local school district; </section><section prefix="5">Two (2) members shall be principals, including one (1) from an elementary or middle school and one (1) from a high school; </section><section prefix="6">Two (2) members shall be coordinators of gifted and talented programs and services in local school districts; </section><section prefix="7">One (1) member shall be a local board of education member; </section><section prefix="8">One (1) member shall represent the visual and performing arts; and </section><section prefix="9">One (1) member shall be appointed from the private business sector. </section></section><section prefix="b">The three (3) nonvoting ex officio members shall be: the state consultant for gifted and talented education in the Kentucky Department of Education, a staff person designated by the executive secretary of the Education Professional Standards Board, and a staff person designated by the president of the Council on Postsecondary Education. Vacancies shall be filled by the Governor as they occur in a manner consistent with the provisions for initial appointment. </section><section prefix="c">Each board member shall serve a three (3) year term or until a successor is appointed, except that for initial appointments to the board, three (3) of the members shall be appointed to serve a one (1) year term, eight (8) of the members shall be appointed to serve a two (2) year term, and eight (8) of the members shall be appointed to serve a three (3) year term. A member may be reappointed but may not serve more than two (2) consecutive terms. </section></section><section prefix="2">The council shall advise the commissioner of education, the Kentucky Board of Education, and the Education Professional Standards Board concerning the development of administrative regulations and education policy regarding gifted and talented students. The commissioner of education and the executive secretary for the Education Professional Standards Board shall submit proposed administrative regulations and educational policies relating to gifted and talented education and other administrative regulations that impact gifted and talented students for review by the advisory council prior to seeking approval of the appropriate board. </section><section prefix="3">As the advisory council considers issues relating to gifted and talented students, it shall seek dialogue with other agencies and organizations, including the Parent Teachers Association, the Governor's Scholars Program, the Governor's School for the Arts, the Kentucky Association of School Councils, the Kentucky Association for Gifted Education, the Kentucky School Boards Association, the Kentucky Association of School Administrators, and the Kentucky Council for Exceptional Children. </section><section prefix="4">The advisory council shall annually elect a chair from its membership, establish meeting operational procedures, and meet at least two (2) times annually. </section><section prefix="5">The Department of Education shall provide staff and administrative support and shall administer the funds appropriated to support the expenses of the council. </section><section prefix="6">The members of the advisory council shall serve without compensation but shall be reimbursed for necessary expenses in the same manner as state employees. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 547, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, C, 3, (11) at 630. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3564</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>