<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="324" order_by="324">REAL ESTATE BROKERS AND SALESMEN </unit></structure><section_number>324.090</section_number><catch_line>Expiration of license -- Fine for failure to renew on time -- Expired status. </catch_line><order_by>090</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Licenses shall expire annually and shall be renewed each year on the date determined by the commission by administrative regulation. The commission shall renew a license for each ensuing year, in the absence of any reason or condition which might warrant the refusal of the granting of the license, upon receipt of the written request of the applicant and payment of the annual fees required. A new license shall be mailed only if the licensee's name, address, status, or affiliation changes. </section><section prefix="2">A fine not to exceed two hundred dollars ($200) shall be assessed for failure to renew on time before a new license is issued. Failure to receive a renewal form shall not constitute an adequate excuse for failure to renew on time nor shall failure of the mail. </section><section prefix="3">Any license not renewed at the end of the renewal year as prescribed by the commission shall automatically revert to expired status. An expired license may be reactivated before a lapse of one (1) year, if delinquent fees are paid by the licensee. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 488, sec. 8, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 313, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 448, sec. 10, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 352, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 196, sec. 16, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 5. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 184, secs. 3 and 11. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 3990e-5. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31559</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>