<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="216" order_by="216">HEALTH FACILITIES AND SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>216.875</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 216.880 to 216.890. </catch_line><order_by>875</order_by><text>As used in KRS 216.880 to 216.890 the following definitions shall apply: <section prefix="1">"Prescribed pediatric extended care center" hereinafter referred to as a "PPEC center," means any building or other place, whether operated for profit or not, which undertakes through its ownership or management to provide, for a part of the day, basic services to three (3) or more medically dependent or technologically dependent children who are not related to the owner or operator by blood, marriage, or adoption and who require such services; </section><section prefix="2">"Basic services" include, but are not limited to, development, implementation, and monitoring of a comprehensive protocol of care, developed in conjunction with the parent or guardian, which specifies the medical, nursing, psychosocial, and developmental therapies required by the medically dependent or technologically dependent child served as well as the caregiver training needs of the child's legal guardian; </section><section prefix="3">"Cabinet" means the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="4">"Owner or operator" means any individual who has general administrative charge of a PPEC center; </section><section prefix="5">"Medical records" means medical records maintained in accordance with accepted professional standards and practices as specified in the administrative regulations; </section><section prefix="6">"Medically dependent or technologically dependent child" means a child who because of a medical condition requires continuous therapeutic interventions or skilled-nursing supervision which must be prescribed by a licensed physician and administered by, or under the direct supervision of, a licensed registered nurse; and </section><section prefix="7">"Supportive services or contracted services" include, but are not limited to, speech therapy, occupational therapy, physical therapy, social work, developmental, child life, and psychological services. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 494, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 440, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 325, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9140</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>