<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.9109</section_number><catch_line>Certification as radon measurement contractor -- Renewal of certification -- Fees -- Duties of measurement contractor.   </catch_line><order_by>9109</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet shall issue a certification as a radon measurement contractor to any person who: <section prefix="a">Submits a complete and accurate application for certification on a form prescribed by the cabinet through promulgation of an administrative regulation; </section><section prefix="b">Pays the certification fee established by the cabinet through promulgation of an administrative regulation within the following restrictions: <section prefix="1">An initial certification fee shall not exceed two hundred fifty dollars ($250); </section><section prefix="2">An annual renewal fee shall not exceed two hundred fifty dollars ($250); </section><section prefix="3">A duplicate certificate fee shall not exceed twenty dollars ($20); and </section><section prefix="4">A late renewal fee shall not exceed one hundred dollars ($100); </section></section><section prefix="c">Provides the cabinet with documentation of successful completion of a cabinet-approved radon measurement course and exam; </section><section prefix="d">For renewal of certification, provides proof of completion of at least eight (8) hours of continuing education per year; </section><section prefix="e">Submits a quality control program plan that meets the minimum standard operating procedures requirements as established by the cabinet through promulgation of an administrative regulation; and </section><section prefix="f">Furnishes evidence of financial responsibility to the cabinet consisting of a liability insurance policy that satisfies the requirements of KRS 211.9113. </section></section><section prefix="2">A measurement contractor shall: <section prefix="a">Ensure all measurements are conducted in accordance with the measurement standard operating procedures established by the cabinet through promulgation of an administrative regulation; </section><section prefix="b">Maintain a quality control program plan that meets the minimum standard operating procedures requirements established by the cabinet through promulgation of an administrative regulation; </section><section prefix="c">Ensure all measurement activities are conducted under the general supervision of an individual certified to conduct radon measurement; </section><section prefix="d">Use or sell only cabinet-approved devices to conduct radon measurement; and </section><section prefix="e">Ensure all services procured from a radon laboratory are procured from a radon laboratory certified by the cabinet. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 68, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 74, sec. 5, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42260</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>