<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="278" order_by="278">PUBLIC SERVICE COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>278.506</section_number><catch_line>Gas to meet pipeline quality standards -- Delivery and curtailment provisions. </catch_line><order_by>506</order_by><text>All natural gas, authorized and required to be transported pursuant to KRS 278.505 shall: <section prefix="1">Be of the same quality and meet the same specifications as that natural gas being purchased by the intrastate pipeline or local distribution company as contained in the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission tariff applicable to the intrastate pipeline or local distribution company's natural gas supplier; </section><section prefix="2">Be delivered to the intrastate pipeline or local distribution company by the person for whom the natural gas is to be transported at a point in the system technically capable of receiving gas at the proposed delivery rate and proper pressure; </section><section prefix="3">Be transported pursuant to a written contract between the parties setting forth specific arrangements as to volumes to be transported, points of delivery, method of metering, timing of receipts and deliveries of gas and other matters relating to individual customer circumstances; </section><section prefix="4">Not be transported if the performance of this service would detrimentally affect the ability of the intrastate pipeline or local distribution company to supply regular gas service to its customers; </section><section prefix="5">Be subject to curtailment and interruption when in the judgment of the intrastate pipeline or local distribution company, said curtailment or interruption is necessary to enable the maintenance of deliveries to residential and other high priority customers or to respond to an emergency. </section></text><history>Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 39, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14136</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>