<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="196" order_by="196">CORRECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>196.700</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 196.700 to 196.735. </catch_line><order_by>700</order_by><text>As used in KRS 196.700 to 196.735, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Commission" means the Kentucky State Corrections Commission created in KRS 196.701; </section><section prefix="2">"Community corrections program" means a local government agency, private nonprofit, or charitable organization within the judicial circuit which shall perform one (1) or more of the following: <section prefix="a">Prepare community penalties plans; </section><section prefix="b">Directly provide, arrange, or contract with public and private agencies for sentencing services for offenders; and </section><section prefix="c">Monitor the progress of offenders placed on community penalty plans or who receive sentencing services through provisions of KRS 196.700 to 196.735; </section></section><section prefix="3">"Community corrections programs plan" means a written plan for the development, implementation, operation, and improvement of a community corrections program; </section><section prefix="4">"Community penalties plan" means a plan presented in writing to the sentencing judge which provides a detailed description of and rationale for the targeted offender's proposed sentence to a community corrections program or to one (1) or more special programs, conditions of probation, community punishments, or sanctions in lieu of lengthy incarceration; </section><section prefix="5">"Conditions of supervision" means conditions of probation, parole, mandatory reentry supervision, or other form of post-prison supervision; </section><section prefix="6">"Judicial circuit" means the circuits prescribed by KRS 23A.020; </section><section prefix="7">"Supervised individual" means an individual placed on probation by a court or serving a period of parole or other form of post-release supervision; and </section><section prefix="8">"Targeted offenders" means persons charged with or convicted of one (1) or more felonies who under application of law are eligible for probation or suspension of sentence. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch.2, sec.70, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 7, effective June 24, 2003. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39585</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>