<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="334" order_by="334">A SPEECH-LANGUAGE PATHOLOGISTS AND AUDIOLOGISTS </unit></structure><section_number>334A.035</section_number><catch_line>Interim license requirement -- Exemption for public school speech-language pathologists with teacher certification in communication disorders. </catch_line><order_by>035</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">A person who has a Master's degree in the area of speech-language pathology or communication disorders, or is currently enrolled in a doctoral degree program with emphasis in speech-language pathology or communication disorders, or has substantive equivalent course work as defined by the board's administrative regulations and who has completed supervised direct clinical practicum with individuals presenting a variety of disorders of communication and swallowing, the experience being obtained with a training institution or in one (1) of its cooperating programs, shall apply for an interim license during the time that person is completing postgraduate professional experience deemed necessary by the board. The postgraduate professional experience shall be completed under the supervision of a speech-language pathologist who holds a Kentucky license or certification by other accrediting bodies, at the discretion of the board.  </section><section prefix="b">A person with interim licensure shall make every effort to take and pass a national examination in speech-language pathology approved by the board at the time of the application for licensure. If unsuccessful with the examination, the licensee shall submit documentation of the applicant's preparation to take the national examination and continue to practice under supervision in accordance with this section. The board shall promulgate an administrative regulation in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to establish the documentation required under this paragraph.  </section><section prefix="c">Upon completion of postgraduate professional experience deemed necessary by the board, the speech-language pathologist shall make an application to the board within thirty (30) days for permanent licensure, if all requirements have been completed satisfactorily, or for renewal of the interim license at the discretion of the board. Failure to do so shall result in forfeiture of the interim license.  </section><section prefix="d">An interim license shall not exceed a period of twenty-four (24) months without board approval. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">A person who has a baccalaureate degree in the area of speech-language pathology or communication disorders as defined by administrative regulation shall apply for an interim license as a speech-language pathology assistant during the time that person is completing his or her professional experience as established by the board by administrative regulation. The postgraduate professional experience shall be completed under the supervision of an appropriately qualified supervisor.  </section><section prefix="b">Upon completion of the postgraduate professional experience, the speech-language pathology assistant shall make immediate application to the board within thirty (30) days for permanent licensure if all requirements have been completed satisfactorily, or for renewal of the interim license at the discretion of the board. Failure to do so shall result in forfeiture of the interim license. </section><section prefix="c">An interim license shall not exceed a period of twenty-four (24) months without board approval. </section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">A speech-language pathologist employed solely by the public schools in a certified position who holds a teacher certification in communication disorders issued by the Education Professional Standards Board shall be exempt from holding a license issued by the board.  </section><section prefix="b">A speech-language pathologist in a classified position who does not hold a teacher certification in communication disorders issued by the Education Professional Standards Board shall apply for and maintain appropriate licensure.  </section><section prefix="c">The public school speech-language pathologist shall determine from the local school board how his or her position is categorized. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 375, sec. 5, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 1, effective March 31, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31894</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>