<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="318" order_by="318">PLUMBERS AND PLUMBING </unit></structure><section_number>318.077</section_number><catch_line>Hearing on amendments to code -- Appeals. </catch_line><order_by>077</order_by><text>The committee shall hold hearings, upon adequate notice to affected parties specifying the matters to be considered before the submission to the commissioner of its suggested amendments to the code. No amendment of the code or any other related regulation shall be issued or promulgated by the department without the prior review and comment of the committee under the requirements of KRS 198B.030(8) and (9) and 198B.040(11). Any person aggrieved by any rule, regulation, or amendment approved by the department, within 30 days after such action has become final, may appeal therefrom to the Circuit Court. For the purposes of this section, "persons aggrieved" shall include any person directly or indirectly injured or threatened with injury on account of any such regulation, rule, or amendment, whether or not such person was a party to the proceedings out of which the order, rule, regulation, or amendment arose. </text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 20, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1680, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 256, sec. 9, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 54, effective July 1, 1978; and ch. 155, sec. 152, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 193, sec. 4; and ch. 299, sec. 67. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 6. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39915</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>