<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.13-053</section_number><catch_line>Filing procedures for rates for use after December 31, 1998. </catch_line><order_by>13-053</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Unless the commissioner enters an order pursuant to KRS 304.13-041 declaring workers' compensation to be a noncompetitive market, rates filed for use after December 31, 1998, shall be filed pursuant to KRS 304.13-051(1). </section><section prefix="2">Notwithstanding the provisions of KRS 304.13-051 to the contrary, after December 31, 1998, no insurer providing workers' compensation insurance shall place into effect any rates, manuals, or underwriting rules for workers' compensation insurance which it proposes to use pursuant to KRS 304.13-051(1) or (4) if the rates, manuals, or underwriting rules will result in an increase or decrease of more than fifteen percent (15%) from the workers' compensation insurer's then-existing workers' compensation insurance rates for any classification of risks within a twelve (12) month period of time. </section><section prefix="3">After December 31, 1998, any workers' compensation insurer which proposes to change its then-existing rates, manuals, or underwriting rules so as to effectively increase or decrease the rates of any classification of risks more than fifteen percent (15%) within a twelve (12) month period shall file all the rates and supplemental rating information which shall not become effective until approved by the commissioner pursuant to the provisions of KRS 304.13-051. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1117, effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 166, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1996 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 49, effective December 12, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  This section was amended by 2010 Ky. Acts chs. 24 and 166. Where these Acts are not in conflict, they have been codified together. Where a conflict exists, Acts ch. 166 which was last enacted by the General Assembly, prevails under KRS 446.250. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:07</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17056</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>