<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">F LOCAL RESCUE PROGRAMS - STATE AND LOCAL SEARCH AND RESCUE PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>39F.120</section_number><catch_line>Requirements for rescue grant funding -- Written standard operating procedures -- Bylaws -- Rescue vehicle -- Membership -- Training -- Affiliation -- Service fee prohibited. </catch_line><order_by>120</order_by><text>In order to ensure that rescue squads seeking funding under the rescue grant program achieve and maintain compliance with the provisions of this chapter, the following requirements shall be met: <section prefix="1">Each rescue squad shall develop written bylaws to specify as a minimum: <section prefix="a">The mission of the rescue squad. </section><section prefix="b">The election or appointment, succession, and term of officers. </section><section prefix="c">Financial accounting and property accountability. </section><section prefix="d">Administrative procedures. </section><section prefix="e">Definition of active membership in the squad. </section></section><section prefix="2">Each rescue squad shall develop written standard operating procedures which specify as a minimum: <section prefix="a">Procedures and rules for notification and response to emergencies. </section><section prefix="b">Procedures for all operations and response activities of the squad in accordance with the mission statement. </section></section><section prefix="3">A current copy of the bylaws and a current copy of all standard operating procedures shall be sent by the squad to the division. Amendments to the bylaws and standard operating procedures shall be sent to the division within ten (10) working days of their adoption. The division shall maintain a file of rescue squad bylaws and standard operating procedures. These files shall be public records. Copies of the bylaws and standard operating procedures of the squad, updated as required in this subsection, shall also be sent concurrently to the local emergency management director. </section><section prefix="4">Each rescue squad shall have a vehicle dedicated solely to rescue service. The make, model, year, vehicle identification number, and license number of each vehicle used by the squad solely for rescue service shall be supplied to the local emergency management director and to the division. When a new vehicle is put in service, or a vehicle is withdrawn from service, both the local director and the division shall be notified within ten (10) working days. </section><section prefix="5">A minimum of twelve (12) persons shall be identified by name as active members of the rescue squad. </section><section prefix="6">The active membership list of the rescue squad shall be submitted quarterly to the division through the area manager with a copy of the same list submitted concurrently to the local emergency management director. </section><section prefix="7">The active membership list shall be continuously maintained in an accurate and current status by the rescue squad, and shall be available for inspection by state and local government officials, employees, and the public. </section><section prefix="8">Rescue squads shall maintain a formal training program appropriate to accomplish the mission of the rescue squad. <section prefix="a">The training program shall consist of not less than two (2) hours of formal training per month. Actual rescue missions shall not constitute training. </section><section prefix="b">To be eligible for continued funding, each squad shall report not less than one hundred sixty-eight (168) man-hours of training for its members annually. This training shall be reported on the incident and training reports submitted pursuant to this chapter. </section><section prefix="c">Training at a rescue school provided by an emergency management agency or other appropriate training may be utilized to meet the requirements of subsection (2)(b) of this section. </section></section><section prefix="9">Rescue squads shall be formally affiliated with the local disaster and emergency services organization through the following means: <section prefix="a">Execution of a city or county order or ordinance, the adoption of a written search and rescue plan pursuant to KRS 39F.190, and the promulgation of a written statement of affiliation as the local charter of authorization signed by the county judge/executive or mayor, the local emergency management director, and the chief rescue officer outlining a specific working agreement. The statement of affiliation shall be subject to annual renewal. No statement of affiliation shall be subject to automatic renewal; it shall be an affirmative process. The document shall include, as a minimum, call out authority, chain of command, the responsibilities of each concerned party, terms and conditions of the local charter of authorization to operate in the jurisdiction, and procedures for revocation of the local charter, and shall be reviewed by the chief elected official of the government signing it and the local director. Both shall certify, if signing the document, that they have reviewed the mission statement of the rescue squad and the statement of affiliation and that they find that the rescue squad possesses: <section prefix="1">Adequate numbers of trained personnel to perform the mission; </section><section prefix="2">Proper and adequate equipment, including at least all of the required equipment specified by administrative regulations of the division, to perform the mission, and that the equipment is in proper working order; </section><section prefix="3">A rescue vehicle, dedicated solely to rescue purposes, which is adequate to perform the mission of the squad, and is in proper working order; and </section><section prefix="4">Adequate command and control personnel, training, and policies to ensure that the squad can quickly and efficiently respond and perform its mission when called upon. </section></section><section prefix="b">Incorporation, into the statement of affiliation, of a finding by the chief elected official and the local director that, following review of the mission statement of the rescue squad and the statement of affiliation, the rescue squad is performing a function not performed by other agencies of government or private agencies or organizations. If other organizations are performing functions which are listed on the mission statement of the rescue squad, then the statement shall contain reasons why duplication of existing services of other organizations by the rescue squad is necessary; and </section><section prefix="c">Incorporation of the responsibilities of the rescue squad into the rescue services annex of the local emergency operations plan or other appropriate annex. </section></section><section prefix="10">If either the chief elected official or the local director declines to sign the statement of affiliation provided for in subsection (9) of this section, the rescue squad shall be without local charter and shall return to the division all equipment purchased with state funds. This return of equipment shall take place within five (5) days of the refusal of either designee to sign the statement of affiliation. Neither the chief elected official nor the local director shall be required to state a reason why they sign or decline to sign a statement of affiliation. </section><section prefix="11">When a rescue squad is not independent, but is incorporated within other emergency service agencies or divisions, such as a fire department or fire division, the squad members shall be available for and capable of performing rescue services not incidental to their primary mission. </section><section prefix="12">Rescue squads shall maintain a full complement of minimum equipment appropriate to the type of rescue to be undertaken. Minimum equipment lists and other requirements for rescue squads shall be promulgated by the director by administrative regulation. </section><section prefix="13">Rescue squads shall not assess fees or charges for any rescue activity. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 94, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21805</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>