<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6">THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY </unit></structure><section_number>6.905</section_number><catch_line>Legislative Program Review and Investigations Committee -- Membership -- Meetings -- Vote required to act. </catch_line><order_by>905</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is created a Legislative Program Review and Investigations Committee which shall be a permanent standing committee of the General Assembly, consisting of eight (8) members of the Senate, six (6) of whom shall be appointed by the President and two (2) of whom shall be appointed by the Minority Leader of the Senate, and eight (8) members of the House of Representatives, six (6) of whom shall be appointed by the Speaker and two (2) of whom shall be appointed by the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives. At least one (1) appointee by each appointive authority shall be a member of the Senate or House Standing Committee on Appropriations and Revenue. The appointments shall be made within seven (7) legislative days of the end of each regular session of the General Assembly held in even-numbered years, and the members so appointed shall serve for a term of two </section><section prefix="2">years coextensive with the biennium in which the appointment is made. </section>Vacancies shall be filled within sixty (60) days of occurrence in the same manner as the original appointments, and for the balance of the term of the vacated member. (2) The members appointed from each chamber shall elect one (1) member from their chamber to serve as co-chair. Co-chairs shall be elected at the first meeting of the committee following the end of the regular session in even-numbered years. The co-chairs shall have joint responsibilities for committee meeting agendas and presiding at committee meetings. On an alternating basis, each co-chair shall have the first option to set the monthly meeting date. A monthly meeting may be canceled by agreement of both co-chairs. A majority of the entire membership of the Legislative Program Review and Investigations Committee shall constitute a quorum, and all actions of the committee shall be by vote of a majority of its entire membership. <section prefix="3">When a study is instituted, the committee shall request that the Legislative Research Commission appoint the co-chairs and two (2) minority members from the interim joint committee of relevant jurisdiction to serve as nonvoting ex officio members of the committee in activities related to the relevant study. One (1) of the minority members shall be a member of the House of Representatives designated by the House Minority Floor Leader and the other minority member shall be a member of the Senate designated by the Senate Minority Floor Leader. </section><section prefix="4">Each regular and nonvoting ex officio member of the committee shall receive the same travel allowances and compensation for attending interim meetings of the committee as are received by members of subcommittees of the Legislative Research Commission under KRS 7.090(3). </section></text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 185, sec. 1, effective March 31, 2003. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 125, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 486, secs. 8 and 36, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 356, sec. 1, effective January 1, 1983. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 328, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 254, sec. 1, effective March 30, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> March 31, 2003 </effective><lrc-note> (3/31/2003).  In codifying the 2003 Regular Session changes to this statute, the Reviser of Statutes, under the authority of KRS 7.136, has changed an existing reference in subsection (4) of this statute from "KRS 7.090(2)" to "KRS 7.090(3)." In codification following the 1982 Regular Session, subsection (2) of KRS 7.090 was renumbered as subsection (3), but the necessary adjustment to the reference in this statute was not made. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=412</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>