<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.16-060</section_number><catch_line>Trustee groups. </catch_line><order_by>16-060</order_by><text>The lives of a group of individuals may be insured under a policy issued to the trustees of a fund established by two (2) or more employers in the same industry or in related industries or by one (1) or more labor unions, or by one (1) or more employers and one <section prefix="1">or more labor unions, which trustees shall be deemed the policyholder, to insure </section>employees of the employers or members of the unions for the benefit of persons other than the employers or the unions, subject to the following requirements: (1) At no time shall a policy be issued to insure employees of any employer whose eligibility to participate in the fund as an employer arises out of considerations directly related to the employer's being a commercial correspondent or business client or patron of another employer, except where such other employer exercises substantial control over the business operations of the participating employers. <section prefix="2">The persons eligible for insurance shall be all of the employees of the employers or all of the members of the unions, or all of any class or classes thereof determined by conditions pertaining to their employment, or to membership in the unions, or to both. The policy may provide that the term "employees" shall include retired employees or union members, and the individual proprietor or partners if an employer is an individual proprietor or a partnership. No director of a corporate employer shall be eligible for insurance under the policy unless such person is otherwise eligible as a bona fide employee of the corporation by performing services other than the usual duties of a director. No individual proprietor or partner shall be eligible for insurance under the policy unless he is actively engaged in and devotes a substantial part of his time to the conduct of the business of the proprietor or partnership. The policy may provide that the term "employees" shall include trustees or their employees, or both, if their duties are principally connected with such trusteeship. </section><section prefix="3">The premium for the policy shall be paid by the trustees wholly from funds contributed by the employer or employers of the insured persons, or by the union or unions, or by both or partly from such funds and partly from funds contributed by the insured persons. A policy on which no part of the premium is to be derived from funds contributed by the insured persons specifically for their insurance shall insure all eligible persons, except those who reject the coverage in writing. </section><section prefix="4">An insurer may exclude or limit the coverage on any person for whom evidence of individual insurability is not satisfactory to the insurer. </section><section prefix="5">The amounts of insurance under the policy shall be based upon some plan precluding individual selection either by the insured persons or by the policyholder, employers or unions. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 140, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 16, sec. 6, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:11</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17267</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>