<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="350" order_by="350">SURFACE COAL MINING </unit></structure><section_number>350.470</section_number><catch_line>Review of regulations. </catch_line><order_by>470</order_by><text>For the purposes of regulations promulgated under the provisions of KRS 350.465, and pursuant to any other section which confers authority on the cabinet to promulgate regulations for the permanent regulatory program consistent with P.L. 95-87, the interim joint committee of jurisdiction shall have the same authority and responsibility as the administrative regulation review subcommittee has under KRS Chapter 13A. Following acceptance or rejection of the regulations by the interim committee the same shall be reviewed by the administrative regulation review subcommittee for the purposes of KRS Chapter 13A, provided that:  (1) review by the administrative regulation review subcommittee may begin before acceptance or rejection of the regulations by the interim committee; and (2) the interim committee must accept or reject the regulations within twenty (20) days of the date the regulations are submitted to the Legislative Research Commission for purposes of legislative review. The Governor shall have the same authority to issue emergency regulations under this section that he has under KRS Chapter 13A. </text><history>Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 377, sec. 6. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 330, sec. 29, effective June 1, 1979.</history><metadata><lrc-note> (1987).  A technical correction has been made in this section by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to KRS 7.136. The provisions of this section became operative on May 18, 1982, when the conditional approval granted by the United States Secretary of the Interior appeared in the Federal Register. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32854</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>