<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="324" order_by="324">A REAL ESTATE APPRAISERS </unit></structure><section_number>324A.045</section_number><catch_line>Issuance of certificate or license -- Renewal.   </catch_line><order_by>045</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall issue to each qualified applicant a certificate or license in form and size as shall be prescribed by the board. </section><section prefix="2">Every certificate and license shall be subject to annual renewal on the date or dates determined by the board by administrative regulation. Each certificate and license holder shall submit proof of compliance with the continuing education requirements when appropriate and the annual renewal fee to the board on or before the last day of the designated month. Failure to receive a renewal form shall not constitute an adequate excuse for failure to renew on time. </section><section prefix="3">If the certificate or license holder fails to renew in a timely manner, the certificate or license shall expire. Within six (6) months after the renewal date, the former certificate or license holder  shall be reinstated by complying with all appropriate renewal requirements and paying a late fee not to exceed two hundred dollars ($200). </section><section prefix="4">If six (6) months or more elapse after the renewal date, the former certificate or license holder shall be required to meet all current requirements as if applying for initial certification or licensure. </section></text><history>Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 46, sec. 11, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 247, sec. 6, effective April 7, 1992. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 383, sec. 8, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42098</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>