<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="407" order_by="407">INTERSTATE SUPPORT ENFORCEMENT </unit></structure><section_number>407.5204Simultaneous</section_number><catch_line>proceedings.   </catch_line><order_by>5204Simultaneous</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A tribunal of this state may exercise jurisdiction to establish a support order if the petition or comparable pleading is filed after a petition or comparable pleading is filed in another state or a foreign country only if: <section prefix="a">The petition or comparable pleading in this state is filed before the expiration of the time allowed in the other state or the foreign country for filing a responsive pleading challenging the exercise of jurisdiction by the other state or the foreign country; </section><section prefix="b">The contesting party timely challenges the exercise of jurisdiction in the other state or the foreign country; and </section><section prefix="c">If relevant, this state is the home state of the child. </section></section><section prefix="2">A tribunal of this state may not exercise jurisdiction to establish a support order if the petition or comparable pleading is filed before a petition or comparable pleading is filed in another state or a foreign country if: <section prefix="a">The petition or comparable pleading in the other state or foreign country is filed before the expiration of the time allowed in this state for filing a responsive pleading challenging the exercise of jurisdiction by this state; </section><section prefix="b">The contesting party timely challenges the exercise of jurisdiction in this state; and </section><section prefix="c">If relevant, the other state or foreign country is the home state of the child. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 7, effective June 24, 2015. -- Contingent effective date repealed 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 20, effective March 23, 1998. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 365, sec. 19, effective upon contingency. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44083</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>