<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="117" order_by="117">REGULATION OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>117.015</section_number><catch_line>State Board of Elections -- Powers, duties, membership. </catch_line><order_by>015</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There shall be a State Board of Elections which shall administer the election laws of the state and supervise registration and purgation of voters within the state. The board: <section prefix="a">May promulgate administrative regulations necessary to properly carry out its duties; and </section><section prefix="b">Shall promulgate administrative regulations establishing a procedure for elections officials to follow when an election has been suspended or delayed as described in KRS 39A.100. </section></section><section prefix="2">The board shall consist of the Secretary of State and six (6) members to be appointed by the Governor as provided in this subsection. The Secretary of State shall serve as the chairman of the state board and the chief election official for the Commonwealth. The members shall serve for a term of four (4) years or until their successors are appointed. Members shall be at least twenty-five (25) years of age and qualified voters of this state. No appointed member shall be a candidate for public office, have been a candidate for public office for two (2) years prior to his appointment, or have been convicted of any election law offense. Two (2) members shall be appointed by the Governor from a separate list of at least five (5) names submitted by the state central executive committee of each of the two (2) political parties that polled the largest vote in the last preceding election for state officials. The list shall be submitted to the Governor by February 15 of 1992, and the appointments of the Governor shall be made by April 1 of the same year. Two (2) separate lists shall be submitted to the Governor by August 15 of 1990 and every four (4) years thereafter, and two (2) appointments shall be made from these lists by September 15 of each year in which the lists are received. Vacancies shall be filled in the same manner as provided for original appointments, and the person appointed to fill the vacancy shall be of the same political party as his predecessor. </section><section prefix="3">The board shall meet as often as necessary to carry out its duties and shall keep a record of its acts, orders, findings, and proceedings. A majority of the board shall constitute a quorum. The Secretary of State shall preside at the meetings and may vote. </section><section prefix="4">The members of the board shall be paid a reasonable sum to be fixed by the secretary of the Personnel Cabinet, with the approval of the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, and in addition, their expenses in attending board meetings. The compensation shall be paid out of the State Treasury upon requisition signed by the chairman of the board and approved by the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 91, sec. 2, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 74, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 293, sec. 1. effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 341, sec. 24, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 457, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 18, effective June 21, 1974. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27342</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>