<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="78" order_by="78">COUNTY EMPLOYEES' CIVIL SERVICE AND RETIREMENT </unit></structure><section_number>78.533</section_number><catch_line>Employees of Metropolitan Park and Recreation Board of Jefferson County, credit for former service. </catch_line><order_by>533</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Metropolitan Park and Recreation Board of Jefferson County, Kentucky established by joint and concurrent resolution of the Jefferson County Fiscal Court and ordinance of the board of aldermen of the City of Louisville to become effective on July 1, 1968, is hereby declared to be the successor of the Jefferson County Playground and Recreation Board for purposes of participation in the County Employees Retirement System. </section><section prefix="2">Regular full-time employees of the Metropolitan Park and Recreation Board of Jefferson County shall be given credit for regular full-time service before July 1, 1958, with the City of Louisville Department of Parks and Recreation, the Jefferson County Playground and Recreation Board and any other agency participating in the County Employees Retirement System. </section><section prefix="3">Any regular full-time employee of the Metropolitan Park and Recreation Board of Jefferson County shall be allowed credit for regular full-time service with the City of Louisville Department of Parks and Recreation, the Jefferson County Playground and Recreation Board and any other agency participating in the County Employees Retirement System, for the period July 1, 1958, to the date such employee becomes a member of the retirement system, provided such employee pays contributions to the retirement system in accordance with the provisions of KRS 61.552. </section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 556, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 6. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:12</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24728</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>