<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="337" order_by="337">WAGES AND HOURS </unit></structure><section_number>337.050</section_number><catch_line>Time and a half for work done on seventh day of week -- Exceptions. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any employer who permits any employee to work seven (7) days in any one (1) workweek shall pay him at the rate of time and a half for the time worked on the seventh day. For the purposes of this subsection, the term "workweek" shall mean a calendar week or any other period of seven (7) consecutive days adopted by the employer as the workweek with the intention that the same shall be permanent and without the intention to evade the overtime provision set out herein. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Subsection (1) shall not apply in any case in which the employee is not permitted to work more than forty (40) hours during the workweek. In that case the employer may credit against the overtime payable under this section any overtime paid by him to the employees for the same hours under the requirements of any other law or contract. </section><section prefix="b">Subsection (1) shall not apply to telephone exchanges having less than five hundred (500) subscribers, nor to stenographers, bookkeepers, or technical assistants of professions such as doctors, accountants, lawyers, and other professions licensed under the laws of this state, nor to any employees subject to the Federal Railway Labor Act and seamen or persons engaged in operating boats or other water transportation facilities upon navigable streams, nor to persons engaged in icing railroad cars, nor to common carriers under the supervision of the Department of Vehicle Regulation. </section></section><section prefix="3">"Employee" as used in subsection (1) does not include any officer, superintendent, foreman, or supervisor whose duties are principally limited to directing or supervising other employees. </section></text><history>Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 28, sec. 1; and ch. 74, Art. IV, sec. 20(2). -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 1599c-20. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32049</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>