<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="244" order_by="244">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- PROHIBITIONS, RESTRICTIONS, AND REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>244.990</section_number><catch_line>Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>990</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person who, by himself or herself or acting through another, directly or indirectly, violates any of the provisions of this chapter for which no other penalty is provided shall, for the first offense, be guilty of a Class B misdemeanor; and for the second and each subsequent violation, he or she shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. The penalties provided for in this subsection shall be in addition to the revocation of the offender's license. If the offender is a corporation, joint stock company, association, or fiduciary, the principal officer or officers responsible for the violation may be imprisoned. </section><section prefix="2">Any person who violates KRS 244.170 shall, upon the first conviction, be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. Upon a second conviction he or she shall be guilty of a Class D felony. Upon the third and each subsequent conviction, he or she shall be guilty of a Class C felony. </section><section prefix="3">Any person who violates any of the provisions of KRS 244.480 to 244.600 shall be guilty of a violation. </section><section prefix="4">Except as provided in subsection (7) of this section, any person, firm, or corporation violating any provision of KRS 244.083 and 244.085 shall be guilty of a violation and each violation shall constitute a separate offense. </section><section prefix="5">Except as provided in subsection (7) of this section, any person who violates the provisions of subsection (5) of KRS 244.085 shall, for the first offense, be guilty of a violation, and for each subsequent offense shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="6">Any person who violates KRS 244.125 shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor for the first offense and a Class D felony for each subsequent offense. </section><section prefix="7">For any person under the age of eighteen (18) years, a violation of KRS 244.085 (2), (3), (4), (5), or (8) shall be deemed a status offense and shall be under the jurisdiction of the juvenile session of the District Court or the family division of the Circuit Court, as appropriate. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 87, sec. 23, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 35, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 463, sec. 32, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 336, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 312, sec. 10, effective July 1, 1986. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 254, sec. 10. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 286, sec. 3. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 6. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2554b-67, 2554b-152, 2554b-196, 2554b-219. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11506</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>