<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="218" order_by="218">A CONTROLLED SUBSTANCES </unit></structure><section_number>218A.286</section_number><catch_line>Theft, criminal possession, trafficking, or unlawful possession of a prescription or blank. </catch_line><order_by>286</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of theft of a prescription blank when he unlawfully takes or exercises control over a prescription blank belonging to another. </section><section prefix="2">A person is guilty of criminal possession of a prescription blank when, with knowledge that he has no lawful authority to possess a prescription blank, he possesses a prescription blank with the intent to utter a forged prescription or sell or transfer the prescription blank to another person for that purpose. </section><section prefix="3">A person is guilty of trafficking in prescription blanks when he knowingly and unlawfully traffics in a prescription blank or a forged prescription for a controlled substance. </section><section prefix="4">The knowing, with intent to violate this chapter, possession of a prescription blank by a person other than a pharmacist, practitioner, or other person authorized by law to prescribe or dispense a controlled substance, a manufacturer, wholesaler, or distributor, or by a person lawfully printing or reproducing prescription blanks, shall be prima facie evidence that the prescription blank was possessed for the purpose of uttering a forged prescription or for sale or transfer to another person for that purpose. </section><section prefix="5">Any person who violates any subsection of this section shall be guilty of a Class D felony for the first offense and a Class C felony for a second or subsequent offense. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 301, sec. 19, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9693</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>