<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.070</section_number><catch_line>City and consolidated local government licenses -- Kinds -- Fees -- Restriction on increase of fees.   </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The legislative body of any city or a consolidated local government in which traffic in alcoholic beverages is not prohibited under KRS Chapter 242 may impose license fees for the privilege of manufacturing and trafficking in alcoholic beverages. Only those licenses set out in this section shall be issued. The license fees are subject to the provisions of subsections (16), (17), and (18) of this section, and shall not exceed the amounts specified in subsections (2) to (15) of this section. </section><section prefix="2">Distilled spirit licenses as set forth in KRS 243.030: <section prefix="a">Distiller's license, per annum  .................................................................$500.00 </section><section prefix="b">Rectifier's license, per annum  .............................................................$3,000.00 </section><section prefix="c">Wholesaler's distilled spirits and wine license, per annum  .................$3,000.00 </section><section prefix="d">Quota retail package license, per annum: <section prefix="1">In counties containing a consolidated local government  ...........$1,200.00 </section><section prefix="2">In all other counties  ...................................................................$1,000.00 </section></section></section><section prefix="3">Quota retail drink license, per annum: <section prefix="a">In counties containing a consolidated local government  ....................$1,600.00 </section><section prefix="b">In all other counties..............................................................................$1,000.00 </section></section><section prefix="4">Special temporary license, per event: <section prefix="a">In counties containing a consolidated local government  .......................$266.66 </section><section prefix="b">In all other counties.................................................................................$166.66 </section></section><section prefix="5">Nonquota type 1 retail drink license (includes distilled spirits, wine, and malt beverages), per annum  .................................................................................$2,000.00 </section><section prefix="6">Nonquota type 2 retail drink license (includes distilled spirits, wine, and malt beverages), per annum: <section prefix="a">In counties containing a consolidated local government ....................$1,800.00 </section><section prefix="b">In all other counties .............................................................................$1,000.00 </section></section><section prefix="7">Nonquota type 3 retail drink license (includes distilled spirits, wine, and malt beverages), per annum ....................................................................................$300.00 </section><section prefix="8">Distilled spirits and wine special temporary auction </section>  license, per event  .............................................................................................$200.00 <section prefix="9">Special Sunday retail drink license, per annum  ..............................................$300.00 </section><section prefix="10">Extended hours supplemental license, per annum  .......................................$2,000.00 </section><section prefix="11">Caterer's license, per annum ............................................................................$800.00 </section><section prefix="12">Bottling house or bottling house storage license, per annum .......................$1,000.00 </section><section prefix="13">Malt beverage licenses as follows: <section prefix="a">Brewer's license, per annum  ..................................................................$500.00 </section><section prefix="b">Microbrewery license, per annum  ..........................................................$500.00 </section><section prefix="c">Malt beverage distributor's license, per annum  .....................................$400.00 </section><section prefix="d">Nonquota retail malt beverage package license, per annum  ..................$200.00 </section><section prefix="e">Nonquota type 4 retail malt beverage drink license, per annum .............$200.00 </section><section prefix="f">Malt beverage brew-on-premises license, per annum  ............................$100.00 </section></section><section prefix="14">Limited restaurant license (includes distilled spirits, wine, and malt beverages), per annum: <section prefix="a">In counties containing a consolidated local government  ....................$1,800.00 </section><section prefix="b">In all other counties..............................................................................$1,200.00 </section></section><section prefix="15">Limited golf course license (includes distilled spirits, wine, and malt beverages), per annum: <section prefix="a">In counties containing a consolidated local government ....................$1,800.00 </section><section prefix="b">In all other counties  ............................................................................$1,200.00 </section></section><section prefix="16">The fee for the following license types may not be increased by more than five percent (5%) above the January 1, 2013, fee for the current license or the former license type listed beside it, during any five (5) year period. The fees for the licenses described in this subsection are still subject to the maximum amounts listed for those licenses in subsections (2) to (15) of this section: <section prefix="a">Quota retail package license: retail package liquor license; </section><section prefix="b">Quota retail drink license: retail drink license; </section><section prefix="c">Nonquota type 1 retail drink license: convention center or convention hotel complex license; </section><section prefix="d">Nonquota type 2 retail drink license: restaurant drink license; </section><section prefix="e">Nonquota retail malt beverage package license: retail malt beverage license; </section><section prefix="f">Nonquota type 4 retail malt beverage drink license: retail malt beverage license; </section><section prefix="g">Limited restaurant license; and </section><section prefix="h">Limited golf course license. </section></section><section prefix="17">The fee for each of the first five (5) supplemental bar licenses shall be the same as the fee for the primary drink license. There shall be no charge for each supplemental license issued in excess of five (5) to the same licensee at the same premises. </section><section prefix="18">The holder of a nonquota retail malt beverage package license may obtain a Nonquota type 4 malt beverage drink license for a fee of fifty dollars ($50). The holder of a Nonquota type 4 malt beverage drink license may obtain a nonquota retail malt beverage package license for a fee of fifty dollars ($50). </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 55, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 8, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 220, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 3, effective March 6, 2000; and ch.  435, sec. 11, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 518, sec. 5, effective April 13, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 60, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 99, effective June 17, 1978; and ch. 432, sec. 4, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 335, sec. 3 -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2554b-113. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42490</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>