<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="7" order_by="7">A PLANNING AND OVERSIGHT OF GOVERNMENTAL FINANCE </unit></structure><section_number>7A.120</section_number><catch_line>State capital improvement plan. </catch_line><order_by>120</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every two (2) years, the board shall prepare a state capital improvement plan containing its proposals for state spending for capital projects. </section><section prefix="2">Copies of the plan shall be submitted to the Governor, the Chief Justice, and the Legislative Research Commission no later than November 1 of each odd-numbered year. The plan shall provide: <section prefix="a">A detailed list of all capital projects of the state, including transportation projects as submitted by the Kentucky Transportation Cabinet and approved by the Joint Transportation Committee, which the board recommends be undertaken or continued by any state agency during the six (6) fiscal year period commencing with the upcoming biennial budget, together with information as to the effect of these capital projects on future operating expenses of the Commonwealth, and with recommendations as to the priority of these capital projects and the means of funding them; </section><section prefix="b">The forecast of the board as to the requirements for capital projects of state agencies during the six (6) fiscal year period and for those additional periods, if any, necessary or desirable for adequate presentation of particular capital projects, and a schedule for the planning and implementation or construction for these additional periods; </section><section prefix="c">A schedule for the next biennial budget of recommended appropriations of bond funds from issues of bonds previously authorized; </section><section prefix="d">A review of capital projects which have recently been implemented or completed or are in process of implementation or completion; </section><section prefix="e">Recommendations as to the maintenance of physical properties and equipment of state agencies; and </section><section prefix="f">Any other information that the board deems relevant to the foregoing matters. </section></section><section prefix="3">Each state agency, excluding the Department of Highways, shall no later than April 15 of each odd-numbered year provide the board with information described in subsection (2) of this section in the form that shall be prescribed by the board. </section><section prefix="4">In addition to information available to the board under the computerized record keeping of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, each state agency shall, when requested, provide the board with supplemental information concerning any real property owned or leased by the agency, including its current or future availability for other state uses. </section></text><history>Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 503, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=499</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>