<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="223" order_by="223">SANITARIANS, WATER PLANT OPERATORS, AND WATER WELL CONSTRUCTION PRACTICES </unit></structure><section_number>223.430</section_number><catch_line>Liability coverage -- Surety bond. </catch_line><order_by>430</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each application for issuance or renewal of a certificate shall be accompanied by a proof of either split limits liability coverage for bodily injury of at least twenty-five thousand dollars ($25,000) per person with an aggregate of at least fifty thousand dollars ($50,000) and for property damage of at least fifty thousand dollars ($50,000) per accident with an aggregate of at least one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000), or single limits liability coverage of not less than one hundred thousand dollars ($100,000) for all damages whether arising out of bodily injury or damage to property as a result of any one (1) accident or occurrence.  Notice shall be given by certified mail to the executive secretary and treasurer of the board by the insurer upon lapse of coverage by the insurance company for any reason, including nonpayment of premiums. </section><section prefix="2">Prior to the issuance of a driller certificate, proof of a surety bond must be filed along with the application for a certificate. The penal sum of this bond shall be five thousand dollars ($5,000), with the applicant designated as the principal obligor and the Commonwealth designated as the obligee. The surety may be called on by the secretary if the certified individual violates any design standards adopted as administrative regulations pursuant to KRS 223.420 or 223.435 or provision of KRS 223.405 to 223.460. The surety bond shall be used for the express purposes of correcting the violations. Notice of lapse of coverage for any reason by the surety shall be given by certified mail to the executive secretary and treasurer of the board by the surety. </section></text><history> Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 212, sec. 4, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 249, sec. 1, effective April 3, 1986. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 215, sec. 7, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9979</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>