<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.15-100</section_number><catch_line>Dividends. </catch_line><order_by>15-100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There shall be a provision in participating policies that, beginning not later than the end of the third policy year, the insurer shall annually ascertain and apportion the divisible surplus, if any, that will accrue on the policy anniversary or other dividend date specified in the policy provided the policy is in force and all premiums to that date are paid. Except as hereinafter provided, any dividend becoming payable shall at the option of the party entitled to elect such option be either: <section prefix="a">Payable in cash, or </section><section prefix="b">Applied to any one (1) of such other dividend options as may be provided by the policy. If any such other dividend options are provided, the policy shall further state which option shall be automatically effective if such party shall not have elected some other option. If the policy specifies a period within which such other dividend option may be elected, such period shall be not less than thirty (30) days following the date on which such dividend is due and payable. The annually apportioned dividend shall be deemed to be payable in cash within the meaning of paragraph (a) of this subsection even though the policy provides that payment of such dividend is to be deferred for a specified period, provided such period does not exceed six (6) years from the date of apportionment and that interest will be added to such dividend at a specified rate. </section></section><section prefix="2">Renewable term policies of ten (10) years or less may provide that the surplus accrued to such policies shall be determined and apportioned each year after the second policy year, and accumulated during each renewal period, and that at the end of the renewal period, on renewal of the policy by the insured, the insurer shall apply the accumulated surplus as an annuity for the next succeeding renewal term in the reduction of premiums. </section><section prefix="3">In participating industrial life insurance policies, in lieu of the provision required in subsection (1) of this section, there shall be a provision that, beginning not later than the end of the fifth policy year, the policy shall participate annually in the divisible surplus, if any, in the manner set forth in the policy. </section><section prefix="4">This section does not apply as to insurance issued in consideration of lapsed or surrendered policies. </section></text><history>Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 15, sec. 10, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective>June 18, 1970</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:06</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17206</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>