<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">A STATEWIDE EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>39A.100</section_number><catch_line>Emergency powers of Governor and local chief executive officers. </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In the event of the occurrence or threatened or impending occurrence of any of the situations or events contemplated by KRS 39A.010, 39A.020, or 39A.030, the Governor may declare, in writing, that a state of emergency exists. The Governor shall have and may exercise the following emergency powers during the period in which the state of emergency exists: <section prefix="a">To enforce all laws, and administrative regulations relating to disaster and emergency response and to assume direct operational control of all disaster and emergency response forces and activities in the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="b">To require state agencies and to request local governments, local agencies, and special districts to respond to the emergency or disaster in the manner directed; </section><section prefix="c">To seize, take, or condemn property, excluding firearms and ammunition, components of firearms and ammunition, or a combination thereof, for the protection of the public or at the request of the President, the Armed Forces, or the Federal Emergency Management Agency of the United States, including: <section prefix="1">All means of transportation and communication; </section><section prefix="2">All stocks of fuel of whatever nature; </section><section prefix="3">Food, clothing, equipment, materials, medicines, and all supplies; and </section><section prefix="4">Facilities, including buildings and plants; </section></section><section prefix="d">To sell, lend, give, or distribute any of the property under paragraph (c) of this subsection among the inhabitants of the Commonwealth and to account to the State Treasurer for any funds received for the property; </section><section prefix="e">To make compensation for the property seized, taken, or condemned under paragraph (c) of this subsection; </section><section prefix="f">To exclude all nonessential, unauthorized, disruptive, or otherwise uncooperative personnel from the scene of the emergency, and to command those persons or groups assembled at the scene to disperse. A person who refuses to leave an area in which a written order of evacuation has been issued in accordance with a written declaration of emergency or a disaster may be forcibly removed to a place of safety or shelter, or may, if this is resisted, be arrested by a peace officer. Forcible removal or arrest shall not be exercised as options until all reasonable efforts for voluntary compliance have been exhausted; </section><section prefix="g">To declare curfews and establish their limits; </section><section prefix="h">To prohibit or limit the sale or consumption of goods, excluding firearms and ammunition, components of firearms and ammunition, or a combination thereof, or commodities for the duration of the emergency; </section><section prefix="i">To grant emergency authority to pharmacists pursuant to KRS 315.500, for the duration of the emergency; </section><section prefix="j">Except as prohibited by this section or other law, to perform and exercise other functions, powers, and duties deemed necessary to promote and secure the safety and protection of the civilian population; </section><section prefix="k">To request any assistance from agencies of the United States as necessary and appropriate to meet the needs of the people of the Commonwealth; and </section><section prefix="l">Upon the recommendation of the Secretary of State, to declare by executive order a different time or place for holding elections in an election area for which a state of emergency has been declared for part or all of the election area. The election shall be held within thirty-five (35) days from the date of the suspended or delayed election. The State Board of Elections shall establish procedures for election officials to follow. </section></section><section prefix="2">In the event of the occurrence or threatened or impending occurrence of any of the situations or events contemplated by KRS 39A.010, 39A.020, or 39A.030, which in the judgment of a local chief executive officer is of such severity or complexity as to require the exercise of extraordinary emergency measures, the county judge/executive of a county other than an urban-county government, or mayor of a city or urban-county government, or chief executive of other local governments or their designees as provided by ordinance of the affected county, city, or urban-county may declare in writing that a state of emergency exists, and thereafter, subject to any orders of the Governor, shall have and may exercise for the period as the state of emergency exists or continues, the following emergency powers: <section prefix="a">To enforce all laws and administrative regulations relating to disaster and emergency response and to direct all local disaster and emergency response forces and operations in the affected county, city, urban-county, or charter county; </section><section prefix="b">To exclude all nonessential, unauthorized, disruptive, or uncooperative personnel from the scene of the emergency, and to command persons or groups of persons at the scene to disperse. A person who refuses to leave an area in which a written order of evacuation has been issued in accordance with a written declaration of emergency or a disaster may be forcibly removed to a place of safety or shelter, or may, if this is resisted, be arrested by a peace officer. Forcible removal or arrest shall not be exercised as options until all reasonable efforts for voluntary compliance have been exhausted; </section><section prefix="c">To declare curfews and establish their limits; </section><section prefix="d">To order immediate purchase or rental of, contract for, or otherwise procure, without regard to procurement codes or budget requirements, the goods and services essential for protection of public health and safety or to maintain or to restore essential public services; and </section><section prefix="e">To request emergency assistance from any local government or special district and, through the Governor, to request emergency assistance from any state agency and to initiate requests for federal assistance as are necessary for protection of public health and safety or for continuation of essential public services. </section></section><section prefix="3">Nothing in this section shall be construed to allow any governmental entity to impose additional restrictions on the lawful possession, transfer, sale, transport, carrying, storage, display, or use of firearms and ammunition or components of firearms and ammunition. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 1, effective March 8, 2006; and ch. 240, sec. 10, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 91, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21704</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>