<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.113</section_number><catch_line>Financial Integrity Enforcement Division -- Duties -- Prevention of identity theft. </catch_line><order_by>113</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Financial Integrity Enforcement Division is created in the Department of Law. The division shall: <section prefix="a">Investigate illegal redemption of food stamp benefits in cooperation with the United States Department of Agriculture and the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="b">Verify eligibility of food stamp program applicants as to past criminal history; </section><section prefix="c">Investigate the illegal distribution of counterfeit merchandise; and </section><section prefix="d">Investigate the use of personal identification and financial information by persons for the purpose of theft, or fraud, or both theft and fraud, and other illegal or fraudulent activity which may involve electronic commerce. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Office of the Attorney General shall coordinate with the Department of Financial Institutions, the United States Secret Service, the Federal Trade Commission, the Kentucky Bankers' Association, and any other agency or organization to prepare and disseminate information to prevent identity theft. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 13, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 77, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 175, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 28, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=888</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>