<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="91" order_by="91">A FINANCE AND REVENUE OF CITIES </unit></structure><section_number>91A.0808</section_number><catch_line>Local premium tax advisory council -- Members -- Purpose. </catch_line><order_by>0808</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">The commissioner of the Department of Insurance shall appoint a local premium tax advisory council to provide advice and expertise on the imposition, administration, and collection of taxes and fees imposed pursuant to KRS 91A.080. The council shall be chaired by the commissioner of the Department of Insurance and shall be composed of eight (8) members which shall include two (2) city government representatives nominated by the Kentucky League of Cities, two (2) county government representatives nominated by the Kentucky Association of Counties, one (1) independent insurance agent, one (1) representative of a domestic insurance company, one (1) representative of a foreign insurance company, and one (1) representative of an insurance trade association. Members shall serve four (4) year terms, except for the initial members whose appointments shall be staggered. </section><section prefix="b">The chair shall preside over meetings of the advisory council but shall have no vote except that he or she may cast a vote in order to break a tie. </section><section prefix="c">The Department of Insurance shall staff and assist the council which shall meet at least two (2) times per year at meetings called by the chair or a majority of the members. </section></section><section prefix="2">The council may identify ways to make the system more effective and efficient for all parties by making recommendations on needed legislative changes and providing comments on needed regulatory reforms. In addition, the council may provide information and assistance to insurance companies and local governments regarding procedures and practices related to compliance with provisions of this chapter related to the imposition, administration, and collection of taxes and fees imposed pursuant to KRS 91A.080. At least once each year, the council shall review the criteria for verification of risk location systems or programs established by the Department of Insurance under KRS 91A.0806 and make recommendations for updating and improving the verification criteria. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 79, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 94, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:10</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=25572</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>