<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="314" order_by="314">REGISTERED NURSES -- PRACTICAL NURSES </unit></structure><section_number>314.089</section_number><catch_line>Immediate temporary suspension of license against which disciplinary action or investigation is pending -- Procedure. </catch_line><order_by>089</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board's president or the president's designee may determine that immediate temporary suspension of a license or privilege against which disciplinary action or an investigation is pending is necessary in order to protect the public. When it appears that this action may be necessary, the executive director or the executive director's designee shall issue an emergency order suspending the nurse's license or privilege. Upon appeal of an emergency order, an emergency hearing shall be conducted in accordance with KRS 13B.125. </section><section prefix="2">No board member shall be disqualified from serving on a disciplinary action hearing panel for the reason that he has previously sat on a hearing panel considering temporary suspension of the same license or privilege. </section><section prefix="3">The board shall expedite disciplinary actions in which a license or privilege has been temporarily suspended. </section><section prefix="4">The order of immediate temporary suspension shall remain in effect until either reconsidered or superseded by final disciplinary action by the board. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 8, effective June 1, 2007. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 55, sec. 6, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 266, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 266, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 128, sec. 9, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> June 1, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30908</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>