<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="262" order_by="262">SOIL AND WATER CONSERVATION </unit></structure><section_number>262.610</section_number><catch_line>Acquisitions of equipment or infrastructure by Soil and Water Conservation Commission. </catch_line><order_by>610</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Soil and Water Conservation Commission as referred to in KRS Chapter 146, subject to the supervision of the commissioner for natural resources, to the restrictions provided in KRS 262.610 to 262.660, and to the requirements of KRS Chapters 42 and 45A, is hereby authorized to acquire and to make available, or to assist in acquiring or making available to soil and water conservation districts, heavy or specialized equipment or infrastructure which an individual district cannot itself economically obtain. </section><section prefix="2">When the commission acquires or makes available to any district the equipment or infrastructure above referred to, it shall require said district to fully amortize, in the form of rentals or payments, to the Division of Conservation, as referred to in KRS Chapter 146, any amount so expended by the commission for such assistance. The amount and method of amortization for each piece of heavy equipment or infrastructure shall be determined by the commission, subject to approval of the commissioner of natural resources. The amount and method of amortization for each piece of heavy or specialized equipment shall be determined on the basis of a rental to be charged by the district to the user of equipment sufficient to: <section prefix="a">Fully amortize to the division the capital outlay for the machinery itself over the period of its reasonably anticipated full usefulness; </section><section prefix="b">Cover the cost of operation, maintenance and repairs; </section><section prefix="c">Pay the usual cost of providing an operator; and </section><section prefix="d">Compensate the district for the usual costs of transportation from one (1) job to another. </section></section><section prefix="3">In giving effect to all of the foregoing, the commission shall estimate the amount of time such equipment would ordinarily be idle. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 4, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 496, sec. 59, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 63. -- Created 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><lrc-note> (6/20/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 95, 97, 98, 99, 123, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-16</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12771</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>