<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.6-225</section_number><catch_line>Specific duties of board. </catch_line><order_by>6-225</order_by><text>It shall be the duty of the board of directors to: <section prefix="1">Act upon applications for membership or to appoint one (1) or more membership officers to approve applications for membership under such conditions as the board prescribes. A record of the actions taken by a membership officer on applications shall be available to the board of directors for inspection. A person denied membership by a membership officer may appeal the denial to the board; </section><section prefix="2">Purchase a blanket fidelity bond, in accordance with any rules and regulations of the commissioner, to protect the credit union against losses caused by occurrences covered therein such as fraud, dishonesty, forgery, embezzlement, misappropriation, misapplication, or unfaithful performance of duty by a director, officer, employee, member of a committee, attorney-at-law or other agent; </section><section prefix="3">Determine from time to time the interest rate or rates, consistent with this subtitle, which shall be charged on loans and to authorize any interest refunds on such classes of loans and under such conditions as the board prescribes; </section><section prefix="4">Establish the policies of the credit union with respect to the granting of loans and the extending of lines of credit, including the maximum amount which may be loaned to any one (1) member; </section><section prefix="5">Establish different types or classes of shares; </section><section prefix="6">Declare dividends on shares and share certificates in the manner and form as provided in the bylaws; and determine the interest rate or rates which will be paid on deposits and deposit certificates; </section><section prefix="7">If deemed desirable, limit the number of shares and the amount of share certificates, deposits and deposit certificates which may be owned by a member. Any such limitation shall apply alike to all members; </section><section prefix="8">Have charge of the investment of funds, except that the board may designate an investment committee or any qualified individual to have charge of making investments under conditions established by the board; </section><section prefix="9">Authorize the employment of such persons necessary to carry on the business of the credit union, including the credit manager, loan officers and auditing assistants requested by the supervisory committee, and fix the compensation, if any, of the president; </section><section prefix="10">Approve an annual operating budget for the credit union, which shall include provision for the compensation of employees; </section><section prefix="11">Authorize the conveyance of property; </section><section prefix="12">Authorize contributions to civic, charitable or service organizations, subject to regulations of the commissioner; </section><section prefix="13">Borrow or lend money to carry on the functions of the credit union; </section><section prefix="14">Designate a depository or depositories for the funds of the credit union; </section><section prefix="15">Suspend any or all members of the credit or supervisory committee for failure to perform their duties; </section><section prefix="16">Appoint any special committees deemed necessary; and </section><section prefix="17">Perform such other duties as the members from time to time direct, and perform or authorize any action not inconsistent with this subtitle and not specifically reserved by the bylaws for the members. </section></text><history>Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 408, sec. 25, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984 </effective><former-codification> KRS 290.225. </former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  In accordance with 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, secs. 38 and 39, this statute has been renumbered as a section of the Kentucky Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286, and KRS references within this statute have been adjusted to conform with the 2006 renumbering of that code. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14780</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>