<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="503" order_by="503">GENERAL PRINCIPLES OF JUSTIFICATION </unit></structure><section_number>503.110</section_number><catch_line>Use of force by person with responsibility for care, discipline, or safety of others. </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The use of physical force by a defendant upon another person is justifiable when the defendant is a parent, guardian, or other person entrusted with the care and supervision of a minor or an incompetent person or when the defendant is a teacher or other person entrusted with the care and supervision of a minor, for a special purpose, and: <section prefix="a">The defendant believes that the force used is necessary to promote the welfare of a minor or mentally disabled person or, if the defendant's responsibility for the minor or mentally disabled person is for a special purpose, to further that special purpose or maintain reasonable discipline in a school, class, or other group; and </section><section prefix="b">The force that is used is not designed to cause or known to create a substantial risk of causing death, serious physical injury, disfigurement, extreme pain, or extreme mental distress. </section></section><section prefix="2">The use of physical force by a defendant upon another person is justifiable when the defendant is a warden or other authorized official of a correctional institution, and: <section prefix="a">The defendant believes that the force used is necessary for the purpose of enforcing the lawful rules of the institution; </section><section prefix="b">The degree of force used is not forbidden by any statute governing the administration of the institution; and </section><section prefix="c">If deadly force is used, its use is otherwise justifiable under this code. </section></section><section prefix="3">The use of physical force by a defendant upon another person is justifiable when the defendant is a person responsible for the operation of or the maintenance of order in a vehicle or other carrier of passengers and the defendant believes that such force is necessary to prevent interference with its operation or to maintain order in the vehicle or other carrier, except that deadly physical force may be used only when the defendant believes it necessary to prevent death or serious physical injury. </section><section prefix="4">The use of physical force by a defendant upon another person is justifiable when the defendant is a doctor or other therapist or a person assisting him at his direction, and: <section prefix="a">The force is used for the purpose of administering a recognized form of treatment which the defendant believes to be adapted to promoting the physical or mental health of the patient; and </section><section prefix="b">The treatment is administered with the consent of the patient or, if the patient is a minor or a mentally disabled person, with the consent of the parent, guardian, or other person legally competent to consent in his behalf, or the treatment is administered in an emergency when the defendant believes that no one competent to consent can be consulted and that a reasonable person, wishing to safeguard the welfare of the patient, would consent. </section></section></text><history>Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 135, effective July 1, 1982. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 36, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective>July 1, 1982 </effective><note>1980 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 147 would have amended this section effective July 1, 1982. However, 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 396 was repealed by 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 146, also effective July 1, 1982. </note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19677</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>