<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="201" order_by="201">JEFFERSON COUNTY CHILDREN'S HOME </unit></structure><section_number>201.040</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of board. </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall be a corporation with the usual corporate powers, and may do all things reasonable or necessary to effectively carry out the work and perform the duties contemplated in this chapter. </section><section prefix="2">The board may make all rules and regulations, not inconsistent with the law, necessary or proper for the effective management of the home, and of the property owned, held, or controlled by the board, and for the care, maintenance, training and education, grouping, discipline, discharge, release, and parole of the children received into the home's care, and for their placement and supervision in foster family or group homes, in adoptive homes, in homes of parents, relatives or friends, or in shelter, detention or day care; and all the children received into the home's care shall be subject to such rules. </section><section prefix="3">The board may delegate to the superintendent, and to such other officers or employees of the home as may be designated by the board, the authority to carry out such functions of the board as described in subsection (2) of this section, KRS 201.080, 201.090, 201.100, 201.110 and 201.120 as may be determined to be in the interest of the home and the children under the home's care. </section></text><history>Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 173, sec. 4, effective June 18, 1964. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 938b-1, 938b-11. </history><metadata><effective>June 18, 1964</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7344</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>