<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171">STATE LIBRARIES -- LIBRARIANS -- STATE ARCHIVES AND RECORDS </unit></structure><section_number>171.757</section_number><catch_line>Commission's powers. </catch_line><order_by>757</order_by><text>The Commonwealth of Kentucky War of 1812 Bicentennial Commission may: <section prefix="1">Study and recommend activities that may be carried out by the Commonwealth to honor the Kentuckians that served in the War of 1812; </section><section prefix="2">Educate Kentucky residents and the nation about Kentucky's role in the War of 1812; </section><section prefix="3">Disseminate information to local governments and organizations that may help them with planning, preparation, and grant applications for bicentennial events and projects; </section><section prefix="4">Assist in federal, state, and local bicentennial activities occurring in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="5">Plan and implement appropriate events, including celebrations and educational initiatives, to commemorate the bicentennial; </section><section prefix="6">Perform other duties as necessary to highlight Kentucky's role in the War of 1812; </section><section prefix="7">Cooperate with the governments of the United States, Illinois, Indiana, Ohio, Michigan, Louisiana, and Ontario, Canada and other states and countries commemorating the War of 1812 Bicentennial as resources allow; and </section><section prefix="8">Seek federal grants and philanthropic support for bicentennial activities when possible. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 68, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4857</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>