<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="508" order_by="508">ASSAULT AND RELATED OFFENSES </unit></structure><section_number>508.155</section_number><catch_line>Restraining order or interpersonal protective order to be issued uponviolation of KRS 508.140 or 508.150.  </catch_line><order_by>155</order_by><text>(1)(a)Before January 1, 2016, a verdict of guilty or a plea of guilty to KRS508.140 or 508.150 shall operate as an application for a restraining orderutilizing the provisions of this section and limiting the contact of thedefendant and the victim who was stalked, unless the victim requestsotherwise.(b)Beginning January 1, 2016, a verdict of guilty or a plea of guilty to KRS508.140 or 508.150 shall operate as an application for an interpersonalprotective order issued under KRS Chapter 456, unless the victimrequests otherwise. Notwithstanding the provisions of KRS Chapter 456:1.An interpersonal protective order requested under this subsectionmay be issued by the court that entered the judgment of conviction;2.The judgment of conviction shall constitute sufficient cause for theentry of the order without the necessity of further proof being taken;and3.The order may be effective for up to ten (10) years, with furtherrenewals in increments of up to ten (10) years.(2)The court shall give the defendant notice of his or her right to request a hearingon the application for a restraining order. If the defendant waives his or herright to a hearing on this matter, then the court may issue the restraining orderwithout a hearing.(3)If the defendant requests a hearing, it shall be held at the time of the verdict orplea of guilty, unless the victim or defendant requests otherwise. The hearingshall be held in the court where the verdict or plea of guilty was entered.(4)A restraining order may grant the following specific relief:(a)An order restraining the defendant from entering the residence, property,school, or place of employment of the victim; or(b)An order restraining the defendant from making contact with the victim,including an order forbidding the defendant from personally, or through anagent, initiating any communication likely to cause serious alarm,annoyance, intimidation, or harassment, including but not limited topersonal, written, telephonic, or any other form of written or electroniccommunication or contact with the victim. An order issued pursuant to thissubsection relating to a school, place of business, or similarnonresidential location shall be sufficiently limited to protect the stalkingvictim but shall also protect the defendant's right to employment,education, or the right to do legitimate business with the employer of astalking victim as long as the defendant does not have contact with thestalking victim. The provisions of this subsection shall not apply to acontact by an attorney regarding a legal matter.(5)A restraining order issued pursuant to this section shall be valid for a period ofnot more than ten (10) years, the specific duration of which shall be determinedby the court. Any restraining order shall be based upon the seriousness of thefacts before the court, the probability of future violations, and the safety of thevictim, his or her immediate family, or both.(6)Unless the defendant has been convicted of a felony, or is otherwise ineligibleto purchase or possess a firearm under federal law, a restraining order issuedpursuant to this section shall not operate as a ban on the purchase orpossession of firearms or ammunition by the defendant.(7)The restraining order shall be issued on a form prescribed by theAdministrative Office of the Courts and may be lifted upon application of thestalking victim to the court which granted the order.(8)Within twenty-four (24) hours of entry of a restraining order or entry of an orderrescinding a restraining order, the circuit clerk shall forward a copy of the orderto the Law Information Network of Kentucky (LINK).(9)A restraining order issued under this section shall be enforced in any county ofthe Commonwealth. Law enforcement officers acting in good faith in enforcinga restraining order shall be immune from criminal and civil liability.(10)A violation by the defendant of an order issued pursuant to this section shall bea Class A misdemeanor. Nothing in this section shall preclude the filing of acriminal complaint for stalking based on the same act which is the basis for theviolation of the restraining order.</text><history>Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 46, effective January 1, 2016. --Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44794</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>