<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.9-075</section_number><catch_line>Complaints filed against licensees -- Investigative powers of commissioner. </catch_line><order_by>9-075</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person aggrieved by the conduct of a licensee under this subtitle in connection with the licensee's regulated activities may file a written complaint with the commissioner who may investigate the complaint. </section><section prefix="2">In the course of the investigation initiated by a complaint or by the commissioner, the commissioner may: <section prefix="a">Subpoena witnesses; </section><section prefix="b">Administer oaths; </section><section prefix="c">Examine any individual under oath; and </section><section prefix="d">Compel the production of records, books, papers, contracts, or other documents relevant to the investigation. </section></section><section prefix="3">If any person fails to testify or to comply with a subpoena from the commissioner under this section, the commissioner may petition any court of competent jurisdiction for enforcement. </section><section prefix="4">The license of any licensee under this subtitle who fails to comply with a subpoena of the commissioner may be suspended pending compliance with the subpoena. </section><section prefix="5">The commissioner shall have administrative power to investigate all complaints filed by any person if the complaints are not criminal in nature and if they relate to the check cashing or the deferred deposit service business. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 807, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 98, sec. 20, effective January 1, 2010. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 601, sec. 12, effective April 14, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 368.075. </former-codification><lrc-note> (7/12/2006).  In accordance with 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, secs. 38 and 39, this statute has been renumbered as a section of the Kentucky Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286, and KRS references within this statute have been adjusted to conform with the 2006 renumbering of that code. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:13</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14910</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>