<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="210" order_by="210">STATE AND REGIONAL MENTAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>210.770</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 210.770 to 210.795.     </catch_line><order_by>770</order_by><text>As used in KRS 210.770 to 210.795, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Mental impairment" includes an intellectual disability, organic brain syndrome, emotional or mental illness, and specific learning disabilities; </section><section prefix="2">"Person with a disability" means someone with a physical or mental impairment and includes individuals who have a record or history of an impairment, or are regarded as having a physical or mental impairment that substantially limits one (1) or more major life activities; </section><section prefix="3">"Physical impairment" means any physiological disorder or corrective, cosmetic disfigurement, or an anatomical loss affecting one (1) or more of the following body systems: neurological, musculo-skeletal, special sense organs, respiratory including speech organs, cardiovascular, reproductive, digestive, genito-urinary, hemic and lymphatic, skin, and endocrine; </section><section prefix="4">"Substantial limitation of a major life activity" includes limiting such things as walking, talking, seeing, hearing, caring for oneself, or working; </section><section prefix="5">"Hart-Supported Living Program" means grants which provide a broad category of highly flexible, individualized services which, when combined with natural unpaid or other eligible paid supports, provide the necessary assistance to do the following: <section prefix="a">Provide the support necessary to enable a person who is disabled to live in a home of the person's choice which is typical of those living arrangements in which persons without disabilities reside; </section><section prefix="b">Encourage the individual's integrated participation in the community with persons who are members of the general citizenry; </section><section prefix="c">Promote the individual's rights and autonomy; </section><section prefix="d">Enhance the individual's skills and competences in living in the community; and </section><section prefix="e">Enable the individual's acceptance in the community by promoting home ownership or leasing arrangements in the name of the individual or the individual's family or guardian; </section></section><section prefix="6">"Hart-Supported Living Program" does not include any services that support the following arrangements: <section prefix="a">Segregated living models such as any housing situation which physically or socially isolates people with disabilities from general citizens of the community; </section><section prefix="b">Segregated programs or activities which physically or socially isolate people with disabilities from general citizens of the community; </section><section prefix="c">Congregate living models such as any housing situation which groups individuals with disabilities as an enclave within an integrated setting; </section><section prefix="d">Any model where the individual, as an adult, does not have maximum control of the home environment commensurate with the individual's disabilities; and </section><section prefix="e">Any single living unit where more than three (3) people with disabilities live; </section></section><section prefix="7">"Hart-Supported Living Council" means a supported living council appointed by the Governor and recognized by the secretary; and </section><section prefix="8">"Hart-supported living services" include but are not limited to: <section prefix="a">Hart-supported living community resource developers; </section><section prefix="b">Homemaker services; </section><section prefix="c">Personal care services; </section><section prefix="d">In-home training and home management assistance; </section><section prefix="e">Start-up grants; </section><section prefix="f">Transportation; </section><section prefix="g">Home modifications; </section><section prefix="h">Adaptive and therapeutic equipment; and </section><section prefix="i">Facilitation by an independent and trained facilitator to develop and implement individualized life planning. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 95, effective July 12, 2012; and ch. 158, sec. 41, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 261, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note>(7/12/2012). This statute was amended by 2012 Ky. Acts chs. 146 and 158. Where these Acts are not in conflict, they have been codified together. Where a conflict exists, Acts ch. 146, which was last enacted by the General Assembly, prevails under KRS 446.250. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44641</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>