<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">A AUTOMATED MOTOR VEHICLE REGISTRATION SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>186A.250</section_number><catch_line>Suspension or revocation of title -- Conditions and methods for action. </catch_line><order_by>250</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department of Vehicle Regulation shall suspend or revoke a certificate of title, after giving notice and providing a reasonable opportunity for the holder to be heard, when authorized by any other provision of law, or, if it finds: <section prefix="a">The certificate of title was fraudulently procured or erroneously issued; or </section><section prefix="b">The vehicle has been scrapped, dismantled, or destroyed. Suspension or revocation of a certificate of title does not, in itself, affect the validity of a security interest noted on it. </section></section><section prefix="2">When the Department of Vehicle Regulation suspends or revokes a certificate of title, the owner or person in possession of it shall, immediately upon receiving notice of the suspension or revocation, mail or deliver the certificate to the Department of Vehicle Regulation. </section><section prefix="3">The department shall promptly notify the Department of Kentucky State Police of the suspension or revocation of any certificate of title. </section><section prefix="4">Any peace officer shall seize and impound any certificate of title which has been suspended or revoked except when such document is in the custody of the Department of Vehicle Regulation or the Department of Kentucky State Police. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 205, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 47, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6186</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>