<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.7882</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky educational excellence scholarship moneys to be awarded to students enrolled in comprehensive transition and postsecondary program.   </catch_line><order_by>7882</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding any other statute to the contrary, a student shall be eligible for a Kentucky educational excellence scholarship who: <section prefix="a"><section prefix="1">Received an alternative high school diploma described in KRS 158.140(2)(b) after June 30, 2012; or </section><section prefix="2">Attended a Kentucky public high school after June 30, 2008, and is a student with an intellectual disability as defined in 34 C.F.R. sec. 668.231; and </section></section><section prefix="b">Enrolls in a comprehensive transition and postsecondary program at a participating institution located in Kentucky. </section></section><section prefix="2">A student enrolled in credit-bearing or non-credit-bearing courses as part of a comprehensive transition and postsecondary program shall receive: <section prefix="a">Two hundred fifty dollars ($250) for enrollment in at least six (6) hours in an academic term; and </section><section prefix="b">One hundred twenty-five dollars ($125) for enrollment in less than six (6) hours in an academic term. </section></section><section prefix="3">A student shall be eligible for a scholarship under this section for a maximum of eight (8) academic terms. </section><section prefix="4">The authority shall promulgate administrative regulations establishing the procedures for making awards under this section. </section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 42, sec. 4, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42081</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>