<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="177" order_by="177">STATE AND FEDERAL HIGHWAYS -- LIMITED ACCESS FACILITIES -- TURNPIKES -- ROAD BONDS -- BILLBOARDS -- RECYCLERS </unit></structure><section_number>177.060</section_number><catch_line>Payment for right-of-way. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as otherwise provided in this section and in KRS 177.070, all cost of acquiring any necessary land or right-of-way for primary road purposes and all damages incurred shall be paid by the county. </section><section prefix="2">Temporary rights-of-way and private surfaced roads, other than those owned by the county, which are acquired for primary road purposes shall be paid for by the state. </section><section prefix="3">When a highway has been located by the department and a right-of-way procured by the county and accepted by the department, any additional right of way required by the department as a result of a change in the highway may be acquired by the department and shall be paid for by the state unless it is a road owned by the county. </section><section prefix="4">The cost of acquiring right-of-way for initial construction of industrial access roads, state park access roads and other roads the construction of which would best serve the interests of the Commonwealth in promoting economic and industrial growth shall be paid by the state. </section></text><history>Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 163, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4356t-7. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5249</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>