<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">BUDGET AND FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION </unit></structure><section_number>45.590</section_number><catch_line>Exemptions. </catch_line><order_by>590</order_by><text>A contractor or subcontractor otherwise subject to the provisions of KRS 45.570 is exempt as to any affirmative action or reporting requirements if: <section prefix="1">The contract or subcontract awarded is in the amount of five hundred thousand dollars ($500,000) or less, and the amount of the contract is not a subterfuge to avoid compliance with the provisions of KRS 45.560 to 45.640; </section><section prefix="2">The contractor or subcontractor utilizes the services of fewer than eight (8) employees during the course of the contract; </section><section prefix="3">The contractor or subcontractor employs only family members or relatives; </section><section prefix="4">The contractor or subcontractor employs only persons having a direct ownership interest in the business, and such interest is not a subterfuge to avoid compliance with the provisions of KRS 45.560 to 45.640; or </section><section prefix="5">The subcontract is below the second-tier level of contracts. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 173, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 173, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 5, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 183, provides, "The specific textual provisions of Sections 1 to 178 of this Act which reflect amendments made to those sections by 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137 shall be deemed effective as of June 26, 2007, and those provisions are hereby made expressly retroactive to that date, with the remainder of the text of those sections being unaffected by the provisions of this section." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22286</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>