<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIX" order_by="39">PROVISIONAL REMEDIES, ENFORCEMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="425" order_by="425">PROVISIONAL REMEDIES </unit></structure><section_number>425.506</section_number><catch_line>Attachment or garnishment of earnings -- Priority -- Order. </catch_line><order_by>506</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An order of garnishment of earnings, as defined in KRS 427.005, shall create a lien on all nonexempt earnings earned during the pay period in which the order is served on the employer and during those succeeding pay periods which may be designated by the order. </section><section prefix="2">Orders of attachment or garnishment of earnings shall have priority according to the date of service on the employer, each inferior order taking effect as if served at the commencement of the next succeeding pay period not subject to a prior order; provided that no creditor shall cause two (2) orders to be served on the employer against the same employee in the same pay period. </section><section prefix="3">The order shall be served on the employer in triplicate and shall have printed thereon an explanation of subsections (1) and (2) of this section, the percentage of the disposable earnings, as defined in KRS 427.005, exempted from the order by subsection (2) of KRS 427.010, and the percentage to be forwarded to the court. </section><section prefix="4">The order shall have printed thereon the following directions to the employer: <section prefix="a">That a copy of the order shall be delivered to the employee, a copy retained by the employer for his records, and a copy returned by the employer to the court. </section><section prefix="b">That on the reverse side of the court copy shall be stated, under oath by the employer, the gross amount of earnings and the nonexempt amount of disposable earnings for the designated pay periods subject to the order. If no funds are due, the reasons therefor shall be given. </section><section prefix="c">That the court copy of the order and the nonexempt amount of disposable earnings shall be forwarded to the court. </section></section></text><history>Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 103, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 91, sec. 31. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1988 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=18419</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>