<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.802</section_number><catch_line>Office of Career and Technical Education -- Kentucky Board of Education.   </catch_line><order_by>802</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Office of Career and Technical Education is hereby created within the Department of Education. The office shall consist of those administrative bodies and employees provided by or appointed by the commissioner of education pursuant to KRS 156.010. </section><section prefix="2">The commissioner of education may appoint an assistant, pursuant to KRS 156.010, and delegate authority to the assistant regarding the Office of Career and Technical Education. </section><section prefix="3">The Department of Education shall have the responsibility for all administrative functions of the state in relation to the management, control, and operation of state-operated secondary area vocational education and technology centers. When appropriate, the Department of Education shall provide education training programs through contracts with private business and industries. These programs may be on a shared cost basis or on a total cost recovery basis. </section><section prefix="4">The commissioner of education shall have the authority to enter into agreements or contracts with other government or education agencies, including local school districts, in order to carry out services under the office's jurisdiction. </section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">Secondary area vocational education and technology centers shall be operated in compliance with program standards established by the Kentucky Board of Education. Principals, counselors, and teaching staff shall meet the qualifications and certification standards for all secondary vocational personnel as established by the Educational Professional Standards Board. </section><section prefix="b">The Kentucky Board of Education shall be the eligible agency solely designated for the purpose of developing and approving state plans required by state or federal laws and regulations as prerequisites to receiving federal funds for vocational-technical or technology education. The Kentucky Board of Education shall involve representatives from all eligible recipient categories in the development of the required plans. </section><section prefix="c">In accordance with 20 U.S.C. sec. 2302(12), the Kentucky Board of Education is hereby designated to be the "eligible agency" that is the sole state agency responsible for the administration of vocational and technical education and the supervision of the administration of vocational and technical education. </section></section><section prefix="6"><section prefix="a">Except for the duties that the Kentucky Board of Education must retain pursuant to 20 U.S.C. sec. 2341, the Kentucky Board of Education shall be authorized to delegate all of the other duties and responsibilities of the eligible agency to the Office of Career and Technical Education within the Department of Education, including but not limited to the administration, operation, and supervision of the Perkins program and the authority to receive, hold, and disburse funds awarded under the state plan. </section><section prefix="b">The Kentucky Board of Education shall delegate to the Kentucky Workforce Investment Board the state leadership activities referred to in 20 U.S.C. sec. 2344 to be conducted in accordance with the required and permissible uses of funds specified in the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 and subsequent amendments thereto. The maximum amount of funds allowed by 20 U.S.C. sec. 2322(a)(2) shall be reserved and made available for state leadership activities. </section></section><section prefix="7">The commissioner of education shall be permitted to enter into memorandums of agreement with individuals on a year-to-year basis to fill positions in hard-to-find teaching specialties. The agreements and compensation for hard-to-find teaching specialties shall be approved by the commissioner of education and shall not be subject to the provisions of KRS Chapter 45A. All agreements shall be filed with the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet. </section><section prefix="8">The commissioner of education shall, from time to time, prepare or cause to be prepared any bulletins, programs, outlines of courses, placards, and courses of study deemed useful in the promotion of the interests of technical and vocational education. </section></text><history> Repealed, reenacted, renumbered, and amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 3, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 14, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006; and ch. 211, sec. 22, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 7, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 44, effective May 30, 1997. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 469, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 470, sec. 2, effective July 1, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2006).  This section was amended by 2006 Ky. Acts chs. 151 and 211. Where these Acts are not in conflict, they have been codified together. Where a conflict exists, Acts ch. 211, which was last enacted by the General Assembly, prevails under KRS 446.250.  (7/12/2006).  2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 171, instructs the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in the Act, as it confirms the reorganization of the executive branch and establishment of the Education Cabinet. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><former-codification>KRS 151B.025. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42153</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>