<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.45-020</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for subtitle. </catch_line><order_by>45-020</order_by><text>As used in this subtitle: <section prefix="1">"Commissioner" means the commissioner of the Kentucky Department of Insurance or the insurance supervisor of another state; </section><section prefix="2">"Completed operations liability" means liability arising out of the installation, maintenance, or repair of any product at a site which is not owned or controlled by: <section prefix="a">Any person who performs that work; or </section><section prefix="b">Any person who hires an independent contractor to perform that work, but shall include liability for activities which are completed or abandoned before the date of the occurrence giving rise to the liability; </section></section><section prefix="3">"Domicile," for the purposes of determining the state in which a purchasing group is domiciled, means: <section prefix="a">For a corporation, the state in which the purchasing group is incorporated; and </section><section prefix="b">For an unincorporated entity, the state of its principal place of business; </section></section><section prefix="4">"Hazardous financial condition" means a condition in which, based on its present or reasonably anticipated financial condition, a risk retention group, although not yet financially impaired or insolvent, is unlikely to be able: <section prefix="a">To meet obligations to policyholders with respect to known claims and reasonably anticipated claims; or </section><section prefix="b">To pay other obligations in the normal course of business; </section></section><section prefix="5">"Insurance" means primary insurance, excess insurance, reinsurance, surplus lines insurance, and any other arrangement for shifting and distributing risks which is determined to be insurance under the laws of this state; </section><section prefix="6">"Liability": <section prefix="a">Means legal liability for damages (including costs of defense, legal costs and fees, and other claims expenses) because of injuries to other persons, damage to their property, or other damage or loss to such other persons resulting from or arising out of: <section prefix="1">Any business (whether profit or nonprofit), trade, product, services (including professional services), premises, or operations; or </section><section prefix="2">Any activity of any state or local government, or any agency or political subdivision thereof; but </section></section><section prefix="b">Does not include personal risk liability or an employer's liability with respect to its employees other than legal liability under the Federal Employers' Liability Act (45 U.S.C. secs. 51 et seq.); </section></section><section prefix="7">"Personal risk liability" means liability for damages because of injury to any person, damage to property, or other loss or damage arising from any personal, familial, or household responsibilities or activities, rather than from responsibilities or activities referred to in subsection (6) of this section; </section><section prefix="8">"Plan of operation or a feasibility study" means an analysis which presents the expected activities and results of a risk retention group, including, at a minimum: <section prefix="a">Information sufficient to verify that its members are engaged in businesses or activities similar or related with respect to the liability to which such members are exposed by virtue of any related, similar, or common business, trade, product, services, premises, or operations; </section><section prefix="b">For each state in which it intends to operate, the coverages, deductibles, coverage limits, rates, and rating classification system for each kind of insurance the group intends to offer; </section><section prefix="c">Historical and expected loss experience of the proposed members and national experience of similar exposures to the extent that this experience is reasonably available; </section><section prefix="d">Pro forma financial statements and projections; </section><section prefix="e">Appropriate opinions by a qualified, independent casualty actuary, including a determination of minimum premium or participation levels required to commence operations and to prevent a hazardous financial condition; </section><section prefix="f">Identification of management, underwriting, and claim procedures, marketing methods, managerial oversight methods, and investment policies; and </section><section prefix="g">Such other matters as may be prescribed by the commissioner for liability insurance companies authorized by the insurance laws of the state in which the risk retention group is chartered; </section></section><section prefix="9">"Product liability" means liability for damages because of any personal injury, death, emotional harm, consequential economic damage, or property damage (including damages resulting from the loss of use of property) arising out of the manufacture, design, importation, distribution, packaging, labeling, lease, or sale of a product, but does not include the liability of any person for those damages if the product involved was in the possession of such person when the incident giving rise to the claim occurred; </section><section prefix="10">"Purchasing group" means any group which: <section prefix="a">Has as one (1) of its purposes the purchase of liability insurance on a group basis; </section><section prefix="b">Purchases such insurance only for its group members and only to cover their similar or related liability exposure, as described in paragraph (c) of this subsection; </section><section prefix="c">Is composed of members whose businesses or activities are similar or related with respect to the liability to which members are exposed by virtue of any related, similar, or common business, trade, product, services, premises, or operations; and </section><section prefix="d">Is domiciled in any state; </section></section><section prefix="11">"Risk retention group" means any corporation or other limited liability association: <section prefix="a">Whose primary activity consists of assuming and spreading all, or any portion, of the liability exposure of its group members; </section><section prefix="b">Which is organized for the primary purpose of conducting the activity described under paragraph (a) of this subsection; </section><section prefix="c">Which: <section prefix="1">Is chartered and licensed as a liability insurance company and authorized to engage in the business of insurance under the laws of any state; or </section><section prefix="2">Before January 1, 1985, was chartered or licensed and authorized to engage in the business of insurance under the laws of Bermuda or the Cayman Islands and, before such date, had certified to the commissioner of at least one (1) state that it satisfied the capitalization requirements of such state, except that any such group shall be considered to be a risk retention group only if it has engaged in business continuously since such date and only for the purpose of continuing to provide insurance to cover product liability or completed operations liability (as such terms were defined under the Product Liability Risk Retention Act of 1981 prior to the date of the enactment of the Liability Risk Retention Act of 1986); </section></section><section prefix="d">Which does not exclude any person from membership in the group solely to provide for members of such group a competitive advantage over such person; </section><section prefix="e">Which: <section prefix="1">Has as its owners only persons who comprise the membership of the risk retention group and who are provided insurance by such group; or </section><section prefix="2">Has as its sole owner an organization which has as its members only persons who comprise the membership of the risk retention group and as its owners only persons who comprise the membership of the risk retention group and who are provided insurance by such group; </section></section><section prefix="f">Whose members are engaged in businesses or activities similar or related with respect to the liability to which such members are exposed by virtue of any related, similar, or common business, trade, product, services, premises, or operations; and </section><section prefix="g">Whose activities do not include the provision of insurance other than: <section prefix="1">Liability insurance for assuming and spreading all or any portion of the liability of its group members; and </section><section prefix="2">Reinsurance with respect to the liability of any other risk retention group or any members of such other group which is engaged in businesses or activities so that such group or member meets the requirement described in paragraph (f) of this subsection from membership in the risk retention group and which provides such reinsurance; and </section></section><section prefix="h">The name of which includes the phrase "risk retention group"; and </section></section><section prefix="12">"State" means any state of the United States or the District of Columbia. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1573, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:00</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30155</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>