<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="146" order_by="146">NATURAL RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>146.110</section_number><catch_line>Powers and functions of Soil and Water Conservation Commission. </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commission shall have the general power to take any action it may consider necessary or proper to assist soil and water conservation districts, agricultural districts, or watershed conservancy districts in carrying out their functions, powers, duties, and programs in accordance with the provisions of KRS Chapter 262, and for such purpose it may furnish financial and other aid to the districts and perform such services for them at their request as may be possible under available appropriations and resources; </section><section prefix="2">The commission has all the powers and duties formerly possessed by the State Soil Conservation Committee; </section><section prefix="3">The commission shall take any action it may consider necessary or proper in order to discharge for the state any of the state's functions, responsibilities, or duties relating to flood control, drainage, and other activities with respect to the conservation, utilization, or control of soil or water resources; </section><section prefix="4">The commission may promulgate those administrative regulations as may be necessary to the performance of its duties and may enter into and execute any agreements or legal instruments that may be necessary for these purposes, and it shall have the authority to acquire necessary supplies, materials, and equipment, and warehousing, servicing, and maintenance facilities for equipment. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 241, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 58. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 68, Art. XIV, sec. 3. -- Created 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 52, sec. 4. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29291</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>