<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="345" order_by="345">COLLECTIVE BARGAINING FOR FIREFIGHTERS </unit></structure><section_number>345.030</section_number><catch_line>Employees' right to organize for the purpose of collective bargaining. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Firefighters of a city of the first class shall have, and shall be protected in the exercise of, the right of self-organization, to form, join, or assist any labor organization, to bargain collectively through representatives of their own choosing on questions of wages, hours, and other conditions of employment free from interference, restraint, or coercion. </section><section prefix="2">Labor organizations designated by the State Labor Relations Board as the representative of the majority of firefighters in an appropriate unit or recognized by a public employer as the representative of the majority of employees in an appropriate unit shall be the exclusive representative for the employees of such unit for the purpose of collective bargaining with respect to rates of pay, wages, hours, and other conditions of employment. </section><section prefix="3">Labor organizations recognized by a public employer as the exclusive representative or so designated in accordance with the provisions of this chapter shall be responsible for representing the interest of all firefighters in the unit without discrimination. </section></text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 144, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 4. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32680</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>