<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="160" order_by="160">SCHOOL DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>160.291</section_number><catch_line>Manner of payment of salaries to school employees -- Pay for extra duties or services -- Fringe benefits program. </catch_line><order_by>291</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All school employees working on a continuing, regular basis, shall be paid regularly, on dates determined by the employing board of education, during the school year or during the fiscal year for twelve (12) month employees, the provisions of KRS 337.020 notwithstanding. The gross salary received on each pay date will be an amount equal to the school employee's annual salary divided by the number of pay dates, except a local board of education shall pay an employee any remaining salary owed prior to the end of the fiscal year upon completion of the employee's responsibilities or duties if so notified by the employee. </section><section prefix="2">Salary amounts shall be paid on the prescribed pay dates without deduction for days on which schools were closed; provided, however, any time not worked for which pay is received must be made up prior to the end of that current school year, or pay so received shall be withheld from the final salary payment of that school year. </section><section prefix="3">Gross Salary payments under subsection (1) of this section need not, but may, include pay for extra duties or services. Payment for extra duties or services must be paid pursuant to a payment plan adopted by the board of education prior to the beginning of the school year. The board of education may also adopt a plan for providing a program of fringe benefits to its employees. </section><section prefix="4">All payments made for salaries, extra duties, and fringe benefits by the board of education under the authority of this section are deemed to be for services rendered and for the benefit of the common schools; the payments do not affect the eligibility of any school system to participate in the public school fund as established in KRS Chapter 157. Nor shall any individual board member or administrator be held liable where additional payments for such service become necessary. Provided, however, that nothing in this section authorizes or requires the payment of salaries to personnel when schools are closed as a result of a strike or other work stoppage or when schools are open and personnel fail to render services. No part of this section shall be law if any part is declared unconstitutional. </section><section prefix="5">Subsection (2) of this section does not apply to those employed on a twelve (12) month basis. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 177, sec. 1, effective March 27, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 174, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. IV, sec. 229, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 341, sec. 1, effective June 15, 1980. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 49, sec. 1, effective March 28, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> March 27, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3701</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>