<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="217" order_by="217">FOODS, DRUGS, AND POISONS </unit></structure><section_number>217.998</section_number><catch_line>Penalties for violation of KRS 217.542 to 217.630. </catch_line><order_by>998</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person who violates any of the provisions of KRS 217.542 to 217.630 or who fails to perform any duties imposed by those sections, or who violates any determination or order of the department promulgated pursuant thereto, shall be liable to a civil penalty of not to exceed the sum of one thousand dollars ($1,000) for said violation, and an additional civil penalty of not to exceed one thousand dollars ($1,000) for each day during which such violation continues, and in addition, may be enjoined from continuing such violations as hereinafter provided in this section. Such penalties shall be recoverable in an action brought in the name of the Commonwealth of Kentucky by the Attorney General. </section><section prefix="2">It shall be the duty of the Attorney General, upon the request of the department, to bring an action for the recovery of the penalties hereinabove provided for, and to bring an action for an injunction against any person violating or threatening to violate any provision of KRS 217.542 to 217.630, or violating or threatening to violate any order or determination of the department promulgated pursuant thereto. In any such action any finding of the department shall be prima facie evidence of the fact or facts found therein. </section><section prefix="3">Any person who shall willfully violate any of the provisions of KRS 217.542 to 217.630 or any determination or order of the department promulgated pursuant to those sections which have become final shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and upon conviction thereof shall be punished by a fine of not less than one hundred dollars ($100) nor more than one thousand dollars ($1,000) or by imprisonment for a term of not more than one (1) year, or by both fine and imprisonment for each separate violation. Each day upon which such violation occurs shall constitute a separate violation. </section></text><history>Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 200, sec. 15. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9500</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>