<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="242" order_by="242">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LOCAL OPTION </unit></structure><section_number>242.195</section_number><catch_line>Vote for prohibition in precinct of a city with population of 12,000 or more to be applied precinct-wide -- Exemptions.   </catch_line><order_by>195</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding KRS 242.125, when the voters of any precinct located either partially or entirely within a qualifying city make KRS 242.220 to 242.430 apply to the precinct, the provisions of KRS 242.220 to 242.430 shall apply throughout the entire territory of the precinct, except in any area exempted under subsection (2) of this section. For purposes of this section, a "qualifying city" means a city that contains a total population of twelve thousand (12,000) or greater within its municipal boundaries, based on the most recent decennial census. </section><section prefix="2">The provisions of KRS 242.220 to 242.430 shall not apply to any of the following that existed in a precinct prior to the submission of a petition under KRS 242.020 for that precinct: <section prefix="a">An entertainment destination center project meeting the qualifications of KRS 148.853(2)(b); </section><section prefix="b">A theme restaurant destination attraction project meeting the qualifications of KRS 148.853(2)(c); or </section><section prefix="c">Within the established boundaries of a district of special interest created by the city pursuant to the provisions of KRS 100.203(1)(e) that: <section prefix="1">Is designated as an entertainment district; and </section><section prefix="2">Has a minimum direct investment by the city government in infrastructure or other public space of at least five million dollars ($5,000,000). </section></section></section><section prefix="3">The boundaries of a district of special interest meeting the qualifications of subsection (2)(c) of this section shall not be enlarged or modified to include any additional territory at any time after the submission of a petition under KRS 242.020 unless the voters of the precinct do not make KRS 242.220 to 242.430 apply to the precinct. </section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 8, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41802</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>