<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.577</section_number><catch_line>Testing applicants for initial operator's license or initial instruction permit -- Restrictions or driving privileges based on visual acuity test -- Certain drivers restricted to use of bioptic telescopic devices. </catch_line><order_by>577</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All persons applying for an initial operator's license or an initial instruction permit shall submit to a test of visual acuity and visual field at the time of application. </section><section prefix="2">Persons whose visual acuity is 20/40 or better without corrective lenses shall not have a restriction placed on their driving privileges. Persons whose visual acuity is 20/40 or better with corrective lenses shall have their driving privileges restricted to mandate the use of the corrective lenses. If a person fails to meet a 20/40 visual acuity standard, the Department of Kentucky State Police shall refer the person to a vision specialist for examination. </section><section prefix="3">A person referred to a vision specialist by the Department of Kentucky State Police under subsection (2) of this section whose visual acuity is 20/60 or better shall be eligible to test for an instruction permit or operator's license. If corrective lenses were prescribed by the vision specialist, the person's driving privileges shall be restricted to mandate the use of the corrective lenses. </section><section prefix="4">Persons who meet the requirements of KRS 186.578 and are issued operator's licenses under KRS 186.579 shall have their driving privileges restricted to the use of a bioptic telescopic device. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 198, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 2, effective January 1, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6085</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>