<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.016</section_number><catch_line>Abolition of employment positions -- Reorganization. </catch_line><order_by>016</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Effective at the close of business on June 30, 1991, all employment positions in the Department of Education shall be abolished and the employment of all employees in the positions shall be terminated. Employees whose employment has been terminated under the provisions of this section shall have the same reemployment rights granted career employees by KRS Chapter 18A, except these employees shall not have priority status on the register for reemployment in the Department of Education. This shall not be construed as prohibiting the Department of Education from rehiring an employee whose employment has been terminated. </section><section prefix="2">After a comprehensive study of the Department of Education and the goals and duties of the commissioner of education and the department as established under the Kentucky Education Reform Act of 1990, 1990 Ky. Acts Ch. 476, the commissioner shall reorganize the department, effective July 1, 1991. The reorganization of the department shall incorporate a strong orientation toward providing technical assistance to school districts. After the comprehensive study, which shall include consultations with current department employees, the commissioner shall establish all positions in the department and set the qualifications for the positions, effective no earlier than July 1, 1991. The commissioner may rehire any department employees whose employment is terminated at the close of business on June 30, 1991, under this section. </section><section prefix="3">This section is in response to a specific court decision demanding specific actions of the General Assembly. The actions authorized by this section are designed for a single time use only in response to the education situation. The actions authorized by this section shall not extend to any other situation or circumstance. </section></text><history>Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. II, sec. 42, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3091</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>