<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="150" order_by="150">FISH AND WILDLIFE RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>150.355</section_number><catch_line>Ferrets. </catch_line><order_by>355</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall use ferrets in hunting. No person shall keep a ferret which was born in the wild as a pet or for any purpose, unless he has procured a ferret permit from the commissioner. A permit must be obtained within ten (10) days after the person acquires possession of a ferret and one (1) permit shall entitle the holder to keep any number of ferrets. If the owner of any ferret uses it contrary to the provisions of this chapter, the commissioner may revoke his permit and confiscate all of his ferrets. Each use of a ferret in hunting shall constitute a separate offense. </section><section prefix="2">The provisions of subsection (1) of this section shall not apply to a ferret which has been born and raised in captivity nor to a ferret born and raised in captivity which was obtained from a pet store or private vendor. Except for the prohibition on using a ferret for hunting, no permit shall be necessary to keep a ferret which was born and raised in captivity and a ferret born and raised in captivity shall be exempt from regulation under this chapter or administrative regulations promulgated thereunder. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 356, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 200, sec. 47, effective June 19, 1952. -- Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 68, sec. 36. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2003</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>