<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="217" order_by="217">B FERTILIZER AND PESTICIDE USE AND APPLICATION </unit></structure><section_number>217B.185</section_number><catch_line>Pesticide sales agent's license -- Application -- Fee -- Renewal -- Sale or distribution of pesticides restricted to licenses. </catch_line><order_by>185</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The department shall establish a licensure program for pesticide sales agents. The department shall require an applicant for licensure to show upon examination that the applicant possesses adequate knowledge concerning the proper use and application of pesticides. </section><section prefix="2">Application for a pesticide sales agent license shall be in the form and shall contain information prescribed by the department. Each application shall be accompanied by a fee of five dollars ($5). All licenses issued under this section shall expire on December 31 of the year issued. The license for a pesticide sales agent may be renewed annually upon application to the department, accompanied by a fee of five dollars ($5) for each license, on or before the first day of January of the calendar year for which the license is issued. </section><section prefix="3">The department shall issue to each applicant who meets the requirements of this section a license that entitles the applicant to hold himself or herself out as a pesticide sales agent. </section><section prefix="4">No person shall hold himself or herself out as a pesticide sales agent unless that person is licensed as provided for in this section. </section><section prefix="5">No person shall make recommendations for the use or application of pesticides unless that person is licensed as provided for in this section. </section><section prefix="6">No person shall sell or distribute restricted use pesticides to the final user unless that person is licensed as provided for in this section. </section><section prefix="7">No license shall be issued unless the applicant holds a valid certification within this category. </section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 11, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9545</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>