<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="407" order_by="407">INTERSTATE SUPPORT ENFORCEMENT </unit></structure><section_number>407.5701Definitions</section_number><catch_line>for Article 7.   </catch_line><order_by>5701Definitions</order_by><text>In this Article: <section prefix="1">"Application" means a request under the Convention by an obligee or obligor, or on behalf of a child, made through a central authority for assistance from another central authority; </section><section prefix="2">"Central authority" means the entity designated by the United States or a foreign country described in KRS 407.5101(5)(d) to perform the functions specified in the Convention; </section><section prefix="3">"Convention support order" means a support order of a tribunal of a foreign country described in KRS 407.5101(5)(d); </section><section prefix="4">"Direct request" means a petition filed by an individual in a tribunal of this state in a proceeding involving an obligee, obligor, or child residing outside the United States; </section><section prefix="5">"Foreign central authority" means the entity designated by a foreign country described in KRS 407.5101(5)(d) to perform the functions specified in the Convention; </section><section prefix="6">"Foreign support agreement": <section prefix="a">Means an agreement for support in a record that: <section prefix="1">Is enforceable as a support order in the country of origin; </section><section prefix="2">Has been: <section prefix="a">Formally drawn up or registered as an authentic instrument by a foreign tribunal; or </section><section prefix="b">Authenticated by, or concluded, registered, or filed with a foreign tribunal; and </section></section><section prefix="3">May be reviewed and modified by a foreign tribunal; and </section></section><section prefix="b">Includes a maintenance arrangement or authentic instrument under the Convention; and </section></section><section prefix="7">"United States central authority" means the Secretary of the United States Department of Health and Human Services. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 55, effective June 24, 2015. -- Contingent effective date repealed 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 20, effective March 23, 1998. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 365, sec. 58, effective upon contingency. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44131</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>