<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="229" order_by="229">BOXING AND WRESTLING </unit></structure><section_number>229.155</section_number><catch_line>Executive director -- Duties -- Interagency agreements. </catch_line><order_by>155</order_by><text><section prefix="1">To carry out the functions relating to the authority's duties and responsibilities and to afford the full experience and resources of the Public Protection Cabinet, after revenue of five hundred thousand dollars ($500,000) is generated in two (2) consecutive fiscal years by the authority, the Governor may appoint an executive director who shall serve at the pleasure of the Governor. The Governor shall set the qualifications and salary for the position of executive director under the provisions of KRS 64.640. The secretary of the Public Protection Cabinet shall act as executive director until the fiscal requirement is met. </section><section prefix="2">The executive director shall employ sufficient regulatory staff for the authority that shall be responsible for the day-to-day operations of the authority, including but not limited to the following: <section prefix="a">Complying with regulations; </section><section prefix="b">Issuing licenses and permits; </section><section prefix="c">Establishing appropriate organizational structures; </section><section prefix="d">Carrying out policy and program directives of the authority; and </section><section prefix="e">Performing all other duties and responsibilities as assigned. </section></section><section prefix="3">With approval of the authority, the executive director and regulatory staff may enter into agreements with any state agency or political subdivision of the state, any postsecondary education institution, or any other person or entity to enlist assistance to implement the duties and responsibilities of the authority. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 442, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 91, sec. 16, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 5, effective June 20, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10795</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>