<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="136" order_by="136">CORPORATION AND UTILITY TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>136.310Tax</section_number><catch_line>on and reports from foreign savings and loan associations, savings banks, and similar institutions.   </catch_line><order_by>310Tax</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every federally or state chartered savings and loan association, savings bank, and other similar institution authorized to transact business in this state, with property and payroll within and without this state, shall, during January of each year, file with the Department of Revenue a report containing information and in such form as the department may require. </section><section prefix="2">The Department of Revenue shall fix the fair cash value, as of January 1 of each year, of the capital attributable to Kentucky in each financial institution included in subsection (1) of this section. The methodology employed by the department shall be a three (3) step process as follows: <section prefix="a"><section prefix="1">The total value of deposits maintained in Kentucky less any amounts where the amount borrowed by a member equals or exceeds the amount deposited by that member shall be determined. </section><section prefix="2">The total value of deposits maintained in Kentucky shall be determined by the same method used for filing the summary of deposits report with the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation; </section></section><section prefix="b"><section prefix="1">The Kentucky apportioned value of capital shall be determined by including undivided profits, surplus, general reserves, and paid-up stock. </section><section prefix="2">For Agricultural Credit Associations chartered by the Farm Credit Administration, capital shall be computed by deducting the book value of the association's investment in any other wholly owned institution chartered by the Farm Credit Administration that is either subject to the tax imposed by KRS 136.300 or this section or that is exempt from state taxation by federal law. </section><section prefix="3">The Kentucky value of capital shall be determined by a fraction, the numerator of which is the receipts factor plus the outstanding loan balance factor plus the payroll factor, and the denominator of which is three (3); and </section></section><section prefix="c"><section prefix="1">The values determined in steps (a) and (b) of this subsection shall be added together to determine total Kentucky capital and then reduced by the influence of ownership in tax-exempt United States obligations to determine Kentucky taxable capital. </section><section prefix="2">The influence of tax-exempt United States obligations is to be determined from the reports of condition filed with the applicable supervisory agency as follows: the average amount of tax-exempt United States obligations for the calendar year, over the average amount of total assets for the calendar year multiplied by total Kentucky capital. </section><section prefix="3">The department shall immediately notify each institution of the value so fixed. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">The receipts factor specified in subsection (2)(b) of this section is a fraction, the numerator of which is all receipts derived from loans and other sources negotiated through offices or derived from customers in Kentucky, and the denominator of which is total business receipts for the preceding calendar year. </section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">The outstanding loan balance factor specified in subsection (2)(b) of this section is a fraction, the numerator of which is the average balance of outstanding loans negotiated from offices or made to customers in Kentucky, and the denominator of which is the average balance of all outstanding loans. </section><section prefix="b"><section prefix="1">The average outstanding loan balance is determined by adding the outstanding loan balance at the beginning of the preceding calendar year to the outstanding loan balance at the end of the preceding calendar year and dividing by two (2). </section><section prefix="2">If the yearly beginning balance and ending balance results in an inequitable factor, the average outstanding loan balance may be computed on a monthly average balance. </section></section></section><section prefix="5">The payroll factor specified in subsection (2)(b) of this section shall be determined for the preceding calendar year under the provisions of KRS 141.120(8)(b) and administrative regulations promulgated according to KRS Chapter 13A. </section><section prefix="6"><section prefix="a">By July 1 succeeding the filing of the report as provided in subsection (1) of this section, each financial institution included in subsection (1) of this section shall pay directly into the State Treasury a tax of one dollar ($1) for each one thousand dollars ($1,000) paid in on its Kentucky taxable capital as fixed in subsection (2)(c) of this section. </section><section prefix="b">The institution shall not be required to pay local taxes upon its capital stock, surplus, undivided profits, notes, mortgages, or other credits, and the tax provided by this section shall be in lieu of all taxes for state purposes on intangible property of the institution, nor shall any depositor of the institution be required to list his deposits for taxation under KRS 132.020. </section><section prefix="c">Failure to make reports and pay taxes as provided in this section shall subject the institution to the same penalties imposed for such failure on the part of the other corporations. </section></section><section prefix="7">If a financial institution included in subsection (1) of this section selects, it may deduct taxes imposed in subsection (6) of this section from the dividends paid or credited to a nonborrowing shareholder. </section><section prefix="8"><section prefix="a">Every Agricultural Credit Association chartered by the Farm Credit Administration being authorized to transact business in Kentucky but having no employees located within or without the state shall be subject to the same tax imposed pursuant to either KRS 136.300 or this section as that imposed upon its wholly owned Production Credit Association subsidiary. </section><section prefix="b">For purposes of computing Kentucky apportioned value of capital pursuant to subsection (2) of this section, those Agricultural Credit Associations subject to the tax imposed by this section shall utilize that Kentucky apportionment fraction computed and utilized by its wholly owned Production Credit Association subsidiary for the same report period. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 67, sec. 6, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 319, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 142, sec. 6, effective April 21, 2004. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 262, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 496, sec. 6, effective August 1, 1986. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 132. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 876d. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:01</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44479</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>