<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="315" order_by="315">PHARMACISTS AND PHARMACIES </unit></structure><section_number>315.518</section_number><catch_line>Application for license -- Fee -- Record retention -- Administrative regulations -- Confidentiality.   </catch_line><order_by>518</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A home medical equipment and services provider shall be licensed by the board under KRS 315.510 to 315.524 prior to engaging in providing home medical equipment and services in the Commonwealth. Each license application shall be accompanied by a reasonable fee prescribed by administrative regulation not to exceed two hundred dollars ($200) initially per year or increase more than twenty-five dollars ($25) per year up to a maximum of four hundred dollars ($400). Upon receipt of an application for a license to operate as a home medical equipment and services provider, the board shall issue a license if the provider meets the standards and requirements of this chapter and the administrative regulations of the board. </section><section prefix="2">Home medical equipment and services providers shall be required to maintain adequate records of all home medical equipment and services provided as established by administrative regulation by the board. Records shall be made available to agents of the board for inspection at reasonable times. The board may require by administrative regulation that home medical equipment and services providers periodically report to the board all home medical equipment and services provided. </section><section prefix="3">Failure to report to the board or willful submission of inaccurate information shall be grounds for disciplinary action under KRS 315.121. </section><section prefix="4">The board shall promulgate an administrative regulation pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A to specify the criteria for licensure. </section><section prefix="5">Pursuant to KRS 61.878, information provided by an applicant under this section and any related administrative regulation shall not be disclosed to any person or entity other than the board. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 73, sec. 5, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40280</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>