<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="121" order_by="121">CAMPAIGN FINANCE REGULATION </unit></structure><section_number>121.005</section_number><catch_line>Legislative findings on electronic storage and retrieval of campaign finance information. </catch_line><order_by>005</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The General Assembly finds and declares that: <section prefix="a">The intent of disclosure of campaign finance information is to make that information about the role of money in politics accessible to the public; </section><section prefix="b">The volume of campaign finance reports submitted each year to the state renders it virtually impossible, without the help of computer technology, to derive meaningful conclusions from the records; </section><section prefix="c">Computer automation is a necessary and effective means of transmitting, organizing, storing, and retrieving vast amounts of data submitted by candidates in election campaigns; and </section><section prefix="d">Although candidates are currently permitted to file campaign finance reports electronically if they so choose, very few candidates have chosen to do so, and therefore access to campaign finance data through electronic or on-line technology is limited. </section></section><section prefix="2">The General Assembly enacts this legislation to accomplish the following: <section prefix="a">To improve the existing system of electronic reporting and extend its usage to more candidates; </section><section prefix="b">To allow concerned persons easy, convenient, and timely access to campaign finance reports submitted to the state; </section><section prefix="c">To ease the burden on candidates and committees of tabulating, filing, and maintaining public records of financial activity; </section><section prefix="d">To strengthen both the disclosure and enforcement capabilities of the Registry of Election Finance; </section><section prefix="e">To cooperate in the standardization of reporting formats among states so that interstate as well as intrastate sources of political money can be known; </section><section prefix="f">To provide for a fully informed electorate; and </section><section prefix="g">To help restore public trust in the governmental and electoral institutions of this state. </section></section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 398, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:04</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27844</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>