<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">A URBAN-COUNTY GOVERNMENT </unit></structure><section_number>67A.220</section_number><catch_line>Executive unit established -- Personnel duties -- Control by civil service commission. </catch_line><order_by>220</order_by><text>An urban-county government may by comprehensive plan or ordinance establish an executive unit charged with personnel matters. In the event such a unit is established, the urban-county government shall by comprehensive plan or ordinance delegate to such unit, in addition to its regular functions not related to this statute, the initial performance of all or a part of the functions described as functions of the commission in KRS 67A.230 to 67A.250 and 67A.270, but no other sections hereof, except that in any event the decisions of the said unit shall be subject to review, amendment or change by the commission. In the case of the certification of lists of eligible applicants for employment, such lists may be prepared by the executive unit, but shall be submitted to the appointing authority only after approval of the commission; and in respect of all other matters delegated, periodic reports shall be made by the unit to the commission, not less than monthly, and any directions of the commission, or any proposed alterations or changes in the action of the unit shall be promptly complied with by the unit. The legislative body of the urban-county government, subject to its comprehensive plan, may from time to time, revoke such delegation of authority to the executive unit, and may establish reasonable procedures for review of the actions of the executive unit, not in conflict with the provisions hereof, and not in conflict with the principle that personnel policy should in the first instance be determined by professional and trained personnel experts, but subject to the control of the civil service commission. All other provisions of this section notwithstanding, in the event that the commission amends, alters or changes any action of the unit, or in the event that the commission gives any directions to the unit as provided herein, or in any way acts to control the unit as provided herein, such amendment, change, alteration, direction or control shall be in writing and shall be supported by findings, which findings shall be supported by substantial evidence of the error of the unit. </text><history>Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 246, sec. 2, effective June 21, 1974. </history><metadata><effective>June 21, 1974</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23855</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>