<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">A AUTOMATED MOTOR VEHICLE REGISTRATION SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>186A.130</section_number><catch_line>Fee for title application. </catch_line><order_by>130</order_by><text>There shall be paid for issuing and processing documents required by this chapter fees according to the following schedule: <section prefix="1">Each application for a certificate of title shall be nine dollars ($9), of which the county clerk shall retain six dollars ($6) and the Transportation Cabinet shall receive three dollars ($3). </section><section prefix="2">Each application for a replacement or corrected certificate of title shall be six dollars ($6), of which the county clerk shall retain four dollars ($4) and the Transportation Cabinet shall receive two dollars ($2). If a corrected certificate must be issued because of an error of the county clerk or the Department of Vehicle Regulation, there shall be no charge. </section><section prefix="3">Each application for a speed title shall be twenty-five dollars ($25), of which the county clerk shall retain five dollars ($5) and the Transportation Cabinet shall receive twenty dollars ($20). </section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">Each application for a certificate of title for an all-terrain vehicle shall be fifteen dollars ($15), of which the county clerk shall retain six dollars ($6) and the Transportation Cabinet shall receive nine dollars ($9). </section><section prefix="b">Each application for a replacement or corrected certificate of title for an all-terrain vehicle shall be ten dollars ($10), of which the county clerk shall retain four dollars ($4) and the Transportation Cabinet shall receive six dollars ($6). If a corrected certificate must be issued because of an error of the county clerk or the Department of Vehicle Regulation, there shall be no charge. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 64, sec. 3, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 11, effective January 1, 2007. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 35, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 428, sec. 34, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 23, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6159</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>