<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">A KENTUCKY MODEL PROCUREMENT CODE </unit></structure><section_number>45A.183Selection</section_number><catch_line>committee procedures to apply when capital project is to be constructed using the construction management-at-risk method -- Competitive process consistent with code to apply when construction project is to be constructed using the construction manager-general contractor method -- Administrative regulations.   </catch_line><order_by>183Selection</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When a capital project is to be constructed using the construction management-at-risk method, a process parallel to the selection committee procedures established in KRS 45A.810 shall apply when procuring a construction management-at-risk firm and regulations promulgated in accordance with KRS 45A.180 shall apply that set forth requirements for: <section prefix="a">Description of the bond, insurance, and other security provisions that apply to a project; </section><section prefix="b">Description of appropriate contract clauses and fiscal responsibility requirements that apply to each project; and </section><section prefix="c">Restrictions relating to conflicts of interest, including a provision that a construction management-at-risk entity shall be eligible to become an offeror of goods or services on a project it manages only when a subcontractor fails to perform and upon prior approval by the contracting body. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">When a construction project is to be constructed using the construction manager-general contractor method, a competitive process consistent with this code established by administrative regulations promulgated under KRS 45A.180 shall apply. </section><section prefix="b">The procurement process shall set forth the requirements for: <section prefix="1">Description of the bond, insurance, and other security provisions that apply to the project; </section><section prefix="2">Description of appropriate contract clauses and fiscal responsibility requirements that apply to the project; and </section><section prefix="3">Restrictions relating to conflicts of interest, including a provision that a construction manager-general contractor shall be eligible to become an offeror of goods or services on a project it manages only when a subcontractor fails to perform and upon prior approval by the contracting body. </section></section><section prefix="c">The selection of the construction manager-general contractor shall be based on: <section prefix="1">Qualifications; and </section><section prefix="2">Price, including preconstruction consulting services, overhead, and profit. </section></section><section prefix="d">Prior to the construction phase, the construction manager-general contractor shall competitively bid the subcontracts by public notice and award each subcontract to the lowest responsive and responsible bidder. </section><section prefix="e">The final construction cost and completion date for the project shall be established by change order after the construction manager-general contractor enters into all applicable subcontracts. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 11, effective June 24, 2015. -- Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 98, sec. 11, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44586</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>