<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.037</section_number><catch_line>Supplemental bar license -- Main bar and service bars -- Fees.   </catch_line><order_by>037</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as where specifically authorized by statute, a retailer licensed to sell distilled spirits or wine by the drink shall only be permitted to sell or serve distilled spirits and wine by the drink at one (1) main bar, counter, or similar contrivance at the licensed premises. </section><section prefix="2">A retailer may have necessary service bars, if they are not located in any room in which the members or guests or patrons of the place are invited or permitted to come. No distilled spirits or wine shall be served at service bars. </section><section prefix="3">A supplemental bar license shall authorize the licensee to sell and serve distilled spirits and wine by the drink at retail from an additional location other than the main bar. A supplemental bar license is a nonquota license and shall not be transferable to other premises. </section><section prefix="4">A supplemental bar license shall not be issued unless: <section prefix="a">The licensee applies to the state distilled spirits director and meets all requirements for obtaining a supplemental bar license; and </section><section prefix="b">The licensee pays a fee identical to the fee for the primary license authorizing retail distilled spirits and wine drink sales for each of up to five (5) supplemental bar licenses. There shall be no charge for each supplemental license issued in excess of five (5) to the same licensee at the same premises. </section></section><section prefix="5">A license authorizing retail malt beverage sales, by the drink or by the package, authorizes the licensee to sell and serve malt beverages at any location on the licensed premises without obtaining a supplemental bar license. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 50, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 179, sec. 8, effective January 1, 2007. -- Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><lrc-note> (6/25/2013). 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 50, made changes to subsection (3) of this statute. It is apparent from consultation with the drafter, examination of the bill folder, and from context that the second use of the  phrase "sell and serve malt beverages" should have been deleted from subsection (3), now subsection (5). The Reviser of Statutes has deleted the phrase "may sell and serve malt beverages" under the authority of KRS 7.136.  (6/20/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 95, 97, 98, 99, 123, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42485</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>