<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.4-533</section_number><catch_line>Authorized charges for extension of credit. </catch_line><order_by>4-533</order_by><text>Notwithstanding the provisions of KRS 286.4-530(10) or of any other law, in any extension of credit in accordance with Subtitle 4 of KRS Chapter 286, the licensee may charge and collect the following: <section prefix="1">A fee, or premium for insurance, in lieu of perfecting a security interest to the extent that the fee or premium does not exceed the fee payable to public officials for perfecting the security interest; </section><section prefix="2">A bad check charge of twenty-five dollars ($25), or the amount passed on from other financial institutions, whichever is greater, for any check, draft, negotiable order of withdrawal, or like instrument returned or dishonored for any reason by a depository institution, which charge licensee may charge and collect, through regular billing procedures, or otherwise from the borrower; </section><section prefix="3">A reasonable attorney's fee, in connection with the collection of a loan, actually incurred by the licensee and paid to an attorney who is not an employee of the licensee; </section><section prefix="4">A charge for credit investigations of one dollar and fifty cents ($1.50) for each fifty dollars ($50) or fraction thereof of the principal amount of the loan. This charge shall be permitted only on the first two thousand dollars ($2,000) of the principal amount of the loan. No charge shall be collected unless a loan has been made as a result of the investigation; </section><section prefix="5">An alternative to the default charge described in KRS 286.4-530(4), not to exceed five percent (5%) of each scheduled installment, or fifteen dollars ($15), whichever is greater. Only one (1) charge may be collected for each scheduled installment; and </section><section prefix="6">Costs or other expenses authorized for a secured party in accordance with KRS 355.9-207 and 355.9-607. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 28, sec. 21, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 93, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 157, sec. 4, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 198, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 222, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 288.533. </former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  In accordance with 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, secs. 38 and 39, this statute has been renumbered as a section of the Kentucky Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286, and KRS references within this statute have been adjusted to conform with the 2006 renumbering of that code. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14642</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>