<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="148" order_by="148">PARKS AND TOURISM </unit></structure><section_number>148.630</section_number><catch_line>Classes of trails established. </catch_line><order_by>630</order_by><text>The state system of trails shall be composed of: <section prefix="1">State scenic trails, which will be extended trails so located as to provide maximum potential for the appreciation of natural areas and for the conservation and enjoyment of the significant scenic, historic, natural, ecological, geological, and cultural qualities of the areas through which such trails pass. Each of these trails will be limited exclusively to foot use, except that the use of horses or off-road motorized vehicles or nonmotorized bicycles may also be permitted on segments of scenic trails where specifically designated by the department. Because of their extended length, the state scenic trails shall be supplemented by support facilities but only on that part of a trail which is in a state park or recreation area. Such support facilities may include, where deemed necessary and feasible, primitive shelters, fireplaces, safe water supply, and other related public-use facilities. These facilities shall comply with the state's health standards. No open wood fires shall be permitted on state scenic trails except in areas with support facilities specifically designated for such purpose. </section><section prefix="2">State recreation trails, which will provide a variety of outdoor recreation uses in or reasonably accessible to urban areas. These trails may be of the following types: foot, horse, off-road motorized vehicles or nonmotorized bicycles as specifically designated by the department. </section><section prefix="3">Connecting or side trails, which will provide additional points of public access to state recreation trails, state scenic trails, or which will provide connections between such trails. They shall be of the nature of the trails they serve. </section></text><history>Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 288, sec. 4. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1777</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>