<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.9-200</section_number><catch_line>Contents of license -- Change of address -- Refundability of fees. </catch_line><order_by>9-200</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The license issued under this subtitle or to a surplus lines broker, life settlement broker, or life settlement provider shall contain the licensee's name, city and state of principal place of business address, personal identification number, and the date of issuance, the lines of authority, and any other information the commissioner deems necessary. </section><section prefix="2">The licensee shall inform the commissioner in writing in a format acceptable to the commissioner of a change of address or change of legal name within thirty (30) days of the change. </section><section prefix="3">After completion of application for a license, completion of any prelicensing education required under this chapter, payment of applicable fees, and the taking and passing of any examination required under this chapter, the commissioner shall promptly consider the application. If the commissioner finds that the applicant has fully met the requirements for licensure, the commissioner shall promptly issue the license to the applicant; otherwise, the commissioner shall refuse to issue the license and promptly notify the applicant of the refusal, stating the grounds thereof. </section><section prefix="4">If a license is refused, the commissioner shall promptly refund any appointment fee tendered with the license application. All other fees for application for license or examination shall be deemed earned when paid and shall not be refundable. </section><section prefix="5">In order to assist in the performance of the commissioner's duties, the commissioner may contract with nongovernmental entities, including the National Association of Insurance Commissioners or its affiliate or subsidiary, to perform ministerial functions, including the collection of fees or data related to licensing. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1059, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 16, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 273, sec. 21, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 393, sec. 17, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 9, sec. 20, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  A reference to the "executive director" of insurance in subsection (4) of this section, as amended by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1059, has been changed in codification to the "commissioner" of insurance to reflect the reorganization of certain parts of the Executive Branch, as set forth in Executive Order 2009-535 and confirmed by the General Assembly in 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24. This change was made by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1938. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:07</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=16913</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>