<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.555</section_number><catch_line>Center for Middle School Academic Achievement -- Duties -- Location at college or university. </catch_line><order_by>555</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Center for Middle School Academic Achievement is created to improve the content knowledge and instructional practice of middle school teachers through the coordination of professional development programs for middle school teachers, the provision of technical assistance to schools and teachers, and the collection and dissemination of information and research regarding effective models of teaching the core disciplines to middle school students. </section><section prefix="2">The center shall: <section prefix="a">Foster collaboration between the center, the Department of Education, the Education Professional Standards Board, postsecondary institutions of education, postsecondary departments or colleges of arts and sciences, and other entities to develop content-based teacher preparation programs and ongoing professional development programs for middle school teachers, aligned with the Department of Education's core content for assessment; </section><section prefix="b">Assist school districts in assessing and addressing their needs and deficiencies in middle school curriculum and instruction; </section><section prefix="c">Assist grant recipients of the Middle School Mathematics and Science Scholars Program established under KRS 158.848 with professional development for participating teachers; </section><section prefix="d">Assist middle school teachers in establishing and maintaining networks of communication to share information regarding middle school instructional practice, curriculum development, and other areas of common interest, building upon existing networks; </section><section prefix="e">Develop and maintain a clearinghouse for information about: <section prefix="1">Educational models addressing content knowledge and skills of middle school students, based on reliable, replicable research; </section><section prefix="2">Core content achievement levels of Kentucky students in relation to students in other states and other countries; and </section><section prefix="3">The relationship between student achievement levels and curriculum content, curriculum structure and alignment with content, teacher training, and teaching methods; </section></section><section prefix="f">Develop and implement a research structure, in collaboration with the Department of Education, to evaluate the effectiveness of different middle school instructional models; and </section><section prefix="g">Submit an annual report to the Governor and the Legislative Research Commission by September 1 of each year. The report shall include information outlining the center's activities, information provided by the Kentucky Department of Education regarding the use of money from the Teachers' Professional Growth Fund, and other information regarding efforts to improve the quality of middle school instruction in Kentucky. </section></section><section prefix="3">With the advice of the commissioner of education and the Education Professional Standards Board, the Council on Postsecondary Education shall develop a process to solicit, review, and approve a proposal for locating the Center for Middle School Academic Achievement at a public or private college or university. The council shall choose a college or university that has demonstrated the coordination of course delivery between the faculties of the college of education and arts and sciences departments within the college or university. The council shall approve the location for the center no later than November 15, 2000. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 14, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 527, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3224</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>