<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="242" order_by="242">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LOCAL OPTION </unit></structure><section_number>242.1244</section_number><catch_line>Local option for limited sale of alcoholic beverages purchased in conjunction with a meal -- Separate local option elections to be held for restaurants seating fifty persons and those seating one hundred persons.   </catch_line><order_by>1244</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">In order to promote economic development and tourism, other provisions of the Kentucky Revised Statutes notwithstanding, a dry or moist city or county may, by petition in accordance with KRS 242.020, hold a local option election on the sale of alcoholic beverages by the drink at restaurants and dining facilities that seat a minimum of fifty (50) persons and derive a minimum of seventy percent (70%) of their gross receipts from the sale of food if alcoholic beverages are purchased in conjunction with a meal. A petition seeking a local option election under this subsection shall state "We the undersigned registered voters hereby petition for an election on the following question: 'Are you in favor of the sale of alcoholic beverages by the drink at restaurants and dining facilities with a seating capacity of at least fifty (50) persons and which derive at least seventy percent (70%) of their gross receipts from the sale of food if the alcoholic beverage is purchased in conjunction with a meal?'". </section><section prefix="b">The election shall be held in accordance with KRS 242.030(1), (2), and (5), 242.040, and 242.060 to 242.120, and the proposition on the ballot shall state "Are you in favor of the sale of alcoholic beverages by the drink in (name of city or county) at restaurants and dining facilities with a seating capacity of at least fifty (50) persons and which derive at least seventy percent (70%) of their gross receipts from the sale of food if the alcoholic beverage is purchased in conjunction with a meal?". If the majority of the votes in an election held pursuant to this subsection are "Yes," licenses may be issued to qualified restaurants and dining facilities, and the licensees may be regulated and taxed in accordance with KRS 243.072. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">In order to promote economic development and tourism, other provisions of the Kentucky Revised Statutes notwithstanding, a dry or moist city or county may, by petition in accordance with KRS 242.020, hold a local option election on the sale of alcoholic beverages by the drink at restaurants and dining facilities which seat a minimum of one hundred (100) persons and derive a minimum of seventy percent (70%) of their gross receipts from the sale of food. </section><section prefix="b">A petition seeking a local option election under this subsection shall state "We the undersigned registered voters hereby petition for an election on the following question: 'Are you in favor of the sale of alcoholic beverages by the drink in (name of city or county) at restaurants and dining facilities with a seating capacity of at least one hundred (100) persons and which derive at least seventy percent (70%) of their gross receipts from the sale of food?'". </section><section prefix="c">The election shall be held in accordance with KRS 242.030(1), (2), and (5), 242.040, and 242.060 to 242.120, and the proposition on the ballot shall state "Are you in favor of the sale of alcoholic beverages by the drink in (name of city or county) at restaurants and dining facilities with a seating capacity of at least one hundred (100) persons and which derive at least seventy percent (70%) of their gross receipts from the sale of food?". If the majority of the votes in an election held pursuant to this subsection are "Yes," licenses may be issued to qualified restaurants and dining facilities and the licensees may be regulated and taxed in accordance with KRS 243.072. </section></section><section prefix="3">A local option proposition under subsection (1) of this section is a separate proposition than a local option proposition held under subsection (2) of this section, so that a separate limited local option election is required for sales under each subsection. A territory may, by separate limited local option elections, simultaneously allow alcoholic beverage sales under subsections (1) and (2) of this section. A territory may also hold a limited local option election to allow alcoholic beverage sales under either subsection (1) or (2) of this section without authorizing alcoholic beverage sales under the other subsection. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 14, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 8, effective June 26, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42448</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>