<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17A-705</section_number><catch_line>Electronic claims submission. </catch_line><order_by>17A-705</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, "insurer" has the same meaning as in KRS 304.17A-005. </section><section prefix="2">Any contract between an insurer and its pharmacy benefits administrator that requires claims to be submitted electronically shall require that payment is to be made electronically to the participating provider or its designee for clean claims submitted electronically, if electronic payment is requested by the provider. </section><section prefix="3">Any contract between an insurer and a participating pharmacy or its contracting agency that requires claims to be submitted electronically shall require that payment is to be made electronically to the participating provider or its designee for clean claims submitted electronically, if electronic payment is requested by the provider. </section><section prefix="4">An electronic claim shall be submitted in the form required by the insurer if the participating provider or designee agrees to accept claims details for these payments electronically and provides accurate electronic funds transfer information to the insurer. </section><section prefix="5">All electronic claims shall be in compliance with the provisions of 45 C.F.R. Part 142. </section><section prefix="6">The provisions of this section shall apply to all contracts in subsections (2) and (3) of this section that are entered into, amended, extended, or renewed on or after January 1, 2009. </section></text><history> Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2008).  The House Committee Substitute for 2008 HB 551 intended to change the word "carrier" to "insurer" throughout. One instance of "carrier" at the end of subsection (4) of this statute was inadvertently not changed. This manifest clerical or typographical error has been corrected by the Reviser of Statutes in codifying 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 1, under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(h). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29331</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>