<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="63" order_by="63">RESIGNATIONS, REMOVALS, AND VACANCIES </unit></structure><section_number>63.080</section_number><catch_line>Governor may remove officers appointed by him, without cause -- Exceptions. </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided in subsection (2) of this section and otherwise provided by law, any person appointed by the Governor, either with or without the advice and consent of the Senate, may be removed from office by the Governor for any cause the Governor deems sufficient, by an order of the Governor entered in the executive journal removing the officer. </section><section prefix="2">Members of the board of trustees of the University of Kentucky, the board of trustees of the University of Louisville, members of the board of regents respectively of Eastern Kentucky University, Western Kentucky University, Morehead State University, Kentucky State University, Northern Kentucky University, Murray State University, and the Kentucky Community and Technical College System, and members of the Kentucky Board of Education and the Council on Postsecondary Education shall not be removed except for cause. </section></text><history> Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 41, effective May 30, 1997. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 16, effective July 1, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts Acts ch. 60, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990; ch. 476, Pt. II, sec. 37, effective July 13, 1990; and ch. 504, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 28. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 67. -- Amended 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 25, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 3750. </history><metadata><effective> May 30, 1997 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23158</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>