<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="403" order_by="403">DISSOLUTION OF MARRIAGE -- CHILD CUSTODY </unit></structure><section_number>403.832</section_number><catch_line>Simultaneous proceedings. </catch_line><order_by>832</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as otherwise provided in KRS 403.828, a court of this state shall not exercise jurisdiction under Article 2 if, at the time of the commencement of the proceeding, a proceeding concerning the custody of the child has been commenced in a court of another state having jurisdiction substantially in conformity with KRS 403.800 to 403.880, unless the proceeding has been terminated or is stayed by the court of the other state because a court of this state is a more convenient forum under KRS 403.834. </section><section prefix="2">Except as otherwise provided in KRS 403.828, a court of this state, before hearing a child custody proceeding, shall examine the court documents and other information supplied by the parties pursuant to KRS 403.828. If the court determines that a child custody proceeding has been commenced in a court in another state having jurisdiction substantially in accordance with KRS 403.800 to 403.880, the court of this state shall stay its proceeding and communicate with the court of the other state. If the court of the state having jurisdiction substantially in accordance with KRS 403.800 to 403.880 does not determine that the court of this state is a more appropriate forum, the court of this state shall dismiss the proceeding. </section><section prefix="3">In a proceeding to modify a child custody determination, a court of this state shall determine whether a proceeding to enforce the determination has been commenced in another state. If a proceeding to enforce a child custody determination has been commenced in another state, the court may: <section prefix="a">Stay the proceeding for modification pending the entry of an order of the other state enforcing, staying, denying, or dismissing the proceeding for enforcement; </section><section prefix="b">Enjoin the parties from continuing with the proceeding for enforcement; or </section><section prefix="c">Proceed with the modification under conditions it considers appropriate. </section></section></text><history> Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 133, sec. 17, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:32</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17510</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>