<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.170</section_number><catch_line>Meetings of board -- Quorum -- Expenses -- Public character. </catch_line><order_by>170</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board of trustees of the university shall meet quarterly. Special meetings may be called by the chairperson or by any three (3) members upon giving ten (10) days' written notice to each member of the board of trustees. The business to be transacted at special meetings shall be specified in the notice of the meeting. All meetings shall be held on the campus of the university unless otherwise specified by a majority vote of the board of trustees. A majority of the voting members of the board of trustees shall constitute a quorum. All necessary expenses incurred by the trustees in going to, returning from and while attending meetings of the board of trustees shall be paid out of the funds of the university, except a member who resides outside the Commonwealth shall not be reimbursed for out-of-state travel. </section><section prefix="2">The meetings of the board of trustees shall be open to the public. The board of trustees shall cause a stenographic transcript of each of its meetings to be prepared and filed. An agenda for each of the meetings shall be sent to each member of the board of trustees and a copy made available to the press. </section></text><history> Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 39, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 12, effective July 1, 1992. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 112, sec. 2. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 4527-14, 4527-15, 4527-16. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4216</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>