<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="252" order_by="252">APIARIES </unit></structure><section_number>252.170</section_number><catch_line>Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>170</order_by><text>As used in KRS 252.180 to 252.240, and KRS 252.990, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Bees" means any stage of the common hive or honey bee (apis mellifica) or other bees kept for the production of honey or wax; </section><section prefix="2">"Bee diseases" means American or European foul brood, sacbrood, bee paralysis, disappearing disease, Isle of Wight disease, or any other disease or abnormal condition of the egg, larval, pupal or adult stages of bees; </section><section prefix="3">"Apiary" means any place where one (1) or more colonies or nuclei of bees are kept; </section><section prefix="4">"Queen apiaries" means any apiary in which queen bees shall be reared for sale or gift; </section><section prefix="5">"Hive" means any modern frame hive, box hive, box, barrel, log gum, skep, or any other receptacle, natural or artificial, or any part thereof which may be used as a domicile for bees; </section><section prefix="6">"Appliances" means any honey house, used tools, machines, or devices used in the handling or manipulation of bees, honey, wax, or used hives. It shall also mean any container of honey, or wax, which may be used in an apiary; </section><section prefix="7">"Department" means the Department of Agriculture or any division thereof to which the administration of KRS 252.180 to 252.240 may be delegated by the Commissioner of Agriculture; and </section><section prefix="8">"Commissioner" means the Commissioner of Agriculture. </section></text><history>Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 9, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 1. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12295</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>