<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="230" order_by="230">HORSE RACING AND SHOWING </unit></structure><section_number>230.361</section_number><catch_line>Regulation of pari-mutuel wagering -- Authorized operation not grounds for revocation or suspension of temporary alcoholic beverage license -- Tickets presumed abandoned -- License for special charitable events.   </catch_line><order_by>361</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The racing commission shall promulgate administrative regulations governing and regulating mutuel wagering on horse races under what is known as the pari-mutuel system of wagering. The wagering shall be conducted only by a person licensed under this chapter to conduct a race meeting and only upon the licensed premises. The pari-mutuel system of wagering shall be operated only by a totalizator or other mechanical equipment approved by the racing commission. The racing commission shall not require any particular make of equipment. </section><section prefix="2">The operation of a pari-mutuel system for betting where authorized by law shall not constitute grounds for the revocation or suspension of any license issued and held under KRS 242.1238 and 243.265. </section><section prefix="3">All reported but unclaimed pari-mutuel winning tickets held in this state by any person or association operating a pari-mutuel or similar system of betting at horse race meetings shall be presumed abandoned if not claimed by the person entitled to them within one (1) year from the time the ticket became payable. </section><section prefix="4">The racing commission may issue a license to conduct pari-mutuel wagering on steeple chases or other racing over jumps; if all proceeds from the wagering, after expenses are deducted, is used for charitable purposes. If the dates requested for such a license have been granted to a track within a forty (40) mile radius of the race site, the racing commission shall not issue a license until it has received written approval from the affected track. Pari-mutuel wagering licensed and approved under this subsection shall be limited to four (4) days per year. All racing and wagering authorized by this subsection shall be conducted in accordance with applicable administrative regulations promulgated by the racing commission. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 102, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 460, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 16, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 237, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 25, effective March 30, 1992. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 376, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 214, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 307, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 403, sec. 7. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 184, sec. 14. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><former-codification> KRS 230.340. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42539</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>