<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="148" order_by="148">PARKS AND TOURISM </unit></structure><section_number>148.280</section_number><catch_line>Functions of commission -- Acquisition, control, and use of property -- Holding of events -- Contracts. </catch_line><order_by>280</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commission: <section prefix="a">Shall have the authority and control of such property as now is under its custody and control, and of such property as may hereafter be placed under its control or transferred to it by the State Property and Buildings Commission, for any purpose mentioned in this section; </section><section prefix="b">May erect and repair buildings on the State Horse Park and make any and all necessary or proper improvements, and generally carry on a program of development and extension of facilities designed to accomplish the objectives defined in this section; </section><section prefix="c">Shall promote the progress of the state and stimulate public interest in the advancement and development of the state by providing the facilities of the State Horse Park for exhibitionary, competitive, and other events relative to various aspects of the horse industry and other functions calculated to advance and enhance the tourist industry, economy, entertainment, cultural, and educational interests of the public. </section></section><section prefix="2">The commission may take, acquire, and hold property, and all interest herein, by deed, gift, devise, bequest, lease, or by transfer from the state property so acquired in the manner provided by law. </section><section prefix="3">The commission may enact by administrative regulation as provided in KRS Chapter 13A, rules governing the operation, maintenance, or use of property under its custody and control. </section><section prefix="4">The commission may employ or contract with other persons, firms, or corporations the commission may deem necessary or desirable to accomplish its duties and functions; may fix the compensation and the terms of employment or contract of those employed or contracted with; and may assign to them duties and responsibilities the commission may determine, including the responsibility of actual operation of any or all of the facilities under the control of the commission. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 196, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 96, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 17, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1979 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 3, effective July 1, 1979. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1741</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>