<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="214" order_by="214">DISEASES </unit></structure><section_number>214.605</section_number><catch_line>Public education program. </catch_line><order_by>605</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall establish a program to educate the public about the threat of acquired immunodeficiency syndrome. </section><section prefix="2">The Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome Education Program shall: <section prefix="a">Be designed to reach all segments of the Commonwealth's population; </section><section prefix="b">Contain special components designed to reach minority groups within the state; </section><section prefix="c">Impart knowledge to the public about methods of transmission of acquired immunodeficiency syndrome and methods of prevention; </section><section prefix="d">Educate the public about transmission risks in social, employment, and educational situations; </section><section prefix="e">Educate health-care workers and health facilities' employees about methods of transmission and prevention in their unique workplace environments; </section><section prefix="f">Contain special components designed to reach persons who may frequently engage in behaviors placing them at a high risk for acquiring acquired immunodeficiency syndrome; </section><section prefix="g">Provide information and consultation to state agencies to educate all state employees; </section><section prefix="h">Provide information and consultation to state and local agencies to educate law enforcement and correctional personnel and inmates; </section><section prefix="i">Provide information and consultation to local governments to educate local government employees; </section><section prefix="j">Make information available to private employers and encourage them to distribute this information to their employees; and </section><section prefix="k">Contain special components which emphasize appropriate behavior and attitude change. </section></section><section prefix="3">The program designed by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall utilize all appropriate forms of the media and shall identify sources of educational materials that can be used by businesses, schools, and health-care providers in the regular course of their business. </section><section prefix="4">The department may contract with other persons in the design, development, and distribution of the components of the education program. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 464, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 411, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 443, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8844</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>