<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="197" order_by="197">PENITENTIARIES </unit></structure><section_number>197.120</section_number><catch_line>Employment of prisoners by other state agencies -- Restriction. </catch_line><order_by>120</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department of Corrections may enter into contracts with any other state agency for the use and employment of prisoners who may be eligible for the assignments. The contracts shall specifically set forth the compensation to be paid to the Department of Corrections for the use and employment of the prisoners, for the payment of the expenses of transporting, guarding, housing, disciplining, and maintaining the prisoners while so employed. The amount to be paid shall be certified by the contracting parties to the Finance and Administration Cabinet at the end of each month and shall be charged to the appropriation of the agency liable for the payment thereof and credited to the budget of the department to be disbursed and expended as it directs. Any contract may provide for a fixed per diem compensation to be paid to the department for each day's work performed by the prisoner and the department shall pay, out of the per diem compensation, the expenses of transporting, guarding, disciplining, housing, and maintaining prisoners as may be provided in the contracts. </section><section prefix="2">The Department of Corrections shall not enter into any contract with the Department of Revenue for the use or employment of prisoners in any capacity that allows prisoners access to taxpayer information, including, but not limited to, tax returns, informational reporting returns, social security numbers, telephone numbers, or addresses. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 618, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 383, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 52, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 344, sec. 27, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. II, sec. 9(1); and Art. V, sec. 24(14). -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 3828b-12. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6880</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>