<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="278" order_by="278">PUBLIC SERVICE COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>278.507</section_number><catch_line>Public Service Commission's policy to facilitate greater use of natural gas produced in Kentucky -- Commission's duties and prohibited activities. </catch_line><order_by>507</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It shall be the policy of the Public Service Commission to facilitate greater utilization of the natural gas produced or available for production within the state, where this can be done without detriment to the customers of utilities under jurisdiction of the commission. </section><section prefix="2">This policy may be implemented by requiring the transportation of natural gas in intrastate commerce for persons who own or have purchased gas, as provided in KRS 278.505. </section><section prefix="3">The commission shall maintain at its offices for public inspection all rates and charges for natural gas transportation which are filed with the commission, and copies of federal or state rules which govern transportation of natural gas. </section><section prefix="4">The commission may implement this policy by gathering and maintaining, for public inspection, various information concerning natural gas markets.  Such information may include, but not by way of limitation: <section prefix="a">Lists of producers of undedicated natural gas, together with such descriptions of available quantity, location or price as may be available to the commission; </section><section prefix="b">Lists of persons seeking a supply of natural gas, together with such descriptions as may be available to the commission; </section><section prefix="c">Sources of legal or technical expertise in natural gas procurement or marketing, which may be available to the commission; </section><section prefix="d">Transportation contracts filed with the commission, except to the extent that the parties to such contracts have requested that portions of these contracts be treated as confidential. </section></section><section prefix="5">The commission may adopt or develop model contracts or forms if it determines that such models would simplify negotiations between parties in the direct sale of natural gas. </section><section prefix="6">The commission shall not implement this policy by engaging directly in the procurement or marketing of natural gas as an agent of any person. </section><section prefix="7">The commission shall not regulate contracts between producers and purchasers of natural gas except to the extent that any party or parties to the contract are otherwise subject to commission regulation and commission review of contracts under this chapter. </section></text><history>Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 39, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14137</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>