<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="625" order_by="625">TERMINATION OF PARENTAL RIGHTS </unit></structure><section_number>625.065</section_number><catch_line>Putative father party to proceedings. </catch_line><order_by>065</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The putative father of a child shall be made a party and brought before the circuit court in the same manner as any other party to an involuntary termination action if one (1) of the following conditions exists: <section prefix="a">He is known and voluntarily identified by the mother by affidavit; </section><section prefix="b">Prior to the entry of a final order in a termination proceeding, he shall have acknowledged the child as his own by affirmatively asserting paternity in the action or to the custodial agency or the party bringing the action within sixty (60) days after the birth of the child; </section><section prefix="c">He has caused his name to be affixed to the birth certificate of the child; </section><section prefix="d">He has commenced a judicial proceeding claiming parental right; </section><section prefix="e">He has contributed financially to the support of the child, either by paying the medical or hospital bills associated with the birth of the child or financially contributed to the child's support; or </section><section prefix="f">He has married the mother of the child or has lived openly or is living openly with the child or the person designated on the birth certificate as the biological mother of the child. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any person to whom none of the above conditions apply shall be deemed to have no parental rights to the child in question. </section></text><history>Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 72, effective April 10, 1988. </history><metadata><effective>April 10, 1988 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20255</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>