<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>355.9-514</section_number><catch_line>Assignment of powers of secured party of record. </catch_line><order_by>9-514</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (3) of this section, an initial financing statement may reflect an assignment of all of the secured party’s power to authorize an amendment to the financing statement by providing the name and mailing address of the assignee as the name and address of the secured party. </section><section prefix="2">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (3) of this section, a secured party of record may assign of record all or part of its power to authorize an amendment to a financing statement by filing in the filing office an amendment of the financing statement which: <section prefix="a">Identifies, by its file number, the initial financing statement to which it relates; </section><section prefix="b">Provides the name of the assignor; and </section><section prefix="c">Provides the name and mailing address of the assignee. </section></section><section prefix="3">An assignment of record of a security interest in a fixture covered by a record of a mortgage which is effective as a financing statement filed as a fixture filing under KRS 355.9-502(3) may be made only by an assignment of record of the mortgage in the manner provided by law of this Commonwealth other than this chapter. </section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 408, sec. 105, effective July 1, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33819</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>