<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="350" order_by="350">SURFACE COAL MINING </unit></structure><section_number>350.054</section_number><catch_line>Illegal mining and conveyance reclamation fund -- Purpose -- Control. </catch_line><order_by>054</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is established a special fund to be known as the "Illegal Mining and Conveyance Reclamation Fund" which shall be under the control of the Energy and Environment Cabinet. </section><section prefix="2">The fund shall consist of all moneys from the sale or forfeiture of all instrumentalities used in violation of KRS 350.057(3) or 350.060(1) as provided for in KRS 350.053. </section><section prefix="3">Moneys in the fund may be used for the following purposes: <section prefix="a">To reclaim lands mined without a permit or authorization, as required by KRS 350.057 or 350.060(1), and not eligible for the abandoned mine lands reclamation fund; and </section><section prefix="b">To defray all expenses associated with the seizure, storing, and sale of forfeited property pursuant to KRS 350.053. </section></section><section prefix="4">Moneys contained in the illegal mining and conveyance reclamation fund shall be deemed a trust and agency account and shall not lapse. </section><section prefix="5">The cabinet shall have access to and control of the moneys held in the illegal mining and conveyance reclamation fund, but shall expend the moneys only for the purposes set forth in subsection (3) of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1877, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 212, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32776</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>