<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="502" order_by="502">PARTIES TO OFFENSES: ACCOUNTABILITY </unit></structure><section_number>502.050</section_number><catch_line>Corporate liability. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A corporation is guilty of an offense when: <section prefix="a">The conduct constituting the offense consists of a failure to discharge a specific duty imposed upon corporations by law; or </section><section prefix="b">The conduct constituting the offense is engaged in, authorized, commanded or wantonly tolerated by the board of directors or by a high managerial agent acting within the scope of his employment in behalf of the corporation; or </section><section prefix="c">The conduct constituting the offense is engaged in by an agent of the corporation acting within the scope of his employment and in behalf of the corporation and: <section prefix="1">The offense is a misdemeanor or violation; or </section><section prefix="2">The offense is one defined by a statute which clearly indicates a legislative intent to impose such criminal liability on a corporation. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Agent" means any officer, director, servant or employee of the corporation or any other person authorized to act in behalf of the corporation. </section><section prefix="b">"High managerial agent" means an officer of a corporation or any other agent of a corporation who has duties of such responsibility that his conduct reasonably may be assumed to represent the policy of the corporation. </section></section></text><history>Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 24, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 1975</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:23</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19663</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>