<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="337" order_by="337">WAGES AND HOURS </unit></structure><section_number>337.075</section_number><catch_line>Lien on property of employer who violates provisions of chapter -- Recording of lien. </catch_line><order_by>075</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A lien may be placed on all property, both real and personal, of an employer who has been assessed civil penalties by the commissioner for violations of the wages and hours provisions of this chapter, but not before all administrative and judicial appeals have been exhausted. The lien shall be in favor of the Labor Cabinet and shall be an amount totaling the unpaid wages and penalties due, together with interest at a rate of twelve percent (12%) per annum from the date the notice of the violation is final, but not before all administrative and judicial appeals have been exhausted. The lien shall be attached to all property and rights to property owned or subsequently acquired by the employer. The commissioner or the commissioner's designee shall record the lien as provided in subsection (2) of this section. The lien shall show the date on which the notice of violation was issued, the date of the violation, the name and last known address of the employer against whom the assessment was made, and the amount of unpaid wages, penalties, and interest. The lien shall be superior to the lien of any mortgage or encumbrance thereafter created and shall continue for ten (10) years from the time of the recording, unless sooner released or otherwise discharged. </section><section prefix="2">The lien shall be filed in any of the following offices in which the employer owns property or rights to property and any filing fees associated with filing the lien shall be pursuant to KRS 64.012: <section prefix="a">The office of the county clerk of the county in which the defendant employer resides. </section><section prefix="b">The office of the county clerk of the county in which the defendant employer has its principal place of business. </section><section prefix="c">The office of the county clerk of any county in which the defendant employer has property or an interest in property. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1728, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 24, effective January 1, 2007. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32054</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>