<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.8925</section_number><catch_line>Web site to provide public access to expenditure records of regional wastewater commission -- Monthly updates -- Registration with Department for Local Government -- Application of KRS 65A.010 to 65A.090. </catch_line><order_by>8925</order_by><text><section prefix="1">By January 1, 2012, the commissioners of a regional wastewater commission established under the provisions of KRS 65.8901 to 65.8923 shall provide public access to records relating to expenditures of the commission through display of the records on a Web site. </section><section prefix="2">The Web site shall be in a searchable format and shall provide financial information about expenditures not exempt under the provisions of state or federal law, including: <section prefix="a">The payee name; </section><section prefix="b">The category or type of expenditure; </section><section prefix="c">A description of the reason for the expenditure, if available; </section><section prefix="d">The expenditure amount; </section><section prefix="e">An electronic link to documents relating to the expenditure, if the documents are available electronically; </section><section prefix="f">The budget adopted by the commission and subsequent amendments to that budget; </section><section prefix="g">The completed annual audit results; and </section><section prefix="h">Any other information deemed relevant by the commission. </section></section><section prefix="3">Information on the Web site shall be updated at least on a monthly basis and shall be maintained on the Web site for at least three (3) years. </section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">The regional wastewater commission shall register with the Department for Local Government as required by KRS 65A.090. </section><section prefix="b">For fiscal periods beginning on and after July 1, 2014, the provisions of KRS 65A.010 to 65A.090 shall apply to regional wastewater commissions. Commissioners shall work with the Department for Local Government to provide the information required by this section through the registry established by KRS  65A.020. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 24, effective March 21, 2013. -- Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch.98, sec.14, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> March 21, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41704</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>