<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="74" order_by="74">WATER DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>74.415</section_number><catch_line>Commissioners may consider installation of fire hydrants on new or extended water lines. </catch_line><order_by>415</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commissioners of a water district, or the governing body of a water association referred to in KRS 74.012(1), in order to provide adequate means of fire protection, may consider the installation of fire hydrants on new or extended water lines within their area. They may investigate the availability of supplementary funding to pay the incremental costs of line sizing and hydrant installation. The commissioners or governing body shall not eliminate fire hydrants from new or extended water lines unless they determine that hydrants are not feasible. Their analysis shall include consideration of the incremental costs of adequately sized pipe and associated pumps and towers, and the benefits of real estate development, water sales, the availability of fire protection insurance, and the reduced fire insurance premiums which may result from the installation of hydrants at specified intervals. </section><section prefix="2">If a private real estate subdivision developer has not included adequately sized pipe and fire hydrants in his development plan, the commissioners of a water district or the governing body of a water association which has the capacity to supply adequate water for fire hydrants shall require, at the time the developer applies for permission to hook into the district's water lines, an analysis by the developer of the incremental cost of hydrants and piping adequately sized for hydrants, the effect of hydrants on the cost and availability of fire protection insurance, and conclusions as to why the installation of hydrants is not feasible. </section></text><history> Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 122, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 1(2). </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24418</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>