<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="224" order_by="224">A KENTUCKY INFRASTRUCTURE AUTHORITY </unit></structure><section_number>224A.030</section_number><catch_line>Creation of Kentucky Infrastructure Authority -- Membership. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created the Kentucky Infrastructure Authority, which authority shall be a body corporate and politic, constituting a public corporation and a governmental agency and instrumentality of the state. The affairs of the authority shall be managed and carried out by a board consisting of eleven (11) members. The secretaries of the Economic Development, Finance and Administration, and Energy and Environment Cabinets; the executive director of the Public Service Commission; and the commissioner of the Department for Local Government shall serve as ex officio members of the authority. The secretaries, the executive director, and the commissioner may designate alternates. The Governor shall additionally appoint six (6) at-large members. One (1) member shall be selected from a list of three (3) nominees submitted by the Kentucky Association of Counties, one (1) member selected from a list of three (3) nominees submitted by the Kentucky League of Cities, one (1) member selected from a list of three (3) nominees submitted by the Kentucky Rural Water Association, one (1) member representing for-profit private water companies, one (1) member selected from a list of three (3) nominees submitted by the Kentucky section of the American Water Works Association, and one (1) member selected from a list of three (3) nominees submitted by the Kentucky Municipal Utilities Association. As the terms of the at-large members expire, the Governor shall appoint successors for terms of four (4) years and until their successors are appointed. The members shall constitute the Kentucky Infrastructure Authority, with power in that name to contract and be contracted with, sue and be sued, have and use a corporate seal, and exercise, in addition to the powers and functions specifically stated in this chapter, all of the usual powers of private corporations to the extent that the powers are not inconsistent with specifically enumerated powers of the authority. In the carrying out of its purposes and the exercise by it of the powers conferred by this chapter, the authority is deemed and declared to be performing essential governmental functions and public purposes of the state. </section><section prefix="2">The members of the authority shall receive no compensation for their services in their official capacity but shall be entitled to reimbursement for all reasonable expenses necessarily incurred in connection with performance of their duties and functions as authority members. </section><section prefix="3">Six (6) members of the authority shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business, and in the absence of a quorum, one (1) or more members may adjourn from time to time until a quorum is convened. The members of the authority shall choose from their ranks a chair and a vice chair. The authority shall elect a secretary and a treasurer who shall not be members of the authority, each of whom shall serve at the pleasure of the authority and shall receive compensation as may be determined by the authority. </section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">The authority shall, for administrative purposes, be attached to the Department for Local Government, which shall provide any office space required by the authority. </section><section prefix="b">The secretary of the authority shall at all times maintain therein complete records of all of the authority's actions and proceedings which shall constitute public records open to inspection at all reasonable times. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 386, effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 117, sec. 85, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 49, effective June 25, 2009; and ch. 29, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 89, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 529, sec. 16, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 74, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 373, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 73, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 477, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 3, effective March 31, 1988. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 216, sec. 10, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 51, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 329, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  This section was amended by 2010 Ky. Acts chs. 24 and 117, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10554</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>