<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="70" order_by="70">SHERIFFS, CONSTABLES, AND COUNTY POLICE FORCE </unit></structure><section_number>70.290</section_number><catch_line>Employment contract for deputy sheriff or peace officer -- Reimbursement of law enforcement agency when deputy or peace officer accepts employment with another agency. </catch_line><order_by>290</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">City and county law enforcement agencies, including sheriff's offices, may, as a condition of employment, require a newly appointed deputy sheriff or peace officer who will participate in the Kentucky Law Enforcement Foundation Fund Program, authorized by KRS 15.410 to 15.510, to enter into an employment contract for a period of no longer than three (3) years from the date of graduation from the Department of Criminal Justice Training, or other training approved by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council. </section><section prefix="b">If a deputy sheriff or peace officer who has entered into a contract authorized under this subsection accepts employment as a peace officer with another law enforcement agency, that law enforcement agency shall reimburse the law enforcement agency that initially hired the deputy sheriff or peace officer for the actual costs incurred and expended which are associated with the initial hiring of that officer, including but not limited to the application process, training costs, equipment costs, salary and fringe benefits. The law enforcement agency that initially hired the deputy sheriff or peace officer shall be reimbursed for the costs from the time of the deputy sheriff or peace officer's initial application until graduation from the Department of Criminal Justice Training. </section><section prefix="c">The amount of reimbursement authorized by this subsection shall be prorated based upon the percentage of time that the deputy sheriff or peace officer completed of his or her employment contract. The amount of reimbursement authorized by this subsection after the pro rata amount is calculated shall be reduced by the cost of the training provided by the Department of Criminal Justice Training for the subject officer. </section></section><section prefix="2">If a peace officer who has been employed by a state law enforcement agency for three (3) years or less accepts employment as a peace officer with a city or local law enforcement agency, that city or local law enforcement agency shall reimburse the state law enforcement agency that initially hired the peace officer for the costs expended with the initial hiring of that officer, including but not limited to the application process, training costs, equipment costs, salary and fringe benefits. The state law enforcement agency that initially hired the peace officer shall be reimbursed for the costs incurred and expended from the time of the peace officer's initial application until graduation from a Kentucky Law Enforcement Council approved training academy. The amount of reimbursement authorized by this subsection shall be prorated based upon the percentage of time that the peace officer has been employed. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 305, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24227</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>