<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="104" order_by="104">FLOOD CONTROL AND WATER USAGE </unit></structure><section_number>104.450</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 104.450 to 104.680. </catch_line><order_by>450</order_by><text>As used in KRS 104.450 to 104.680, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Secretary" means the secretary of the Energy and Environment Cabinet of the Commonwealth of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="2">"Flood control work" means all land, pumping equipment, buildings, motor vehicles, mowing machines, or any other fixtures, tools or equipment a part of or used in connection with a floodwall or other construction designed to protect an area from being flooded. </section><section prefix="3">"District" means a flood control district organized and created under the terms of KRS 104.450 to 104.680. </section><section prefix="4">"Board" or "directors" means the board of directors of a flood control district organized and created under the terms of KRS 104.450 to 104.680. </section><section prefix="5">"Director" means a person appointed as a member of the board of directors as provided in KRS 104.450 to 104.680. </section><section prefix="6">"Person" means any person, firm, copartnership, association or corporation other than a public corporation. </section><section prefix="7">"Public corporation" means any county, city, school district, water district or drainage district, and any other governmental agency or political subdivision clothed with the power of levying general or special taxes or issuing bonds payable from special funds. </section><section prefix="8">"Land" or "property" means real property. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 88, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 118. -- Created 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 42, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:11</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27083</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>