<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.50-055</section_number><catch_line>Plans for premium payment, assessments, and dividends -- Approval by commissioner -- Investments -- Financing of payments by governmental entities.   </catch_line><order_by>50-055</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A workers' compensation self-insured group shall establish plans for premium payment, determination and collection of assessments, and for declaration and payment of dividends or other disbursements, which shall be filed for prior approval with the commissioner. Any change in the plans for premium payment, assessments, or dividends shall be filed for prior approval with the commissioner. Approval of plans for assessments and dividends does not constitute approval of any particular assessment or dividend by the commissioner. </section><section prefix="2">Prior to the inception of each group member's self-insurance year, the trustees shall collect from that member at least twenty-five percent (25%) of the estimated premium for the ensuing year, except that in the case of a self-insured group formed by governmental entities twenty-five percent (25%) of the estimated premium for the ensuing year shall be collected no later than thirty (30) days after the beginning of the self-insured group's self-insurance year. The balance of the estimated premium shall be collected in either quarterly or monthly installments as set forth in the enabling documents described in KRS 304.50-030(2)(b) or 304.50-060(2)(b). Each group member's payroll shall be audited annually and an adjustment to premium shall be made accordingly. </section><section prefix="3">A disbursement from a workers' compensation self-insured group fund shall be for a purpose related to the self-insured group. A dividend shall not be approved or paid until at least thirty-six (36) months after the expiration of the self-insurance year and shall be paid from surplus funds not required for payment of claims or other liabilities. The dividends shall be paid or credited to members according to the reasonable classifications the trustees may establish. A dividend shall not be paid which unfairly discriminates between members of the same classifications. A dividend plan shall specify whether past group members are eligible for the dividend. Payment of a dividend under a dividend plan shall not be made unless the self-insured group has notified the commissioner of its intent to make a dividend payment at least thirty (30) days prior to the payment, and the commissioner has not disapproved the payment within that time. </section><section prefix="4">The formula to be used for collection of assessments shall be determined by the trustees and approved by the commissioner. Assessments shall be fair and equitable and shall not unfairly discriminate between members of the same classification. </section><section prefix="5">A trustee, fiscal agent, or service organization shall not utilize an asset of the self-insured group for a purpose unrelated to workers' compensation. The trustees shall maintain cash or cash equivalent accounts as may be prudently necessary to pay expenses without having to liquidate long-term investments. </section><section prefix="6">The trustees may invest funds in: <section prefix="a">United States Government bonds, United States Treasury notes, Treasury bills, or other direct obligations guaranteed by the full faith and credit of the United States Government or its agencies; </section><section prefix="b">Tax exempt obligations issued by the Commonwealth of Kentucky or its agencies with a minimum rating of "A" by Standard &amp; Poor; </section><section prefix="c">Obligations issued by a county, district, municipality, or other legal authority within the Commonwealth with a minimum rating of "AA" by Standard &amp; Poor; </section><section prefix="d">Investment share accounts in a savings and loan association in the Commonwealth whose deposits are insured by a federal agency; </section><section prefix="e">Certificates of deposit if issued by a duly chartered commercial bank; </section><section prefix="f">At the time of purchase, equity securities actively traded on the New York or NASDAQ Stock Exchanges or other registered national securities exchanges with no individual equity holding comprising greater than ten percent (10%) of the equity portion of the portfolio reflected on the most recent quarterly or annual statement of financial condition on file with the commissioner. <section prefix="1">An investment in an individual equity holding shall not represent at the time of purchase more than five percent (5%) of the total market value of the security. </section><section prefix="2">At the time of purchase, investments in equity securities shall not exceed twenty percent (20%) of the total market value of the investment portfolio of the self-insured group reflected on the most recent quarterly or annual statement of financial condition on file with the commissioner; </section></section><section prefix="g">Corporate bonds if: <section prefix="1">The bond is issued, assumed, or guaranteed by a solvent institution created or existing under the laws of the United States, or a state, province, district, or territory; </section><section prefix="2">At the time of purchase, the corporate bond investments do not exceed twenty-five percent (25%) of the total market value of the investment portfolio reflected on the most recent quarterly or annual statement of financial condition on file with the commissioner; and </section><section prefix="3">The bond has a minimum rating of "A" by Standard and Poor; and </section></section><section prefix="h">At the time of purchase, mutual funds and exchange traded funds if the investments do not exceed twenty percent (20%) of the total market value of the investment portfolio reflected on the most recent quarterly or annual statement of financial condition on file with the commissioner. </section></section><section prefix="7">Of the aggregate investments made by the trustees of the self-insured group under this section: <section prefix="a">Not less than fifty percent (50%) of the total market value of the entire investment portfolio shall be held in cash, cash equivalents, or securities as described in subsection (6)(a) to (e) of this section; and </section><section prefix="b">A minimum of five percent (5%) of the total investment portfolio value shall be maintained in cash or cash equivalent accounts or United States Treasury and Federal Agency Securities with a remaining maturity of one (1) year or less. </section></section><section prefix="8">The commissioner may permit variation from the requirements of this section for good cause. </section><section prefix="9"><section prefix="a">Governmental entities that: <section prefix="1">Participate or have participated in a workers' compensation self-insured group authorized by this subtitle; and </section><section prefix="2">Are assessed by the workers' compensation self-insured group to cover an accrued deficit; </section></section> may finance the payment of the assessment over a period not to exceed twenty (20) years. <section prefix="b">Financing obtained pursuant to paragraph (a) of this subsection may be accomplished by: <section prefix="1">The issuance of bonds, notes, or other obligations; or </section><section prefix="2">A lease, installment payment agreement, or other similar agreement. </section></section><section prefix="c">If the governmental entity fails to make a scheduled payment on the financing obtained pursuant to paragraph (a) of this subsection, any payments due to that governmental entity shall be withheld or intercepted using the process established in KRS 160.160(5). </section></section><section prefix="10">Except as provided in subsection (9) of this section, all other provisions of the Kentucky Revised Statutes applying to any financing obtained by a governmental entity shall apply. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 75, sec. 5, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1633, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 183, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 11, effective March 1, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><lrc-note> (3/1/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts ch. 7, which creates this section, contains the enrolled text of Senate Bill 86 as amended by a Senate committee substitute. In drafting the committee substitute, an additional subsection was inserted into this section, but a reference to "subsection (5)(a) of this section" in subsection (7) was not changed to reflect this addition. Pursuant to KRS 7.136(1), the reference has been changed to "subsection (6)(a) of this section" in codification. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42297</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>