<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.750</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 65.750 to 65.760. </catch_line><order_by>750</order_by><text>As used in this section to KRS 65.760: <section prefix="1">"911 emergency telephone service" means a telephone service which provides the user of the public telephone system the ability to place calls to a public safety answering point on a twenty-four (24) hour basis and reach local emergency service agencies by dialing the digits 9-1-1. Such a service is capable, at minimum, of transmitting requests for law enforcement, firefighting, and emergency medical and ambulance services to a public safety agency or other provider that provides the requested service at the place where the call originates. A 911 emergency telephone service may also provide for other emergency services. The term "911 emergency telephone service" includes the term wireline "enhanced 911 system," which means an emergency telephone system that provides the caller with wireline emergency 911 system service and, in addition, directs 911 calls to appropriate public safety answering points based on the geographical location from which the call originated and may provide the capability for automatic number identification, pseudo-automatic number identification, selective routing, and automatic location identification features. As used in KRS 65.760, the term "911 emergency telephone service" does not include the term "wireless enhanced 911 system," "wireless enhanced 911 service," or "wireless E911 service" as used in KRS 65.7621 to 65.7643; </section><section prefix="2">"Automatic number identification (ANI)" means a feature that allows for the automatic display of the ten (10) digit number, or equivalent, used to place a 911 call; </section><section prefix="3">"Automatic location identification (ALI)" means a feature by which the name and address associated with the calling party's telephone number is made available to a PSAP; </section><section prefix="4">"Automatic location identification data management system (ALI/DBS)" means a system of manual procedures and computer programs used to create, store, and update the data required for ALI in support of enhanced 911; </section><section prefix="5">"Dispersed private telephone system (DPTS)" means a multiline, shared tenant system or PBX used for the purpose of reselling telephone service to residential customers and whose connection to a telephone network is capable of carrying emergency calls from more than one (1) specific location within a structure or structures but does not mean a multiline, shared tenant system or PBX owned and operated by a state agency or used in providing service within a hotel or motel; </section><section prefix="6">"Fully enhanced 911 emergency telephone service" means a telephone network feature that selectively routes calls placed to the national 911 emergency number to the proper public service answering points (PSAPs) and provides the PSAP with a voice connection and ANI and ALI information; </section><section prefix="7">"Private branch exchange (PBX)" means a privately owned switch system that connects calls to a telephone company; </section><section prefix="8">"Public safety answering point" or "PSAP" means a communications facility that is assigned the responsibility to receive 911 calls originating in a given area and, as appropriate, to dispatch public safety services or to extend, transfer, or relay 911 calls to appropriate public safety agencies; </section><section prefix="9">"Service supplier" means a person or entity that administers, maintains, and operates the ALI/DBS and may include telephone companies that provide local exchange telephone service to a telephone subscriber; and </section><section prefix="10">"Station identification number (SIN)" means a number that a DPTS uses to identify a specific station on the switch. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 521, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 535, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/98).  This section was amended by 1998 Ky. Acts chs. 521 and 535 which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23495</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>