<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.10-212</section_number><catch_line>Hazardous waste records open to public inspection -- Confidential nature of certain data. </catch_line><order_by>10-212</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any record or any other information furnished to or obtained by the cabinet relating to hazardous waste shall be open to reasonable public inspection, except that any record or information which constitutes a trade secret or confidential business information and is designated as such by the cabinet upon a satisfactory showing by the owner in accordance with the rules and regulations of the cabinet shall not be disclosed. Further, no record or information designated by the owner to be either a trade secret or confidential business information but not designated as such by the cabinet due to the failure of the owner to make a satisfactory showing of confidentiality shall be released to the public or to any other agency, department or officer of the Commonwealth without providing the owner fifteen (15) days written notice. </section><section prefix="2">Nothing herein shall be construed to prevent the use of such records or information by the cabinet in compiling or publishing reports, analyses or summaries relating to general conditions in the environment, nor shall anything herein prevent the use of any record or other information for the purposes of administration or enforcement of any federal, state or local pollution control law. However, no such report, analyses, summary or use shall directly or indirectly publicly reveal information otherwise confidential under this section. </section></text><history>Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 73, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 264, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1982 </effective><former-codification> KRS 224.036. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:34</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10316</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>