<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.33-130</section_number><catch_line>Conduct of hearings in summary proceedings. </catch_line><order_by>33-130</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Confidentiality of commissioner's hearings. The commissioner shall hold all hearings in summary proceedings privately unless the insurer requests a public hearing, in which case the hearing shall be public. </section><section prefix="2">Confidentiality of court hearings. The court may hold all hearings in summary proceedings and judicial reviews thereof privately in chambers, and shall do so on request of the insurer proceeded against. </section><section prefix="3">Records. In all summary proceedings and judicial reviews thereof, all records of the company, other documents, and all Department of Insurance files and court records and papers, so far as they pertain to or are a part of the record of the summary proceedings, shall be and remain confidential except as is necessary to obtain compliance therewith, unless the court, after hearing arguments from the parties in chambers, shall order otherwise, or unless the insurer requests that the matter be made public. Until such court order, all papers filed with the clerk of the court shall be held by him or her in a confidential file. </section><section prefix="4">Parties. If at any time it appears to the court that any person whose interest is or will be substantially affected by an order did not appear at the hearing and has not been served, the court may order that notice be given and the proceedings be adjourned to give him or her opportunity to appear on such terms as may be just. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1438, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 33, sec. 13, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:00</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29830</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>