<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXII" order_by="32">OWNERSHIP AND CONVEYANCE OF PROPERTY</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="385" order_by="385">UNIFORM TRANSFERS TO MINORS ACT </unit></structure><section_number>385.022</section_number><catch_line>Scope and jurisdiction. </catch_line><order_by>022</order_by><text><section prefix="1">KRS 385.012 to 385.222 apply to a transfer that refers to KRS 385.032 to 385.222 in the designation under KRS 385.092(1) by which the transfer is made if at the time of the transfer, the transferor, the minor, or the custodian is a resident of this state or the custodial property is located in this state.  The custodianship so created remains subject to KRS 385.032 to 385.222 despite a subsequent change in residence of a transferor, the minor, or the custodian, or the removal of custodial property from this state. </section><section prefix="2">A person designated as custodian under KRS 385.032 to 385.222 is subject to personal jurisdiction in this state with respect to any matter relating to the custodianship. </section><section prefix="3">A transfer that purports to be made and which is valid under the Uniform Transfers to Minors Act, the Uniform Gifts to Minors Act, or a substantially similar act, of another state is governed by the law of the designated state and may be executed and is enforceable in this state if at the time of the transfer, the transferor, the minor, or the custodian is a resident of the designated state or the custodial property is located in the designated state. </section></text><history>Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35775</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>