<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.830</section_number><catch_line>Powers of board. </catch_line><order_by>830</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board of trustees of the University of Louisville shall constitute a body corporate, with the usual corporate powers, and shall possess all the authorities, immunities, rights, privileges, and franchises usually attaching to the governing bodies of Kentucky public higher educational institutions. Powers of the board shall include the following: <section prefix="a">Appointment of a president, all faculty members, and other personnel and determination of the compensation, duties, and official relations of each. No relative of a board of trustee member shall be employed by the university. </section><section prefix="b">Suspension or removal of the president, officers, faculty, agents, or other personnel that it is authorized to appoint, except that no president, professor, or teacher shall be removed except for incompetence, neglect of or refusal to perform his duty, or for immoral conduct and that the removal shall be made in accordance with procedures established by law for state institutions. </section><section prefix="c">Election of a vice chairperson and any other officers as it deems wise, including the annual election of a six (6) member executive committee which shall have the powers that the board delegates to it and shall operate under the rules the board shall establish under its authority to make bylaws, rules, and regulations consistent with this chapter. The committee shall have one (1) member representing the students, faculty, and nonteaching personnel with the group alternating each year. The initial appointment to the executive committee after May 30, 1997, shall be a faculty member, to be followed by a student and a nonteaching personnel, respectively. </section><section prefix="d">Receipt, retention, and administration, on behalf of the university, subject to the conditions attached, all revenues accruing from endowments, appropriations, allotments, grants or bequests, and all types of property. </section><section prefix="e">Requirement of reports from the president, officers, faculty, and employees as it deems necessary and proper from time to time. </section><section prefix="f">Granting degrees to graduates of the university, prescription of conditions upon which postgraduate honors may be obtained, and conferment of honorary degrees. </section><section prefix="g">The board shall periodically evaluate the institution's progress in  implementing its missions, goals, and objectives to conform to the strategic agenda. Officers and officials shall be held accountable for the status of the institution's progress. </section></section><section prefix="2">The provisions of KRS 164.030, 164.200, and 164.410, shall be applicable to the University of Louisville except where inconsistent with the purposes of KRS 164.810 to 164.870. </section></text><history> Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 126, effective May 30, 1997. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 15, effective July 1, 1992. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 257, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> May 30, 1997 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4469</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>