<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIII" order_by="33">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS AND ESTATES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>386A.4-060</section_number><catch_line>Events requiring dissolution of a series.   </catch_line><order_by>4-060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A series shall be dissolved, and it shall commence to wind up its activities and affairs, upon the first to occur of the following: <section prefix="a">The dissolution of the statutory trust; </section><section prefix="b">An event or circumstance that the governing instrument states causes dissolution of the series; </section><section prefix="c">Except as otherwise provided in the governing instrument, the consent of all of the beneficial owners associated with the series; </section><section prefix="d">The passage of ninety (90) days after the occurrence of the dissociation of the last remaining beneficial owner associated with the series; or </section><section prefix="e">On application by a beneficial owner associated with the series, the entry by the appropriate court of an order dissolving the series on the grounds that it is not reasonably practicable to carry on the series's activities in conformity with the governing instrument. </section></section><section prefix="2">The date of dissolution of a series shall be: <section prefix="a">The date of dissolution of the statutory trust; </section><section prefix="b">The effective date of the event or circumstance that the governing instrument states causes dissolution; </section><section prefix="c">The effective date of the consent of the beneficial owners; </section><section prefix="d">The ninety-first day after the dissociation of the last beneficial owner associated with the series; or </section><section prefix="e">The effective date of the decree of dissolution issued by an appropriate court. </section></section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 27, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40369</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>