<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="510" order_by="510">SEXUAL OFFENSES </unit></structure><section_number>510.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter.   </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>The following definitions apply in this chapter unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Deviate sexual intercourse" means any act of sexual gratification involving the sex organs of one person and the mouth or anus of another; or penetration of the anus of one person by a foreign object manipulated by another person. "Deviate sexual intercourse" does not include penetration of the anus by a foreign object in the course of the performance of generally recognized health-care practices; </section><section prefix="2">"Forcible compulsion" means physical force or threat of physical force, express or implied, which places a person in fear of immediate death, physical injury to self or another person, fear of the immediate kidnap of self or another person, or fear of any offense under this chapter. Physical resistance on the part of the victim shall not be necessary to meet this definition; </section><section prefix="3">"Mental illness" means a diagnostic term that covers many clinical categories, typically including behavioral or psychological symptoms, or both, along with impairment of personal and social function, and specifically defined and clinically interpreted through reference to criteria contained in the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders (Third Edition) and any subsequent revision thereto, of the American Psychiatric Association; </section><section prefix="4">"Individual with an intellectual disability" means a person with significantly subaverage general intellectual functioning existing concurrently with deficits in adaptive behavior and manifested during the developmental period, as defined in KRS Chapter 202B; </section><section prefix="5">"Mentally incapacitated" means that a person is rendered temporarily incapable of appraising or controlling his conduct as a result of the influence of an intoxicating substance administered to him without his consent or as a result of any other act committed upon him without his consent; </section><section prefix="6">"Physically helpless" means that a person is unconscious or for any other reason is physically unable to communicate unwillingness to an act. "Physically helpless" also includes a person who has been rendered unconscious or for any other reason is physically unable to communicate an unwillingness to an act as a result of the influence of a controlled substance or legend drug; </section><section prefix="7">"Sexual contact" means any touching of the sexual or other intimate parts of a person done for the purpose of gratifying the sexual desire of either party; </section><section prefix="8">"Sexual intercourse" means sexual intercourse in its ordinary sense and includes penetration of the sex organs of one person by a foreign object manipulated by another person. Sexual intercourse occurs upon any penetration, however slight; emission is not required. "Sexual intercourse" does not include penetration of the sex organ by a foreign object in the course of the performance of generally recognized health-care practices; and </section><section prefix="9">"Foreign object" means anything used in commission of a sexual act other than the person of the actor. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 123, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 259, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 401, sec. 4, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 300, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 355, sec. 1 effective July 14, 1992. --Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 448, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988; and ch. 283, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 486, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 81. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40848</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>