<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>14A.1-040</section_number><catch_line>Interrogatories by Secretary of State.   </catch_line><order_by>1-040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Secretary of State may propound to any entity or foreign entity that the Secretary of State has reason to believe is subject of the provisions of this chapter, and to any authorized representative thereof including a registered agent, such written interrogatories as may be necessary and proper to enable the Secretary of State to ascertain whether the entity or foreign entity is subject to the provisions of this chapter applicable to it and is in compliance therewith. The interrogatories shall be answered within thirty (30) days after the mailing thereof, or within such additional time as may be fixed by the Secretary of State, and the answers thereto shall be full and complete and shall be made in writing and under oath. Interrogatories directed to an individual shall be answered by the individual. Interrogatories directed to an entity or a foreign entity shall be answered by a person with the authority, pursuant to the organic law governing the entity or foreign entity, to bind the entity or foreign entity. </section><section prefix="2">The Secretary of State may take such action as is deemed appropriate, including a referral to the Attorney General, when the interrogatories and the answers thereto disclose a violation of any of the provisions of this chapter or of the organic law governing an entity or foreign entity. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 4, effective January 1, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36515</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>