<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="153" order_by="153">THE ARTS -- STATE ZOO </unit></structure><section_number>153.410Kentucky</section_number><catch_line>Center for the Arts Corporation.   </catch_line><order_by>410Kentucky</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Center for the Arts Corporation is hereby established, and shall consist of nineteen (19) members representing metropolitan Louisville and Kentucky to be appointed by the Governor, who shall also designate a chairman. Initial terms shall be staggered; thereafter, members shall be appointed to four (4) year terms. </section><section prefix="2">Members may be removed by the Governor only for cause after being afforded notice, a hearing with counsel before the Governor or his designee, and a finding of fact by the Governor. A copy of charges, transcript of the record of the hearings, and findings of fact shall be filed with the Secretary of State. </section><section prefix="3">The Kentucky Center for the Arts Corporation shall be a body corporate with full corporate powers. A quorum of the corporation shall consist of ten (10) members, with a majority of members present authorized to act upon any matter legally before the corporation. Full minutes and records shall be kept of all meetings of the corporation and all official actions shall be recorded. </section><section prefix="4">The corporation may enact bylaws concerning the election of other officers, the creation of an executive committee with full authority to act between regular meetings, and the designation of alternates for members with full voting authority. </section><section prefix="5">The corporation shall be attached to the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet for administrative purposes. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 36, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 31, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 209, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 66, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 382, sec. 2, effective April 9, 1980. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 295, sec. 37, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44577</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>