<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">A DRIVING UNDER THE INFLUENCE </unit></structure><section_number>189A.500</section_number><catch_line>Ignition interlock devices and licenses -- Certification of devices and device providers -- Provider contract provisions.   </catch_line><order_by>500</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Transportation Cabinet shall: <section prefix="a">Issue ignition interlock license application forms and other forms necessary for the implementation of ignition interlock licenses; </section><section prefix="b">Create a uniform certificate of installation to be provided to a defendant by an ignition interlock provider upon installation of a certified ignition interlock device; </section><section prefix="c">Create an ignition interlock license for issuance to any person granted authorization by the court to receive an ignition interlock license; </section><section prefix="d">Certify ignition interlock devices approved for use in the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="e">Publish and periodically update on the Transportation Cabinet Web site a list of contact information, including a link to the Web site of each certified ignition interlock device provider, with the entity appearing first on the list changing on a statistically random basis each time a unique visitor visits the list of the approved ignition interlock installers and the approved servicing and monitoring entities; and </section><section prefix="f">Promulgate administrative regulations to carry out the provisions of this section. </section></section><section prefix="2">No model of ignition interlock device shall be certified for use in the Commonwealth unless it meets or exceeds standards promulgated by the Transportation Cabinet pursuant to this section. </section><section prefix="3">In bidding for the contract with the Transportation Cabinet to provide ignition interlock devices and servicing or monitoring or both, the ignition interlock provider shall take into account that some defendants will not be able to pay the full cost of the ignition interlock device or servicing and monitoring fees. </section><section prefix="4">Upon June 24, 2015, any contract between the cabinet and an ignition interlock device provider shall include the following: <section prefix="a">A requirement that the provider accept reduced payments as a full payment for all purposes from persons determined to be indigent by a court authorizing the use of an ignition interlock device pursuant to KRS 189A.420(7); </section><section prefix="b">A requirement that no unit of state or local government and no public officer or employee shall be liable for the cost of purchasing or installing the ignition interlock device or associated costs; </section><section prefix="c">A requirement that the provider agree to a price for the cost of leasing or purchasing an ignition interlock device and any associated servicing or monitoring fees during the duration of the contract. This price shall not be increased but may be reduced during the duration of the contract; </section><section prefix="d">Requirements and standards for the servicing, inspection, and monitoring of the ignition interlock device; </section><section prefix="e">Provisions for training for service center technicians and clients; </section><section prefix="f">A requirement that the provider electronically transmit reports on driving activity within seven (7) days of servicing an ignition interlock device to the respective court, prosecuting attorney, and defendant; </section><section prefix="g">Requirements for a transition plan for the ignition interlock device provider before the provider leaves the state to ensure that continuous monitoring is achieved and to provide a minimum forty-five (45) day notice to the cabinet of any material change to the design of the ignition interlock device, or any changes to the vendor's installation, servicing, or monitoring capabilities; </section><section prefix="h">A requirement that, before beginning work, the ignition interlock device provider have and maintain insurance as approved by the cabinet, including vendor's public liability and property damage insurance, in an amount determined by the cabinet, that covers the cost of defects or problems with product design, materials, workmanship during manufacture, calibration, installation, device removal, or any use thereof; </section><section prefix="i">A provision requiring that an ignition interlock provider agree to hold harmless and indemnify any unit of state or local government, public officer, or employee from all claims, demands, and actions, as a result of damage or injury to persons or property which may arise, directly or indirectly, out of any action or omission by the ignition interlock provider relating to the installation, service, repair, use, or removal of an ignition interlock device; </section><section prefix="j">A requirement that a warning label to be affixed to each ignition interlock device upon installation. The label shall contain a warning that any person who tampers with, circumvents, or otherwise misuse the device commits a violation of law under KRS 189A.345; and </section><section prefix="k">A requirement that a provider will remove an ignition interlock device without cost, if the device is found to be defective. </section></section></text><history> Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 15, effective June 24, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44692</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>