<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.684</section_number><catch_line>Authorization to establish state child fatality review team -- Annual report on child fatalities. </catch_line><order_by>684</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For the purposes of KRS Chapter 211: <section prefix="a">"Child fatality" means the death of a person under the age of eighteen (18) years; and </section><section prefix="b">"Local child fatality response team" and "local team" means a community team composed of representatives of agencies, offices, and institutions that investigate child deaths, including but not limited to, coroners, social service workers, medical professionals, law enforcement officials, and Commonwealth's and county attorneys. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Department for Public Health may establish a state child fatality review team. The state team may include representatives of public health, social services, law enforcement, prosecution, coroners, health-care providers, and other agencies or professions deemed appropriate by the commissioner of the department. </section><section prefix="3">If a state team is created, the duties of the state team may include the following: <section prefix="a">Develop and distribute a model protocol for local child fatality response teams for the investigation of child fatalities; </section><section prefix="b">Facilitate the development of local child fatality response teams which may include, but is not limited to, providing joint training opportunities and, upon request, providing technical assistance; </section><section prefix="c">Review and approve local protocols prepared and submitted by local teams; </section><section prefix="d">Receive data and information on child fatalities and analyze the information to identify trends, patterns, and risk factors; </section><section prefix="e">Evaluate the effectiveness of prevention and intervention strategies adopted; and </section><section prefix="f">Recommend changes in state programs, legislation, administrative regulations, policies, budgets, and treatment and service standards which may facilitate strategies for prevention and reduce the number of child fatalities. </section></section><section prefix="4">The department shall prepare an annual report to be submitted no later than November 1 of each year to the Governor, the Legislative Research Commission, the Chief Justice of the Kentucky Supreme Court, and to be made available to the citizens of the Commonwealth. The report shall include a statistical analysis of the incidence and causes of child fatalities in the Commonwealth during the past fiscal year and recommendations for action. The report shall not include any information which would identify specific child fatality cases. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 61, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 311, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 347, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8459</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>