<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="441" order_by="441">JAILS AND COUNTY PRISONERS </unit></structure><section_number>441.800</section_number><catch_line>Creation of regional jail authority -- Powers of authority. </catch_line><order_by>800</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Two (2) or more counties may by ordinances establish a regional jail authority. </section><section prefix="2">The authority shall constitute a public body corporate and politic, exercising public and essential governmental functions, and having all the powers necessary or convenient to carry out and effectuate the purposes and provisions of this section and KRS 441.810, including, but not limited to, the following powers: <section prefix="a">To sue and be sued; to have a seal and to alter the same at pleasure; to have perpetual succession; to make and execute contracts and other instruments necessary or convenient to the exercise of the powers of the authority; and to make and from time to time amend and repeal bylaws, rules and regulations to carry into effect the powers and purposes of the authority; </section><section prefix="b">To acquire property by lease or purchase, construct, reconstruct or renovate a regional jail and to provide for the operation and maintenance of the facility; and </section><section prefix="c">To exercise the power, authority and duties of counties under this chapter and other provisions of the Kentucky Revised Statutes related to the operations of jails and the incarceration of prisoners. </section></section></text><history>Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 415, sec. 13, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19381</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>