<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="18" order_by="18">A STATE PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>18A.205</section_number><catch_line>Life insurance for state employees and certain retirees -- Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>205</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, upon the recommendation of the secretary, may procure from one (1) or more life insurance companies, authorized to do business in this state, a policy or policies of group life insurance insuring the lives of all or any class or classes of state employees. The policy or policies shall be approved by the commissioner of insurance and may contain such provisions as the commissioner of insurance approves whether or not otherwise permitted by the insurance laws. It is intended that life insurance may be made available for state employees, except that the procuring is permissive. </section><section prefix="2">The term "state employee," for purposes of KRS 18A.205 to 18A.215, shall mean a person who is regularly employed by any department, board, agency, or branch of state government, and who is also: <section prefix="a">A contributing member of any one (1) of the state-administered retirement systems; or </section><section prefix="b">A retiree of a state-administered retirement system who is employed in a regular full-time position for purposes of retirement coverage, but who is not eligible to contribute to one (1) of the systems administered by Kentucky Retirement Systems pursuant to KRS 61.637(17). </section></section> Notwithstanding the definition of "state employee" in this subsection, any federally funded time-limited employee may receive insurance coverage. <section prefix="3">The term "premiums," for the purposes of KRS 18A.205 to 18A.225, shall mean premiums to be paid on any type of insurance authorized under KRS 18A.205 to 18A.225. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 52, sec. 1, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 26, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 44, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 6, effective July 13, 1984. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended as KRS 18A.410, 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 448, sec. 41, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 35, sec. 1. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 12. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. II, sec. 9(2). -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 1. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 225, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><former-codification> KRS 18.410. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39733</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>