<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.130</section_number><catch_line>Private action for damages -- Time limitation. </catch_line><order_by>130</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding any other remedies available, any person or party, in an individual capacity or on behalf of a class of persons or parties, damaged as a result of a violation of this chapter or the Uniform State Building Code, has a cause of action in any court of competent jurisdiction against the person or party who committed the violation. An award may include damages and the cost of litigation, including reasonable attorney's fees. </section><section prefix="2">Any action based upon a claim of violation of this section shall be brought within one (1) year of the date on which the damage is discovered or in the exercise of reasonable diligence could have been discovered. However, in no event shall an action be brought under this section more than ten (10) years after the date of first occupation or settlement date, whichever is sooner. </section><section prefix="3">Nothing in this section shall be construed to bar any common law liability of a contractor or subcontractor or any right or cause of action against any contractor or subcontractor created by any other statute. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 445, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 13, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6978</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>