<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="199" order_by="199">PROTECTIVE SERVICES FOR CHILDREN - ADOPTION </unit></structure><section_number>199.380</section_number><catch_line>Boarding and lodging homes for children under sixteen in counties containing city of second class -- Authority to operate -- Investigation -- Revocation of authority. </catch_line><order_by>380</order_by><text>No person or persons shall board or lodge children under the age of sixteen (16) years, or in any manner conduct a boarding home or boarding house for children under the age of sixteen (16) years, unless authorized and empowered so to do, in writing, by the health officer of the county in which such boarding home or boarding house is conducted. Before authorizing or empowering any person or persons to board or lodge children under the age of sixteen (16) years, or in any manner to conduct a boarding house or boarding home for such children, the health officer to whom an application is made for such authority or power shall make or cause to be made, an investigation to determine whether such person or persons have made suitable, sanitary and satisfactory arrangements for the health of such children. When such authority and power have been granted by a health officer the same may be revoked at any time, in the discretion of said health officer, when he shall determine that arrangements for the health of the children boarded or lodged in such boarding home or boarding house are unsuitable and unsatisfactory, and in no event shall such authority and power be effective for a longer period than one (1) year following the granting of same. Whenever the health officer of any county shall be notified by the juvenile session of District Court of such county, or notified by the probation officer thereof, that the person or persons operating a boarding home or boarding house for children under the age of sixteen (16) years are not making suitable and satisfactory arrangements for the health of the children being boarded or lodged therein, he shall make or cause to be made an investigation to determine whether or not the power and authority of such person or persons to operate such home shall be revoked. Any person who boards or lodges a child under the age of sixteen (16) years without having the permit provided for herein shall be guilty of an offense and punished as provided in subsection (3) of KRS 199.990. </text><history>Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 152, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 62. -- Created 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 13, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1980</effective><note>This section was amended by 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 280, sec. 141, which was to have become effective July 1, 1982. Thereafter, 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 284 changed the effective date of that act to July 15, 1984. Then, 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 184 repealed both 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 280, and 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 284. </note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7155</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>