<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="141" order_by="141">INCOME TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>141.422</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 141.422 to 141.425. </catch_line><order_by>422</order_by><text>As used in KRS 141.422 to 141.425: <section prefix="1">"Annual biodiesel and renewable diesel tax credit cap" means: <section prefix="a">For calendar years beginning prior to January 1, 2008, one million five hundred thousand dollars ($1,500,000); </section><section prefix="b">For the calendar year beginning on January 1, 2008, five million dollars ($5,000,000); and </section><section prefix="c">For calendar years beginning on or after January 1, 2009, ten million dollars ($10,000,000); </section></section><section prefix="2">"Annual cellulosic ethanol tax credit cap" means five million dollars ($5,000,000), unless the annual cellulosic ethanol tax credit cap is modified pursuant to KRS 141.4248, in which case the cap established by KRS 141.4248 shall be the annual cellulosic ethanol tax credit cap for that year. Any adjustments to the annual cellulosic ethanol tax credit cap made pursuant to KRS 141.4248 shall be made on an annual basis and shall not carry forward to subsequent years; </section><section prefix="3">"Annual ethanol tax credit cap" means five million dollars ($5,000,000), unless the annual credit cap is modified pursuant to KRS 141.4248, in which case the cap established by KRS 141.4248 shall be the annual ethanol tax credit cap for that year. Any adjustments to the annual ethanol tax credit cap made pursuant to KRS 141.4248 shall be made on an annual basis and shall not carry forward to subsequent years; </section><section prefix="4">"Biodiesel" means a renewable, biodegradeable, mono alkyl ester combustible liquid that is derived from agriculture crops, agriculture plant oils, agriculture residues, animal fats, or waste products that meets current American Society for Testing and Materials specification D6751 for biodiesel fuel (B100) blend stock distillate fuels; </section><section prefix="5">"Biodiesel producer" means an entity that manufactures biodiesel at a location in this Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="6">"Cellulosic ethanol" means ethyl alcohol for use as motor fuel that meets the current American Society for Testing and Materials specification D4806 for ethanol that is produced from cellulosic biomass materials of any lignocellulosic or hemicellulosic matter that is available on a renewable or recurring basis, including: <section prefix="a">Plant wastes from industrial processes such as sawdust and paper pulp; </section><section prefix="b">Energy crops grown specifically for fuel production such as switchgrass; or </section><section prefix="c">Agricultural plant residues such as corn stover, rice hulls, sugarcane, and cereal straws; </section></section><section prefix="7">"Cellulosic ethanol producer" means an entity that uses cellulosic biomass materials to manufacture cellulosic ethanol at a location in this Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="8">"Blended biodiesel" means a blend of biodiesel with petroleum diesel so that the percentage of biodiesel in the blend is at least two percent (2%) (B2 or greater); </section><section prefix="9">"Ethanol" means ethyl alcohol produced from corn, soybeans, or wheat for use as a motor fuel that meets the current American Society for Testing and Materials specification D4806 for ethanol; </section><section prefix="10">"Ethanol-based tax credits" means the cellulosic ethanol tax credit provided for in KRS 141.4244 and the ethanol tax credit provided for in KRS 141.4242; </section><section prefix="11">"Ethanol producer" means an entity that uses corn, soybeans, or wheat to manufacture ethanol at a location in this Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="12">"Renewable diesel" means a renewable, biodegradeable, non-ester combustible liquid that: <section prefix="a">Is derived from biomass resources as defined in KRS 152.715; and </section><section prefix="b">Meets the current American Society for Testing and Materials Specification D396 for fuel oils intended for use in various types of fuel-oil-burning equipment; D975 for diesel fuel oils suitable for various types of diesel fuel engines; or D1655 for aviation turbine fuels; and </section></section><section prefix="13">"Renewable diesel producer" means an entity that manufactures renewable diesel at a location in this Commonwealth. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 (2d Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 20, effective August 30, 2007. -- Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 136, effective March 18, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> August 30, 2007 </effective><lrc-note>(3/18/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 165, provides that this section shall apply to tax years beginning on or after January 1, 2005. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:01</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29145</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>