<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="341" order_by="341">UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>341.100</section_number><catch_line>Suitable work. </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In determining for any purpose under this chapter whether or not any work is suitable for a worker the secretary shall consider, among other pertinent conditions, the degree of risk involved to his health, safety and morals; his physical fitness and prior training; his experience and prior earnings; his length of unemployment and prospects for securing local work in his customary occupation; and the distance of the available work from his residence. </section><section prefix="2">For the purpose of this chapter, no work shall be suitable nor shall benefits be denied under this chapter to any otherwise eligible worker for refusing to accept new work or new conditions of work under one (1) or more of the following: <section prefix="a">If the position offered is vacant due directly to a strike, lock-out or other labor dispute; </section><section prefix="b">If the wages, hours, or other conditions of the work offered are substantially less favorable than those prevailing for similar work in the locality; </section><section prefix="c">If, as a condition of being employed, the worker would be required to join a company union or to resign from or refrain from joining any bona fide labor organization; </section><section prefix="d">If the acceptance of such work would be prejudicial to the continuance of an established employer-employee relationship to which the worker is a party. </section></section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 389, sec. 12, effective July 1, 1978. --Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(21). -- Amended 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4748g-3. </history><metadata><effective>July 1, 1978</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32247</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>