<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.760</section_number><catch_line>School-to-Careers System -- Legislative intent -- Goals. </catch_line><order_by>760</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It is the intent of the General Assembly that a School-to-Careers System be developed to serve as an umbrella for career-related programs in the public schools, including School-to-Work, Tech Prep, and High Schools That Work initiatives. </section><section prefix="2">The goals of the School-to-Careers System shall be to: <section prefix="a">Increase the math, science, communications, social studies, and technical skills of all students through the implementation of a more rigorous and relevant applied curriculum and instructional process; </section><section prefix="b">Increase the awareness of job and career availability in the future workforce and the skills required to obtain those positions; </section><section prefix="c">Increase the postsecondary education's entry and completion rates and reduce the percentage of students taking remedial courses; </section><section prefix="d">Decrease the high school dropout rate through a system of increased guidance and extra help focused on academics and career achievement; </section><section prefix="e">Make all students aware of employer expectations in order to be successful; </section><section prefix="f">Increase the daily attendance rate at all secondary schools; and </section><section prefix="g">Provide the educational experiences that will cause all students to meet the goals and capacities identified in KRS 158.645 and KRS 158.6451 for Kentucky students. </section></section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 444, sec. 1, effective April 9, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> April 9, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3580</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>