<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="367" order_by="367">CONSUMER PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>367.4082Prohibited</section_number><catch_line>solicitation of person involved in motor vehicle accident by a healthcare provider or intermediary.   </catch_line><order_by>4082Prohibited</order_by><text><section prefix="1">During the first thirty (30) days following a motor vehicle accident a healthcare provider or an intermediary, at the request or direction of a healthcare provider, shall not solicit or knowingly permit another individual to solicit a person involved in a motor vehicle accident for the provision of reparation benefits, as defined by KRS 304.39-020(2). </section><section prefix="2">A healthcare provider shall not: <section prefix="a">Pay or receive compensation for the referral or solicitation of reparation benefits for a person involved in a motor vehicle accident; </section><section prefix="b">Provide monetary compensation or other consideration to any individual for the purpose of inducing, enticing, or directing the provision of reparation benefits for a person involved in a motor vehicle accident; or </section><section prefix="c">Contact, request, or direct an intermediary to contact, for the purpose of solicitation, a person involved in a motor vehicle accident during the first thirty (30) days following a motor vehicle accident. </section></section><section prefix="3">A healthcare provider shall be responsible for the content of any contact, made at the direction or request of the healthcare provider, by an intermediary with a person involved in a motor vehicle accident within the first thirty (30) days following the motor vehicle accident involving a person. </section><section prefix="4">Any healthcare provider having knowledge of facts, actual or direct, of a violation of this section by another healthcare provider, an intermediary, or on behalf of the healthcare provider within their scope of practice, shall report the suspected violation to the appropriate board listed in KRS 367.4081(1). </section><section prefix="5">An individual licensed or certified as a healthcare provider, who violates this section, shall be subject to the disciplinary process of the respective licensing or regulatory authority. </section></text><history> Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 46, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44403</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>