<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17A-540</section_number><catch_line>Disclosure of limitations on coverage -- Denial letter. </catch_line><order_by>17A-540</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any insurer that limits coverage for any treatment, procedure, a drug, or device shall define the limitations and fully disclose those limits in the health insurance policy or certificate coverage. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Any insurer that denies coverage for a treatment, procedure, a drug that requires prior approval, or device for an enrollee shall provide the enrollee with a denial letter that shall include: <section prefix="1">The name, license number, state of licensure, and title of the person making the decision; </section><section prefix="2">A statement setting forth the specific medical and scientific reasons for denying coverage of a service, if the coverage is denied for reasons of medical necessity; and </section><section prefix="3">Instructions for initiating or complying with the plan's grievance or appeal procedure stating at a minimum whether the appeal must be in writing, any time limitations or schedules for filing appeals and the name and phone number of a contact person who can provide additional information. </section></section><section prefix="b">The denial letter shall be provided within: <section prefix="1">Two (2) regular working days of the submitted request where preauthorization for a treatment, procedure, drug, or device is involved; </section><section prefix="2">Twenty-four (24) hours of the submitted request where hospital preadmission review is sought; </section><section prefix="3">Twenty (20) working days of the receipt of requested medical information where the plan has initiated a retrospective review; and </section><section prefix="4">Twenty (20) working days of the initiation of the review process in all other instances. </section></section></section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 500, sec. 6, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 496, sec. 33, effective April 10, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17437</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>