<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="227" order_by="227">FIRE PREVENTION AND PROTECTION -- ELECTRICIANS </unit></structure><section_number>227.700</section_number><catch_line>"Fireworks" defined -- Exceptions. </catch_line><order_by>700</order_by><text>As used in KRS 227.700 to 227.750, "fireworks" means any composition or device for the purpose of producing a visible or an audible effect by combustion, deflagration, or detonation, and which meets the definition of "consumer fireworks" as defined in KRS 227.702 or "display" fireworks as defined in KRS 227.706 and as set forth in the United States Department of Transportation's (DOT) hazardous materials regulations. "Fireworks" does not include: <section prefix="1">Exception number 1: Toy pistols, toy canes, toy guns or other devices in which paper or plastic caps manufactured in accordance with DOT regulations, and packed and shipped according to said regulations, are not considered to be fireworks and shall be allowed to be used and sold at all times. </section><section prefix="2">Exception number 2: Model rockets and model rocket motors designed, sold, and used for the purpose of propelling recoverable aero models are not considered to be fireworks. </section><section prefix="3">Exception number 3: Propelling or expelling charges consisting of a mixture of sulfur, charcoal, and saltpeter are not considered as being designed for producing audible effects. </section></text><history>Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 66, sec. 2, effective March 16, 2011. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 436, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 49, sec. 15, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective>March 16, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39502</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>