<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="216" order_by="216">B LICENSURE AND REGULATION OF HEALTH FACILITIES AND SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>216B.025</section_number><catch_line>Commission of Health Economics Control in Kentucky. </catch_line><order_by>025</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created a separate administrative agency of state government to be known as the Commission of Health Economics Control in Kentucky for the purpose of carrying out its duties prescribed in this chapter. The commission shall be composed of the members of the Kentucky Health Care Cost Containment Advisory Committee. The chairman of the Kentucky Health Care Cost Containment Advisory Committee shall serve as chairman of the commission. Members of the commission shall serve for a term of four (4) years. In the event of a vacancy the person appointed shall serve only for the remaining portion of the vacated term. All members shall serve until such time as their successors are qualified and appointed. </section><section prefix="2">The secretary shall employ the members of the commission on a full-time basis and furnish necessary office space and assistance. </section><section prefix="3">A majority of the commission members shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of any business, for the performance of any duty, or for the exercise of any power of the commission. No vacancy in the commission shall impair the right of the remaining members to exercise all of the powers of the commission. </section><section prefix="4">No member of the commission may, in the exercise of any function described in this chapter, vote on any matter before the commission respecting any applicant, licensee or holder of a certificate of need with which such member has or, within the twelve (12) months preceding the vote, had any substantial ownership, employment, medical staff, fiduciary, contractual, creditor, or consultative relationship. A member who has or has had such a relationship with the applicant, licensee or holder of a certificate of need involved in a matter before the commission shall make a written disclosure of the relationship before any action is taken by the commission, and such disclosure shall become part of the record of the proceeding. </section></text><history>Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 210, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 377, sec. 8, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 347, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1982. --Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 135, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1988 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:37</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9183</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>