<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIII" order_by="33">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS AND ESTATES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="387" order_by="387">GUARDIANS -- CONSERVATORS -- CURATORS OF CONVICTS </unit></structure><section_number>387.690</section_number><catch_line>Specific duties of limited conservator or conservator. </catch_line><order_by>690</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A limited conservator or conservator shall expend or distribute, or authorize the expenditure or distribution of, or assist in the expenditure or distribution of, the principal or income from the financial resources placed under his supervision and control to assure that:  <section prefix="a">The essential requirements for the physical health or safety of the ward are met;  </section><section prefix="b">The rights of the ward are protected;  </section><section prefix="c">The financial resources of the ward which are subject to the conservatorship are prudently managed;  </section><section prefix="d">The ward has the opportunity to develop or regain the capacity to perform the functions listed in paragraphs (a), (b), and (c) of subsection (2) of KRS 387.680; and  </section><section prefix="e">The limited guardian or guardian for the ward, if any, is able to carry out the duties and powers assigned to him by the court.  </section></section><section prefix="2">In performing his duties, the limited conservator or conservator shall consider:  <section prefix="a">The size of the financial resources under the limited conservator's or conservator's supervision or control;  </section><section prefix="b">The probable duration of the conservatorship;  </section><section prefix="c">The likelihood that the ward may be able to manage his financial resources in the future;  </section><section prefix="d">The accustomed standard of living of the ward;  </section><section prefix="e">Other funds or resources used for the support of the ward which have not been placed under the control or supervision of the limited conservator or conservator; and  </section><section prefix="f">The requests of the ward and the ward's limited guardian or guardian, if any.  </section></section><section prefix="3">In addition to the duties and powers listed in subsection (1) of this section, the court may assign to a limited conservator any of the duties and powers listed in KRS 387.700 which the partially disabled person lacks the ability to perform.  </section></text><history>Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 20, effective July 1, 1982. </history><metadata><effective>July 1, 1982 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36059</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>