<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">F LOCAL RESCUE PROGRAMS - STATE AND LOCAL SEARCH AND RESCUE PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>39F.090</section_number><catch_line>Coordinating and planning responsibility. </catch_line><order_by>090</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The local search and rescue coordinator of each political subdivision, appointed in accordance with KRS 39F.200, shall be responsible for coordinating and planning for local search and rescue activities. Operation of search and rescue activities shall be in accordance with the Kentucky Emergency Operations Plan, and the local emergency operations plan approved by the elected chief executives of each local political subdivision. The local search and rescue coordinator shall notify the duty officer of the Division of Emergency Management of all search and rescue missions. The local search and rescue coordinator shall work in a coordinating capacity directly supporting all search and rescue activities in that political subdivision, and in registering emergency search and rescue workers. The chief of the appropriate law enforcement agency of each political subdivision may, upon request of the local director or local search and rescue coordinator, restrict access to a specific search and rescue area to personnel authorized by the local director. Access shall be restricted only for the period of time necessary to accomplish the search and rescue mission. An unauthorized person shall not interfere with a search and rescue mission. </section><section prefix="2">When search and rescue activities result in the discovery of a deceased person or search and rescue workers assist in the recovery of human remains, the chief law enforcement officer of the political subdivision shall insure compliance with the provisions of KRS Chapter 72. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 91, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21802</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>