<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.12-2035</section_number><catch_line>Electronic database of approved program projects -- Annual report -- Programs included -- Coordination with other agencies. </catch_line><order_by>12-2035</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet shall maintain a searchable electronic database on its Web site containing information on the cost and status of the programs listed in subsection (3)(a) of this section. The database shall include all projects approved at any time in the last five (5) years and shall include for each, where applicable, the following information: <section prefix="a">The name of the program, the recipient or participant, the type of project, and its location by county; </section><section prefix="b">Total and approved costs of the project or investment, and the amount of incentives or other benefits authorized; </section><section prefix="c">For the Kentucky Business Investment Program and the Kentucky Enterprise Initiative Act, the amount of incentives or other benefits actually recovered as self-reported by the recipient; </section><section prefix="d">The number of new jobs estimated and for the Kentucky Business Investment Program and the Kentucky Enterprise Initiative Act, actually created, along with wage information for those jobs; </section><section prefix="e">Project status and the date and nature of the most recent activity; and </section><section prefix="f">Any other comparable data or information necessary to achieve transparency and accountability for the specified programs. </section></section><section prefix="2">In addition to the electronic database required in subsection (1) of this section, the cabinet shall submit a single annual report on the programs listed in subsection </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="b">of this section to the Governor and the Legislative Research Commission by </section></section>November 1 of each year. The report shall include all projects approved in the preceding fiscal year and shall provide for these projects the information specified in subsection (1) of this section plus aggregate data for each program, summary evaluations of program activity and effectiveness, and anything required by statute to be reported for any particular program. The report shall also list all projects that were approved in prior years but active at any time in the preceding fiscal year, although for these projects the report need not provide further data. (3) The following programs shall be subject to the reporting requirements of this section: (a) The electronic database required in subsection (1) of this section shall include the Bluegrass State Skills Corporation, grants-in-aid and skills training investment credit; Kentucky Business Investment Program; Kentucky Enterprise Initiative Act; Office of Entrepreneurship programs; Incentives for Energy Independence Act; Kentucky Economic Development Finance Authority small business and direct loan programs; Kentucky Environmental Stewardship Act; Kentucky Industrial Revitalization Act; Kentucky Reinvestment Act; small business investment credit; economic development bonds; Kentucky Industrial Development Act; Kentucky Jobs Development Act; Kentucky Jobs Retention Act; and the Kentucky Rural Economic Development Act; and (b) The single annual report required by subsection (2) of this section shall include all programs listed in paragraph (a) of this subsection plus the Kentucky Investment Fund Act, the Tourism Development Act, film production industry incentives, and tax increment financing, state participation projects. <section prefix="4">The cabinet shall coordinate with the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet and any other agency necessary to supply the information required by this section. </section></text><history> Created 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2014). 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 13, instructs the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in the Act, as it confirms the reorganization of the Cabinet for Economic Development. Such a correction has been made in subsection (3)(a) of this statute. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43514</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>