<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.6401</section_number><catch_line>Fire sprinkler inspection certification -- Eligibility requirements -- Certification cards.  </catch_line><order_by>6401</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The department shall issue a fire sprinkler inspector certification to an applicant who meets the following requirements: <section prefix="a">Is at least eighteen (18) years of age; </section><section prefix="b">Submits a completed fire sprinkler inspector's written or electronic application form as provided by the department; </section><section prefix="c">Provides a certificate of insurance that: <section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">Is issued by an insurance company or other legal entity permitted to transact insurance business in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="b">Insures for general liability coverage of at least five hundred thousand dollars ($500,000); and </section><section prefix="c">Includes liability insurance that shall cover the legal liability of the certified fire sprinkler inspector as the result of erroneous acts or failure to act in his or her capacity as a fire sprinkler inspector and shall be in the form of a certificate of insurance executed by an insurer permitted to do business in this state or exported by a licensed surplus lines broker to an eligible carrier pursuant to KRS 304.10-020 to 304.10-210; or </section></section><section prefix="2">Submits an affidavit completed by a sprinkler contractor that the applicant is and will be an employee of a currently licensed sprinkler contractor in good standing with the department; </section></section><section prefix="d"><section prefix="1">Provides proof of passing scores on all portions of a standardized examination approved by the commissioner; or </section><section prefix="2">Is a current holder of certification from the National Institute for Certification in Engineering Technologies (NICET) for "Inspection and Testing of Water-Based Systems" Level 2 or higher; and </section></section><section prefix="e">Upon request by the department, supplemental documentation of information as required under this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="2">All certification cards issued by the department shall remain the property of the department. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 30, effective July 1, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2011 </effective><lrc-note> (7/1/2011).  References to the "office" of housing, buildings and construction and the "executive director" of housing, buildings and construction in this section, as created by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 30, have been changed in codification to the "department" of housing, buildings and construction and the "commissioner" of housing, buildings and construction, respectively, to reflect the reorganization of certain parts of the Executive Branch, as set forth in Executive Order 2009-535 and confirmed by the General Assembly in 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24. These changes were made by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1938. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-16</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36623</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>