<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="244" order_by="244">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- PROHIBITIONS, RESTRICTIONS, AND REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>244.165</section_number><catch_line>Unlawful sale and shipment by out-of-state seller directly to a Kentucky consumer -- Permissible shipments of wine into Kentucky by out-of-state small farm wineries -- Penalty. </catch_line><order_by>165</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided in subsection (2) of this section, it shall be unlawful for any person in the business of selling alcoholic beverages in another state or country to ship or cause to be shipped any alcoholic beverage directly to any Kentucky resident who does not hold a valid wholesaler or distributor license issued by the Commonwealth of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="2">A small farm winery located in another state may ship wine to a customer in Kentucky if: <section prefix="a">The wine is purchased by the customer in person at the winery; </section><section prefix="b">The wine is shipped by licensed common carrier; and </section><section prefix="c">The amount of wine shipped is limited to two (2) cases per customer per visit. </section></section><section prefix="3">Any person who violates subsection (1) of this section shall, for the first offense, be mailed a certified letter by the department ordering that person to cease and desist any shipments of alcoholic beverages to Kentucky residents, and for the second and each subsequent offense, be guilty of a Class D felony. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 589, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 179, sec. 2, effective January 1, 2007. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 72, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11450</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>