<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIII" order_by="33">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS AND ESTATES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>386B.1-090</section_number><catch_line>Nonjudicial settlement agreements. </catch_line><order_by>1-090</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For purposes of this section, "interested persons" means persons whose consent would be required to achieve a binding settlement were the settlement to be approved by the court. </section><section prefix="2">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (3) of this section, interested persons may enter into a binding nonjudicial settlement agreement with respect to any matter involving a trust. This procedure is not intended to foreclose or limit any other avenue of settlement under the laws of this Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="3">A nonjudicial settlement agreement is valid only to the extent it does not violate a material purpose of the trust and includes conditions that could be properly approved by the court under this chapter or other applicable law. </section><section prefix="4">Matters that may be resolved by a nonjudicial settlement agreement include: <section prefix="a">The interpretation or construction of the terms of the trust; </section><section prefix="b">The approval of a trustee’s report or accounting; </section><section prefix="c">Direction to a trustee to refrain from performing a particular act or the grant to a trustee of any necessary or desirable power; </section><section prefix="d">The resignation or appointment of a trustee and the determination of a trustee’s compensation; </section><section prefix="e">Transfer of a trust’s principal place of administration; and </section><section prefix="f">Liability of a trustee for an action relating to the trust. </section></section><section prefix="5">Any interested person may request the court to approve a nonjudicial settlement agreement, to determine whether the representation under Subchapter 3 of this chapter was adequate, and to determine whether the agreement contains conditions the court could have properly approved. </section><section prefix="6">The District Court shall have exclusive jurisdiction over matters under this section. </section></text><history> Created 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 25, sec. 9, effective July 15, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43072</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>