<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="227" order_by="227">FIRE PREVENTION AND PROTECTION -- ELECTRICIANS </unit></structure><section_number>227.530Electrical</section_number><catch_line>Advisory Committee created -- Members -- Meetings -- Purpose -- Compensation.   </catch_line><order_by>530Electrical</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created an Electrical Advisory Committee which shall be attached to the Electrical Division within the Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction for administrative purposes. The committee shall be constituted as follows: <section prefix="a">Two (2) members chosen from public utility companies; </section><section prefix="b">Two (2) members who are electricians; </section><section prefix="c">Two (2) members who are certified electrical inspectors, one (1) of whom shall be employed by a governmental entity and the other who shall be an electrical inspector contracted to conduct inspections of electrical installations; </section><section prefix="d">Two (2) members who are licensed professional electrical engineers; </section><section prefix="e">Two (2) members who are engaged in the business of electrical contracting; </section><section prefix="f">One (1) member who is engaged in the business of electrical contracting and who employs no more than five (5) full-time employees when appointed; and </section><section prefix="g">The commissioner of the Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction or his or her designee. </section></section><section prefix="2">Appointed committee members shall be appointed by the Governor for four (4) year terms. No committee member shall be appointed for more than one (1) successive term. </section><section prefix="3">The committee shall meet at least quarterly or upon request of the department for the purpose of considering matters relating to electrical installations and electrical inspections. The committee shall have the opportunity to review and comment on relevant administrative regulations that are subject to the requirements of KRS 198B.030(8) and (9) and 198B.040(11) and shall make recommendations to and otherwise advise the department on these matters. </section><section prefix="4">All committee members shall be compensated for expenses incurred in the conduct of Commonwealth business. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 7, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 125, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 16, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 410, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 256, sec. 5, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 17, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 6, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 361, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44582</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>