<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="434" order_by="434">OFFENSES AGAINST PROPERTY BY FRAUD </unit></structure><section_number>434.660</section_number><catch_line>Fraud by authorized persons, business organization, or financial institution. </catch_line><order_by>660</order_by><text>A person, business organization, or financial institution who is authorized by an issuer to furnish money, goods, services, or anything else of value upon presentation of a credit or debit card by a cardholder, or any agent or employee of such person, business organization, or financial institution, who, with intent to defraud the issuer, a participating party, the cardholder, or any other person, furnishes money, goods, or services or anything else of value upon presentation of a credit or debit card obtained or retained in violation of KRS 434.570 to 434.650, or any of such sections, or a credit or debit card which he knows is forged, expired, or revoked is guilty of a Class A misdemeanor, if the value of all money, goods, services, or other things of value furnished in violation of this section over a six (6) month period is less than five hundred dollars ($500), a Class D felony if such value is five hundred dollars ($500) or more but is less than ten thousand dollars ($10,000), or a Class C felony if such value is ten thousand dollars ($10,000) or more. </text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 3, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 463, sec. 56, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 67, sec. 15, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 83, sec. 12. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=18904</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>