<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6">THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY </unit></structure><section_number>6.747</section_number><catch_line>Prohibition against honoraria -- Authorization for certain out-of-state travel -- Penalty. </catch_line><order_by>747</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A legislator shall not accept any compensation in consideration for an appearance, speech, or article unless the appearance, speech, or article is both related to the legislator's employment outside the General Assembly and is unrelated to his or her position as a legislator. </section><section prefix="2">A legislator may accept prepaid transportation, food, and lodging or be reimbursed for actual expenses for out-of-state travel associated with the performance of his or her duties as a legislator if he or she obtains prior approval of the travel from a majority of the Legislative Research Commission. However, a legislative agent or employer shall not furnish or pay for out-of-state transportation or lodging for a legislator. A legislative agent or employer may furnish food, beverages, or local transportation for an event held in conjunction with a meeting of a multistate or national organization referenced in KRS 6.611(2)(b)11., if the event is conducted in accordance with KRS 6.611(2)(b)8.a. to d. The reimbursement of expenses pursuant to this subsection shall be reported to the Legislative Research Commission. </section><section prefix="3">Violation of this section is ethical misconduct. </section></text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 75, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2014. -- Created 1993 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 11, effective September 16, 1993. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43305</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>