<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="157" order_by="157">STATE SUPPORT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>157.3175</section_number><catch_line>Preschool education program -- Grant allocation – Eligibility for free preschool education -- Program components.   </catch_line><order_by>3175</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each local school district shall assure that a developmentally appropriate half-day preschool education program is provided for each child who is at risk of educational failure and who is four (4) years of age: <section prefix="a">By October 1, for any year prior to 2017; or </section><section prefix="b">By August 1, for 2017 or any year thereafter. </section></section> All other four (4) year old children shall be served to the extent placements are available. The Kentucky Board of Education, upon the recommendation of the chief state school officer, shall adopt administrative regulations establishing the guidelines for the program. Administrative regulations shall establish eligibility criteria, program guidelines, and standards for personnel. <section prefix="2">"Developmentally appropriate preschool program" means a program which focuses on the physical, intellectual, social, and emotional development of young children. The preschool program shall help children with their interpersonal and socialization skills. </section><section prefix="3">Funds appropriated by the General Assembly for the preschool education programs shall be granted to local school districts according to a grant allotment system approved by the Kentucky Board of Education. Children who are at risk shall be identified based on the Federal School Lunch Program eligibility criteria for free lunch. Appropriations shall be separate from all other funds appropriated to the Department of Education and shall be administered in accordance with applicable federal and state statutes and administrative regulations. Eligible local school districts shall receive funds based on the average number of preschool children being served on December 1 and March 1 of the prior academic year who are appropriately identified as: <section prefix="a">Three (3) and four (4) years of age with disabilities; and </section><section prefix="b">Four (4) years of age identified as at risk of educational failure. </section></section> Local school districts may develop cooperative arrangements with other school districts or organizations in accordance with KRS 157.280. <section prefix="4">A child shall be eligible for a free and appropriate preschool education and related services if: <section prefix="a"><section prefix="1">The child has been identified as a child with a disability in accordance with the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act, 20 U.S.C. secs. 1400 et seq.; or </section><section prefix="2">The child has been identified in accordance with the definitions and procedures for exceptional children and youth in accordance with KRS 157.200(1)(a) to (m); and </section></section><section prefix="b">The child is three (3) or four (4) years of age: <section prefix="1">By October 1, for any year before 2017; or </section><section prefix="2">By August 1, for 2017 or any year thereafter. </section></section></section><section prefix="5">The chief state school officer shall receive and review proposals from local school districts for grants to operate or oversee the operation of developmentally appropriate preschool education programs. Districts may submit proposals for implementing new services, enhancing existing preschool education services, or contracting for services. In designing a local early childhood education program, each district shall work with existing preschool programs to avoid duplication of programs and services, to avoid supplanting federal funds, and to maximize Head Start funds in order to serve as many four (4) year old children as possible. </section><section prefix="6">Each program proposal shall include, at a minimum: <section prefix="a">A description of the process conducted by the district to assure that the parents or guardians of all eligible participants have been made aware of the program and of their right to participate; </section><section prefix="b">A description of the planned educational programming and related services; </section><section prefix="c">The estimated number of children participating in the program; </section><section prefix="d">Strategies for involving children with disabilities; </section><section prefix="e">Estimated ratio of staff to children with the maximum being one (1) adult for each ten (10) children; </section><section prefix="f">The estimated percentage of children participating in the program who are at risk of educational failure; </section><section prefix="g">Information on the training and qualifications of program staff and documentation that the staff meet required standards; </section><section prefix="h">A budget and per-child expenditure estimate; </section><section prefix="i">A plan to facilitate active parental involvement in the preschool program, including provisions for complementary parent education when appropriate; </section><section prefix="j">Facilities and equipment which are appropriate for young children; </section><section prefix="k">The days of the week and hours of a day during which the program shall operate; </section><section prefix="l">A plan for coordinating the program with existing medical and social services, including a child development and health screening component; </section><section prefix="m">Assurances that participants shall receive breakfast or lunch; </section><section prefix="n">Program sites which meet state and local licensure requirements; </section><section prefix="o">A plan for coordinating program philosophy and activities with the local district's primary school program; </section><section prefix="p">An evaluation component; and </section><section prefix="q">Certification from the Head Start director that the Head Start program is fully utilized pursuant to subsection (4) of this section. </section></section><section prefix="7">Programs shall reflect an equitable geographic distribution representative of all areas of the Commonwealth. </section></text><history>Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2013, and ch. 102, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 456, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. I, sec. 16, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, C, 3, (4) at 629. See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, C, 3, (6) at 629. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><lrc-note>(6/25/2013). This statute was amended by 2013 Ky. Acts chs. 86 and 102. Where those Acts are not in conflict, they have been codified together. Where a conflict exists, Acts ch. 86, which was last enacted by the General Assembly, prevails under KRS 446.250. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42321</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>