<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="335" order_by="335">SOCIAL WORKERS AND PROFESSIONAL COUNSELORS </unit></structure><section_number>335.340</section_number><catch_line>Renewal of licensure -- Suspended or revoked license -- Continuing education. </catch_line><order_by>340</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Licensure issued under KRS 335.330 shall be renewed annually upon payment of a fee to be established by administrative regulation promulgated by the board not to exceed one hundred fifty dollars ($150). </section><section prefix="2">On January 1, 1999, all persons authorized to use the title "certified marriage and family therapist" shall be deemed "licensed marriage and family therapists" until the date of their second annual license renewal. As of that date, each formerly certified licensee seeking license renewal shall provide the board with verification of education or experience relating to psychopathology, as determined by administrative regulations promulgated by the board, to include: <section prefix="a">Coursework in psychopathology; </section><section prefix="b">Supervised experience with a focus on diagnosis; or </section><section prefix="c">Completion of equivalent continuing education units relating to psychopathology. </section></section> This subsection shall not apply to license renewals for those persons also licensed or certified by another mental health profession which authorizes diagnosis within its scope of practice. <section prefix="3">A ninety (90) day grace period shall be granted during which time licensees may continue to practice and may renew their licenses upon payment of the renewal fee plus a late renewal fee as promulgated by administrative regulation of the board. Any license not renewed during this period shall expire. The board may reinstate an expired license within three (3) years of its expiration date upon payment of the renewal fee and satisfaction of other requirements. </section><section prefix="4">A suspended license is subject to expiration and termination and shall be renewed as provided in this chapter. Renewal shall not entitle the licensee to engage in the practice of marriage and family therapy until the suspension has ended, or is otherwise removed by the board and the right to practice is restored by the board. </section><section prefix="5">A revoked license is subject to expiration or termination but may not be renewed. If it is reinstated, the licensee shall pay the renewal fee as set forth in subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="6">A person who fails to reinstate his or her license within three (3) years of its termination may not have it renewed, restored, reissued, or reinstated. A person may apply for and obtain a new license by meeting the current requirements of this chapter. </section><section prefix="7">The board shall require that a person applying for renewal or reinstatement of licensure show evidence of completion of continuing education as prescribed by the board by administrative regulations, not to exceed twenty (20) clock hours per renewal period. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 594, sec. 10, effective January 1, 1999. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 352, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 1999 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31948</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>