<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="212" order_by="212">LOCAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>212.632</section_number><catch_line>Board membership. </catch_line><order_by>632</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall be composed of thirteen (13) members, one (1) of whom shall be an ex officio member and the mayor of the urban-county government, one (1) of whom shall be an ex officio member and a member of the urban-county government legislative body and appointed by the mayor, and eleven (11) of whom shall be appointed by the mayor with the approval of the urban-county government legislative body. Of the eleven (11) appointed members, three (3) shall be licensed and practicing physicians, one (1) a licensed and practicing dentist, one (1) a licensed and practicing registered nurse, and six (6) members at large. Appointment of the physician, dentist, and nurse shall be made from a list of three (3) nominees submitted by any of the respective county professional societies for which a vacancy exists. All appointed members shall reside in the county of the board to which they are appointed and shall be eligible for reappointment. </section><section prefix="2">At the expiration of any term of office, the successor to each member shall be appointed in the manner prescribed under the provisions of subsection (1) of this section for a term of office of two (2) years and until the successor is appointed and qualified. </section><section prefix="3">All vacancies occurring on the board by reason of death, resignation, disqualification, removal, or otherwise shall be filled for the unexpired term in the manner prescribed under the provisions of subsection (1) of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2002; and ch. 214, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 347, sec. 6, effective July 1, 1977. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><lrc-note> ((7/15/2002).  This section was amended by 2002 Ky. Acts chs.80 and 214, which are in conflict. Under KRS 446.250, Acts ch.214, which was last enacted by the General Assembly, prevails. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8653</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>