<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="70" order_by="70">SHERIFFS, CONSTABLES, AND COUNTY POLICE FORCE </unit></structure><section_number>70.267</section_number><catch_line>Prohibited conduct -- Construction of section -- Probationary period. </catch_line><order_by>267</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No deputy sheriff covered by the provisions of KRS 70.260 to 70.273 shall directly or indirectly solicit, receive, or be in any manner concerned in receiving, soliciting, or publicizing any assessment, gift, subscription, or contribution to or for any political party or candidate for public office. </section><section prefix="2">No deputy sheriff covered by the provisions of KRS 70.260 to 70.273 shall be suspended, laid-off, demoted, promoted, disciplined, threatened, or in any way changed in duty or compensation for withholding or neglecting to pay or make contributions of any sort, either in money, goods, services, or anything of value for any political purpose. Nothing in this subsection shall limit the power of a sheriff to revoke the appointment of a deputy during the probationary period described in subsection (5) of this section. </section><section prefix="3">No deputy sheriff covered by the provisions of KRS 70.260 to 70.273 shall be a candidate for any public office. Any person who violates this subsection shall forfeit his position as deputy sheriff. </section><section prefix="4">Nothing contained in this section shall be construed to abridge the rights of any deputy sheriff with respect to his personal opinions, beliefs, or right to vote. </section><section prefix="5">A deputy sheriff's employment shall be probationary during the first year of service following an initial appointment or a promotional appointment. A sheriff may, at his pleasure, revoke the appointment of a deputy who works for him at any time within one (1) year following the appointment. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 334, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 438, sec. 3, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24221</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>