<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="91" order_by="91">A FINANCE AND REVENUE OF CITIES </unit></structure><section_number>91A.0810</section_number><catch_line>Identification of amount of local government tax charged and taxing jurisdiction due tax -- Notice to policyholders. </catch_line><order_by>0810</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Effective December 31, 2008, if the local government premium tax is included in the premium charge to the policyholder, the insurance company shall include the amount of the local government tax charged for the period and the name of the taxing jurisdiction to which the local premium tax is due for: <section prefix="a">Newly issued policies on the: <section prefix="1">Policy; </section><section prefix="2">Declaration sheet; or </section><section prefix="3">Initial billing instruments; and </section></section><section prefix="b">Renewed policies on the: <section prefix="1">Renewal certificate; or </section><section prefix="2">Billing instrument for each period for which premium or additional premium is charged to a policyholder by the insurance company. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">Before December 31, 2008, each insurance company shall cause each current policyholder to be notified of the policyholder's rights under this chapter. The one (1) time notice may be sent to the policyholder under any mode of communication normally used between the insurance company and the policyholder and may be sent as a separate notice or included as an additional item within routine statements, billings, or other notices. The Kentucky Department of Insurance shall promulgate by administrative regulation the text of such notice, which shall include: <section prefix="a">A statement that past and future premium charges may include a local insurance premium tax; and </section><section prefix="b">A statement that a policyholder who has been erroneously charged or overcharged the local insurance premium tax may obtain information for requesting a refund or credit by contacting the insurance company to which the local insurance premium tax was erroneously paid. </section></section><section prefix="3">Any insurance company contacted by a policyholder under subsection (2) of this section shall, within thirty (30) days of the contact, provide the policyholder the full text of KRS 91A.0804(4) to inform the policyholder of the procedural requirements for requesting a refund or a credit. The insurance company may, at its option, include a summary or explanation of the procedural requirements in addition to providing the text. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 80, effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 165, secs. 3 and 6, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 94, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  This section was amended by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 80, and ch. 165, secs. 3 and 6, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:10</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=25573</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>