<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="278" order_by="278">PUBLIC SERVICE COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>278.542</section_number><catch_line>Effect of KRS 278.541 to 278.544 on commission's jurisdiction -- Filing by telephone utilities required. </catch_line><order_by>542</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Nothing in KRS 278.541 to 278.544 shall affect the commission's jurisdiction with respect to: <section prefix="a">Any agreement or arrangement between or among ILECs; </section><section prefix="b">Any agreement or arrangement between or among ILECs and other local exchange carriers; </section><section prefix="c">Consumer complaints as to compliance with basic local exchange service obligations, and the quality of basic voice-grade service transmission for basic and nonbasic services, consistent with accepted industry standards for telecommunications services; </section><section prefix="d">The emergency 911 telephone service as set forth in KRS 65.750 to 65.760 or wireless enhanced emergency 911 systems as set forth in KRS 65.7621 to 65.7643; </section><section prefix="e">Accuracy of billing for telecommunications services, in accordance with the truth-in-billing regulations prescribed by the Federal Communications Commission; </section><section prefix="f">Assessments as set forth in KRS 278.130, 278.140, and 278.150; </section><section prefix="g">Unauthorized change of telecommunications providers or "slamming" under KRS 278.535; </section><section prefix="h">Billing of telecommunications services not ordered by or on behalf of the consumer or "cramming" to the extent that such services do not comply with the truth-in-billing regulations prescribed by the Federal Communications Commission; </section><section prefix="i">The federal Universal Service Fund and Lifeline Services Program and any Kentucky state counterpart; </section><section prefix="j">Any special telephone service programs as set forth in KRS 278.547 to 278.5499; </section><section prefix="k">Tariffs, except as expressly provided for in KRS 278.541 to 278.544; </section><section prefix="l">Setting objectives for performance as to basic local exchange service; except that the objectives shall not exceed existing commission standards or associated penalties as of July 12, 2006; </section><section prefix="m">Prohibiting price differences among retail telecommunications customers to the extent that such differences are attributable to race, creed, color, religion, sex, or national origin; or </section><section prefix="n">Ensuring that a telephone utility furnishes safe, adequate, and reasonable basic local exchange service to customers within that utility’s service area. </section></section><section prefix="2">Telephone utilities operating pursuant to KRS 278.541 to 278.544 shall file with the commission a form containing: <section prefix="a">The complete name of the telephone utility; </section><section prefix="b">The physical address of its principal office; and </section><section prefix="c">The name, title, and telephone number of the person responsible for answering consumer complaints on behalf of the telephone utility. </section></section><section prefix="3">No telephone utility shall engage in predatory pricing as defined by the United States Supreme Court in Brooke Group Ltd. v. Brown &amp; Williamson Tobacco Corp., 509 U.S. 209 (1993). </section><section prefix="4">Nothing in KRS 278.541 to 278.544 shall affect the alternative regulation process for small telephone utilities as set forth in KRS 278.516. </section></text><history> Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14150</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>