<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.35-010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for subchapter. </catch_line><order_by>35-010</order_by><text>As used in this subchapter, unless the context indicates otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Beneficiary of an economic incentive package" means any entity for which any assessment, incentive, inducement, or tax credit is issued or awarded pursuant to KRS 154.22-010 to 154.22-070, KRS 154.24-010 to 154.24-150, KRS 154.26-015 to 154.26-100, and KRS 154.28-010 to 154.28-090; </section><section prefix="2">"Board" means the governance board of the Kentucky Science and Technology Council, Inc.; </section><section prefix="3">"Cabinet" means the Cabinet for Economic Development; </section><section prefix="4">"Center" means either or both of the following as the context requires: <section prefix="a">"Basic research centers" which means centers under contract with the University of Kentucky and the University of Louisville; and </section><section prefix="b">"Applied research centers" which means centers for applied research and technologies development; </section></section><section prefix="5">"Commonwealth" means the Commonwealth of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="6">"Council" means the Kentucky Science and Technology Council, Inc.; </section><section prefix="7">"Fund" means the Kentucky Research and Development Infrastructure fund created and established pursuant to KRS 154.35-040; </section><section prefix="8">"Infrastructure" means the Kentucky Research and Development Infrastructure; </section><section prefix="9">"Contracting university" means any of the following that contract with the council to operate a center: the University of Kentucky, the University of Louisville, Eastern Kentucky University, Western Kentucky University, Morehead State University, Northern Kentucky University, Murray State University, and Kentucky State University; and </section><section prefix="10">"Secretary" means the secretary of the Cabinet for Economic Development. </section></text><history> Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 508, sec. 48, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2904</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>