<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="64" order_by="64">FEES AND COMPENSATION OF PUBLIC OFFICERS AND EMPLOYEES </unit></structure><section_number>64.690</section_number><catch_line>Applicability of other statutes dealing with compensation -- Applicability of KRS 64.368 if population decreases below 70,000. </catch_line><order_by>690</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided in KRS 64.610 and in this section, KRS 64.480 to 64.740 are intended to supersede any existing statute, fixing the compensation, or authorizing any public officer or body to fix the compensation, of any public officer or employee covered by KRS 64.480 to 64.740. </section><section prefix="2">Any public officer or body which has authority to fix the compensation of any state officer or employee covered by KRS 64.640 shall exercise such authority, subject to the schedule and limits of compensation for the particular office or position prescribed in KRS 64.640. The secretary of the Personnel Cabinet shall have the authority to monitor and require compliance with the provisions of this section and KRS 64.640 and 64.475. </section><section prefix="3">KRS 64.480 to 64.740 are not intended to supersede any existing statute, with respect to the compensation of circuit clerks, county clerks, sheriffs, master commissioners, and receivers, and their deputies and assistants, in counties containing a population of seventy thousand (70,000) or more, or property valuation administrators, their deputies, and assistants, in any county. </section><section prefix="4">If a county's population that equaled or exceeded seventy thousand (70,000) is less than seventy thousand (70,000) after the most recent federal decennial census, then the provisions of KRS 64.368 shall apply. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 495, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000. --  Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 220, sec. 9, effective January 1, 1994. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 385, sec. 24, effective July 1, 1982. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 77. -- Created 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 27. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23293</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>