<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="48" order_by="48">BUDGET </unit></structure><section_number>48.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Account" is a technical accounting term meaning a formal record in which related transactions and events, (i.e., expenditures, receipts, encumbrances, and inter-account charges or credits) which occur during a specific period of time, are summarized and accumulated; </section><section prefix="2">"Activities" means those actions or services performed by a budget unit which depict in a quantitative manner the fulfillment of lawful purposes; </section><section prefix="3">Appropriation-related terms are defined for procedures prescribed by this chapter as follows: <section prefix="a">"Appropriation" means an authorization by the General Assembly to expend a sum of money not in excess of the sum specified, for the purposes specified in the authorization and under the procedure prescribed in this chapter; </section><section prefix="b">"Appropriation provision" means a section of any enactment by the General Assembly which is not provided for by this chapter and which authorizes the expenditure of funds other than by a general appropriation bill; and </section><section prefix="c">"General appropriation bill" means an enactment by the General Assembly that authorizes the expenditure of funds in a branch budget bill as provided for by this chapter; </section></section><section prefix="4">"Biennial highway construction plan" means the specifically identified individual transportation projects or portions thereof identified for funding during the upcoming biennium, which correspond to the first two (2) years of the six (6) year road plan; </section><section prefix="5">"Budget" means the complete financial plan for each fiscal year contained in a branch budget bill provided for by this chapter; </section><section prefix="6">"Branch budget bill" or "branch budget" means an enactment by the General Assembly which provides appropriations and establishes fiscal policies and conditions for the biennial financial plan for the judicial branch, the legislative branch, and the executive branch, which shall include a separate budget bill for the Transportation Cabinet; </section><section prefix="7">"Branch budget recommendation" means the recommendations made to the General Assembly by: <section prefix="a">The Governor for the executive branch, including a separate recommendation for the Transportation Cabinet; </section><section prefix="b">The Chief Justice for the judicial branch; and </section><section prefix="c">The Legislative Research Commission for the legislative branch; </section></section><section prefix="8">"Budget unit request" means a detailed statement of the financial requirements of a budget unit by principal budget class, and an estimate of its receipts and expenditures for the next two (2) fiscal years, with the accompanying explanations provided for by this chapter; </section><section prefix="9">"Budget unit" or "appropriation unit" means any subdivision of any branch of government, however designated in any branch budget bill; </section><section prefix="10">"Capital outlay" means the exchange of values involved in acquiring lands, buildings, equipment, or other permanent properties, or in their construction, development, or permanent improvement; </section><section prefix="11">"Consensus forecasting group" means the group established by KRS 48.115 that is responsible for developing consensus revenue forecasts for the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="12">"Disbursement" means cash actually paid out for any purpose; </section><section prefix="13">"Enacted estimates" means the revenue estimates used by the General Assembly as the basis for appropriations made in the enacted branch budget bills; </section><section prefix="14">"Expenditure" means cash actually paid out or an exchange of value for any purpose; </section><section prefix="15">"Fund" means an independent fiscal and accounting entity with a self-balancing set of accounts recording cash or other resources or both together with all related liabilities, obligations, reserves, and equities which are segregated for the purpose of carrying on specific activities in accordance with legal restrictions or other limitations, to include: <section prefix="a">"General Fund." This fund shall consist of all moneys, not otherwise restricted, available for the general operations of state government; </section><section prefix="b">"Bond Debt Related Fund." This fund shall consist of all outstanding bonded debt liability and related funds of state government, including all revenue bonds issued by or approved by the State Property and Buildings Commission. Accounts necessary to assure integrity of trust indentures shall be maintained. Funds appropriated for debt service shall be allotted to these accounts and any excess of appropriation over net requirements for principal, interest, and reserves for any issue shall lapse to the surplus account of the general fund if general funds are a part of the appropriation for that budget unit; </section><section prefix="c">"Capital Construction Fund." This fund shall consist of moneys appropriated under the provision of KRS 45.750 to 45.800 for capital construction projects, except road construction projects, for all budget units of state government; </section><section prefix="d">"Federal Fund." This fund shall include all receipts from the federal government for any purpose; </section><section prefix="e">"Fiduciary Fund." This fund shall consist of moneys held by a budget unit in a trustee capacity; </section><section prefix="f">"Restricted Fund." This fund shall consist of budget unit receipts restricted as to purpose by statute; and </section><section prefix="g">"Road Fund." This fund shall consist of money derived from excise or license taxation relating to gasoline and other motor fuels, and moneys derived from fees, excise or license taxation relating to registration, operation, or use of vehicles for use on public highways. A separate record of each source of receipt within this fund group shall be maintained; </section></section><section prefix="16">"Principal budget class" includes the following: <section prefix="a">"Capital outlay" means the exchange of values involved in acquiring lands, buildings, or other permanent properties, or in their construction, development, or permanent improvement estimated to cost less than six hundred thousand dollars ($600,000), and items of equipment or other capital items estimated to cost less than two hundred thousand dollars ($200,000); </section><section prefix="b">"Debt service" means the amount of money required to pay the interest, principal, and required contributions to accumulate moneys for future retirement of lawfully incurred debt; </section><section prefix="c">"Grants, loans, or benefits" means expenditures for any grant, aid, loan, or relief payment to individuals, organizations, or jurisdictions not otherwise classified pursuant to this chapter; </section><section prefix="d">"Operating expenses" means expenditures directly attributable to the operation of state government not otherwise classified pursuant to this chapter; and </section><section prefix="e">"Personnel costs" means the salaries, wages, benefits (including but not limited to, employer share of FICA, retirement contributions, insurance, unemployment insurance, workers' compensation), and increments of all officers and employees, and payment to persons awarded personal service contracts; </section></section><section prefix="17">"Receipts" includes the following: <section prefix="a">"Nonrevenue receipts" means values accruing that either decrease an asset or create a liability; </section><section prefix="b">"Operating receipts" means cash received by a budget unit for services rendered, or from the sale of materials, goods, or supplies created by the budget unit or of items held for resale; and </section><section prefix="c">"Revenue receipts" means values accruing as a result of taxation or revenues, or both, and without resultant increase in liabilities or decrease in assets, whether such values are represented by cash actually received or by amounts due and payable, or partly by each; </section></section><section prefix="18">"Revenue shortfall" means either: <section prefix="a">An official revenue estimate for either the general fund or road fund that is less than the enacted estimates; or </section><section prefix="b">Actual receipts at the end of the fiscal year for either the general fund or road fund that are less than the enacted estimates, as determined by the Office of State Budget Director; </section></section><section prefix="19">"Surplus" means the undesignated fiscal year ending fund balance for the general fund or road fund, reduced by amounts designated to carry forward for appropriation in a subsequent fiscal year; </section><section prefix="20">"Six (6) year road plan" means the road plan developed under KRS 176.430; and </section><section prefix="21">"Writing" or "written" means letters, words, or numbers, or their equivalent, set down by handwriting, typewriting, printing, photostating, photographing, magnetic impulse, mechanical or electronic recording, or other form of data compilation. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 21, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 31, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 387, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 507, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 450, sec. 1, effective July 1, 1983. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22534</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>