<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="141" order_by="141">INCOME TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>141.0406</section_number><catch_line>Time frame for claiming coal incentive tax credit allowed under KRS 141.0405. </catch_line><order_by>0406</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except in the case of an alternative fuel facility as defined in KRS 154.27-010 or a gasification facility as defined in KRS 154.27-010, the Coal Incentive Credit authorized under KRS 141.0405 shall be allowed for ten (10) consecutive years beginning on July 15, 2001. </section><section prefix="2">In the case of an alternative fuel facility as defined in KRS 154.27-010 or a gasification facility as defined in KRS 154.27-010, the Coal Incentive Credit authorized by KRS 141.0405 shall be allowed for tax periods beginning after December 31, 2008, and ending before January 1, 2021. </section><section prefix="3">Continuation of the credit authorized under this section shall require reauthorization by the General Assembly. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 (2d Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 19, effective August 30, 2007. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 320, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> August 30, 2007 </effective><lrc-note> (7/14/2000).  Although 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 320, sec. 3, directed that this section was created as a new section of KRS Chapter 131, the statute has been codified in KRS Chapter 141 because that chapter of the statutes is the more logical placement and, given the subject matter of the two KRS chapters, the assignment to KRS Chapter 131 may well have been a typographical error. See KRS 7.136(1)(a). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:01</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29047</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>