<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="218" order_by="218">A CONTROLLED SUBSTANCES </unit></structure><section_number>218A.200</section_number><catch_line>Record-keeping and inventory requirements -- Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>200</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every practitioner who is authorized to administer or professionally use controlled substances, shall keep a record of substances received by him, and a record of all substances administered, dispensed, or professionally used by him otherwise than by prescription. Every such record shall be kept for a period of five (5) years. </section><section prefix="2">Manufacturers and wholesalers shall keep records of all controlled substances compounded, mixed, cultivated, grown, or by any other process produced or prepared, and of all controlled substances received and disposed of by them. Every such record shall be kept for a period of two (2) years. </section><section prefix="3">Pharmacists shall keep records of all controlled substances received and disposed of by them. Every such record shall be kept for a period of five (5) years. </section><section prefix="4">The record of controlled substances received shall in every case show the date of receipt, the name and address of the person from whom received, and the kind and quantity of drugs received. The record of all controlled substances sold, administered, dispensed, or otherwise disposed of, shall show the date of selling, administering, or dispensing, the name and address of the person to whom, or for whose use, or the owner and species of animal for which the drugs were sold, administered, or dispensed, and the kind and quantity. </section><section prefix="5">The keeping of a record under the federal controlled substances laws, containing substantially the same information as is specified in subsection (4) of this section, shall constitute compliance with this section. </section><section prefix="6">A copy of the detailed list of controlled substances lost, destroyed, or stolen shall be forwarded to the Cabinet for Health and Family Services as soon as practical. </section><section prefix="7"><section prefix="a">Every manufacturer, distributor, wholesaler, repacker, practitioner, pharmacist, or other person authorized to possess controlled substances shall take an inventory of all controlled substances in his possession at least every two (2) years. </section><section prefix="b">A substance which is added to any schedule of controlled substances and which was not previously listed in any schedule shall be initially inventoried within thirty (30) days of the effective date of the statute or administrative regulation which adds the substance to the provisions of this chapter. Thereafter, the substance shall be included in the inventory required by paragraph (a) of this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="8">Any person who violates any provision of this section shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor for a first offense and a Class D felony for subsequent offenses. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 542, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 301, sec. 25, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 426, sec. 485, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(3). -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 21. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9676</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>