<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.12-310</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Innovation and Commercialization Centers -- Organization -- Powers of commissioner. </catch_line><order_by>12-310</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Innovation and Commercialization Centers are private-public partnerships, operating as a cohesive statewide infrastructure to support the implementation of key Kentucky Innovation Act initiatives. </section><section prefix="2">The organization of the ICCs shall include a central statewide headquarters, six (6) affiliate centers, and a number of satellite offices. <section prefix="a">The central headquarters has primary responsibility for the following: <section prefix="1">Managing and administering the ICC Program; </section><section prefix="2">Establishing uniform program application, protocol, and operating guidelines when appropriate; </section><section prefix="3">Supporting the protocol by creating and funding centralized services to be distributed throughout the network; and </section><section prefix="4">Identifying those issues, opportunities, and challenges that have statewide implications. </section></section><section prefix="b">The regional affiliates are responsible for fulfilling the duties as set forth in KRS 154.12-305 relating to the implementation of the region's innovation strategic plan and supporting the implementation of the Kentucky Innovation Act initiatives in the region or subregion; </section><section prefix="c">The satellites are responsible for generating technology business development in their assigned geographic area, acting as a bridge between individuals and businesses needing critical early state concept and development work and the affiliate centers that can provide this support. </section></section> The affiliates and satellites provide a valuable assurance for equal access to the Kentucky Innovation Act initiatives and funding, and provide an opportunity for full participation in rural and remote, as well as metropolitan, areas of the state. <section prefix="3">The commissioner shall have all the powers and authority, not explicitly prohibited by statute, necessary and convenient to carry out and effectuate the purposes of KRS 154.12-300 to 154.12-310. </section><section prefix="4">The commissioner may, in effectuating the provisions of KRS 154.12-300 to 154.12-310, contract with a science and technology organization as defined in KRS 164.6011 to administer and manage the ICC Program. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 98, sec. 9, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 230, sec. 11, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2657</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>