<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="272" order_by="272">COOPERATIVE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>272.440</section_number><catch_line>Board of directors. </catch_line><order_by>440</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The affairs of the association shall be managed by a board of not less than five (5) directors, elected by the members from their own number. The bylaws may provide that the territory in which the association has members shall be divided into districts and that the directors shall be elected according to such districts, either directly or by district delegates elected by the members in that district. In such a case the bylaws shall specify the number of directors to be elected by each district, the manner and method of reapportioning the directors and of redistricting the territory covered by the association. The bylaws may provide that primary elections shall be held in each district to elect the directors apportioned to such districts and that the result of all such primary elections may be ratified by the next regular meeting of the association or may be considered final as to the association. The bylaws may provide that one or more directors may be appointed by any public official or commission or by the other directors selected by the members or their delegates. Such directors shall represent primarily the interest of the general public in such associations. The director or directors so appointed need not be members of the association, but shall have the same powers and rights as other directors. Such directors shall not number more than one-fifth (1/5) of the entire number of directors.  </section><section prefix="2">An association may provide a fair remuneration for the time actually spent by its officers and directors in its service and for the service of the members of its executive committee. No director, during the term of his office, shall be a party to a contract for profit with the association differing in any way from the business relations accorded regular members of the association or others, or differing from terms generally current in that district.  </section><section prefix="3">The bylaws may provide for an executive committee and may allot to such committee all the functions and powers of the board of directors, subject to the general direction and control of the board.  </section><section prefix="4">When a vacancy on the board of directors occurs other than by expiration of term, the remaining members of the board, by a majority vote, shall fill the vacancy, unless the bylaws provide for an election of directors by district. In such a case the board of directors shall immediately call a special meeting of the members in that district to fill the vacancy. </section></text><history>Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 88, sec. 10. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13577</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>