<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="7" order_by="7">LEGISLATIVE RESEARCH COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>7.103</section_number><catch_line>Interim joint committees -- Monthly meeting schedule -- Commission authorized to adopt new interim joint committee structure. </catch_line><order_by>103</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">The monthly meeting schedule for interim joint committees of the Legislative Research Commission shall begin on June 1 and continue through December 1 of each year. During that period, upon agreement of the co-chairs, an interim joint committee shall have the authority to meet according to the most recent regular monthly meeting schedule approved by a majority of the entire membership of the Commission. With an affirmative vote of a majority of its entire membership, the Commission may alter the beginning and concluding dates of authorization granted in this subsection for regular monthly meetings of interim joint committees during the current calendar year, authorize any additional meeting of any interim joint committee, or disapprove any meeting of any interim joint committee. </section><section prefix="b">The co-chairs of each interim joint committee shall have joint responsibility for approving meeting agendas and presiding at meetings. If the co-chairs of any interim joint committee cannot agree on convening a monthly meeting, each co-chair, with the agreement of the presiding officer of the co-chair's chamber, may convene a meeting of the interim joint committee members who are members of the co-chair's chamber. If such a meeting is convened, it shall be on the regular monthly meeting date of the interim joint committee, and it shall be staffed by the Commission. Not more than three (3) such meetings shall be convened by each co-chair in a calendar year. </section><section prefix="c">Subcommittees of interim joint committees shall be authorized to meet according to the policies and practices of the Commission. </section></section><section prefix="2">For purposes of this section, "interim joint committees" means those subcommittees of the Commission which are constituted by combining the membership of Senate and House standing committees pursuant to the most recent interim joint committee structure approved by a majority of the entire membership of the Commission. After March 31, 2003, until such time as the Commission, by an affirmative vote of a majority of its entire membership, adopts a new interim joint committee structure, the most recent interim joint committee structure adopted by the Commission shall be considered to include an Interim Joint Committee on Seniors, Veterans, Military Affairs, and Public Protection, consisting of the members of the Senate Standing Committee on Veterans, Military Affairs, and Public Protection and the House Standing Committee on Seniors, Military Affairs, and Public Safety. </section></text><history> Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 185, sec. 10, effective March 31, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> March 31, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=455</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>