<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="508" order_by="508">ASSAULT AND RELATED OFFENSES </unit></structure><section_number>508.078</section_number><catch_line>Terroristic threatening in the second degree. </catch_line><order_by>078</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of terroristic threatening in the second degree when, other than as provided in KRS 508.075, he or she intentionally: <section prefix="a">With respect to a school function, threatens to commit any act likely to result in death or serious physical injury to any student group, teacher, volunteer worker, or employee of a public or private elementary or secondary school, vocational school, or institution of postsecondary education, or to any other person reasonably expected to lawfully be on school property or at a school-sanctioned activity, if the threat is related to their employment by a school, or work or attendance at school, or a school function. A threat directed at a person or persons or at a school does not need to identify a specific person or persons or school in order for a violation of this section to occur; </section><section prefix="b">Makes false statements that he or she has placed a weapon of mass destruction at any location other than one specified in KRS 508.075; or </section><section prefix="c">Without lawful authority places a counterfeit weapon of mass destruction at any location other than one specified in KRS 508.075. </section></section><section prefix="2">A counterfeit weapon of mass destruction is placed with lawful authority if it is placed as part of an official training exercise by a public servant, as defined in KRS 522.010. </section><section prefix="3">A person is not guilty of commission of an offense under this section if he or she, innocently and believing the information to be true, communicates a threat made by another person to school personnel, a peace officer, a law enforcement agency, a public agency involved in emergency response, or a public safety answering point and identifies the person from whom the threat was communicated, if known. </section><section prefix="4">Terroristic threatening in the second degree is a Class D felony. </section></text><history> Created 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 2, effective June 21, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> June 21, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19737</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>