<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="95" order_by="95">A FIRE PROTECTION PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>95A.240</section_number><catch_line>Funds administered by commission. </catch_line><order_by>240</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commission shall administer the fund pursuant to the provisions of KRS 95A.200 to 95A.300 and may issue such reasonable rules and regulations as, in its discretion, will facilitate the administration of the fund and further the purposes of KRS 95A.200 to 95A.300. </section><section prefix="2">The commission shall determine which local governments are eligible to share in the fund and may withhold or terminate payments to any local government that does not comply with the requirements of KRS 95A.200 to 95A.300 or the rules and regulations issued by the commission thereunder. </section><section prefix="3">The commission shall, from the moneys appropriated to and accruing to the fund from any source, reimburse the Kentucky Community and Technical College System for salaries and other costs of administering the fund, including, but not limited to the costs of commission operations. The amount of reimbursement for any given year shall be determined by the commission and shall not exceed five percent (5%) of the total appropriation to the fund for that year. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 270, sec. 4, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 381, sec. 5, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 327, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 125, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 373, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:08</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26142</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>