<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="273" order_by="273">RELIGIOUS, CHARITABLE, AND EDUCATIONAL SOCIETIES -- NONSTOCK, NONPROFIT CORPORATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>273.415</section_number><catch_line>Organization -- Separate organizations to provide specific services otherwise unavailable. </catch_line><order_by>415</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A community action agency shall be organized and shall operate subject to the provisions of KRS 273.405 to 273.453. To the extent KRS 273.405 to 273.453 are inconsistent with the provisions of this chapter, the provisions of KRS 273.405 to 273.453 shall be controlling. </section><section prefix="2">A community action agency shall be organized and operate subject to the provisions of KRS 65.210 through 65.300 and KRS 273.405 to 273.453. </section><section prefix="3">One (1) or more community action agencies may form a separate organization to provide a specific service that would be otherwise unavailable to low income persons within the community action agencies' service area. The board of any organization so formed shall include local elected officials from the service area, representatives of the private sector in the service area and representatives of the community action agencies in the service area to ensure the representation of the low income and target residents. Any organization so formed, serving as an instrumentality of one (1) or more community action agencies, shall be eligible for associate membership in any association of community action agencies consistent with group bylaws, and shall be eligible for benefits such as group insurance and retirement programs for which community action agencies are eligible, subject to approval by the association. </section></text><history>Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 10, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 453, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 393, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1988 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13735</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>