<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="12" order_by="12">ADMINISTRATIVE ORGANIZATION </unit></structure><section_number>12.357</section_number><catch_line>Issuance of temporary or regular license or certificate to spouse of active duty member of Armed Forces. </catch_line><order_by>357</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding any other statute to the contrary, an administrative body shall issue a temporary or regular license or certificate within thirty (30) days to the spouse of an active duty member of the Armed Forces of the United States if the spouse of the active duty member meets the statutory requirements of the administrative body and applies to the administrative body in a format promulgated in administrative regulation by the administrative body. </section><section prefix="2">An application for temporary or regular licensure of the spouse of an active duty member of the Armed Forces of the United States shall include but not be limited to the following: <section prefix="a">Proof that the applicant is married to an active duty member of the Armed Forces of the United States; </section><section prefix="b">Proof that the applicant holds a valid license or certificate for the profession issued by another state, the District of Columbia, or any possession or territory of the United States; </section><section prefix="c">Proof that the applicant's spouse is assigned to a duty station in this state and that the applicant is also assigned to a duty station in this state pursuant to the spouse's official active duty military orders; and </section><section prefix="d">An application fee to be established by the administrative body in an amount that is no more than is necessary to offset the cost of issuing the temporary or regular license. </section></section><section prefix="3">A temporary license issued pursuant to this section shall expire six (6) months after the date of issuance and is not renewable. </section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 3, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-16</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:13</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39919</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>