<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="18" order_by="18">A STATE PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>18A.113</section_number><catch_line>Lay-off rules -- General. </catch_line><order_by>113</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It shall be unlawful to coerce employees who may be or who are subject to lay-off to resign or retire in lieu of lay-off. Dismissals shall comply with statutes relating thereto, and lay-offs shall not be utilized as a method of dismissal. </section><section prefix="2">In the same cabinet, county, and job classification, federally funded time-limited, interim, and probationary employees shall be laid-off before full-time or part-time employees with status. For purposes of lay-off, "probationary employee" does not include an employee with status serving a promotional probation. A cabinet shall not transfer positions, including vacant positions, in order to circumvent the provisions of this section. </section><section prefix="3">If two (2) or more employees subject to lay-off in a lay-off plan submitted to the secretary have the same qualifications, the employee with the lesser seniority shall be laid-off first. </section><section prefix="4">An employee who is laid-off shall be placed on a reemployment register for the class of position from which he was laid-off and for any class for which he is qualified. He shall have the right to test for any class of position for which he is qualified to take an examination. If he passes the examination, he shall be placed on the register for the class. </section><section prefix="5">For a period of five (5) years, laid-off employees shall be hired before any applicant or eligible except another laid-off employee with greater seniority who is already on such register. </section><section prefix="6">For a period of five (5) years, a laid-off employee shall not be removed from any register unless: <section prefix="a">He notifies the cabinet in writing that he no longer desires consideration for a position on such register; </section><section prefix="b">He declines two (2) written offers of appointment to a position of the same classification and salary, and located in the same county, as the position from which he was laid-off; </section><section prefix="c">Without good cause, he fails to report for an interview after he has been notified in writing at least ten (10) calendar days prior to the date of the interview; </section><section prefix="d">He is unqualified for appointment; </section><section prefix="e">He is unable to perform the duties of the class; </section><section prefix="f">He has made a false statement of a material fact in his application; </section><section prefix="g">He has used or attempted to use political influence or bribery to secure an advantage in connection with his placement on the register; </section><section prefix="h">He has been convicted of a felony within the preceding five (5) years and his civil rights have not been restored or he has not been pardoned by the Governor; </section><section prefix="i">He has been convicted of a job related misdemeanor, except that convictions for violations of traffic regulations shall not constitute grounds for disqualification; </section><section prefix="j">He cannot be located by postal authorities at the last address provided by him; or </section><section prefix="k">He has otherwise willfully violated the provisions of this chapter. </section></section><section prefix="7">When the cabinet is notified by an appointing authority that a laid-off employee has accepted a bona fide offer of appointment to any position, effective on a specified date, his name may be removed from the register for all classes for which the maximum salary is the same as or less than that of the class to which he has been appointed. </section><section prefix="8">When a laid-off employee is removed from a register he shall be notified in writing and shall be notified of his right to appeal to the board under the provisions of KRS 18A.095. </section></text><history> Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 127, sec. 2, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 28, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 540, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 494, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, C, 2, (2) at 628.  See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, D, 10, (1) at 636. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1366</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>