<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IV" order_by="4">JUDICIAL BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="30" order_by="30">A COURT PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>30A.410</section_number><catch_line>When interpreter shall be provided -- Removal. </catch_line><order_by>410</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The court in any matter, criminal or civil, shall appoint a qualified interpreter or interpreters, to be paid out of the State Treasury, for the following categories of persons, whether they are parties, jurors, or witnesses: <section prefix="a">Persons who because of deafness or hard of hearing: <section prefix="1">Use sign language, such as pidgin, signed English, American Sign Language, or gestures; or </section><section prefix="2">Are oral/aural and use interpreters and assistive technology, </section></section> as their primary mode of communication; <section prefix="b">Persons who cannot communicate in English; and </section><section prefix="c">Any other person who has, in the opinion of the court, another type of disability which will prevent him from properly understanding the nature of the proceedings or substantially prejudice his rights. </section></section><section prefix="2">Upon request of the person for whom the interpreter is appointed, or on the court's own motion, an interpreter may be removed for inability to communicate with the person, or if for reasonable cause another interpreter is so desired by the person for whom the interpreter is appointed, or because the services of an interpreter are not desired by the person. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 452, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 144, sec. 7, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 66, effective January 2, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21206</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>