<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>14A.3-020</section_number><catch_line>Reserved name.  </catch_line><order_by>3-020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person may reserve the exclusive use of a name, including a fictitious name for a foreign entity whose real name is not available, by delivering an application to the Secretary of State for filing. The application shall set forth the real name and address of the applicant and the name proposed to be reserved. If the Secretary of State finds that the name applied for is distinguishable from any name of record with the Secretary of State, that name shall be reserved for the applicant's exclusive use for a one hundred twenty (120) day period. During the thirty (30) days prior to the expiration of a reservation, the holder thereof may apply to renew the reservation on such form as shall be provided by the Secretary of State. The renewal shall be effective as of the expiration of the current reservation and shall renew the reservation for an additional one hundred twenty (120) days from the otherwise applicable expiration. </section><section prefix="2">A reserved name shall satisfy the requirements of KRS 14A.3-010. </section><section prefix="3">The applicant holding a reserved name may transfer the reservation to another person by delivering to the Secretary of State a signed notice of the transfer that states the name and address of the transferee. </section><section prefix="4">The holder of a reserved name may cancel the reservation by delivery to the Secretary of State of a notice of cancellation, executed by the applicant for whom the name is reserved, that states the reserved name and its initial date of reservation. </section><section prefix="5">It shall not be necessary that a foreign entity desiring to reserve a name be qualified to transact business in this Commonwealth. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 24, effective January 1, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36546</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>