<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="41" order_by="41">DEPARTMENT OF THE TREASURY </unit></structure><section_number>41.220</section_number><catch_line>State depository banks -- How selected -- Change. </catch_line><order_by>220</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Not less than three (3) solvent banks shall be designated as depositories for state funds. Each bank designated shall have not less than the minimum capital stock as required in KRS 286.3-070. Banks shall be designated as depositories for state funds upon agreement of the State Treasurer and the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet. Those designated shall be entered in the executive journal. If at any time it appears that the capital of any depository has become impaired, the state's deposits shall be withdrawn and another depository named. </section><section prefix="2">The State Treasurer and the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet shall determine the needs for moving state funds from one (1) designated depository to another. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 196, sec. 27, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1956 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 7, Art. XVI, sec. 18, effective July 1, 1956. -- Amended 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 115, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 1992b-44, 4692. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247 instructs the Reviser of Statutes to adjust KRS references throughout the statutes to conform with the 2006 renumbering of the Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286. Such an adjustment has been made in this statute. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21908</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>