<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="199" order_by="199">PROTECTIVE SERVICES FOR CHILDREN - ADOPTION </unit></structure><section_number>199.565</section_number><catch_line>Statewide swift adoption procedures -- Protocol -- Teams -- Quarterly report. </catch_line><order_by>565</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department for Community Based Services shall develop a written protocol for statewide swift adoption procedures to decrease the length of time necessary to complete the adoption process for children who are committed to the cabinet. The protocol shall establish outcome measures for the adoption process, and identify all state, local, and federal agencies, and other entities required to provide services in the adoption process. </section><section prefix="2">The department shall develop swift adoption teams to expedite the adoption process for children who are committed to the cabinet. Swift adoption teams shall include department personnel representing the state, district, and local levels. The swift adoption teams shall operate under the protocol developed pursuant to subsection (1) of this section. Case referrals to swift adoption teams shall be accepted from social services offices from across the state. </section><section prefix="3">The department shall issue a quarterly report which shall provide the status of the teams' goals and objectives and identify all adoption proceedings in which the teams have participated during the three (3) month period examined in the quarterly report. The report shall include: <section prefix="a">The number and location of all committed children placed for adoption; </section><section prefix="b">All options made available to those populations; </section><section prefix="c">The experience and activity for each case; </section><section prefix="d">The successful adoptions and locations; </section><section prefix="e">The status of all cases in which the teams have participated; </section><section prefix="f">The identity of all agencies involved in the adoption process; </section><section prefix="g">An evaluation of the team efforts for the quarter; and </section><section prefix="h">A report of initiatives for the swift adoption process for the upcoming quarter. </section></section><section prefix="4">The quarterly report shall also include recommendations for changes in statutes, administrative regulations, and policies that would enable the department to further improve the timeliness of adoption placements. The report shall be provided to the Governor, the Legislative Research Commission, and the Chief Justice of the Kentucky Supreme Court. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 19, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 325, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7191</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>