<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.4037</section_number><catch_line>Elevator safety program trust fund.  </catch_line><order_by>4037</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The elevator safety program trust fund is created in the State Treasury as a separate revolving fund to be administered by the Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction. The trust fund shall consist of amounts deposited in the fund as provided in KRS 198B.530 and any other proceeds from grants, contributions, appropriations, or other money made available for the purposes of the trust fund. </section><section prefix="2">Notwithstanding KRS 45.229, any moneys remaining in the fund at the close of the fiscal year shall not lapse but shall be carried forward to the next fiscal year to be used for the purposes set forth in this section. </section><section prefix="3">Any interest earnings of the trust fund shall become a part of the trust fund and shall not lapse. </section><section prefix="4">Trust fund moneys shall be used and are hereby appropriated for reasonable administrative expenses associated with the elevator safety program and other purposes as specified in KRS 198B.4005(7). </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 18, effective July 1, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2011 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, L, 8, (1) at 661. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><lrc-note> (7/1/2011).  A reference to the "Office of Housing, Buildings and Construction" in this section, as created by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 18, has been changed in codification to the "Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction" to reflect the reorganization of certain parts of the Executive Branch, as set forth in Executive Order 2009-535 and confirmed by the General Assembly in 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24. This change was made by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1938. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-16</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36602</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>