<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="351" order_by="351">DEPARTMENT FOR NATURAL RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>351.186</section_number><catch_line>Workers' compensation premium -- Credit for certified drug-free workplace program at coal mine.   </catch_line><order_by>186</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any employer who is also a licensee that has implemented a drug-free workplace program certified by the division shall be eligible to obtain a credit on the licensee's premium for workers' compensation insurance. </section><section prefix="2">Each insurer authorized to write workers' compensation insurance policies shall provide the credit on the workers' compensation premium to any employer who is also a licensee for which the insurer has written a workers' compensation policy. The credit on the workers' compensation premium shall not: <section prefix="a">Be available to those employers that are also licensees who do not maintain their drug-free workplace program for the entire workers' compensation policy period; or </section><section prefix="b">Apply to minimum premium policies. </section></section><section prefix="3">The Department of Insurance shall approve workers' compensation rating plans that give a credit on the premium for a certified drug-free workplace so long as the credit is actuarially sound. The credit shall be at least five percent (5%) unless the Department of Insurance determines that five percent (5%) is actuarially unsound. </section><section prefix="4">The credit on the workers' compensation premium may be applied by the insurer at the final audit. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 87, sec. 25, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1901, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 241, sec. 6, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44542</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>