<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="109" order_by="109">LOCAL SOLID WASTE MANAGEMENT </unit></structure><section_number>109.042</section_number><catch_line>Enforcement representative -- Regulations -- Financing for program. </catch_line><order_by>042</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A county or waste management district may employ an enforcement representative to ensure compliance with applicable administrative regulations of the cabinet relating to construction and operation of solid waste management facilities. The local government representative shall have the authority to inspect loads of solid waste and prevent any loads, which fail to comply with administrative regulations, from being disposed of at the solid waste management facility. The local government representative shall possess at least minimum qualifications required of representatives of the cabinet performing similar functions. </section><section prefix="2">The cabinet shall adopt administrative regulations for local government inspection of solid waste management facilities and enforcement procedures. The administrative regulations shall include but not be limited to, requiring local enforcement representatives to report violations of state solid waste management facilities laws and administrative regulations immediately to the cabinet and requiring the cabinet to respond to the report within forty-eight (48) hours of its receipt. </section><section prefix="3">A county or waste management district which elects to implement a local inspection and enforcement program for solid waste management facilities may finance the program from the license fees provided for in KRS 68.178. </section></text><history>Amended 1991 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 31, effective February 26, 1991. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 45, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective>February 26, 1991 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27255</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>