<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="148" order_by="148">PARKS AND TOURISM </unit></structure><section_number>148.522</section_number><catch_line>Organization of Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet. </catch_line><order_by>522</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet shall consist of the Office of the Secretary, the Office of Legal Affairs, the Office of Finance, the Office of Governmental Relations and Tourism Development, the Office of Human Resources, the Office of Public Affairs and Constituent Services, the Office of the Kentucky Sports Authority, the Office of Arts and Cultural Heritage, the Office of Creative Services, the Office of Capital Plaza Operations, the Office of Research and Administration, the Kentucky Department of Travel and Tourism, the Kentucky Department of Parks, the Tourism Development Finance Authority, and such other divisions and sections as are from time to time deemed necessary for the proper and efficient operation of the cabinet subject to the provisions of KRS Chapter 12. </section><section prefix="2">The Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet shall encourage the development of the film industry in Kentucky and shall perform all film promotional functions. </section><section prefix="3">The Office of Legal Affairs shall be headed by a general counsel appointed by the secretary pursuant to KRS 12.210, shall provide legal services for the cabinet, and shall be directly responsible to the secretary. </section><section prefix="4">The Kentucky Department of Travel and Tourism shall be headed by a commissioner appointed by the Governor pursuant to the provisions of KRS 12.040. The commissioner shall have the authority and responsibility for the promotion, development, and support services for the tourism industry within the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="5">The Divisions of Tourism Services, Marketing and Administration, and Communications and Promotions are created within the Kentucky Department of Travel and Tourism. Each division shall be headed by a division director who shall be appointed by the commissioner of the department pursuant to the provisions of KRS 12.050. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 18, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 6, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 17, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 10, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 13, sec. 7, effective July 14, 1992; ch. 159, sec. 3, effective July 14, 1992; and ch. 424, sec. 3, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 404, sec. 11, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (6/20/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 97, 98, 99, 123, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1750</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>