<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIII" order_by="33">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS AND ESTATES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="387" order_by="387">GUARDIANS -- CONSERVATORS -- CURATORS OF CONVICTS </unit></structure><section_number>387.580</section_number><catch_line>Responsibilities of jury during a hearing -- Court determinations upon finding of disability or partial disability. </catch_line><order_by>580</order_by><text><section prefix="1">At a hearing convened under KRS 387.500 to 387.770 for a determination of partial disability or disability, the jury shall: <section prefix="a">Inquire into the nature and extent of the general intellectual functioning of the respondent; </section><section prefix="b">Inquire into the respondent's capacity to make informed decisions concerning his personal affairs and financial resources; </section><section prefix="c">Determine whether the respondent is disabled, partially disabled, or has no disability in relation to the management of his financial resources; and </section><section prefix="d">Determine whether the respondent is disabled, partially disabled, or has no disability in relation to the management of his personal affairs. </section></section><section prefix="2">If the respondent is found not to be disabled or partially disabled, the petition shall be dismissed. </section><section prefix="3">If the respondent is found to be disabled or partially disabled, the court shall, at the same hearing, without a jury, determine: <section prefix="a">The type of guardian or conservator to be appointed; </section><section prefix="b">The specific legal disabilities to which the respondent is subject, if the respondent has been determined to be partially disabled; </section><section prefix="c">Whether the respondent retains the right to vote; </section><section prefix="d">The corresponding powers and duties of the limited guardian or limited conservator, if the respondent has been determined to be partially disabled; </section><section prefix="e">The individual or entity to be appointed by the court as limited guardian, guardian, limited conservator, or conservator; </section><section prefix="f">The individual or entity, if any, to be appointed as standby guardian or conservator; and </section><section prefix="g">The duration of the term of guardianship or conservatorship. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 58, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 9, effective July 1, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36047</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>