<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="16" order_by="16">STATE POLICE </unit></structure><section_number>16.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 16.010 to 16.199.   </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in KRS 16.010 to 16.199, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Cabinet" means the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet; </section><section prefix="2">"Secretary" means the secretary of justice and public safety; </section><section prefix="3">"Commissioner" means the commissioner of the Department of Kentucky State Police; </section><section prefix="4">"Officer" means any member of the Department of Kentucky State Police, other than an individual employed as a Trooper R Class or CVE R Class, who possesses the powers of a peace officer; </section><section prefix="5">"Civilian" means such experts, statisticians, clerks, and other assistants who do not possess the powers of a peace officer; </section><section prefix="6">"Board" means the Department of Kentucky State Police Personnel Board; </section><section prefix="7">"Department" means the Department of Kentucky State Police; </section><section prefix="8">"Continuous service" for participation in and eligibility for the promotional process for each rank of officer commissioned under this chapter means: <section prefix="a">For sergeant, service as a commissioned Kentucky State Police officer that has not been interrupted by actual separation from the department, whether in the form of resignation, retirement, or termination; </section><section prefix="b">For lieutenant, service in grade as a sergeant that has not been interrupted by actual separation from the department, whether in the form of resignation, retirement, termination, or by demotion in accordance with KRS 16.140; </section><section prefix="c">For captain, service in grade as lieutenant that has not been interrupted by actual separation from the department, whether in the form of resignation, retirement, termination, or by demotion in accordance with KRS 16.140; </section></section><section prefix="9">"Trooper R Class" means any retired Kentucky State Police officer commissioned under this chapter who has become reemployed with the department on a contractual basis pursuant to KRS 16.196 to 16.199; and </section><section prefix="10">"CVE R Class" means any retired Kentucky State Police commercial vehicle enforcement officer commissioned under KRS 16.187 who has become reemployed with the department on a contractual basis pursuant to KRS 16.196 to 16.199. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 64, sec. 8, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 56, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 60, sec. 1, effective January 1, 2006. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 299, sec. 4. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. V, sec. 22. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 9. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 1. -- Created 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><lrc-note> (6/25/2009).  A reference in the lead-in language of this statute to "KRS 16.010 to 16.185 and Sections 12 to 15 of this Act" in 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 1, has been changed in codification to "KRS 16.010 to 16.199," to account for newly created statutes in 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 75, secs. 1 to 10, and 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 59, secs. 12 to 15, all of which have been assigned numbers in KRS Chapter 16 within that range of statutes. (1/1/2006).  2005 Ky. Acts ch. 60, sec. 3, states that the amendments to this statute made in 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 60, sec. 1, "shall only apply to the 2006 Kentucky State Police sworn promotional process and any sworn promotional processes thereafter." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42240</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>