<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="501" order_by="501">GENERAL PRINCIPLES OF LIABILITY </unit></structure><section_number>501.070</section_number><catch_line>Liability -- Ignorance or mistake. </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person's ignorance or mistake as to a matter of fact or law does not relieve him of criminal liability unless:  <section prefix="a">Such ignorance or mistake negatives the existence of the culpable mental state required for commission of an offense; or  </section><section prefix="b">The statute under which he is charged or a statute related thereto expressly provides that such ignorance or mistake constitutes a defense or exemption; or  </section><section prefix="c">Such ignorance or mistake is of a kind that supports a defense of justification as defined in this Penal Code.  </section></section><section prefix="2">When ignorance or mistake relieves a person of criminal liability under subsection (1) but he would be guilty of another offense had the situation been as he supposed it was, he may be convicted of that other offense.  </section><section prefix="3">A person's mistaken belief that his conduct, as a matter of law, does not constitute an offense does not relieve him of criminal liability, unless such mistaken belief is actually founded upon an official statement of the law, afterward determined to be invalid or erroneous, contained in:  <section prefix="a">A statute or other enactment; or  </section><section prefix="b">A judicial decision, opinion or judgment; or  </section><section prefix="c">An administrative order or grant of permission; or  </section><section prefix="d">An official interpretation of the public officer or body charged by law with responsibility for the interpretation, administration or enforcement of the law defining the offense.  </section></section></text><history>Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 17, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 1975</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19656</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>