<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="330" order_by="330">AUCTIONEERS AND AUCTION HOUSE OPERATORS </unit></structure><section_number>330.095</section_number><catch_line>Reciprocal licensing without examination -- Continuing education requirements. </catch_line><order_by>095</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An individual holding an auctioneer license from the proper authority of a state, territory, or possession of the United States of America or the District of Columbia that has licensing requirements equal to or substantially equivalent to the requirements in this state, and where reciprocal licensing privileges are granted to residents of this state, may obtain an auctioneer license without examination and pre-license education if: <section prefix="a">The board has entered into a valid reciprocal agreement with the proper authority of the state, territory, or possession of the United States of America or the District of Columbia from which the nonresident applicant has a valid license; </section><section prefix="b">The applicant submits to the board the completed reciprocal application, including the irrevocable consent described in KRS 330.060, and the license and exam verification from a reciprocal state; and </section><section prefix="c">The applicant pays the applicable reciprocal fee: <section prefix="1">The initial reciprocal fee shall be the greater of: <section prefix="a">The sum total of the initial license and recovery fees charged by the applicant's reciprocal state to a Kentucky resident for an initial reciprocal license; or </section><section prefix="b">The sum total of the current initial license and recovery fees assessed by the board to a nonreciprocal Kentucky licensee; and </section></section><section prefix="2">The renewal reciprocal fee shall be the greater of: <section prefix="a">The sum total of the renewal license and recovery fees charged by the applicant's reciprocal state to a Kentucky resident for a renewal reciprocal license; or </section><section prefix="b">The sum total of the current renewal license and recovery fees assessed by the board to a nonreciprocal Kentucky licensee. </section></section></section></section><section prefix="2">If a licensee is issued a Kentucky reciprocal license via a jurisdiction that has continuing education requirements, the Kentucky reciprocal licensee shall be exempt from reporting continuing education. If a licensee is issued a Kentucky reciprocal license via a jurisdiction that does not have a continuing education requirement, the Kentucky reciprocal licensee shall report continuing education pursuant to KRS 330.070. </section><section prefix="3">Disciplinary sanctions against a reciprocal licensee imposed by any licensure jurisdiction may be grounds for disciplinary action by the board. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 70, sec. 8, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 285, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 344, sec. 8, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 170, sec. 7, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 407, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 42, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31787</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>