<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXVIII" order_by="38">WITNESSES, EVIDENCE, NOTARIES, COMMISSIONERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="424" order_by="424">LEGAL NOTICES </unit></structure><section_number>424.160</section_number><catch_line>Rates for newspaper advertising required by law. </catch_line><order_by>160</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For all newspaper advertising required by law, the publisher is entitled to receive payment for each insertion at a rate per column inch. The advertisement shall be set in no larger than seven (7) point type on solid leading. The rate shall not exceed the lowest noncontract classified rate paid by advertisers. The terms and conditions of any volume discounts given to commercial customers shall be extended to public agencies of the Commonwealth of Kentucky. Newspapers shall give all local public agencies a written notice of at least thirty (30) days of an advertising rate increase. </section><section prefix="2">If by law or by the nature of the matter to be published, a display form of advertisement is required, or if the person or officer responsible for causing an advertisement to be published determines in his discretion that a display form is practicable or feasible, and so directs the newspaper, the advertisement shall be published in display form and the newspaper shall be entitled to receive its established display rate. </section><section prefix="3">If it is provided by statute that an advertisement shall be published of the filing of a petition or application seeking official action, the filing, if required by other than a governmental official or agency, shall not be deemed complete unless there is deposited with the petition or application an amount sufficient to pay the cost of publication. </section><section prefix="4">The expense of advertisements in judicial proceedings shall be taxed as costs by the clerk of the court. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 8, sec. 5, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 430, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 1. -- Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 42, sec. 6. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=18252</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>