<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.438</section_number><catch_line>Administrative regulations for reviewing and resolving claims of factual errors in adopted textbooks. </catch_line><order_by>438</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Board of Education shall promulgate administrative regulations to establish procedures for reviewing and resolving claims of factual errors found in textbooks after adoption by the State Textbook Commission. </section><section prefix="2">The administrative regulations shall include: <section prefix="a">A process for an individual who believes that a factual error or errors have been found to file notice of his or her findings; </section><section prefix="b">A methodology for validating the accuracy of a claim of factual error; </section><section prefix="c">The development of conditions to include in publishers' contracts specifying protocols for correcting errors which take into account the following: <section prefix="1">The extensiveness of the errors found; </section><section prefix="2">The remaining time left until the next textbook adoption cycle at the time the claim is determined to be valid; </section><section prefix="3">Conditions that would necessitate replacement of a book in its entirety; and </section><section prefix="4">Conditions that could be addressed through the insertion of corrections in textbooks without replacement; </section></section><section prefix="d">Notice to school districts of errors, if found, and the resolution determined to be available; and </section><section prefix="e">Notice to the claimant relative to the validation review and the resolution determined to be available if the claim of error was validated. </section></section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 72, sec. 1, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39780</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>