<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>355.9-613</section_number><catch_line>Contents and form of notification before disposition of collateral: General. </catch_line><order_by>9-613</order_by><text>Except in a consumer-goods transaction, the following rules apply: <section prefix="1">The contents of a notification of disposition are sufficient if the notification: <section prefix="a">Describes the debtor and the secured party; </section><section prefix="b">Describes the collateral that is the subject of the intended disposition; </section><section prefix="c">States the method of intended disposition; </section><section prefix="d">States that the debtor is entitled to an accounting of the unpaid indebtedness and states the charge, if any, for an accounting; and </section><section prefix="e">States the time and place of a public disposition or the time after which any other disposition is to be made. </section></section><section prefix="2">Whether the contents of a notification that lacks any of the information specified in subsection (1) of this section are nevertheless sufficient is a question of fact. </section><section prefix="3">The contents of a notification providing substantially the information specified in subsection (1) of this section are sufficient, even if the notification includes: <section prefix="a">Information not specified by that subsection; or </section><section prefix="b">Minor errors that are not seriously misleading. </section></section><section prefix="4">A particular phrasing of the notification is not required. </section><section prefix="5">The following form of notification and the form appearing in KRS 355.9-614(3), when completed, each provides sufficient information: "NOTIFICATION OF DISPOSITION OF COLLATERAL </section>To: ..... &lt;Name of debtor, obligor, or other person to which the notification is sent&gt; From: .....&lt;Name, address, and telephone number of secured party&gt; Name of Debtor(s): .....&lt;Include only if debtor(s) are not an addressee&gt; &lt;For a public disposition:&gt; We will sell &lt;or lease or license, as applicable&gt; the.....&lt;describe collateral&gt; &lt;to the highest qualified bidder&gt; in public as follows: Day and Date: . . . . . . . . . . . . . . .  Time:  . . . . . . . . . . . . . . .  Place:  . . . . . . . . . . . . . . .  &lt;For a private disposition:&gt; We will sell &lt;or lease or license, as applicable&gt; the.....&lt;describe collateral&gt; privately sometime after.....&lt;day and date&gt;. You are entitled to an accounting of the unpaid indebtedness secured by the property that we intend to sell &lt;or lease or license, as applicable&gt; &lt;for a charge of $...... &gt;. You may request an accounting by calling us at .....&lt;telephone number&gt;". </text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 408, sec. 131, effective July 1, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-09-17</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33845</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>