<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.380</section_number><catch_line>Applications for state licenses -- Requirements for entity owning more than two licensed premises.   </catch_line><order_by>380</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Applications for distilled spirit and wine licenses provided for in KRS Chapters 241 to 244 shall be made to the director of the Division of Distilled Spirits. Applications for malt beverage licenses provided for in KRS Chapters 241 to 244 shall be made to the director of the Division of Malt Beverages. Applications for distilled spirits, wine, and malt beverage licenses provided for in KRS Chapters 241 to 244 shall be made to the director of the Division of Distilled Spirits and to the director of the Division of Malt Beverages. </section><section prefix="2">All applications shall be on forms furnished by the department. They shall be verified and shall set forth in detail all information concerning the applicant and the premises submitted for licensing as the board requires by administrative regulation. Each application shall be accompanied by payment. Payment of the license fee may be by certified check, a postal or express money order, or any other method of payment approved in writing by both the Finance and Administration Cabinet and the Office of the State Treasurer. Promptly upon receipt of the payment the board shall pay it into the State Treasury, giving the Department of Revenue copies of the pay-in vouchers and any other supporting data as the Department of Revenue requires for revenue control purposes. </section><section prefix="3">A business entity that owns more than two (2) licensed premises shall initially submit common information about ownership, officers, directors, managerial employees, and shall provide current criminal background checks once for all separately licensed premises in one (1) master file. Any business qualifying under this subsection shall only be required to amend its master file information for material changes under KRS 243.390(2) or ownership transfers under KRS 243.630. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 20, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 75, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 573, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 649, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 33, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1944 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 14. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2554b-131, 2554b-204. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43042</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>