<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="312" order_by="312">CHIROPRACTORS </unit></structure><section_number>312.017</section_number><catch_line>Types of treatment prohibited -- Scope and methods of chiropractic treatment -- Referral of patients. </catch_line><order_by>017</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No chiropractor shall: <section prefix="a">Treat or attempt to treat contagious or communicable diseases; </section><section prefix="b">Treat or attempt to treat cancer; </section><section prefix="c">Treat by use of x-ray or radiological methods; </section><section prefix="d">Perform surgery; </section><section prefix="e">Treat or attempt to treat by use of acupuncture; or </section><section prefix="f">Administer prescription drugs or controlled substances. </section></section><section prefix="2">Subject to the limitations in this chapter, a chiropractor shall examine, diagnose and treat the human body within the scope of chiropractic as defined in this section and KRS 312.015 and by methods taught in accredited chiropractic colleges as stated in KRS 312.085. A chiropractor may refer a patient to a physician, licensed medical laboratory or licensed health facility for testing or examination to aid in differential diagnosis or treatment. However, nothing contained herein shall require any licensed health care provider to accept such a referral. </section><section prefix="3">No chiropractor shall otherwise treat a patient for any disorder or by any method except as provided in this chapter. Chiropractic patients whose diagnosis is not within the chiropractic scope of practice, as defined in this section and KRS 312.015, shall be referred by the chiropractor to a medical doctor or other licensed health practitioner for treatment of that condition. </section></text><history>Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 359, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1988 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30760</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>