<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="230" order_by="230">HORSE RACING AND SHOWING </unit></structure><section_number>230.3773</section_number><catch_line>Interstate common wagering pools. </catch_line><order_by>3773</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, "interstate common wagering pool" means a pari-mutuel pool established in one (1) horse racing jurisdiction that is combined with comparable pari-mutuel pools from at least one (1) horse racing jurisdiction for the purpose of establishing payoff prices in the various jurisdictions. </section><section prefix="2">Interstate wagers at a receiving track may form an interstate common wagering pool with wagers at a track in another jurisdiction, and the receiving track may adopt the commission and breakage rates of the track at which the race is being run. The racing commission may also approve types of wagering, distribution of winnings, and rules of racing for interstate common wagering pools that are different from those that normally apply in Kentucky. </section><section prefix="3">Wagers placed on any races run at track in Kentucky may be combined with wagers placed at tracks in other jurisdictions to form an interstate common wagering pool located either within or outside Kentucky. </section><section prefix="4">A track's participation in an interstate common wagering pool does not cause that track to be considered to be doing business in any jurisdiction other than the jurisdiction where the track is physically located. Excise taxes and commission rates may not be imposed on any interstate common wagering pool other than on amounts actually wagered in Kentucky. The combination of pari-mutuel pools as provided in this section constitutes the communication of wagering information for purposes of calculating odds and payoffs only and does not constitute the transfer of wagers in interstate commerce. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 478, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 34, effective July 13, 2004. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 438, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10873</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>