<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.32-170</section_number><catch_line>Authorized contracts. </catch_line><order_by>32-170</order_by><text>Any corporation subject to the provisions of this subtitle may contract with any agency, instrumentality, or political subdivision of the United States, or of this state for making available hospital, medical-surgical, dental and other health care services, and in aid or furtherance of such contract may accept, receive, and administer in trust, funds directly or indirectly made available by any agency, instrumentality, or political subdivision. Any corporation may also subcontract with any organization which has contracted with any agency, instrumentality, or political subdivision of the United States, or of this state, for the furnishing of hospital, medical-surgical, dental, or other health services by which subcontract the corporation undertakes to furnish the services specified by the basic contract. Any corporation subject to the provisions of this subtitle may also enter into agreements or contracts with other similar organizations or corporations licensed to do business in this state or any other state for the transfer of subscribers or members, for the reciprocal or joint provision of benefits to the subscribers or members of the corporation and organizations or such other joint undertakings as the corporation's governing board may approve. </text><history>Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 32, sec. 17, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective>June 18, 1970 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:06</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29795</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>