<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="351" order_by="351">DEPARTMENT FOR NATURAL RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>351.310</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 351.315 to 351.375. </catch_line><order_by>310</order_by><text>As used in KRS 351.315 to 351.375 unless the context clearly indicates otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Explosives" means any chemical compound or other substance or mechanical system intended for the purpose of producing an explosion, or that contains oxidizing and combustible units or other ingredients in such proportions or quantities that ignition by detonation may produce an explosion, capable of causing injury to persons or damage to property; </section><section prefix="2">"Blasting operation" means the use of explosives in the surface blasting of stone, rock, ore or any other natural formation, or in any construction or demolition work, but shall not include its use in agricultural operations; </section><section prefix="3">"Blaster" means a person licensed to fire or detonate explosives in blasting operations; </section><section prefix="4">"Charge" means a quantity of explosive or equivalent that is to be detonated within a period of five (5) seconds; </section><section prefix="5">"Subcharge" means a quantity of explosive or equivalent that is to be detonated within a period of less than eight (8) milliseconds; </section><section prefix="6">"Detonation time" means the time at which the detonation is initiated; </section><section prefix="7">"Department" means the Department for Natural Resources; and </section><section prefix="8">"Commissioner" means the commissioner of the Department for Natural Resources. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 61, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 355, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1976Ky. Acts ch. 143,sec. 1. -- Created 1972Ky. Acts ch. 280, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32951</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>