<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="322" order_by="322">PROFESSIONAL ENGINEERS AND LAND SURVEYORS </unit></structure><section_number>322.190</section_number><catch_line>Investigation and resolution of complaints -- Appeals. </catch_line><order_by>190</order_by><text>Any person or organization, including the board upon its own volition, may file with the executive director of the board a written complaint alleging violation of any provision of this chapter. The executive director shall cause the complaint to be investigated. <section prefix="1">If the investigation reveals that the alleged violation did occur but was not of a serious nature, the board may issue a written admonishment to the licensee. A copy of the admonishment shall be placed in the permanent file of the licensee. The licensee shall have the right to file a response to the admonishment within thirty (30) days of its receipt and to have the response placed in the permanent licensure file. The licensee may alternatively, within thirty (30) days of the receipt, file a request for hearing with the board. Upon receipt of this request, the board shall set aside the written admonishment and set the matter for hearing in accordance with the provisions of KRS Chapter 13B. </section><section prefix="2">If the investigation reveals evidence supporting the complaint, the executive director shall set the matter for hearing in accordance with the provisions of KRS Chapter 13B before refusing to renew, suspending, revoking, reprimanding, imposing probation or an administrative fine, or any combination of actions regarding any license under the provisions of this chapter. <section prefix="a">At any time during the investigation or hearing process, the board may accept a written assurance of voluntary compliance from the licensee which effectively deals with the complaint. </section><section prefix="b">When the board issues a written reprimand to the licensee, a copy of the reprimand shall be placed in the permanent file of the licensee. The licensee shall have the right to submit a response within thirty (30) days of its receipt and to have that response filed in the permanent file. </section></section><section prefix="3">After denying an application under the provisions of this chapter, the board may grant a hearing to the denied applicant in accordance with the provisions of KRS Chapter 13B. </section><section prefix="4">The board may reconsider, modify, or reverse its decision on any disciplinary action. </section><section prefix="5">Any party aggrieved by a disciplinary action of the board may bring an action in Franklin Circuit Court in accordance with the provisions of KRS Chapter 13B. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 214, sec. 17, effective January 1, 1999. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 291, sec. 18, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 273, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 148, sec. 14. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 1599e-20. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 1999 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31438</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>