<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="242" order_by="242">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LOCAL OPTION </unit></structure><section_number>242.330</section_number><catch_line>Sale of forfeited property and disposition of proceeds. </catch_line><order_by>330</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon a judgment of forfeiture under KRS 242.320, the court shall direct the sheriff to sell the property. The sale shall be made in the same manner as sales under execution, and the same fees shall be allowed the officers conducting the sale. </section><section prefix="2">The sheriff shall pay first out of the purchase money any valid recorded liens on the property so sold. The court may in its discretion order a sale subject to the liens. </section><section prefix="3">No lien on any property so sold shall be paid unless it is recorded prior to the committing of the nuisance and unless the lienor can establish he had no knowledge of the nuisance. </section><section prefix="4">If the petition is filed by a private citizen and a sale ordered, the citizen shall receive ten percent (10%) of the net proceeds of sale of any property under any judgment of forfeiture, after deducting costs and all valid liens. </section><section prefix="5">The sheriff, after payment of liens, costs and fees, shall pay the balance of the proceeds of sale to the circuit clerk, who shall transmit the balance as in the case of other forfeitures. </section></text><history>Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2554c-24. </history><metadata><effective>October 1, 1942</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11289</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>