<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.598</section_number><catch_line>Withholding of income and state tax refund of person required by court to provide cost of child's health service -- Priority of claims for child support over costs of reimbursement of child medical support. </catch_line><order_by>598</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall withhold the wages, salary, or other employment income of, and require withholding amounts from state tax refunds to, any person who: <section prefix="a">Is required by court or administrative order to provide coverage of the costs of health services to a child who is eligible for medical assistance; </section><section prefix="b">Has received payment from a third party for the costs of the services for the child; but </section><section prefix="c">Has not used these payments to reimburse either the other parent or guardian of the child, or the provider of the services. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any claims for current or past-due child support income shall take priority over the claims for the costs of reimbursing the Medical Assistance Program for child medical support. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 245, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 203, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 366, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7740</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>