<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="350" order_by="350">SURFACE COAL MINING </unit></structure><section_number>350.100</section_number><catch_line>Time for commencement and completion of reclamation -- Deferred planting. </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It shall be the duty of a permittee and operator to commence the reclamation of the area of land affected by the operation as contemporaneously as practicable after the beginning of operations on that area in accordance with plans previously approved by the cabinet. The grading, backfilling, and water management practices that are approved in the plans shall be kept current with the operation as defined by regulations of the cabinet and no permit renewal or revision shall be issued, if, under the regulations of the cabinet, these practices are not current; </section><section prefix="2">If an investigation indicates that planting so as to provide vegetative cover of an area of land affected by surface coal mining may not be successful, consistent with subsection (1), the cabinet may authorize the permittee or person to defer the planting until the soil and/or weather has become suitable for that purpose. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 429, sec. 13, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 12. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. III, sec. 13(7). -- Amended 1972 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 71. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 15. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 61, sec. 5. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 6. -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 8, sec. 10. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32794</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>