<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="40" order_by="40">VETERANS </unit></structure><section_number>40.010Definitions</section_number><catch_line>for chapter.   </catch_line><order_by>010Definitions</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, the following terms have the following respective meanings, unless another meaning is clearly required by the context: <section prefix="1">"Administrator" means the adjutant general of the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="2">"Veteran" means a person who served in the active Armed Forces of the United States, during the Spanish American War, World War I, World War II, or the Korean conflict, for a period of ninety (90) days or more (exclusive of time spent AWOL; or in penal confinement as a result of a sentence imposed by court-martial; or in service for which no allowance is made according to KRS 40.040), with some portion of service within the respective hereinafter prescribed dates, who is still in the Armed Forces, or was released, separated, discharged, or retired therefrom under honorable conditions; </section><section prefix="3">"Duty in active Armed Forces" includes active duty, and any period of inactive duty training during which the individual concerned was disabled; and if a person in the active Armed Forces was released, separated, or discharged therefrom by reason of disability incurred in line of duty before serving as much as ninety (90) days, such person shall be qualified for entitlement to a bonus payment under this chapter, notwithstanding failure to remain in service for the minimum time otherwise prescribed; </section><section prefix="4">"Armed Forces" means the United States Army, Navy, Marine Corps, Air Force, and Coast Guard, including the reserve components thereof on active duty; </section><section prefix="5">"Qualified veteran" means a person answering to the specifications set forth in subsections (2) and (3), and who <section prefix="a">Was a resident of the Commonwealth at the time of entry into active service in the Armed Forces and for at least six (6) months prior thereto; and </section><section prefix="b">Who has not received a bonus or like compensation from another state; and </section><section prefix="c">Who is not subject to the forfeiture provisions of this chapter; </section></section><section prefix="6">"Resident of the Commonwealth at the time of entry into the active service" means any person who gave the Commonwealth of Kentucky, or any specific place in this Commonwealth, as his or her place of residence at such time of entry, without regard to the place of enlistment, commission, or induction. Conclusive and exclusive evidence of such giving of place of residence shall be the official records on file in the Department of Defense of the United States, or any official record thereof in the files of the Veterans Administration of the United States; but if it be shown to the satisfaction of the administrator that for any reason no such record was made, or that the same has been lost, misplaced, or destroyed, or that an authenticated copy thereof cannot be obtained within a reasonable time, other evidence of bona fide residence may be accepted if deemed sufficient by the administrator; </section><section prefix="7">"Resident," in any context other than as in subsection (6), means a legal resident as determined by generally established principles of law, as may be defined, and subject to proof, according to such regulations as the administrator may promulgate; </section><section prefix="8">"Beneficiary" means, in this order, widow, child or children (sharing equally), mother, father, and no other; </section><section prefix="9"><section prefix="a">"Widow" means a woman who was the wife of a veteran at the time of his death, and who had not deserted him (except where there was a separation which was due to the misconduct of, or procured by, the veteran without the fault of the wife), and who had not remarried, (unless the purported remarriage was void or had been annulled); </section><section prefix="b">The term "widow" also includes "widower" in the case of a man who was the husband of a female veteran at the time of her death; </section></section><section prefix="10">"Child" means a person: <section prefix="a">Who is under the age of eighteen (18); or </section><section prefix="b">Who, before attaining the age of eighteen (18) years, became permanently incapable of self-support; or </section><section prefix="c">Who, after attaining the age of eighteen (18) years and until completion of education or training (but not after attaining the age of twenty-one (21) years) is pursuing a course of instruction at a bona fide educational institution; and who, in relationship to the veteran, is a child born in lawful wedlock; a legally adopted child; a stepchild who is a member of a veteran's household or was a member at the time of the veteran's death; or a child born out of wedlock, but, as to the alleged father, only if acknowledged in writing signed by him, or if he had, before his death, been judicially decreed to be the father of such child; </section></section><section prefix="11">"Mother" means a mother, a mother through adoption, or a woman who for a period of not less than one (1) year stood in the relationship of a mother to a qualified veteran before his or her entry into active service in the Armed Forces, or if two (2) persons stood in such relationship for one (1) year or more, the person who last stood in such relationship before the veteran's last entry into active service in the Armed Forces; </section><section prefix="12">"Father" means a father, a father through adoption, or a man who for a period of not less than one (1) year stood in the relationship of a father to a qualified veteran before his or her entry into active service in the Armed Forces, or if two (2) persons stood in such relationship for one (1) year or more, the person who last stood in such relationship before the veteran's last entry into active service in the Armed Forces; </section><section prefix="13">"In the continental United States" means any place in the District of Columbia and the states of the United States which are on the North American continent, exclusive of Alaska; </section><section prefix="14">"Outside the continental United States" means any place elsewhere than as defined in subsection (13); </section><section prefix="15">"Spanish-American War": <section prefix="a">Means the period beginning on April 21, 1898, and ending on July 4, 1902; </section><section prefix="b">Includes the Philippine Insurrection and the Boxer Rebellion; and </section><section prefix="c">In the case of a veteran who served with the United States military forces engaged in hostilities in the Moro Province, means the period beginning on April 21, 1898, and ending on July 15, 1903; </section></section><section prefix="16">"World War I": <section prefix="a">Means the period beginning on April 6, 1917, and ending on November 11, 1918; and </section><section prefix="b">In the case of a veteran who served with the United States military forces in Russia, means the period beginning on April 6, 1917, and ending on April 1, 1920; and </section><section prefix="c">Any service between April 6, 1917, and July 1, 1921, if some part thereof was between April 6, 1917, and November 11, 1918, both dates being inclusive; </section></section><section prefix="17">"World War II" means the period beginning December 7, 1941, and ending December 31, 1946; </section><section prefix="18">"Korean conflict" means the period beginning on June 27, 1950, and ending January 31, 1955; </section><section prefix="19">"Bonus" and "veterans' bonus" means the compensation authorized by this chapter; </section><section prefix="20">"Bonus claim" means a claim or potential claim for a veterans' bonus; </section><section prefix="21">"Claimant" means one who seeks to obtain payment of a bonus claim. </section></text><history>Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 68, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1960 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 1, effective September 30, 1960. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 15, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective>June 24, 2015</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44486</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>