<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="257" order_by="257">LIVESTOCK AND POULTRY DISEASE CONTROL </unit></structure><section_number>257.100</section_number><catch_line>Destruction of suffering, abandoned, or hopelessly diseased animal -- "Abandonment" defined. </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any peace officer, animal control officer, or any person authorized by the board may destroy or kill or cause to be destroyed or killed, any animal found abandoned and suffering and not properly cared for, or appearing to be injured, diseased, or suffering past recovery for any useful purpose. </section><section prefix="2">Before destroying the animal the officer shall obtain the judgment to that effect of a veterinarian, or of two (2) reputable citizens called by him to view the animal in his presence, or shall obtain consent to the destruction from the owner of the animal. </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">Any animal placed in the custody of a licensed veterinarian for treatment, boarding, or other care, which shall be unclaimed by its owner or his agent for a period of more than ten (10) days after written notice by certified mail, return receipt requested, is given the owner or his agent at his last known address, shall be deemed to be abandoned and may be turned over to the nearest humane society or animal shelter or disposed of as the custodian may deem proper. </section><section prefix="b">The giving of notice to the owner, or the agent of the owner of the animal by the licensed veterinarian shall relieve the licensed veterinarian and any custodian to whom the animal may be given of any further liability for disposal. </section></section><section prefix="4">Abandonment shall constitute the relinquishment of all rights and claims by the owner to the animal. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 9, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 189, sec. 27, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 56, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 1246-2, 1246-3, 1246-4. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12350</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>