<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="279" order_by="279">RURAL ELECTRIC AND RURAL TELEPHONE COOPERATIVE CORPORATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>279.220</section_number><catch_line>Foreign cooperatives may extend lines into this state -- Conditions -- Limitation.   </catch_line><order_by>220</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any rural electric cooperative corporation organized under a law of any state contiguous to this state, which law is substantially similar to the law under which such corporations may be organized in this state, may extend its operations into this state for a distance not exceeding three (3) miles from the boundary between that state and this state, and such extension shall not be considered doing business in this state within the meaning of the statutes regulating or taxing foreign corporations doing business in this state. Such corporation shall be entitled to the same exemptions granted to, and shall pay the same tax required of, domestic corporations under KRS 279.200. </section><section prefix="2">The operations of such corporation within this state shall be subject to the supervision of the Public Service Commission, and the commission may take the necessary action to require the corporation to furnish adequate service at reasonable rates. If the corporation fails to comply with the regulations and requirements of the commission it shall forfeit the privilege granted by this section. </section><section prefix="3">The privilege granted by this section shall be effective for a period of five (5) years from June 12, 1940, at which date it shall expire, unless the contiguous state grants a similar privilege to rural electric cooperative corporations incorporated in this state, in which case it shall continue so long as the contiguous state continues to grant the same privilege. </section><section prefix="4">A rural electric cooperative corporation organized under a law of any state other than Kentucky not satisfying the exemptions set forth in subsections (1), (2) and (3) of this section is subject to KRS 14A.9-010. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 83, effective January 1, 2011. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 3952a-1, 3952a-2, 3952a-3. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36733</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>