<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">B METROPOLITAN CORRECTIONAL SERVICES DEPARTMENT </unit></structure><section_number>67B.050</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of department. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text>The department shall, subject to the approval and authorization of the consolidated local government or fiscal court, generally administer, operate, and maintain all county correctional facilities, including facilities operated by private agencies under contract with the consolidated local government or fiscal court, and formulate and implement necessary correctional and rehabilitative programs. In carrying out its duties, the department shall have and possess, subject to the approval and authorization of the consolidated local government or fiscal court, all powers necessary to effectuate its purposes, including, but not by way of limitation the following: <section prefix="1">To prepare an annual budget with reference to the operations of the department for submission to the consolidated local government or fiscal court. </section><section prefix="2">To authorize all expenditures of the department in conformity with the annual budget, as approved by the consolidated local government or fiscal court, all such expenditures to be submitted for consolidated local government or fiscal court approval as in the case of all other county or consolidated local government agencies and departments. </section><section prefix="3">To prepare and submit not less than annually a report of all the activities, programs, and expenditures of the department to the consolidated local government or fiscal court. </section><section prefix="4">To employ and dismiss employees as may be necessary for the proper management and operation of the department and of the correctional facilities which are governed by the department, subject to the department merit system. </section><section prefix="5">To promulgate comprehensive rules, regulations, and bylaws for the regulation, administration, maintenance, and operation of the department, which rules, regulations, and bylaws shall be subject to approval by the consolidated local government or fiscal court. </section><section prefix="6">To formulate and implement penal, correctional, and rehabilitative programs, including the power to enter into contracts with private agencies for the operation of correctional or detention facilities, all of such facilities and programs to be subject to approval by the consolidated local government or fiscal court. </section><section prefix="7">To comply with all statutory requirements contained in the Kentucky Revised Statutes with reference to the operation, maintenance, and upkeep of all correctional facilities. </section><section prefix="8">To provide for the humane care, treatment, and feeding of all inmates of all correctional facilities of the county. </section><section prefix="9">To enter into contracts with private or governmental agencies regarding matters of correctional and rehabilitative import, including the operation, maintenance, and upkeep of correctional or detention facilities. </section><section prefix="10">To apply for, and accept, grants-in-aid from any public or private agency. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 50, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 27, sec. 2, effective February 29, 1996. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23993</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>