<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.15-310</section_number><catch_line>Nonforfeiture provisions. </catch_line><order_by>15-310</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No policy of life insurance, except as stated in KRS 304.15-360 shall be delivered or issued for delivery in this state unless it shall contain, in substance the following provisions, or corresponding provisions which in the opinion of the commissioner are at least as favorable to the defaulting or surrendering policyholder as are the minimum requirements hereinafter specified and are essentially in compliance with KRS 304.15-352: <section prefix="a">Paid-up nonforfeiture benefit. That, in the event of default in any premium payment, the insurer will grant, upon proper request not later than sixty (60) days after the due date of the premium in default, a paid-up nonforfeiture benefit on a plan stipulated in the policy, effective as of such due date, of such amount as may be hereinafter specified. In lieu of such stipulated paid-up nonforfeiture benefit, the insurer may substitute, upon proper request not later than sixty (60) days after the due date of the premium in default, an actuarially equivalent alternative paid-up nonforfeiture benefit which provides a greater amount or longer period of death benefits or, if applicable, a greater amount or earlier payment of endowment benefits; </section><section prefix="b">Cash surrender value. That, upon surrender of the policy within sixty (60) days after the due date of any premium payment in default after premiums have been paid for at least three (3) full years in the case of ordinary insurance or five (5) full years in the case of industrial insurance, the insurer will pay, in lieu of any paid-up nonforfeiture benefit, a cash surrender value of such amount as may be hereinafter specified; </section><section prefix="c">Effective date of benefit. That a specified paid-up nonforfeiture benefit shall become effective as specified in the policy unless the person entitled to make such election elects another available option not later than sixty (60) days after the due date of the premium in default; </section><section prefix="d">Cash surrender value if policy paid up. That, if the policy shall have become paid up by completion of all premium payments or if it is continued under any paid-up nonforfeiture benefit which became effective on or after the third policy anniversary in the case of ordinary insurance or the fifth policy anniversary in the case of industrial insurance, the insurer will pay, upon surrender of the policy within thirty (30) days after any policy anniversary, a cash surrender value of such amount as may be hereinafter specified; </section><section prefix="e">Mortality table and interest rate used. In the case of policies which cause, on a basis guaranteed in the policy, unscheduled changes in benefits or premiums, or which provide an option for changes in benefits or premiums other than a change to a new policy, a statement of the mortality table, interest rate, and method used in calculating cash surrender values and the paid-up nonforfeiture benefits available under the policy. In the case of all other policies, statement of the mortality table and interest rate used in calculating the cash surrender values and the paid-up nonforfeiture benefits available under the policy, together with a table showing the cash surrender value, if any, and paid-up nonforfeiture benefits, if any, available under the policy on each policy anniversary either during the first twenty (20) policy years or during the term of the policy, whichever is shorter, such values and benefits to be calculated upon the assumption that there are no dividends or paid-up additions credited to the policy and that there is no indebtedness to the insurer on the policy; and </section><section prefix="f">Method used in computing value and benefit. A statement that the cash surrender values and the paid-up nonforfeiture benefits available under the policy are not less than the minimum values and benefits required by or pursuant to the insurance law of the state in which the policy is delivered; an explanation of the manner in which the cash surrender values and the paid-up nonforfeiture benefits are altered by the existence of any paid-up additions credited to the policy or any indebtedness to the insurer on the policy; if a detailed statement of the method of computation of the values and benefits shown in the policy is not stated therein, a statement that such method of computation has been filed with the insurance supervisory official of the state in which the policy is delivered; and a statement of the method to be used in calculating the cash surrender value and paid-up nonforfeiture benefit available under the policy on any policy anniversary beyond the last anniversary for which such values and benefits are consecutively shown in the policy. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any of the foregoing provisions or portions thereof not applicable by reason of the plan of insurance may, to the extent inapplicable, be omitted from the policy. </section><section prefix="3">The insurer shall reserve the right to defer the payment of any cash surrender value for a period of six (6) months after demand therefor with surrender of the policy. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1182, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 263, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 15, sec. 31, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:06</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17229</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>