<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.796</section_number><catch_line>Governor's Scholars Program -- Purpose -- Governor's Scholars Program, Inc. -- Board of directors -- Funding -- Reports.   </catch_line><order_by>796</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Governor's Scholars Program is established to implement an enrichment program for academically gifted students to enhance the next generation of civic and economic leaders and create models of educational excellence. Governor's Scholars Program, Inc. is authorized to operate the Governor's Scholars Program. The Governor's Scholars Program shall be attached to the Office of the Secretary in the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet for administrative purposes. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">The Governor or the Governor's designee from the executive cabinet, the commissioner of education, and the president of the Council on Postsecondary Education shall serve as ex officio voting members of the board of directors of Governor's Scholars Program, Inc. In addition, the Governor shall appoint five (5) members of the board as provided in paragraph (b) of this subsection. Other board members of Governor's Scholars Program, Inc. shall be selected in the manner set forth in the articles of incorporation and bylaws of the corporation. </section><section prefix="b">After June 20, 2005, the Governor shall appoint board members as follows: <section prefix="1">In 2005, the Governor shall appoint two (2) board members to serve three (3) year terms; </section><section prefix="2">In 2006, the Governor shall appoint two (2) members to serve three (3) year terms; and </section><section prefix="3">In 2007, the Governor shall appoint one (1) member to serve a three (3) year term. </section></section> Members appointed by the Governor may be reappointed by the Governor to serve successive terms. In making gubernatorial appointments, the Governor shall consider recommendations and information provided by the nominating committee of the board and shall attempt to promote geographic balance on the board. One (1) of the gubernatorial appointees shall be designated by the board to serve on the committee that functions as the executive committee of Governor's Scholars Program, Inc. The Governor shall make appointments to fill gubernatorial vacancies as they occur. Each appointment after the initial appointment shall be for a three (3) year term unless the appointment is to fill the unexpired portion of a term. <section prefix="c">The board of directors shall have the authority to hire, fire, and manage all program personnel, including the executive director. </section></section><section prefix="3">The annual appropriation for the Governor's Scholars Program from the general fund shall be transmitted to Governor's Scholars Program, Inc. on July 1 of each year to facilitate the operation of the summer program. Funds shall be used only for the purposes of the Governor's Scholars Program and shall not lapse at the end of the fiscal year. </section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">Governor's Scholars Program, Inc. shall follow standard accounting practices and shall submit the following financial reports to the Office of the Governor, the Finance and Administration Cabinet, and the Legislative Research Commission: <section prefix="1">Quarterly reports of expenditures of state funds, submitted on or before the thirtieth day after the end of each quarter in the corporation's fiscal year; </section><section prefix="2">Annual reports of receipts and expenditures for the Governor's Scholars Program, submitted on or before the sixtieth day after the end of the fiscal year of the corporation; and </section><section prefix="3">The report of an annual financial audit conducted by an independent auditor, submitted on or before September 1 of each year. </section></section><section prefix="b">On or before March 1 of each year, Governor's Scholars Program, Inc. shall file with the Office of the Governor, the Finance and Administration Cabinet, and the Legislative Research Commission a report detailing the operations of the Governor's Scholars Program for the preceding year. The report shall include information concerning the summer program, student and faculty demographics, and program outcomes according to such measures of success as the board may adopt. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 35, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 209, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note> (6/20/2005). 2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 95, 97, 98, 99, 123, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40275</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>