<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.310</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 15.315 to 15.510, 15.990, and 15.992.   </catch_line><order_by>310</order_by><text>As used in KRS 15.315 to 15.510, 15.990, and 15.992, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Basic training course" means the peace officer or court security officer basic training course provided by the Department of Criminal Justice Training or a course approved and recognized by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council; </section><section prefix="2">"Certified court security officer" means a court security officer who is certified under KRS 15.380 to 15.404; </section><section prefix="3">"Certified peace officer" means a peace officer who is certified under KRS 15.380 to 15.404; </section><section prefix="4">"Certification" means the act by the council of issuing certification to a peace officer or court security officer who successfully completes the training requirements pursuant to KRS 15.404 and the requirements set forth within this chapter; </section><section prefix="5">"Council" means the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council established by KRS 15.315 to 15.510, 15.990, and 15.992; </section><section prefix="6">"Court security officer" means a person required to be certified under KRS 15.380(1)(c) and who is charged with the duties set out in KRS 70.280; </section><section prefix="7">"Department" means the Department of Criminal Justice Training of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet; </section><section prefix="8">"Law enforcement officer" means a member of a lawfully organized police unit or police force of county, city or metropolitan government who is responsible for the detection of crime and the enforcement of the general criminal laws of the state, as well as sheriffs, sworn deputy sheriffs, campus police officers, law enforcement support personnel, public airport authority security officers, other public and federal peace officers responsible for law enforcement, and special local peace officers licensed pursuant to KRS 61.360; </section><section prefix="9">"Peace officer" means a person defined in KRS 446.010; </section><section prefix="10">"Secretary" means the secretary of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet; and </section><section prefix="11">"Validated job task analysis" means the minimum entry level qualifications and training requirements for peace officers in the Commonwealth based upon an actual survey and study of police officer duties and responsibilities conducted by an entity recognized by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council as being competent to conduct such a study. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 9, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 54, sec. 6, effective June 26, 2007; and ch. 85, sec. 17, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 480, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 606, sec. 98, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 64, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 20, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 7, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art, V, sec. 30. -- Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 129, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41830</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>