<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="161" order_by="161">SCHOOL EMPLOYEES -- TEACHERS' RETIREMENT AND TENURE </unit></structure><section_number>161.133</section_number><catch_line>Teachers' national certification incentive trust fund -- Purposes -- Appropriations.   </catch_line><order_by>133</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby established a "Teachers' National Certification Incentive Trust Fund" in the State Treasury for the purposes of: <section prefix="a">Funding stipends for teachers to prepare for certification by the National Board for Professional Teaching Standards; </section><section prefix="b">Reimbursing a portion of the certification fee to each teacher who is awarded national board certification; </section><section prefix="c">Reimbursing local boards of education or the Department of Education for persons who serve as substitute teachers for national board certification candidates; and </section><section prefix="d">Funding stipends for national board certified teachers who serve as mentors to other teachers within the school district or the Kentucky Tech system. </section></section><section prefix="2">Appropriations by the General Assembly in each biennial budget for the purpose of supporting national board certification shall be credited to the fund and invested until needed. All money credited to the fund, including interest earned on money in the fund, shall be retained in the fund for reinvestment and used for the purposes of this section. Funds appropriated to the fund shall not lapse at the end of a fiscal year or a biennium. </section><section prefix="3">The Education Professional Standards Board shall promulgate administrative regulations that establish the procedures for the administration of the funds as described in this section and the requirements for participating teachers, local boards of education, and the Department of Education. The board shall allocate only those funds to teachers, school districts, or the department for the purposes in this section for which other sources of funds are not being received. The board may limit the number of participants accepted in any given enrollment or application period due to the lack of available funds. </section><section prefix="4">Money in the fund shall be distributed to local boards of education, the Department of Education, and teachers by the Education Professional Standards Board in compliance with the administrative regulations promulgated by the board. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 45, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 39, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 160, sec. 1, effective March 31, 2003. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 257, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42224</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>