<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXII" order_by="32">OWNERSHIP AND CONVEYANCE OF PROPERTY</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="382" order_by="382">CONVEYANCES AND ENCUMBRANCES </unit></structure><section_number>382.230</section_number><catch_line>Conveyance not void because of error of clerk -- Validation of prior certification and proof. </catch_line><order_by>230</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No conveyance of real property shall be void or invalid because of a failure by the county clerk to incorporate in his certificate to such conveyance an endorsement of acknowledgment made by his deputy thereon.  </section><section prefix="2">When acknowledgments to conveyances of real property have been taken by a deputy clerk, and a note or memorandum thereof endorsed by him on the conveyance, and a certificate of such acknowledgment has been afterward written out by the principal clerk and signed by him as having been done by such deputy or as if the acknowledgment had been before such principal clerk, such conveyance and certificate, and the recording thereof, shall be valid although the note or memorandum made by the deputy was not copied into the certificate.  </section><section prefix="3">No conveyance of real property certified, proven or lodged for record prior to June 17, 1924, shall be void or invalid because it was not certified, proven, or lodged for record as required by the law in force at the time, if it was certified or proven in the manner prescribed by the Act of 1910 c 82, or by KRS 382.130, 382.140 or 382.150. </section></text><history>Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 514. </history><metadata><effective>October 1, 1942</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35605</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>