<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXII" order_by="32">OWNERSHIP AND CONVEYANCE OF PROPERTY</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="383" order_by="383">LANDLORD AND TENANT </unit></structure><section_number>383.605</section_number><catch_line>Tenant's maintenance obligations. </catch_line><order_by>605</order_by><text>A tenant shall:  <section prefix="1">Comply with all obligations primarily imposed upon tenants by applicable provisions of building and housing codes materially affecting health and safety;  </section><section prefix="2">Keep that part of the premises that he occupies and uses as clean and safe as the condition of the premises permit;  </section><section prefix="3">Dispose from his dwelling unit all ashes, garbage, rubbish, and other waste in a clean and safe manner;  </section><section prefix="4">Keep all plumbing fixtures in the dwelling unit or used by the tenant as clean as their condition permits;  </section><section prefix="5">Use in a reasonable manner all electrical, plumbing, sanitary, heating, ventilating, air-conditioning and other facilities and appliances including elevators in the premises;  </section><section prefix="6">Not deliberately or negligently destroy, deface, damage, impair or remove any part of the premises or knowingly permit any person to do so; and  </section><section prefix="7">Conduct himself and require other persons on the premises with his consent to conduct themselves in a manner that will not disturb his neighbors' peaceful enjoyment of the premises. </section></text><history>Repealed and reenacted 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 176, sec. 21, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 378, sec. 22. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35738</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>