<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="216" order_by="216">HEALTH FACILITIES AND SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>216.890</section_number><catch_line>Administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>890</order_by><text><section prefix="1">On or before July 1, 1989, the Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall promulgate administrative regulations to implement the provisions of KRS 216.875 to 216.890, which shall include reasonable and fair standards. Such standards shall relate to: <section prefix="a">The assurance that PPEC services are family-centered and provide individualized medical, developmental, and family training services; </section><section prefix="b">The maintenance of PPEC centers based upon the size of the structure and number of children, relating to plumbing, heating, lighting, ventilation, and other building conditions, including adequate space, which will ensure the health, safety, comfort, and protection from fire of the children served; </section><section prefix="c">The appropriate provisions of the "Life Safety Code" (NFPA-101, 1985 edition); </section><section prefix="d">The number and qualifications of all personnel who have responsibility for the care of the children served; </section><section prefix="e">All sanitary conditions within the PPEC center and its surroundings, including water supply, sewage disposal, food handling, and general hygiene, and maintenance thereof, which will ensure the health and comfort of children served; </section><section prefix="f">Programs and basic services promoting and maintaining the health and development of the children served and meeting the training needs of the children's legal guardians; </section><section prefix="g">Supportive, contracted, other operational, and transportation services; and, </section><section prefix="h">Maintenance of appropriate medical records, data, and information relative to the children and programs to be maintained in the facility for inspection by the cabinet. </section></section><section prefix="2">Enforcement of standards pursuant to the adoption of administrative regulations under KRS 216.875 to 216.890 shall not take effect until six (6) months after the adoption of such administrative regulations. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 495, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 442, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 325, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9143</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>