<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.045</section_number><catch_line>Issuance of transitional license by Division of Malt Beverages or Division of Distilled Spirits -- Limitations on use. </catch_line><order_by>045</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A transitional license may be issued by the director of the Division of Malt Beverages or the director of the Division of Distilled Spirits during the time a transfer of an ongoing business is being processed under the following conditions: <section prefix="a">The purchaser shall file an application for a permanent license with the appropriate local alcoholic beverage authority and with the department; </section><section prefix="b">The purchaser shall advertise its intention to apply for a license pursuant to KRS 243.360; and </section><section prefix="c">The purchaser shall pay all application fees for the permanent license. </section></section><section prefix="2">If the above requirements are met, the director of the Division of Malt Beverages or the director of the Division of Distilled Spirits, as appropriate, shall have the discretion to issue a transitional license with a term of up to sixty (60) days, plus one (1) thirty (30) day extension period, to the purchaser for a processing fee set forth in KRS 243.030 to 243.040. All transitional licenses immediately expire upon the issuance to the purchaser of one (1) or more permanent licenses. </section><section prefix="3">Upon completion of the sale of the business, the purchaser shall not operate the business on the seller's license. </section><section prefix="4">The transitional license shall not be transferable or used for an application to move a business from one (1) location to another location. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 565, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11315</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>