<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">D CONTINUITY OF GOVERNMENT </unit></structure><section_number>39D.050</section_number><catch_line>Preservation of essential state public records -- Duties of Archives and Records Commission. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text>The state Archives and Records Commission shall establish a system for the preservation of essential state public records necessary for the continuity of governmental functions in the event of an emergency, disaster, or catastrophe. The commission shall: <section prefix="1">Determine what records are essential for operation during a state of emergency and thereafter through consultation with all state cabinets, departments, and independent agencies and the administrator of state archives services and records, establish the manner in which the records shall be preserved, and provide for their preservation; </section><section prefix="2">Require every state cabinet, department, and independent agency to establish and maintain a preservation program for essential state public records; </section><section prefix="3">Provide for security storage of essential state records; </section><section prefix="4">Furnish state cabinets, departments, and independent agencies with copies of the final plan for preservation of essential public records; and </section><section prefix="5">Advise all political subdivisions of the Commonwealth on preservation of essential public records. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 56, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21767</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>