<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="210" order_by="210">STATE AND REGIONAL MENTAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>210.410</section_number><catch_line>State aid for regional mental health and intellectual disability programs. </catch_line><order_by>410</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services is hereby authorized to make state grants and other fund allocations from the Cabinet for Health and Family Services to assist any combination of cities and counties, or nonprofit corporations in the establishment and operation of regional community mental health and intellectual disability programs which may provide primary care services and shall provide at least the following services: <section prefix="a">Inpatient services; </section><section prefix="b">Outpatient services; </section><section prefix="c">Partial hospitalization or psychosocial rehabilitation services; </section><section prefix="d">Emergency services; </section><section prefix="e">Consultation and education services; and </section><section prefix="f">Services for individuals with an intellectual disability. </section></section><section prefix="2">The services required in subsection (1)(a), (b), (c), (d), and (e) of this section, in addition to primary care services, if provided, shall be available to the mentally ill, drug abusers and alcohol abusers, and all age groups including children and the elderly. The services required in subsection (1)(a), (b), (c), (d), (e), and (f), in addition to primary care services, if provided, shall be available to individuals with an intellectual disability. The services required in subsection (1)(b) of this section shall be available to any child age sixteen (16) or older upon request of such child without the consent of a parent or legal guardian, if the matter for which the services are sought involves alleged physical or sexual abuse by a parent or guardian whose consent would otherwise be required. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 20, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 330, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 274, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 283, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 6, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 202, effective January 2, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(1) and (8). -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 278, sec. 5. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 90, sec. 64(3). -- Created 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><former-codification> KRS 203.450. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43455</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>