<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="220" order_by="220">SANITATION DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>220.542</section_number><catch_line>Procedure for increase in service charge, rate, or user fee -- Districts with fewer than 10,000 customer accounts exempted. </catch_line><order_by>542</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If the rate increase in a service charge, rate, or user fee is greater than five percent (5%) of the previous charge, rate, or user fee, then the increase shall be subject to the provisions of subsections (2) and (3) of this section. </section><section prefix="2">In a district consisting of only one (1) county, before a proposed service charge, rate, or user fee may be adopted by the district board of directors of a district, it shall receive the approval of the fiscal court or legislative body of the county having jurisdiction over the district. </section><section prefix="3">In a district governed by the provisions of KRS 220.135, or otherwise having jurisdiction in two (2) or more counties, before a proposed service charge, rate, or user fee may be adopted by the district board of directors, it shall receive the approval of a majority of the fiscal courts or legislative bodies of the counties having jurisdiction over a part of the district. Each approval of a fiscal court shall be equally weighted. </section><section prefix="4">A service charge, rate, or user fee shall not be increased more than once in a twelve (12) month period. </section><section prefix="5">The provisions of this section shall not apply to a district formed under this chapter with fewer than ten thousand (10,000) customer accounts. </section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch.98, sec.13, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39886</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>