<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXVI" order_by="36">STATUTORY ACTIONS AND LIMITATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="413" order_by="413">LIMITATION OF ACTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>413.170</section_number><catch_line>Limitations of actions in KRS 413.090 to 413.160 do not run until removal of disability or death. </catch_line><order_by>170</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If a person entitled to bring any action mentioned in KRS 413.090 to 413.160, except for a penalty or forfeiture, was, at the time the cause of action accrued, an infant or of unsound mind, the action may be brought within the same number of years after the removal of the disability or death of the person, whichever happens first, allowed to a person without the disability to bring the action after the right accrued. </section><section prefix="2">The right of action upon the official bond of a guardian, personal representative, curator, of the sheriff, or the officer acting as personal representative, or of any other person receiving and holding money to be distributed to a ward, distributee or devisee, under the order of court or by authority of law, of a ward, distributee, devisee or other person entitled, who was an infant when the bond was executed, shall not be deemed to have accrued, unless otherwise expressed in the bond, before the plaintiff attained the age of twenty-one (21) years. Where there are several wards, or several distributees or devisees or other beneficiaries secured by the same bond, who, or some of whom, were infants when the bond was given, the right of action of each one (1) of such infants shall not be deemed to have accrued before he attained the age of twenty-one (21) years. </section></text><history>Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2521, 2525. </history><metadata><effective>October 1, 1942</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17873</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>