<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="403" order_by="403">DISSOLUTION OF MARRIAGE -- CHILD CUSTODY </unit></structure><section_number>403.720</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 403.715 to 403.785.  (Effective January 1, 2016)</catch_line><order_by>720</order_by><text>As used in KRS 403.715 to 403.785:(1)"Domestic violence and abuse" means physical injury, serious physical injury,stalking, sexual abuse, assault, or the infliction of fear of imminent physicalinjury, serious physical injury, sexual abuse, or assault between familymembers or members of an unmarried couple;(2)"Family member" means a spouse, including a former spouse, a grandparent,a grandchild, a parent, a child, a stepchild, or any other person living in thesame household as a child if the child is the alleged victim;(3)"Foreign protective order" means any judgment, decree, or order of protectionwhich is entitled to full faith and credit pursuant to 18 U.S.C. sec. 2265 that wasissued on the basis of domestic violence and abuse;(4)"Global positioning monitoring system" means a system that electronicallydetermines a person's location through a device worn by the person whichdoes not invade his or her bodily integrity and which transmits the person'slatitude and longitude data to a monitoring entity;(5)"Member of an unmarried couple" means each member of an unmarriedcouple which allegedly has a child in common, any children of that couple, or amember of an unmarried couple who are living together or have formerly livedtogether;(6)"Order of protection" means an emergency protective order or a domesticviolence order and includes a foreign protective order; and(7)"Substantial violation" means criminal conduct which involves actual orthreatened harm to the person, family, or property of an individual protected byan order of protection.</text><history>Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 2, effective January 1, 2016. --Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 170, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended1992 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1988 Ky.Acts ch. 258, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 152,sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 170, sec.20, provides that the amendments made to KRS 15.334, 403.720, 403.735,403.740, 403.750, 431.005, 431.517, 431.518, 431.520, 533.030, and 533.250and the creation of KRS 67.372, 67.374, 403.741, 403.743, 403.747, 403.761,403.762, and 511.085 in that Act shall be known as the "Amanda RossDomestic Violence Prevention Act."</lrc-note><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:32</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44750</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>