<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.470</section_number><catch_line>Centralized resource and referral center for aging caregivers of individuals with an intellectual disability or other developmental disability.   </catch_line><order_by>470</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, "aging caregiver" means an individual age sixty (60) or older who provides care for an individual with an intellectual disability or other developmental disability. </section><section prefix="2">If state, federal, or other funds are available, the Kentucky Department for Behavioral Health, Developmental and Intellectual Disabilities shall, in cooperation with the Department for Aging and Independent Living and the Department for Medicaid Services, establish a centralized resource and referral center designed as a one-stop, seamless system to provide aging caregivers with information and assistance with choices and planning for long-term supports for individuals with an intellectual disability or developmental disability. </section><section prefix="3">The center created in subsection (2) of this section shall provide but not be limited to the following services: <section prefix="a">Comprehensive information on available programs and services, including but not limited to: <section prefix="1">Residential services; </section><section prefix="2">Employment training; </section><section prefix="3">Supported employment; </section><section prefix="4">Behavioral support; </section><section prefix="5">Respite services; </section><section prefix="6">Adult day health or adult day social services; </section><section prefix="7">Support coordination; </section><section prefix="8">Home or environmental modifications; </section><section prefix="9">Community living services, including an attendant, and assistance with homemaking, shopping, and personal care; </section><section prefix="10">Support groups in the community; </section><section prefix="11">Psychiatric services; </section><section prefix="12">Consumer-directed options; </section><section prefix="13">Attorneys or legal services to assist with will preparation; and </section><section prefix="14">The impact of inheritance on government benefits and options, including establishing a special needs trust; </section></section><section prefix="b">Printed material and Internet-based information related to: <section prefix="1">Options for future planning; </section><section prefix="2">Financial and estate planning; </section><section prefix="3">Wills and trusts; and </section><section prefix="4">Advance directives and funeral and burial arrangements; and </section></section><section prefix="c">Referral to community resources. </section></section><section prefix="4">The center created in subsection (2) of this section shall operate a toll-free number at least during regular business hours and shall publish information required in paragraph (a) of subsection (3) of this section and a description of services provided by the center on a cabinet Web site. </section><section prefix="5">The center created in subsection (2) of this section shall make the information listed in subsection (3) of this section available to the support broker and any representative of an individual who is participating in a Medicaid consumer-directed option. </section><section prefix="6">The center shall use electronic information technology to track services provided and to follow-up with individuals served and provide additional information or referrals as needed. </section><section prefix="7">The department may contract with a private entity to provide the services required under subsections (2) and (3) of this section. </section><section prefix="8">The cabinet may provide services identified in subsection (3) of this section to individuals of any age who are caregivers of individuals with an intellectual disability or developmental disability. </section><section prefix="9">Prior to January 1, 2008, the department shall submit a report to the Interim Joint Committee on Health and Welfare that includes but is not limited to the following information: <section prefix="a">The number of individuals who contacted the center; </section><section prefix="b">A description of the categories of questions asked by individuals calling the center; and </section><section prefix="c">A summary of the services provided, including the community resources to which individuals were referred. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 62, effective July 12, 2012; and ch. 158, sec. 26, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 11, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 15, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 195, sec. 6, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note>(7/12/2012). This statute was amended by 2012 Ky. Acts chs. 146 and 158. Where these Acts are not in conflict, they have been codified together. Where a conflict exists, Acts ch. 146, which was last enacted by the General Assembly, prevails under KRS 446.250.  (7/12/2006).  In subsection (1) of this statute, the Reviser of Statutes has substituted the word "or" for the word "and" in the phrase "age sixty (60) and older" to correct a manifest clerical error. See KRS 7.136(1). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40792</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>