<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.30-030</section_number><catch_line>Licenses. </catch_line><order_by>30-030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall engage in the business of financing insurance premiums in this state without first having obtained a license as a premium finance company from the commissioner. </section><section prefix="2">The annual license fee shall be as specified in Subtitle 4 of this chapter. Licenses may be renewed from year to year as of the first day of May of each year upon payment of the fee. </section><section prefix="3">The person to whom the license or the renewal thereof may be issued shall file sworn answers, subject to the penalties of perjury, to such interrogatories as the commissioner may require. The commissioner shall have authority, at any time, to require the applicant fully to disclose the identity of all stockholders, partners, officers, and employees and he or she may, in his or her discretion, refuse to issue or renew a license in the name of any firm, partnership, or corporation if the commissioner is not satisfied that any officer, employee, stockholder, or partner thereof who may materially influence the applicant's conduct meets the standards of this subtitle. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1408, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 320, sec. 32, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 30, sec. 3, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:06</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29747</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>