<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.8805</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 65.8801 to 65.8839. </catch_line><order_by>8805</order_by><text>As used in KRS 65.8801 to 65.8839, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Local government" means any county, any municipal corporation of any class incorporated in the Commonwealth, any urban-county government organized and governed under KRS Chapter 67A, and any charter county government organized and governed under KRS Chapter 67. </section><section prefix="2">"Code enforcement board" means an administrative body created and acting under the authority of KRS 65.8801 to 65.8839. </section><section prefix="3">"Joint code enforcement board" means two (2) or more local governments that have entered into an interlocal agreement in accordance with KRS 65.210 to 65.300 to perform and enforce the duties of a code enforcement board as provided in KRS 65.8801 to 65.8839. </section><section prefix="4">"Code enforcement officer" means a city police officer, safety officer, citation officer, county police officer, sheriff, deputy sheriff, university police officer, airport police officer, or other public law enforcement officer with the authority to issue a citation. </section><section prefix="5">"Ordinance" means an official action of a local government body, which is a regulation of a general and permanent nature and enforceable as a local law and shall include any provision of a code of ordinances adopted by a local government which embodies all or part of an ordinance. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 177, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23536</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>