<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17A-340</section_number><catch_line>Restrictions on use of Kentucky Children's Health Insurance Program allocated funds. </catch_line><order_by>17A-340</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In no event shall more than ten percent (10%) of federal and state funds allocated to the Kentucky Children's Health Insurance Program be used for: <section prefix="a">Children's health programs other than those targeted for low-income children as defined under Title XXI of the Federal Social Security Act; </section><section prefix="b">Initiatives for improving the health of children except those low income children as defined under Title XXI of the Federal Social Security Act or an approved Title XXI state plan (KCHIP); </section><section prefix="c">Outreach activities that inform families of children who are likely to be eligible for this program or other public or private health coverage programs allowed by the Federal Social Security Act; and </section><section prefix="d">Other reasonable costs incurred by the state to administer the program. </section></section><section prefix="2">The department shall use the insurer's or health maintenance organization's sales and marketing methods and may include the use of agents and payment of commissions, to inform families of the availability of the Kentucky Children's Health Insurance Program and assist them in obtaining coverage for children under the program. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1226, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 253, sec. 8, effective April 2, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17415</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>