<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="99" order_by="99">URBAN RENEWAL AND REDEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>99.615</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 99.610 to 99.680.   </catch_line><order_by>615</order_by><text>The following words or terms shall have the following meanings wherever used in KRS 99.610 to 99.680 unless a different meaning is clearly indicated by the context: <section prefix="1">"Act" means KRS 99.610 to 99.680 which may be called the "Local Development Authority Act"; </section><section prefix="2">"Technical advisory council" means that committee appointed under the terms of KRS 99.655; </section><section prefix="3">"Price advisory council" means that committee appointed under the terms of KRS 99.680; </section><section prefix="4">"Agency" means a development authority established by this statute in and for cities of the first class, cities with populations equal to or greater than fifteen thousand (15,000) based upon the most recent federal decennial census, a consolidated local government, and urban-county governments; </section><section prefix="5">"Bonds" means any bonds, notes, interim certificates, debentures, or other obligations issued by an agency pursuant to the provisions and purposes of KRS 99.610 to 99.680; </section><section prefix="6">"Project area" means any area or specific property designated by an agency or any area or specific property actually acquired or formally proposed for acquisition by an agency, for historical or open space preservation purposes, or for the development permitted by KRS 99.610 to 99.680; </section><section prefix="7">"City" means any city of the first class, cities with populations equal to or greater than fifteen thousand (15,000) based upon the most recent federal decennial census, a consolidated local government, or an urban-county government, in which an agency has been established; </section><section prefix="8">"Development" means the acquisition, planning, designing, clearance, renovation, or rehabilitation of existing improvements, development, and disposal, or any combination thereof, of a project area, including the preparation of such project area for the development of residential, commercial, industrial, public, recreational, open space, or other uses, including the preservation of existing residential, commercial, industrial, public, recreational, open spaces, or other uses valued locally for their economic or historical importance as may be appropriate or necessary, in the opinion of the board of commissioners of an agency; </section><section prefix="9">"Subdevelopment" means the actual construction, renovation, or rehabilitation of improvements to real property including the installation of or improvement to existing utilities, curbs, gutters, sidewalks, storm sewers, and other necessary works and improvements, consistent with the established development plan for each specific project area in order to market, through private enterprise, said improvements to individuals, commercial business, and industry; </section><section prefix="10">"Development plan" means the plan for the development as defined, of all or any part of a project area; </section><section prefix="11">"Mayor" means the mayor of a city as defined in this section; </section><section prefix="12">"Governing board" means a board of aldermen or commissioners, a legislative council in a consolidated local government, an urban-county council, or any legislative body of a city as defined in this section; </section><section prefix="13">"Project" means any undertaking within a project area and any such undertaking which may be included in, and financed by, a single or separate financing agreement or bond issue; </section><section prefix="14">"Persons and families of lower income" means persons and families who lack the amount of income which is necessary (as determined by standards established by the agency) to enable them, without financial assistance, to live in decent, safe, and sanitary dwellings, without overcrowding; and </section><section prefix="15">"Residential housing project" means a specific work or improvement undertaken primarily to provide or to rehabilitate dwelling accommodations for persons and families of lower income, including the acquisition, construction, and rehabilitation of land, buildings, and improvements and such other facilities as may be incidental or appurtenant thereto. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 188, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 124, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 131, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:07</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43773</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>