<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="317" order_by="317">A COSMETOLOGISTS </unit></structure><section_number>317A.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter.   </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Beauty salon" means any establishment in which the practice of cosmetology is conducted for the general public or for consideration; </section><section prefix="2">"Cosmetologist" means a person who engages in the practice of cosmetology for the public generally or for consideration, regardless of the name under which the practice is conducted; </section><section prefix="3">"Cosmetologist board" or "board" means the Kentucky Board of Hairdressers and Cosmetologists; </section><section prefix="4">"Cosmetology" means the practice upon the human neck and head of cutting hair, permanent waving, or hairdressing, and may also include but is not limited to: <section prefix="a">Nail technology and finger waving; </section><section prefix="b">Giving facial and scalp massage or treatments with oils, creams, lotions, or other preparations, either by hand or any contrivance; </section><section prefix="c">Shaping, designing, shampooing, pressing, arranging, tinting, or lightening the hair, or applying hair products; </section><section prefix="d">Applying to the neck or head, cosmetics, lotions, powders, oils, clays, or other products; </section><section prefix="e">Eyelash extensions; </section><section prefix="f">Facial hair removal; and </section><section prefix="g">Eyebrow shaping, design, threading or removal. </section></section> The practice of cosmetology does not include acts performed incident to treatment of an illness or a disease; <section prefix="5">"Cosmetology school" or "school of cosmetology" means any operation, place, or establishment in or through which persons are trained or taught the practice of cosmetology and nail technology; </section><section prefix="6">"Nail salon" means any establishment in which the practice of nail technology only is conducted for the general public or for consideration; </section><section prefix="7">"Nail technician" means a person who practices nail technology for the general public or for consideration; </section><section prefix="8">"Nail technology" means the practice of cutting, trimming, polishing, coloring, cleansing, applying artificial nails, or massaging, cleaning, treating, or beautifying the hands and feet of any human, for which a license is required by this chapter; and </section><section prefix="9">"Threading" means the process of removing hair from below the eyebrow by use of a thread woven through the hair to be removed. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 354, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40878</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>