<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="178" order_by="178">COUNTY ROADS -- GRADE CROSSING ELIMINATION </unit></structure><section_number>178.150</section_number><catch_line>Department of Highways to render assistance in certain cases. </catch_line><order_by>150</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When it is necessary to build or repair a bridge and the building and repair will cost more than five hundred dollars ($500), the county road engineer shall notify the Department of Highways that such work is to be done. The Department of Highways shall then furnish to the county road engineer plans, specifications and estimates of cost, which he shall submit to the fiscal court. The county road engineer shall keep in his records the plans, specifications and estimates of cost furnished by the Department of Highways, and also the plans, specifications and estimates of cost and the actual cost of the repair or construction work which is actually done. The fiscal court shall not be required to accept the plans, specifications and estimates furnished by the Department of Highways. </section><section prefix="2">This same plan shall be followed in making the purchase of all county road machinery, when the amount of the purchase is five hundred dollars ($500) or more. </section><section prefix="3">When a new hard surface road is to be built, or an old dirt road converted into a hard surface road, the county road engineer of the county in which the improvement is to be made shall notify the Department of Highways, and the department shall send an assistant engineer to assist in laying out the road, and in drawing plans and specifications and making up estimates of cost for the road. This shall be done at the expense of the state. The fiscal court shall not be compelled to accept the plans and specifications of the engineer furnished by the Department of Highways, but a record of them shall be kept. After contracts are awarded, the estimates furnished by the Department of Highways and the contract price shall be published as advertisements provided for in KRS 178.050. </section></text><history>Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4305. </history><metadata><effective>October 1, 1942 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5435</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>