<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="36" order_by="36">DEPARTMENT OF MILITARY AFFAIRS </unit></structure><section_number>36.477</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky National Guard Adoption Assistance Program.   </catch_line><order_by>477</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby established the Kentucky National Guard Adoption Assistance Program to be administered by the Kentucky Department of Military Affairs. </section><section prefix="2">Any member of the Kentucky National Guard who finalizes a legal adoption procedure for the adoption of a child, other than the child of a spouse, on or after July 12, 2012, shall be eligible to receive reimbursement from the military family assistance trust fund as provided in KRS 36.474 for actual costs associated with the adoption of the child, including a child with special needs. For the purposes of this section, a child with special needs means the same as defined in KRS 199.555(1). </section><section prefix="3">The eligible member of the Kentucky National Guard shall receive: <section prefix="a">Up to five thousand dollars ($5,000) in unreimbursed direct costs related to the adoption of a child with special needs; or </section><section prefix="b">Up to three thousand dollars ($3,000) in unreimbursed direct costs related to the adoption of any other child. </section></section><section prefix="4">Unreimbursed direct costs related to the adoption of a child with special needs or other child shall include: <section prefix="a">Licensed adoption agency fees; </section><section prefix="b">Legal fees; </section><section prefix="c">Medical costs; </section><section prefix="d">Court costs; and </section><section prefix="e">Other fees or costs associated with the child adoption in accordance with state and federal law and after review and approval by the court at the finalization of the adoption. </section></section><section prefix="5">Application for financial assistance shall be made by submitting a completed Kentucky National Guard adoption assistance application to the adjutant general along with documentary evidence of: <section prefix="a">Finalization of the adoption; and </section><section prefix="b">Certification by the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services that the adopted child is a child with special needs, if reimbursement for special needs adoption is sought. </section></section><section prefix="6">If both adoptive parents are members of the Kentucky National Guard, the application for financial assistance shall be made jointly and the amount of reimbursement shall be limited to that specified in subsection (2) of this section. </section><section prefix="7">Upon approval of the application for financial assistance, the adjutant general shall dispense funds from the military family assistance trust fund to the eligible applicant. </section><section prefix="8">The Department of Military Affairs shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to carry out the provisions of this section. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40095</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>