<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.203</section_number><catch_line>Authorization to provide in-home services to the aging -- Collection of fees. </catch_line><order_by>203</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services may provide, within budgetary limitations, for in-home services to the aging to include, but not necessarily limited to: homemaker services; home-help therapy services; day-care services; home-delivered meal services; transportation services; foster care services; and health services. </section><section prefix="2">The cabinet is authorized to collect fees for services rendered pursuant to this section in accordance with a fee schedule adopted by the secretary for health and family services. The fee schedule shall take into consideration the ability of the patient or client to pay for such services. Fees shall not be collected from any person who is "needy aged" as defined by KRS 205.010. </section><section prefix="3">The secretary may utilize and promote available or potential community resources for the delivery of services to the aging and shall, when he deems appropriate, contract for services with local, community, private agencies, and individuals, including relatives of patients and clients, when such services would not otherwise be available without cost. </section><section prefix="4">The services to the aging authorized under this section are in addition and supplementary to any services to which the aging may be entitled under any other federal, state, or local governmental law, regulation, or program. </section><section prefix="5">The services to the aging authorized under this section shall be designed to meet the needs of the minority elderly as identified by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services pursuant to KRS 205.201. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 221, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 21, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 188, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 246, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 207, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7655</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>