<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">E IMPLEMENTATION OF FEDERAL HAZARDOUS MATERIALS PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>39E.020</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Commission" means the Kentucky Emergency Response Commission and those persons appointed by the Governor to implement provisions of Title III, Pub. L. No. 99-499 and this chapter. </section><section prefix="2">"Local emergency planning committee," hereafter referred to as the "local committee," means those persons appointed by the commission to assist in the implementation of Title III, Pub. L. No. 99-499 and this chapter. </section><section prefix="3">"Release" means, but is not limited to, any spilling, leaking, pumping, pouring, emitting, emptying, discharging, injecting, escaping, leaching, dumping, or disposing into the environment, including the abandonment or discarding of barrels, containers and other closed receptacles, of any hazardous substance. </section><section prefix="4">"Reportable quantity" means an amount of hazardous substances released which requires notification to local and state warning points. </section><section prefix="5">"Hazardous substance" means a substance specified by Title III, Pub. L. No. 99-499, subsequent federal regulations, this chapter, and subsequent administrative regulations as requiring notification if released or if stored, manufactured, or used. </section><section prefix="6">"Warning point" means that location, operated by state or local government, and identified by the state commission or local committee, and which is continuously staffed, and which has the capability or responsibility to contact governmental emergency response organizations and, if capability exists, to warn the public of hazards which may affect them. </section><section prefix="7">"Emergency response organization" means a unit of local government or a unit authorized by local government which may be called to make a response because of a release of a hazardous substance, and whose responsibilities are included in plans developed under this chapter. </section><section prefix="8">"Facility" means all buildings, equipment structures, and other stationary items which are located on a single site or on contiguous or adjacent sites and which are owned or operated by the same person, or by any person which controls, is controlled by, or under common control with such person, and which manufactures, stores, or uses substances covered under this chapter. For purposes of KRS 39E.190, the term includes motor vehicles, rolling stock, and aircraft. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 59, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21770</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>