<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="434" order_by="434">OFFENSES AGAINST PROPERTY BY FRAUD </unit></structure><section_number>434.442</section_number><catch_line>Fraudulent use of an educational record -- Penalty. </catch_line><order_by>442</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of fraudulent use of an educational record when that person, knowingly: <section prefix="a">Falsely makes, completes, alters, or procures to be falsely made or altered, or assists in falsely making or altering, a diploma, certificate, license, or transcript indicating academic achievement in an educational program issued by a secondary school, a postsecondary educational institution, or a governmental agency; </section><section prefix="b">Sells, gives, buys, or obtains, or procures to be sold, given, bought or obtained, or assists in selling, giving, buying, or obtaining, a diploma, certificate, license, or transcript which he knows is false, indicating educational achievement in an educational program issued by a secondary school, postsecondary educational institution, or a governmental agency; </section><section prefix="c">Presents or uses as genuine a falsely made or altered diploma, certificate, license, or transcript indicating educational achievement in an educational program in a secondary school, postsecondary educational institution, or a governmental agency; or </section><section prefix="d">Makes a false written representation of fact that he has received a degree or other certification indicating merit, educational achievement, or completion of an educational program involving study, experience, or testing from a secondary school, a postsecondary educational institution, or governmental agency in an application for: <section prefix="1">Employment; </section><section prefix="2">Admission to an educational program; </section><section prefix="3">An award; or </section><section prefix="4">The purpose of inducing another to issue a diploma, certificate, license, or transcript indicating educational achievement in an educational program of a secondary school, postsecondary educational institution, or a governmental agency. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">Fraudulent use of an educational record is a Class A misdemeanor. </section></text><history> Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 170, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=18882</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>