<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.13-071</section_number><catch_line>Disapproval of rates and rate filings. </catch_line><order_by>13-071</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Existing rates in a noncompetitive market may be disapproved pursuant to the rating standards of this chapter after a hearing. Rates that have been filed in a noncompetitive market but that have not become effective may be disapproved pursuant to the rating standards of this chapter without a hearing. However, any insurer whose rates have been disapproved without a hearing shall be given a hearing on a written request made within thirty (30) days after the disapproval order. Hearings conducted under authority of this section shall be conducted in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. If a rate is disapproved, the commissioner shall issue a final order specifying the reasons for disapproval. Any party aggrieved by the final order of the commissioner may appeal as provided in KRS 304.2-370. The effect of a final order shall be stayed during the pendency of the appeal and the existing rate shall remain in effect until the final conclusion thereof. </section><section prefix="2">At any hearing concerning an increase in worker's compensation rates conducted pursuant to subsection (1), the commissioner may approve a rate other than one that has been proposed by the filer if it is justified by the evidence presented at the hearing. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1123, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 233, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 93, sec. 21, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 278, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:07</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17065</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>