<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">BUDGET AND FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION </unit></structure><section_number>45.3511</section_number><catch_line>Restrictions on applications -- Counties without incorporated area. </catch_line><order_by>3511</order_by><text><section prefix="1">State administering agencies shall not have continuation block grant application requests. Each application for a block grant shall be deemed a new application. </section><section prefix="2">No state administering agency shall receive or expend any block grant or other funds included in a block grant application to a federal administering agency, which has not previously been specifically approved as a block grant by the General Assembly in the biennial budget process as having complied with the criteria specified in KRS 45.353, unless the application is found to be in compliance with the standards and criteria as prescribed in KRS 45.353, as well as the applicable federal and state laws. </section><section prefix="3">If a county contains no incorporated area, that county shall be permitted to submit two (2) applications per year, one (1) as a county and one (1) as a city, for any block grant program or any category of a block grant program that provides funding on a competitive basis. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 252, Pt. XXV, sec. 1, effective April 25, 2006. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 455, sec. 3, effective July 1, 1982 and July 1, 1983. </history><metadata><effective> April 25, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22242</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>