<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.1-205</section_number><catch_line>Uses for environmental trust fund. </catch_line><order_by>1-205</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The environmental trust fund may be used to support scientific, technical, or environmental research needed to develop and guide environmental protection and natural resource management policies. Research topics may include but shall not be limited to air quality; water quality, including groundwater protection; water resource management; environmental impacts of natural resource extractions, including surface mining and oil and gas production; waste management, including solid and hazardous waste; environmental impact of noise; soil conservation; and forest resource management. Research activities may include collecting baseline environmental data and studying environmental problems existing in or of concern to the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="2">The environmental trust fund may be used to finance research and development projects that promote the use of innovative solutions to environmental problems existing in or of concern to the Commonwealth. Research and development projects shall have cosponsors who will cooperate in the gathering and sharing of research data. Cosponsors may include but shall not be limited to local governments, universities, state agencies, nonprofit organizations, and private persons. </section><section prefix="3">The environmental trust fund may be used to collect and disseminate information derived from any activities conducted pursuant to KRS 224.1-200 to 224.1-220. </section><section prefix="4">The environmental trust fund may be used to support educational and training programs relating to the protection of the environment. </section><section prefix="5">The board created in KRS 224.1-210 shall take into consideration state and federal moneys available for projects prior to expending money in the environmental trust fund. </section><section prefix="6">The environmental trust fund shall not be used to support or finance the routine day-to-day activities and responsibilities of the Energy and Environment Cabinet. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 345, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 129, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 224.2113. KRS 224.01-205. </former-codification><former-codification-former-code>224.01-205</former-codification-former-code><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41554</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>