<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="42" order_by="42">FINANCE AND ADMINISTRATION CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>42.320</section_number><catch_line>Court cost distribution fund -- Disbursements -- Payments into general fund. </catch_line><order_by>320</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby established the court cost distribution fund, which is created to provide a central account into which the court costs collected by all circuit clerks, under KRS 23A.205(1) and 24A.175(1), shall be paid. </section><section prefix="2">The fund shall be administered by the Finance and Administration Cabinet, which shall make monthly disbursements from the fund according to the following schedule: <section prefix="a">Forty-nine percent (49%) of each court cost shall be paid into the general fund; </section><section prefix="b">Ten and eight-tenths percent (10.8%) of each court cost, up to five million four hundred thousand dollars ($5,400,000), shall be paid into the State Treasury for the benefit and use of the Kentucky Local Correctional Facilities Construction Authority under KRS 441.605 to 441.695; </section><section prefix="c">Six and one-half percent (6.5%) of each court cost, up to three million two hundred fifty thousand dollars ($3,250,000), shall be paid into the spinal cord and head injury research trust fund created in KRS 211.504; </section><section prefix="d">Five and one-half percent (5.5%) of each court cost, up to two million seven hundred fifty thousand dollars ($2,750,000), shall be paid into the traumatic brain injury trust fund created in KRS 211.476; </section><section prefix="e">Five percent (5%) of each court cost, up to two million five hundred thousand dollars ($2,500,000), shall be paid into a trust and agency account with the Administrative Office of the Courts and is to be used by the circuit clerks to hire additional deputy clerks and to enhance deputy clerk salaries; </section><section prefix="f">Three and one-half percent (3.5%) of each court cost, up to one million seven hundred fifty thousand dollars ($1,750,000), shall be paid to a special trust and agency account that shall not lapse for the Department for Public Advocacy; </section><section prefix="g">Three and four-tenths percent (3.4%) of each court cost, up to one million seven hundred thousand dollars ($1,700,000), shall be paid into the crime victims' compensation fund created in KRS 346.185; </section><section prefix="h">Seven-tenths of one percent (0.7%) of each court cost, up to three hundred fifty thousand dollars ($350,000), shall be paid to the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet to defray the costs of conducting record checks on prospective firearms purchasers pursuant to the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act and for the collection, testing, and storing of DNA samples; </section><section prefix="i">Ten and one-tenth percent (10.1%) of each court cost, up to five million fifty thousand dollars ($5,050,000), deposited in the fund shall be paid to the county sheriff in the county from which the court cost was received; and </section><section prefix="j">Five and one-half percent (5.5%) of each court cost, up to two million seven hundred fifty thousand dollars ($2,750,000), deposited in the fund shall be paid to the county treasurer in the county from which the court cost was received and shall be used by the fiscal court in that county for the purposes of defraying the costs of operation of the county jail and the transportation of prisoners. </section></section><section prefix="3">Any moneys remaining in the fund after the monthly disbursements in subsection (2) of this section shall be paid into the general fund. </section><section prefix="4">Any moneys collected above the prescribed amount shall be paid into the general fund. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 123, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 183, sec. 9, effective August 1, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, H, 4, (3) at 649. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><lrc-note>(6/26/2007).  2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, relating to the creation and organization of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, instructs the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in that Act. Such a correction has been made in this section.  (7/15/2002). This statute number, KRS 42.320, was previously used for a KRS section that was repealed. That earlier section (1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VIII, Part I, sec. 1; 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 5) was repealed by 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 450, sec. 79, effective July 1, 1983. The catchline at repeal read, "State clearinghouse functions for federal funds." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22015</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>