<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.400</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Physicians Care Program -- Provision of primary health care services to eligible individuals -- Volunteer networks -- Advisory committees.   </catch_line><order_by>400</order_by><text><section prefix="1">To the extent possible with available funds, the Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall establish and operate the Kentucky Physicians Care Program to assist low-income uninsured and underinsured individuals in accessing primary health care services provided by volunteer health care practitioners and pharmaceutical drugs donated by pharmaceutical companies. </section><section prefix="2">The program may access networks of practitioners, pharmacies, and pharmaceutical companies that are maintained by entities that recruit volunteers and donations, such as Health Kentucky, Inc. and the Kentucky Free Health Clinic Association, to locate necessary health care services for eligible applicants. </section><section prefix="3">The program shall: <section prefix="a">Operate and maintain a professionally staffed toll-free hotline information and referral service for individuals seeking primary care; </section><section prefix="b">Refer individuals seeking health care services to the Department for Community Based Services or other enrollment sites approved by the cabinet for eligibility determination; </section><section prefix="c">Refer individuals determined to be eligible to available health care service providers; and </section><section prefix="d">Maintain a confidential record of all referrals. </section></section><section prefix="4">The program may: <section prefix="a">Create temporary volunteer advisory committees to provide input on program operations and efficiencies; </section><section prefix="b">Contract with qualified, independent third parties to provide services; and </section><section prefix="c">Apply for federal funds or other grants to operate the program. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 6, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42417</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>