<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.4-010</section_number><catch_line>Fees to be prescribed by administrative regulation -- Time prescribed if fees remitted by electronic submission. </catch_line><order_by>4-010</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commissioner shall by regulation prescribe the fees charged by the commissioner and the services for which fees shall be charged, including the following fees: <section prefix="a">For copies of any document on file with the commissioner, per page, thirty cents ($0.30); and </section><section prefix="b">For copies of annual statements, per page, one dollar ($1). </section></section><section prefix="2">All fees shall be collected in advance. </section><section prefix="3">Notwithstanding subsection (2) of this section, an insurer submitting applications, appointments, or filings through the electronic system adopted by the department shall remit the applicable fees to the department within fifteen (15) calendar days of the electronic submission. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 988, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 483, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 464, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 225, sec. 25, effective July 15, 1988; and ch. 408, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986; ch. 307, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986; and ch. 437, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 7, effective July 13, 1984; ch. 111, sec. 129, effective July 13, 1984; and ch. 322, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 319, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982; and ch. 320, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 161, sec. 6, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 1, effective July 1, 1970; and ch. 301, subtit. 4, sec. 1, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:08</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=16748</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>