<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="159" order_by="159">COMPULSORY ATTENDANCE </unit></structure><section_number>159.080</section_number><catch_line>Director of pupil personnel and assistants. </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each superintendent of a local school district shall appoint a director of pupil personnel and assistants as are deemed necessary. Salaries of directors and assistants shall be fixed by the board of education. </section><section prefix="2">Directors of pupil personnel shall have the general qualifications of teachers and, in addition, shall hold a valid certificate issued in accordance with the administrative regulations of the Education Professional Standards Board. Certificates valid on January 1, 1956, for attendance officer shall hereafter be valid for the positions of director of pupil personnel. Certificates shall be reissued or renewed in accordance with the terms of the administrative regulations of the Education Professional Standards Board in effect at the time of application for reissuance or renewal. </section><section prefix="3">Directors of pupil personnel and assistants shall be allowed their necessary and authorized expenses incurred in the performance of their duties. Each board shall bear the expense of its directors of pupil personnel and assistants incurred in its district. </section><section prefix="4">The office of the superintendent of schools shall be the office of the director of pupil personnel and suitable space shall be provided therein or adjacent thereto for him or her. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 343, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 42, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. IV, sec. 219, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 82, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 237, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4434-6. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3636</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>