<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="315" order_by="315">PHARMACISTS AND PHARMACIES </unit></structure><section_number>315.514</section_number><catch_line>License required to provide or hold oneself out as providing home medical equipment and services -- Exemptions.   </catch_line><order_by>514</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall provide home medical equipment and services, or use the title "home medical equipment and services provider" in connection with his or her profession or business, without a license issued by the board. </section><section prefix="2">Unless home medical equipment and services are provided through a separate legal entity, nothing in KRS 315.510 to 315.524 or any administrative regulations promulgated thereunder shall be construed as preventing or restricting the practices, services, or activities of the following: <section prefix="a">A person licensed or registered in this state under any other law who is engaging in the profession or occupation for which he or she is licensed or registered; </section><section prefix="b">Health care practitioners who lawfully prescribe or order home medical equipment and services, or who use home medical equipment and services to treat their patients; </section><section prefix="c">Home health agencies that do not engage in the provision of home medical equipment and services; </section><section prefix="d">Hospitals that provide home medical equipment and services only as an integral part of patient care; </section><section prefix="e">Manufacturers and wholesale distributors of home medical equipment who do not sell, lease, or rent home medical equipment directly to a patient; </section><section prefix="f">Pharmacies that are engaged in the sale, lease, or rental of home medical equipment and services; </section><section prefix="g">An employee of a person licensed under KRS 315.510 to 315.524; </section><section prefix="h">Hospice programs that do not involve the sale, lease, or rental of home medical equipment and services; </section><section prefix="i">Skilled nursing facilities that do not involve the sale, lease, or rental of home medical equipment and services; </section><section prefix="j">Government agencies, including fire districts which provide emergency medical services; and </section><section prefix="k">Notwithstanding subsection (1) of this section, an out-of-state provider whose primary business is the manufacture, distribution, or both, of highly specialized equipment who ships that equipment into this state if that equipment is not provided by a licensed Kentucky home medical equipment and services provider. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 56, sec. 4, effective June 24, 2015. -- Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 73, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44424</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>