<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.47-010</section_number><catch_line>Legislative findings. </catch_line><order_by>47-010</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky finds that the forests of the Commonwealth provide abundant, renewal timber resources that historically have been underdeveloped, underutilized, and poorly managed, but which have proven to be resilient; and that, with proper planning, management, harvesting, value-added processing and manufacturing, and marketing, these resources will continue to grow in importance to the Commonwealth's economy. </section><section prefix="2">The General Assembly further finds that through proper attention and direction by the agencies of the Commonwealth and its public educational institutions working in partnership with secondary wood products businesses, the secondary wood products industry as a key industrial sector of the Commonwealth's future economic growth and health, should prosper through the generation of new and expanding secondary wood products manufacturers by supporting improved management and harvesting practices, by developing and implementing workers' training programs to upgrade the skills of Kentuckians employed in the wood products processing and manufacturing industry, by assisting the private sector to adapt existing manufacturing systems to new or improved technologies and world class management practices for the purposes of increasing product quality and productivity of Kentucky's wood products manufacturers and processors and enhancing the global competitiveness of Kentucky secondary wood products industries. </section></text><history> Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 224, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2933</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>