<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.9-107</section_number><catch_line>Persons exempt from provisions of KRS 304.9-105(1)(e)1. and 2. -- Administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>9-107</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The following persons shall be exempt from the prelicensing course of study requirements for specific lines of authority of KRS 304.9-105(1)(e)1.: <section prefix="a">Persons holding a Chartered Life Underwriter (CLU) designation for a life line of authority; </section><section prefix="b">Persons holding a Chartered Property and Casualty Underwriter (CPCU) designation for property, personal lines, and casualty lines of authority; </section><section prefix="c">Persons holding a Certified Insurance Counselor (CIC) designation for life, health, property, personal lines, and casualty lines of authority; </section><section prefix="d">Persons holding a designation as a Certified Employee Benefit Specialist (CEBS), Chartered Financial Consultant (ChFC), Certified Financial Planner (CFP), Fellow of the Life Management Institute (FLMI), or Life Underwriter Training Council Fellow (LUTCF) for a life line of authority; </section><section prefix="e">Persons holding a designation as a Registered Health Underwriter (RHU), Certified Employee Benefit Specialist (CEBS), Registered Employee Benefit Consultant (REBC), or Health Insurance Advisor (HIA) for a health line of authority; </section><section prefix="f">Persons holding a designation as an Accredited Advisor in Insurance (AAI) or Associate in Risk Management (ARM) for property, personal lines, and casualty lines of authority; and </section><section prefix="g">Persons holding an insurance degree from an accredited college or university for all lines of authority. </section></section><section prefix="2">The commissioner may promulgate administrative regulations to specify additional designations and degrees for exemption from a prelicensing course of study for specified lines of authority to comply with NAIC uniformity standards. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1048, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 254, sec. 4, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 143, sec. 7, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 393, sec. 8, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 189, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:07</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=16899</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>