<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.854Approval</section_number><catch_line>of supervising physician -- Requirements -- Application -- Number of assistants -- Restrictions on practice and supervision.   </catch_line><order_by>854Approval</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A physician shall not supervise a physician assistant without approval of the board. Failure to obtain board approval as a supervising physician or failure to comply with the requirements of KRS 311.840 to 311.862 or related administrative regulations shall be considered unprofessional conduct and shall be subject to disciplinary action by the board that may include revocation, suspension, restriction, or placing on probation the supervising physician's right to supervise a physician assistant. </section><section prefix="2">To be approved by the board as a supervising physician, a physician shall: <section prefix="a">Be currently licensed and in good standing with the board; </section><section prefix="b">Maintain a practice primarily within this Commonwealth. The board in its discretion may modify or waive this requirement; </section><section prefix="c">Submit a completed application and the required fee to the board. The application shall include but is not limited to: <section prefix="1">A description of the nature of the physician's practice; </section><section prefix="2">A statement of assurance by the supervising physician that the scope of medical services and procedures described in the application or in any supplemental information shall not exceed the normal scope of practice of the supervising physician; </section><section prefix="3">A description of the means by which the physician shall maintain communication with the physician assistant when they are not in the same physical location; </section><section prefix="4">The name, address, and area of practice of one (1) or more physicians who agree in writing to accept responsibility for supervising the physician assistant in the absence of the supervising physician; and </section><section prefix="5">A description of the scope of medical services and procedures to be performed by the physician assistant for which the physician assistant has been trained in an approved program. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">Prior to a physician assistant performing any service or procedure beyond those described in the initial application submitted to the board under subsection (2)(c) of this section, the supervising physician shall supplement that application with information that includes but is not limited to: <section prefix="a">A description of the additional service or procedure; </section><section prefix="b">A description of the physician assistant's education, training, experience, and institutional credentialing; </section><section prefix="c">A description of the level of supervision to be provided for the additional service or procedure; and </section><section prefix="d">The location or locations where the additional service or procedure will be provided. </section></section> The initial and supplemental applications required under this section may be submitted to the board at the same time. <section prefix="4">A physician who has been supervising a physician assistant prior to July 15, 2002, may continue supervision and the physician assistant may continue to perform all medical services and procedures that were provided by the physician assistant prior to July 15, 2002. The supervising physician shall submit the initial application and any supplemental application as required in this section by October 15, 2002. </section><section prefix="5">A physician may enter into supervision agreements with no more than four (4) physician assistants and shall not supervise more than four (4) physician assistants at any one (1) time. Application for board approval to be a supervising physician shall be obtained individually for each physician assistant. </section><section prefix="6">The board may impose restrictions on the scope of practice of a physician assistant or on the methods of supervision by the supervising physician upon consideration of recommendations of the Physician Assistant Advisory Committee established in KRS 311.842 after providing the applicant with reasonable notice of its intended action and after providing a reasonable opportunity to be heard. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2015. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 30, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44677</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>