<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.607</section_number><catch_line>Petition for new license two years after revocation -- Probation period. </catch_line><order_by>607</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except for disciplinary actions taken pursuant to KRS 311.595(8) and KRS 311.599, a licensee who has had his license revoked may, after two (2) years from the effective date of the revocation order, petition the board for a license to again practice in the Commonwealth of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="2">The board shall not be required to issue a new license as described in subsection (1). No new license shall be issued to such former licensee unless the applicant satisfies the board that he is presently of good moral character and qualified both physically and mentally to resume the practice of medicine without undue risk or danger to his patients or the public. </section><section prefix="3">In the event that the board should issue a new license under the circumstances as described in this section, the new license shall be under probation for a period of not less than two (2) years nor more than five (5) years, and any subsequent violation during the probation period shall result in automatic revocation of license. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 265, sec. 16, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 470, sec. 16, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 308, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 107, sec. 11, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/94).  This statute was amended by 1994 Ky. Acts chs. 265 and 470, which were companion bills and are substantively identical. These Acts have been codified together. For the few minor variations between the Acts, Acts ch. 470 prevails under KRS 446.250, as the Act which passed the General Assembly last. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30549</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>