<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="200" order_by="200">ASSISTANCE TO CHILDREN </unit></structure><section_number>200.654</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 200.650 to 200.676. </catch_line><order_by>654</order_by><text>As used in KRS 200.650 to 200.676, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Awards and contracts" means the state and federal funds designated by the cabinet for projects relating to planning, resource development, or provision of direct early intervention services, as defined in this section, to infants and toddlers with disabilities and their families; </section><section prefix="2">"Cabinet" means the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="3">"Child find" means a system to identify, locate, and evaluate all infants and toddlers with disabilities who are eligible for early intervention services, determine which children are receiving services, and coordinate the effort with other state agencies and departments; </section><section prefix="4">"Council" means the Kentucky Early Intervention System Interagency Coordinating Council; </section><section prefix="5">"District" means one (1) of the fifteen (15) area development districts; </section><section prefix="6">"District early intervention committee" means an interagency coordinating committee established within each of the fifteen (15) area development districts to facilitate interagency coordination at the district level; </section><section prefix="7">"Early intervention services" means services for infants and toddlers with disabilities and their families delivered according to an individualized family service plan developed by the child multidisciplinary team to meet the developmental needs of eligible children, as defined in this section, and provided by entities receiving public funds using qualified personnel. The individualized family services plan is developed and the services are provided in collaboration with the families and, to the maximum extent appropriate, in natural environments, including home and community settings in which infants and toddlers without disabilities would participate. These services are necessary to enable the child to reach maximum potential. Services to be made available shall include but not be limited to the following: <section prefix="a">Screening services; </section><section prefix="b">Evaluation services; </section><section prefix="c">Assessment services; </section><section prefix="d">Service coordination; </section><section prefix="e">Transportation and related costs for accessing early intervention services; </section><section prefix="f">Family services including counseling, psychological, and social work services; </section><section prefix="g">Health services including medical services for diagnostic and evaluation purposes only; </section><section prefix="h">Nutrition services; </section><section prefix="i">Occupational therapy services; </section><section prefix="j">Physical therapy services; </section><section prefix="k">Communication development services; </section><section prefix="l">Sensory development services; </section><section prefix="m">Developmental intervention services; </section><section prefix="n">Assistive technology services; and </section><section prefix="o">Respite services; </section></section><section prefix="8">"Early intervention system" means the management structure established in KRS 200.654 to 200.670 and which is comprised of the interdependent array of services and activities for the provision of a statewide, comprehensive, coordinated, multidisciplinary, interagency program for infants and toddlers with disabilities and their families; </section><section prefix="9">"Individual family service plan" means the singular comprehensive written service plan developed by the child's multidisciplinary team, with the child's parents serving as fully participating members of the team, to be followed by all agencies and other entities involved in providing early intervention services to an infant or toddler with disabilities and the child's family; </section><section prefix="10">"Infants and toddlers with disabilities" and "eligible children" mean children from birth to thirty-six (36) months of age in need of early intervention services as a result of one (1) of the following circumstances: <section prefix="a">The child is experiencing developmental delays, as measured by diagnostic instruments and procedures in one (1) or more of the following skill areas: physical; cognitive; communication; social or emotional; or adaptive development; </section><section prefix="b">The child has a diagnosed physical or mental condition which has a high probability of resulting in developmental delay; or </section><section prefix="c">The child has a diagnosis of pervasive developmental disorder; </section></section><section prefix="11">"Multidisciplinary team" means the child-specific group responsible for determining the services needed by the infant or toddler with disabilities and the child's family, and development of the individualized family services plan. The team for each child shall include the parent or guardian of the child and individuals representing at least two (2) applicable disciplines which may include but need not be limited to the following: physical therapy; speech therapy; social work; nursing; or education; </section><section prefix="12">"Point of entry" means an easily identifiable, highly accessible nonstigmatized entry into services; and </section><section prefix="13">"Qualified service provider" means an entity, including but not limited to an individual, program, department, or agency, responsible for the delivery of early intervention services to eligible infants and toddlers with disabilities and their families who has met the highest minimum standards of state-approved or recognized certification, licensing, registration, or other comparable requirements that apply to the area in which the entity is providing early intervention services. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 210, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 174, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 313, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7323</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>