<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="352" order_by="352">MINING REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>352.640</section_number><catch_line>Emergency action plans -- Components -- Copies -- Training -- Evacuation and firefighting programs.   </catch_line><order_by>640</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An emergency action plan shall be submitted with each application for a license to operate an underground mine. The emergency action plan shall be for use during emergencies at the licensed facility. The plan shall consist of the following components: <section prefix="a">A certification, submitted by the applicant, that the telephone or equivalent two-way communications system will be in place and functioning at the facility when operation begins; </section><section prefix="b">A listing of the telephone numbers of the facility personnel, state and federal regulatory agencies, and state, federal, and local emergency response agencies to be contacted in the event of a mine emergency; </section><section prefix="c">The positions and telephone numbers of the persons designated by the licensee to implement the emergency action plan during mine emergencies; </section><section prefix="d">The name of the ambulance service or first responder with which the licensee has made arrangements to provide twenty-four (24) hour emergency medical assistance for any person injured at the licensed facility; </section><section prefix="e">A copy of the licensed facility's mine emergency evacuation and firefighting plan, if one is required; and </section><section prefix="f">A training schedule for all personnel as to their responsibilities under the emergency action plan. On site, each licensed facility shall maintain a log containing training dates, the personnel trained, and their positions and shifts. </section></section><section prefix="2">The licensee shall provide a revised copy of the plan to the regional office and the Frankfort office of the Division of Mine Safety within ten (10) days of a change in any of the information required in subsection (1) of this section becoming effective. </section><section prefix="3">The licensee shall be responsible for ensuring that copies of the licensed facility's emergency action plan are submitted to the appropriate regional office and to the Frankfort office of the Division of Mine Safety. Copies of the plan also shall be kept on the premises of the licensed facility where it shall be made open to inspection by the licensee's employees and their independent contractors and inspectors. </section><section prefix="4">Each licensed facility shall post in a prominent place at the mine office a copy of all emergency contact numbers. The list of emergency contact numbers shall be made available to the licensee's employees and their independent contractors during training on the emergency action plan. </section><section prefix="5">Each licensed facility shall train all employees of the licensee, including their independent contractors, at the beginning of their employment with the licensed facility and on an annual basis on the emergency action plan and the persons responsible for the plan's implementation. </section><section prefix="6">Each licensed facility on which an underground mine is operated shall develop and implement a mine emergency evacuation and firefighting program that instructs all miners and other personnel of the licensed facility in the proper evacuation procedures they must follow if a mine emergency occurs. The program, and any revisions thereto, must be submitted to the director or his designee. All personnel of the licensed facility, including independent contractors, shall be trained in the performance of the plan's revisions prior to any of the revisions being implemented. The program shall include a plan to train all miners on all shifts with procedures for: <section prefix="a">Mine emergency evacuation for mine emergencies that present an imminent danger to miners due to fire, explosion, or gas, or water inundation; </section><section prefix="b">Evacuation of all miners not required for a mine emergency response; </section><section prefix="c">Rapid assembly and transportation of necessary miners, fire suppression equipment, and rescue apparatus to the scene of the mine emergency; and </section><section prefix="d">Operation of fire suppression equipment available in the mine. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 87, sec. 37, effective June 24, 2015. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 185, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44554</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>