<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.9129</section_number><catch_line>Cabinet's powers to examine, inspect, and test -- Prohibition upon interfering with inspection. </catch_line><order_by>9129</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet may examine records of mitigation contractors, measurement contractors, and radon laboratories, and conduct inspections of mitigation system installations in order to ensure radon mitigation systems are installed in compliance with mitigation standard operating procedures established by the cabinet through promulgation of an administrative regulation. </section><section prefix="2">The cabinet may examine records of measurement contractors, mitigation contractors, and radon laboratories to ensure radon measurements are conducted in compliance with measurement standard operating procedures established by the cabinet through promulgation of an administrative regulation. </section><section prefix="3">The cabinet may test any equipment used for measurement or mitigation, photograph or sketch any portion of a site, building, or equipment involved in measurement or mitigation, or copy any documents or records pertaining to measurement or mitigation. </section><section prefix="4">No person shall use or continue to use, or permit the use or continued use of, any radon mitigation system if an agent or inspector of the cabinet finds that the radon mitigation system was not constructed, installed, or altered in accordance with the mitigation standard operating procedures established by the cabinet through promulgation of an administrative regulation. </section><section prefix="5">For purposes of enforcing KRS 211.9101 to 211.9135 or any administrative regulation promulgated by the cabinet pertaining to radon measurement, mitigation, or laboratory analysis, an agent or inspector of the cabinet shall have the power to enter upon premises at all reasonable times to make an inspection, question all persons, and require the production of radon mitigation system plans, sketches, diagnostic information, and other evidence. </section><section prefix="6">Agents and inspectors of the cabinet shall be empowered to issue a stop order to any owner, agent, or occupant of real property requiring that the radon mitigation system thereon cease operation if that system has been found to be in violation of KRS 211.9101 to 211.9135 or any administrative regulation promulgated thereunder by the cabinet pertaining to radon measurement, mitigation, or laboratory analysis. </section><section prefix="7">A person shall not interfere with an inspection conducted by an agent or inspector of the cabinet. </section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 74, sec. 15, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39810</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>