<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.459</section_number><catch_line>Parking limits for vehicles with plates or placards for persons with a disability -- Prohibitions. </catch_line><order_by>459</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When a motor vehicle which is being operated by or for the benefit of the person with a disability who is in the motor vehicle at the time it is being operated is displaying an auto registration plate as provided in KRS 186.041 or 186.042 or 186.0425, an out-of-state or out-of-country registration plate for a person with a disability bearing the international symbol of access, a parking placard issued by any Veterans Administration hospital, or an accessible parking placard issued to a person with a disability as prescribed in KRS 189.456 or 189.458 or by another state or foreign country when the accessible parking placard meets the basic requirements of KRS 189.456 or 189.458, the vehicle may be parked in a parking place designated as accessible to and for the use of a person with a disability. </section><section prefix="2">When parked where a parking limit is imposed, the vehicle may be parked for a period of two (2) hours in excess of the legal parking period permitted by local authorities, except where local ordinances or police regulations prohibit parking on a highway for the purpose of creating a fire lane or where the ordinances or police regulations provide for the accommodation of heavy traffic during morning, afternoon, or evening hours or where the motor vehicle is parked in such a manner as to clearly be a traffic hazard. No person shall park in a parking area designated as accessible to and for the use of a person with a disability in a motor vehicle not displaying either an auto registration plate as provided in KRS 186.041, 186.042, 186.0425, or an out-of-state registration plate designated for the use of a person with a disability on the rear of the vehicle unless he displays on the dashboard of his motor vehicle an accessible parking placard issued to a person with a disability. No person shall park a vehicle displaying an accessible parking placard in a parking area designated as accessible to and for the use of a person with a disability when the person with a disability is not in the motor vehicle. </section><section prefix="3">No person shall make, issue, possess, or knowingly use any imitation, counterfeit, or transferable placard or license plate for a person with a disability. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 405, sec. 42, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 416, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1994. – Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 60, sec. 6, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994. </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/94).  This section was amended by 1994 Ky. Acts chs. 405 and 416. Where these Acts are not in conflict, they have been codified together. Where a conflict exists, Acts ch. 416, which was last enacted by the General Assembly, prevails under KRS 446.250. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6399</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>