<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="620" order_by="620">DEPENDENCY, NEGLECT, AND ABUSE </unit></structure><section_number>620.500</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 620.500 to 620.550. </catch_line><order_by>500</order_by><text>As used in KRS 620.500 to 620.550, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Association" means the state Court-Appointed Special Advocate Association established in KRS 620.530; </section><section prefix="2">"Court" means family court or, if there is no family court in the county where the CASA program is located, then District Court; </section><section prefix="3">"Court-appointed special advocate case" and "CASA case" mean a child or group of siblings who are within the jurisdiction of the court as a result of abuse, neglect, or dependency proceedings and for whom the court has appointed and the program director has assigned a CASA volunteer; </section><section prefix="4">"Court-appointed special advocate program" and "CASA program" mean a program by which trained community volunteers are provided to the court for appointment to represent the best interests of children who have come into the court system as a result of dependency, abuse, or neglect; </section><section prefix="5">"Court-appointed special advocate volunteer" and "CASA volunteer" mean a person who completes training through and is supervised by a CASA program and appointed by a judge to represent the best interests of dependent, abused, and neglected children in court; </section><section prefix="6">"Local board" means the local board of directors appointed or selected in accordance with KRS 620.505 to govern local CASA programs; </section><section prefix="7">"Program director" means the director of each local CASA program selected in accordance with KRS 620.505; </section><section prefix="8">"State board" means the state board of directors elected in accordance with KRS 620.530; and </section><section prefix="9">"State director" means the director of the state association provided for in KRS 620.537. </section></text><history> Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 138, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 245, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 264, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20227</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>