<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="342" order_by="342">WORKERS' COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>342.160</section_number><catch_line>Payments to certain dependents for others -- Effect of legal disability of dependent. </catch_line><order_by>160</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The benefits in case of death shall be paid to one (1) or more dependents of the deceased employee for the benefit of all the dependents entitled thereto, as determined by the administrative law judge. The dependents to whom payments are made shall apply the same to the use of the persons entitled thereto under this chapter, according to their respective claims on the deceased for support. The compensation of a mentally disabled person shall be paid to his guardian or conservator. </section><section prefix="2">If the dependents are a widow, widower, or other head of a family of minor children and one (1) or more minor children, it shall be sufficient for the widow, widower, or head of the family to make application for compensation on behalf of all. Where the dependents are mentally incapacitated or are minors the head of whose family is not a dependent, the application may be made by the guardian, conservator, or next friend of such dependents. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 514, sec. 8, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 56, effective December 12, 1996 -- Amended 1987 Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 20, effective January 4, 1988. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 91, effective July 1, 1982. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 386, sec. 62. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4909. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><note>1980 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 97 would have amended this section effective July 1, 1982. However, 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 396 was repealed by 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 146, also effective July 1,1982. </note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32428</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>