<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="96" order_by="96">UTILITIES IN CITIES </unit></structure><section_number>96.050</section_number><catch_line>Authorized city may regulate construction and operation of utilities.   </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text>The legislative body of any authorized city may, by ordinance:  <section prefix="1">Direct and control the laying and construction of railroad or street railway tracks, bridges, turnouts and switches, poles, wires, apparatus and appliances in the streets and alleys of the city, and the location of depot grounds within the city.  </section><section prefix="2">Require that bridges, turnouts and switches be so constructed and laid as to interfere as little as possible with ordinary travel and the use of the streets and alleys, and that sufficient space be kept on either side of the tracks for safe and convenient passage.  </section><section prefix="3">Prohibit the making of running switches.  </section><section prefix="4">Require all railroad companies to construct and keep in repair suitable crossings at the intersections of streets, alleys, ditches, sewers and culverts, and to light and guard the same.  </section><section prefix="5">Require railroad companies to erect gates at street crossings.  </section><section prefix="6">Direct the use and regulate the speed of locomotive engines, steam, electric, street or other kind of cars within the limits of the city.  </section><section prefix="7">Prohibit and restrain railroad companies from doing any storage and warehouse business, or collecting money for storage, except in cases where the consignor or consignee of goods or wares fails to remove them within a reasonable time from the depots of such companies.  </section><section prefix="8">Compel telephone and telegraph companies and all persons using, controlling or managing telegraph or telephone wires to put and keep their wires underground.  </section><section prefix="9">Compel gas and electric light companies and all persons using, controlling or managing electric light wires for any purpose to change and relocate poles, electric wires, conduits for electric wires, gas mains and pipes, place those above the surface of the ground below it, change the method of conveying light, and generally to do things conducive to the safety and comfort of the inhabitants of the city in the premises.  </section><section prefix="10">Regulate the manner in which electric light, telephone and telegraph wires are placed underground, and the use of all such wires and connections therewith.  </section><section prefix="11">As used in this section, "authorized city" means a city included on the registry maintained by the Department for Local Government under subsection (12) of this section. </section><section prefix="12">On or before January 1, 2015, the Department for Local Government shall create and maintain a registry of cities that, as of August 1, 2014, were classified as cities of the second class. The Department for Local Government shall make the information included on the registry available to the public by publishing it on its Web site. </section></text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 150, effective January 1, 2015. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 3058, 3058-6, 3058-20, 3058-21. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43735</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>