<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="309" order_by="309">MISCELLANEOUS OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS </unit></structure><section_number>309.327</section_number><catch_line>Use of titles -- Application and construction of KRS 309.325 to 309.339.     </catch_line><order_by>327</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person shall use the title "master licensed diabetes educator," "licensed diabetes educator," or "apprentice diabetes educator" or hold himself or herself out as a "master licensed diabetes educator," "licensed diabetes educator," or "apprentice diabetes educator" or a title substantially similar, or engage in the practice of diabetes education, display a sign or in any other way advertise or present himself or herself as a person who practices diabetes education only if he or she holds a current, unsuspended and unrevoked license or permit issued by the board pursuant to KRS 309.325 to 309.339. </section><section prefix="2">Nothing in KRS 309.325 to 309.339 shall apply to persons licensed, certified, or registered under any other provision of the Kentucky Revised Statutes, including but not limited to physicians, nurses, pharmacists, dietitians, and nutritionists or students in accredited training programs in those professions, and nothing in KRS 309.325 to 309.339 shall be construed to limit, interfere with, or restrict the practice, descriptions of services, or manner in which they hold themselves out to the public. </section><section prefix="3">Nothing in KRS 309.325 to 309.339 shall be construed to alter, amend, or interfere with the practice of those who provide health care services, including but not limited to physicians, nurses, pharmacists, dietitians, and nutritionists. </section><section prefix="4">Nothing in KRS 309.325 to 309.339 shall apply to activities and services of an accredited institution of higher education as part of a program of studies. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 4, effective July 1, 2014. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 142, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 87, sec. 2, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42720</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>