<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>14A.2-130</section_number><catch_line>Certificate of existence.   </catch_line><order_by>2-130</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Anyone may apply to the Secretary of State to furnish a certificate of existence for an entity. </section><section prefix="2">A certificate of existence shall set forth: <section prefix="a">The entity's real name; </section><section prefix="b">That the entity was duly organized under the laws of this Commonwealth, the date of its organization, and the period of its duration if less than perpetual; </section><section prefix="c">That no articles of dissolution, statement of cancellation, or document of similar import is effective; </section><section prefix="d">That all fees, taxes, and penalties owed to this Commonwealth have been paid, if: <section prefix="1">Payment is reflected in the records of the Secretary of State; and </section><section prefix="2">Nonpayment affects the existence of the entity; </section></section><section prefix="e">That its most recent annual report required by KRS 14A.6-010 or predecessor law has been filed by the Secretary of State; and </section><section prefix="f">Subject to KRS 14A.2-120(3), other facts of record in the office of the Secretary of State that may be requested by the applicant. </section></section><section prefix="3">Subject to any qualification stated in the certificate, a certificate of existence issued by the Secretary of State may be relied upon as conclusive evidence that the entity is in existence. </section><section prefix="4">This section shall not apply to: <section prefix="a">Partnerships organized pursuant to KRS Chapter 362 or 362.1; </section><section prefix="b">Limited partnerships other than those subject to KRS Chapter 362.2; </section><section prefix="c">Business trusts governed as to their internal affairs by KRS Chapter 386; or </section><section prefix="d">An individual series of a series entity. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 80, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 20, effective January 1, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40420</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>