<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="75" order_by="75">FIRE PROTECTION DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>75.160</section_number><catch_line>Attendance of chief at board meetings -- Definition of chief -- Members as peace officers. </catch_line><order_by>160</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The chief of the fire department in fire protection districts shall attend all sessions of the board, except executive sessions, and he shall execute all the orders of the board. Whenever "chief" is used in KRS 75.100 to 75.260, it shall include the assistant chief when the chief is not on duty. </section><section prefix="2">The regular members of the fire department in fire protection districts, except volunteer firemen, shall have the same powers of arrest as now given by law to sheriffs of this Commonwealth and they are hereby expressly declared conservators of the public peace whose duties, in addition to their other prescribed duties, are to conserve the peace, enforce all laws and preserve order, and they shall have and are hereby expressly given the same right and the same power to arrest, search and seize as is now given by law to sheriffs of this Commonwealth, and they shall be at all times subject to the orders of the county judge/executive in which the fire district lies while enforcing the provisions of this section. Provided, however, that members of said fire departments shall not have the power to serve subpoenas, summonses and notices in civil cases and they shall receive no fees for performing any of the duties prescribed in this section as pertains to powers of law enforcement. The members shall constitute a law enforcement agency in addition to the patrol and investigation functions of the sheriff and his deputies under KRS 75.150 to 75.170. </section></text><history>Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 207, sec. 7, effective February 28, 1956. </history><metadata><effective>February 28, 1956.</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24451</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>