<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="335" order_by="335">SOCIAL WORKERS AND PROFESSIONAL COUNSELORS </unit></structure><section_number>335.620</section_number><catch_line>Application for licensure -- Conversion of certificate to license. </catch_line><order_by>620</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An applicant for licensure as a pastoral counselor shall: <section prefix="a">Pay the board an initial fee for licensure that shall be established by administrative regulation promulgated in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A; </section><section prefix="b">Be at least twenty-one (21) years of age; </section><section prefix="c">Reside or be employed in the Commonwealth of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="d">Have completed a master of divinity degree or its equivalent with a minimum of ninety (90) hours from a seminary accredited by the Association of Theological Schools or an equivalent course of study as defined by the board by promulgation of administrative regulations; </section><section prefix="e">Have completed each of the following: <section prefix="1">At least one thousand three hundred seventy-five (1,375) hours in the practice of supervised pastoral counseling acceptable to the board, subsequent to being granted a master's degree; and </section><section prefix="2">A minimum of two hundred fifty (250) hours of clinical supervision acceptable to the board; </section></section><section prefix="f">Be an ordained minister or the denominational equivalent, as determined by the applicant's denomination or faith group, and have been endorsed by that denomination or faith group to function as a pastoral counselor; </section><section prefix="g">Hold an advanced degree or its equivalent beyond the master of divinity degree with special concentration in the theory and practice of pastoral counseling and which requires at least one (1) year of academic work beyond the first professional degree; and </section><section prefix="h">Pass a written examination approved by the board. </section></section><section prefix="2">If an applicant has been issued a certificate in pastoral counseling by the board prior to January 1, 2015, and maintains that certificate in good standing, the board shall issue the applicant a license as a pastoral counselor upon the applicant's payment of a renewal fee and completion of a renewal process as authorized by KRS 335.625 and as prescribed by the board through the promulgation of administrative regulations. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 64, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2014. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 525, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43265</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>