<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="214" order_by="214">DISEASES </unit></structure><section_number>214.300</section_number><catch_line>Labels on mattresses -- Regulation of. </catch_line><order_by>300</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There shall be securely sewed upon the outside of each mattress manufactured, or offered for sale, a muslin, paper or linen label or tag, upon which shall be legibly written or printed a description of the material used as the filling of the mattress.  </section><section prefix="2">If all the material used in the manufacture of the mattress has not been previously used, the words "manufactured of new material" shall appear upon the label or tag, together with the name and address of the maker.  </section><section prefix="3">Any mattress made from any material previously used shall have stamped or printed upon the tag attached thereto, in type not smaller than twenty-point, the words "secondhand material."  </section><section prefix="4">If labeled felt or felted cotton, it is understood that the cotton or material has all been carded in layers or sheets by a Garnett or cotton felting machine.  </section><section prefix="5">In the description upon the label or tag of the material used as the filling of any mattress, no term or designation likely to mislead shall be used.  </section><section prefix="6">No person except a purchaser at retail shall remove, deface or alter, or attempt or cause the removal, defacement or alteration of any mark or statement placed upon any mattress under the provisions of this section.  </section></text><history>Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2062d-3, 2062d-4, 2062d-5, 2062d-6. </history><metadata><effective>October 1, 1942</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8810</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>