<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IV" order_by="4">JUDICIAL BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="22" order_by="22">A COURT OF APPEALS </unit></structure><section_number>22A.040</section_number><catch_line>Clerk -- Appointment -- Compensation -- Oath -- Bond -- Assistants -- Fee schedule -- Seal -- Annual audit. </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The clerk of the Court of Appeals shall be appointed by the court to serve at its pleasure. The annual salary of the clerk shall be fixed by the Supreme Court not to exceed twenty-two thousand dollars ($22,000). </section><section prefix="2">Before entering upon the duties of his office, the clerk shall take the oath of office prescribed by the Constitution. </section><section prefix="3">The clerk shall perform such duties as the Court of Appeals may assign, and shall be bonded to the Commonwealth, for faithful performance of duty, in such manner and in an amount not less than ten thousand dollars ($10,000) as the Supreme Court shall determine. </section><section prefix="4">The clerk may appoint assistants in the number and at the salaries fixed by the Supreme Court. </section><section prefix="5">The Court of Appeals shall adopt a seal. The clerk shall be the keeper of the seal and shall use it upon such documents as the Court of Appeals may require. </section><section prefix="6">A fee schedule for services rendered by the clerk shall be fixed by rule of the Supreme Court, except that charges to litigants for the reproduction of appellate records and briefs shall be fixed and administered by the clerk. All fees collected by the clerk shall be remitted to the State Treasury. </section><section prefix="7">The Auditor of Public Accounts shall audit the financial accounts of the clerk at least once every year. </section></text><history>Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 70, sec. 5, effective March 23, 1976. </history><metadata><effective>March 23, 1976 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20563</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>