<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.622</section_number><catch_line>Administrative regulations of Kentucky Board of Education relating to advanced placement courses -- Duties of Department of Education relating to advanced placement and dual enrollment programs -- Credit for Virtual High School and advanced placement courses. </catch_line><order_by>622</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Board of Education shall promulgate administrative regulations establishing the criteria a school shall meet in order to designate a course an advanced placement course, including content and program standards concerning student admission criteria, data collection, and reporting. </section><section prefix="2">Upon receipt of adequate federal funding for these purposes, the Department of Education shall: <section prefix="a">Expand advanced placement teacher training institutes, including offering advanced placement teacher training instruction and assistance through the Kentucky Virtual High School or in conjunction with the Council on Postsecondary Education through the Kentucky Virtual University; </section><section prefix="b">Require teachers who are planning to participate in advanced placement teacher training and complete advanced placement training at advanced placement institutes facilitated by the department to sign an agreement to teach at least one (1) advanced placement course in a Kentucky public school or the Kentucky Virtual High School when assigned by the school principal; </section><section prefix="c">Develop the Kentucky Virtual Advanced Placement Academy which shall offer school districts and their students access to a core advanced placement curriculum through the Kentucky Virtual High School; </section><section prefix="d">Identify, in conjunction with the Council on Postsecondary Education, resources at the secondary and postsecondary levels that can be directed toward advanced placement or dual enrollment instruction; </section><section prefix="e">Compare the costs of offering advanced placement courses through traditional on-site instruction, the Kentucky Virtual High School, and other methods and shall offer each school district assistance, if requested, in analyzing how the school district can most cost-effectively offer the largest number of advanced placement courses; </section><section prefix="f">Identify current and future funding sources for advanced placement or dual enrollment instructional programs and the amount of funds available or anticipated from those sources; and </section><section prefix="g">Submit a report to the Kentucky General Assembly outlining compliance with this section. </section></section><section prefix="3">Each school district shall: <section prefix="a">Accept for credit toward graduation any course a student successfully completes through the Kentucky Virtual High School and incorporate the grade the student receives in a Kentucky Virtual High School course in calculating that student's grade point average without distinction between the grade received in the Kentucky Virtual High School course and courses taught within the school district for which the student receives a grade; </section><section prefix="b">Accept for credit toward graduation and completion of high school course requirements an advanced placement, a high school equivalent, or a Kentucky Virtual High School course taken by a student in grades 5, 6, 7, or 8 if that student attains performance levels expected of high school students in that district as determined by achieving a score of "3" or higher on a College Board Advanced Placement examination or a grade of "B" or better in a high school equivalent or a Kentucky Virtual High School course; and </section><section prefix="c">Pay tuition and other costs for students from their districts who are enrolled in a Kentucky Virtual High School course for credit that is part of the student's regular school day coursework by proportionately sharing funds generated under KRS 157.360 or other funding sources. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 16, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 97, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3545</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>