<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.7904</section_number><catch_line>Application for assessment referendum -- Contents of form -- Publication. </catch_line><order_by>7904</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any existing association which is fairly representative of the porcine animal producers of Kentucky may at any time after the enactment of KRS 247.7900 to 247.7928 make application to the State Board of Agriculture on forms prescribed by the board for certification and approval for the purpose of conducting a referendum among the producers of porcine animals upon the question of levying an assessment under the provisions of KRS 247.7900 to 247.7928, and for collecting and utilizing the assessment for the purpose stated in the referendum. The application forms shall include, but not be limited to, the following: <section prefix="a">Applicant's name; </section><section prefix="b">Applicant's address; </section><section prefix="c">Date; </section><section prefix="d">Program to be undertaken for producers; </section><section prefix="e">Brief statement of how the program is to be implemented; </section><section prefix="f">Referendum to be conducted on a statewide or areawide basis; </section><section prefix="g">Proposed effective date of the program; </section><section prefix="h">Geographic area, by counties, of producers to be affected by the program; and </section><section prefix="i">Signature of the applicant. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Commissioner shall publish the application through the medium of the public press in the state within ten (10) days of receipt of the application. </section></text><history> Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 3, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11816</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>