<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="350" order_by="350">SURFACE COAL MINING </unit></structure><section_number>350.050</section_number><catch_line>Powers of cabinet. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text>The Energy and Environment Cabinet under the supervision of the secretary of the Energy and Environment Cabinet shall have and exercise the following authority and powers: <section prefix="1">To exercise general supervision and administration and enforcement of this chapter and all rules and regulations and orders promulgated thereunder; </section><section prefix="2">To encourage and conduct investigations, research, experiments, and demonstrations, and to collect and disseminate information relating to strip mining and reclamation of lands and waters affected by strip mining; </section><section prefix="3">To adopt, without hearing, internal procedures with respect to the filing of reports, the issuance of permits, and other matters of procedure and administration; </section><section prefix="4">To examine and pass upon all plans and specifications submitted by the permit applicant for the method of operation, backfilling, grading, and for the reclamation of the area of land affected by his operation; </section><section prefix="5">To make investigations or inspections which may be deemed necessary to insure compliance with any provision of this chapter; </section><section prefix="6">To order, through personnel of the cabinet, the suspension of any permit for failure to comply with any of the provisions of this chapter or any regulations adopted pursuant thereto; </section><section prefix="7">To order, through personnel of the cabinet, the stopping of any operation that is started without first having secured a permit as required by this chapter. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1876, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 429, sec. 3, July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 332, sec. 3, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. III, sec. 13(2),(7) -- Amended 1972 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 64. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 6. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 3. -- Amended 1956, (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 7, Art. VII, sec. 5. -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 8, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32773</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>