<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="154" order_by="154">A STATE LOTTERY </unit></structure><section_number>154A.120</section_number><catch_line>Procurement procedures -- Administrative regulations for procurement -- Bidding and negotiation processes. </catch_line><order_by>120</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The corporation shall conduct all procurements in accordance with procedures which are not inconsistent with the provisions of KRS Chapter 45A, and this chapter, this chapter being deemed to control in the event that, and to the extent that, any provision in this chapter is expressly inconsistent with any provision of KRS Chapter 45A; or the corporation shall adopt administrative regulations establishing its procurement procedures. If the corporation elects to promulgate administrative regulations establishing its procurement procedures rather than conduct procurements in accordance with the provisions of KRS Chapter 45A, the corporation may include sections of KRS Chapter 45A as part of its administrative regulations. However, major lottery-specific procurements for personal service contracts shall not be subject to the requirements of KRS 45A.695(2)(b), due to the unique operational activities conducted for state government by the corporation as recognized in KRS 154A.020. The corporation's procurement procedures or administrative regulations shall be designed to provide for the purchase of supplies, equipment, services, and construction items that provide the greatest long term benefit to the state, the greatest integrity for the corporation, and the best service and products, for the public. </section><section prefix="2">In its bidding and negotiation processes, the corporation may do its own bidding and procurement, or may utilize the services of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, or a combination thereof. The president of the corporation may, in lieu of the secretary of finance, declare an emergency for purchasing purposes. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 170, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 496, sec. 47, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1988 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 18, effective December 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3020</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>