<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIV" order_by="34">DESCENT, WILLS, AND ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="395" order_by="395">PERSONAL REPRESENTATIVES </unit></structure><section_number>395.015</section_number><catch_line>Applications for appointment of personal representative. </catch_line><order_by>015</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Before being appointed as executor, administrator, curator, or administrator with the will annexed, every person shall make and file in duplicate a written application under oath, which must state the names of the deceased's surviving spouse and all of his heirs-at-law or such as are known, their post office address if known, the date of death and also a statement in general terms as to what the estate consists of and the probable value of the personal and real estate and also a statement of any indebtedness owing by the applicant to the deceased. The foregoing requirement in respect to names and addresses of heirs-at-law may be omitted when the application is being made by the executor named in the will unless requested by the court. The application of a nonresident shall include the designation of a resident of the county where administration is pending as his agent for the service of process in any action against him as personal representative or personally, provided that such personal action must have accrued in the administration of the estate. A duplicate copy of said application shall be mailed by the clerk to the secretary of revenue of the State of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="2">In the case of intestacy, or where an administrator with will annexed or de bonis non is to be appointed, if there be no surviving spouse, or if such spouse waives the right of appointment or is not qualified to act and does not nominate a suitable administrator and there is more than one (1) resident heir-at-law entitled to appointment, the court shall thereupon set a time for hearing such application. Notice of said hearing shall be given to the surviving spouse and all known heirs of the deceased residing in the state, or elsewhere, in the manner provided in KRS 395.016. </section></text><history>Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 382, effective January 2, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 299, sec. 13. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 15. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 2. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 200, sec. 7. -- Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 167, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective>January 2, 1978</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:32</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36311</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>