<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="81" order_by="81">CITY CLASSIFICATION, BOUNDARIES, AND ALTERNATIVE METHOD OF CONSOLIDATING GOVERNMENTAL SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>81.015</section_number><catch_line>Areas designated "unincorporated urban places". </catch_line><order_by>015</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Fairdale area of Jefferson County is an "unincorporated urban place" within the meaning of KRS 177.366 and 177.369. The metes and bounds of the Fairdale area are as follows: Beginning at a point approximately 1,000 feet west of Smith Road on the Jefferson - Bullitt County line; running thence northwardly along a line behind improvements facing Smith Road, Top Hill Road, and Jefferson Hill Road 12,000 feet more or less to Lonesome Hollow Road; thence northwestwardly with Lonesome Hollow road 6,000 feet more or less to Blevins Gap Road; thence northeastwardly along Blevins Gap Road 2,000 feet more or less to Greyling Drive; thence northeastwardly along Greyling Drive 5,500 feet more or less to Manslick Road; thence northwardly along Manslick Road 2,000 feet more or less to the southeast right-of-way line of the Louisville, Henderson &amp; Saint Louis Railroad; thence northeastwardly along said railroad 16,250 feet more or less to the west right-of-way line of the Louisville &amp; Nashville Railroad; thence southwardly along the west right-of-way line of the Louisville &amp; Nashville Railroad 4,000 feet more or less to the Outer Loop; thence eastwardly along the Outer Loop 10,250 feet more or less to Interstate 65; thence southwardly along Interstate 65 18,500 feet more or less to the Bullitt - Jefferson County line; thence westwardly with said county line 28,000 feet more or less to the beginning. </section><section prefix="2">The Parkers Lake area of McCreary County is an "unincorporated urban place" within the meaning of KRS 177.366 and 177.369. The metes and bounds of the Parkers Lake area are as follows: Beginning point at U.S. 27; thence running westwardly to the South Fork River, of Cumberland; thence southeastwardly along the South Fork River, of Cumberland, to the end of Black Ridge Road; thence northeastwardly crossing U.S. 27, to Hwy. 90 and Vanover Ridge Road; thence northwestwardly to the beginning. </section><section prefix="3">The Whitley City area of McCreary County is an "unincorporated urban place" within the meaning of KRS 177.366 and 177.369. The metes and bounds of the Whitley City area are as follows: Beginning at U.S. 27 at the U.S. Forest Service Ranger Station; thence west on Hwy 1651 to the South Fork River, of Cumberland, Alum Ford; thence south on the South Fork River, of Cumberland to Lick Creek; thence southeastwardly on Lick Creek Road crossing Hwy 1651; thence southeastwardly to Laurel Creek Bridge; thence westwardly on Hwy 478; thence southwestwardly to Jenny's Branch; thence southwestwardly to Hatfield Subdivision Road; thence westwardly on Hatfield Subdivision Road; thence northwestwardly to the beginning. </section><section prefix="4">The Smithtown area of McCreary County is an "unincorporated urban place" within the meaning of KRS 177.366 and 177.369. The metes and bounds of the Smithtown area are as follows: Beginning at the intersection of Hwys 92 and 1363; thence southeastwardly on the South Fork River, of Cumberland; thence east to Lick Creek Falls Road; thence southeastwardly to Hwy 701; thence westwardly to 92; thence westwardly on 92; thence southwestwardly to Barthell; thence north parallel of a creek to Yamacraw, to the beginning point. </section><section prefix="5">The Stearns area of McCreary County is an "unincorporated urban place" within the meaning of KRS 177.366 and 177.369. The metes and bounds of the Stearns area are as follows: Beginning at U.S. 27; thence eastwardly to Laurel Bridge; thence southwestwardly on Laurel Creek to McCreary County Reservoir; thence northwestwardly on East Apple Tree to Hwy 92; thence westwardly on Hwy 92 to Hwy 701, to the beginning point. </section><section prefix="6">The Pine Knot area of McCreary County is an "unincorporated urban place" within the meaning of KRS 177.366 and 177.369. The metes and bounds of the Pine Knot area are as follows: Beginning at U.S. 27 and Cal Hill Road to the Neal Road; thence northwardly on the Neal Road to Hwy 92; thence eastwardly on Hwy 92 to the West Road; thence northeastwardly on the West Road to the Smithy Road; thence southeastwardly on Smithy Road to Bethel Road; thence westwardly on the Bethel Road to Jackson Knob Road; thence northwestwardly to Meadows Grove Road; thence southwestwardly to the intersection of Hwy 27 and the Job Corps Road; thence westwardly on the Job Corps Road to Hwy 92; thence southwestwardly to Mud Cut Road; thence circling on Mud Cut Road to Hwy 92; thence eastwardly to Hwy 27, to the beginning point. </section></text><history>Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 327, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 372, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1988 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24940</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>