<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="534" order_by="534">FINES </unit></structure><section_number>534.070</section_number><catch_line>Incarceration for failure to pay fine or court costs or failure to appear in court -- Daily credit against fine or court costs for time served -- Application of partial payment.   </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A defendant who has been sentenced to jail for failure to pay a fine or court costs or for failure to appear in court on a date set for the sole purpose of addressing nonpayment of a fine or court costs shall receive credit against the fine and costs owed for each day the defendant spends in jail at the following rates: <section prefix="a">Fifty dollars ($50) per day if the defendant does not work at a community service or community labor program; or </section><section prefix="b">One hundred dollars ($100) per day if the defendant works eight (8) hours per day at a community service or community labor program. If the defendant works less than eight (8) hours in a community service or community labor program, the defendant shall be allowed an amount of one-eighth (1/8) of the one hundred dollars ($100) for each hour worked in a community service or community labor program. </section></section><section prefix="2">Credit against a fine or court costs earned by a defendant pursuant to this section shall prohibit the collection of any part of a fine or costs which has been credited pursuant to this section, and that portion of the fine or costs shall be considered paid. </section><section prefix="3">The jailer shall be responsible for monitoring a defendant's community service and tracking the number of days to be served to pay any outstanding fine or court costs. </section><section prefix="4">If a partial payment is made by the defendant or on behalf of a defendant, that payment shall be applied first to court costs, then to fees, and then to fines pursuant to KRS 23A.205 or 24A.175 prior to the application of any credit earned pursuant to this section. Credit earned pursuant to this section shall not be applied to restitution. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 156, sec. 5, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch.2, sec.86, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40908</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>