<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.903</section_number><catch_line>Prohibited services by licensed athletic trainers -- Responsibilities and duties of licensed athletic trainers -- Prohibited billing.   </catch_line><order_by>903</order_by><text>A licensed athletic trainer: <section prefix="1">Shall not use spinal or pelvic manipulations or spinal or pelvic chiropractic adjustments; </section><section prefix="2">May dispense, but shall not prescribe, over-the-counter or prescription medications only to an adult athlete and with the supervision of a physician licensed under KRS Chapter 311, and shall maintain accurate records identifying the medication, dose, amount, directions, condition for which the medication is being used, identity of the supervising physician, lot number, and expiration date; </section><section prefix="3">Shall not dispense over-the-counter or prescription medications to a minor athlete; </section><section prefix="4">Shall not perform invasive procedures; </section><section prefix="5">Shall conform to the standard of care required of an ordinary competent and careful licensed athletic trainer in exercising reasonable care for the health and safety of the athlete; </section><section prefix="6">Shall not work in an industrial setting, except in the capacity of screening injuries and referring patients to an occupational therapist licensed under KRS Chapter 319A, a physical therapist licensed under KRS Chapter 327, a chiropractor licensed under KRS Chapter 312, or a physician licensed under KRS Chapter 311; </section><section prefix="7">Shall not seek reimbursement from the federal government for physical therapy services performed by an athletic trainer; </section><section prefix="8">Shall not seek reimbursement from the federal government for occupational therapy services performed by an athletic trainer; </section><section prefix="9">Shall not seek reimbursement from the federal government for chiropractic services performed by an athletic trainer; </section><section prefix="10">Shall not prescribe medications, including controlled substances; and </section><section prefix="11">Shall not independently bill any patient or other payer for services rendered by the athletic trainer. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 30, sec. 3, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 248, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41866</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>