<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.10-110</section_number><catch_line>Enforcement of rules and regulations adopted by secretary -- Policies -- Plans -- Programs. </catch_line><order_by>10-110</order_by><text>The Energy and Environment Cabinet shall enforce the rules and regulations adopted by the secretary of the Energy and Environment Cabinet for the regulation and control of the matters set out below and shall formulate, promote, establish and execute policies, plans and programs relating to natural resources and environmental protection, including but not limited to the following matters: <section prefix="1">The proper disposal of waste; </section><section prefix="2">The purification of water for public and semipublic use; </section><section prefix="3">The proper construction and operation of public water distribution systems and water treatment systems in public water purification plants and swimming pools; </section><section prefix="4">The review, approval or disapproval of plans for construction, modification or extension of water purification and distribution systems and water treatment systems in swimming pools; and </section><section prefix="5">The certification of water and sewage plant operators. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 352, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1978; and ch. 117, sec. 24, effective July 1, 1978. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 299, sec. 95, effective June 19, 1976. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 224.032. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:34</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10310</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>