<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIII" order_by="33">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS AND ESTATES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="386" order_by="386">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS -- LEGAL INVESTMENTS -- UNIFORM PRINCIPAL AND INCOME ACT </unit></structure><section_number>386.165</section_number><catch_line>Deposit of securities in a clearing corporation -- Accounting and crediting of deposits. </catch_line><order_by>165</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any fiduciary holding securities in its fiduciary capacity, any bank or trust company holding securities as a custodian or managing agent, any bank or trust company holding securities as custodian for a fiduciary, is authorized to deposit or arrange for the deposit of such securities in a clearing corporation as defined in KRS 355.8-102. When such securities are so deposited, certificates representing securities of the same class of the same issuer may be merged and held in bulk in the name of the nominee of such clearing corporation with any other such securities deposited in such clearing corporation by any person regardless of the ownership of such securities, and certificates of small denomination may be merged into one (1) or more certificates of larger denomination. The records of such fiduciary and the records of such bank or trust company acting as custodian, as managing agent or as custodian for a fiduciary shall at all times show the name of the party for whose account the securities are so deposited. Title to such securities may be transferred by bookkeeping entry on the books of such clearing corporation without physical delivery or certificates representing such securities. A bank or trust company depositing securities pursuant to this section shall be subject to such rules and regulations with respect to the making and maintenance of such deposit as, in the case of a bank or trust company organized under the laws of this state, the executive director of financial institutions and, in the case of national banking associations, the comptroller of the currency may from time to time issue. A bank or trust company acting as custodian for a fiduciary shall, on demand of the fiduciary, certify in writing to the fiduciary the securities so deposited by such bank or trust company in such clearing corporation for the account of such fiduciary. A fiduciary shall, on demand by any party to its accounting or on demand by the attorney for such party, certify in writing to such party the securities deposited by such fiduciary in such clearing corporation for its account as such fiduciary. </section><section prefix="2">This section shall apply to any fiduciary holding securities in a fiduciary capacity, and to any bank or trust company holding securities as a custodian, managing agent or custodian for a fiduciary, acting on June 21, 1974, or who thereafter may act regardless of the date of the agreement, instrument or court order by which it is appointed and regardless of whether or not such fiduciary, custodian, managing agent or custodian for a fiduciary owns capital stock of such clearing corporation. </section><section prefix="3">As used in this section, "fiduciary" includes an executor, administrator, trustee under any trust, express, implied, resulting or constructive, guardian, conservator, receiver, trustee in bankruptcy, assignee for the benefit of creditors, partner, agent, officer of a corporation, public or private, public officer or any other person acting in a fiduciary capacity for any person, trust or estate. </section></text><history>Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 100, effective July 1, 1982. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 1982 </effective><note>1980 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 109 would have amended this section effective July 1, 1982. However, 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 396 was repealed by 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 146, also effective July 1, 1982. </note><lrc-note> (6/20/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 95, 97, 98, 99, 123, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:37</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35845</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>