<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.4021</section_number><catch_line>Temporary elevator mechanic license -- Proof of competency -- License valid for one year -- Renewal.  </catch_line><order_by>4021</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An elevator contractor shall notify the department when the contractor has no licensed personnel available to perform elevator work. The elevator contractor may request that the department issue temporary elevator mechanic licenses to persons confirmed by the licensed elevator contractor to have a combination of documented experience and education to perform elevator work without direct and immediate supervision. </section><section prefix="2">Any person confirmed by an elevator contractor to have a combination of documented experience and education to perform elevator work without direct and immediate supervision shall immediately seek a temporary elevator mechanic license from the department. </section><section prefix="3">Each temporary license shall be valid for a period of one (1) year and only while the licensee is employed by the licensed elevator contractor that confirmed the individual as qualified. </section><section prefix="4">The temporary license shall be renewable for additional terms of one (1) year each until there is no shortage of ordinary license holders. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 10, effective July 1, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2011 </effective><lrc-note> (7/1/2011).  References to the "office" of housing, buildings and construction in this section, as created by 2010 Ky. ch. 116, sec. 10, have been changed in codification to the "department" of housing, building and construction to reflect the reorganization of certain parts of the Executive Branch, as set forth in Executive Order 2009-535 and confirmed by the General Assembly in 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24. These changes were made by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1938. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-16</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36595</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>