<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="441" order_by="441">JAILS AND COUNTY PRISONERS </unit></structure><section_number>441.530</section_number><catch_line>Manner of transfer -- Compensation of officers -- Computation of expenses. </catch_line><order_by>530</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Immediately upon the receipt of a copy of an order made pursuant to KRS 441.520, the sheriff, or if there is no sheriff, the coroner, shall transfer the prisoners to the jail of the county designated in the order. He shall deliver the prisoners to the jailer of that county at the jail, with a copy of the order, and take from him a receipt for the prisoners, which he shall return to the office of the circuit clerk of the county from which the removal was made. The clerk shall file the receipt in his office. The jailer shall receive the prisoners and safely keep them until they are properly discharged. If the jailer fails to accept and keep such prisoners, he and his sureties shall be liable in the same manner and to the same extent as if the prisoners had been regularly committed by an order of the Circuit Court of his county. The officer conveying the prisoners to the designated jail, and such guards as the judge directs him to take, not exceeding the number of guards allowed in taking convicts to the penitentiary, shall receive the compensation and mileage allowed by KRS 64.070 for taking convicts to the penitentiary. The compensation shall be allowed by the Circuit Judge directing the transfer and paid out of the State Treasury, unless there was no jail in the county or it was rendered insecure by the failure of the fiscal court to keep it in the requisite condition, in which case it shall be paid by the fiscal court of the county. The Circuit Judge, in making the allowance, shall state in the order out of which fund it shall be paid. The order of the judge directing the transfer shall be conclusive evidence that the transfer was proper and to the right jail, and shall be a justification to the jailer for holding any such prisoner in any action against him for false imprisonment. </section><section prefix="2">If a transfer of prisoners is necessary because there is no jail in the county or because the jail was rendered insecure by the failure of the fiscal court to keep it in the requisite condition, the cost of lodging the prisoners in the jail of the county to which they are transferred shall be borne by the fiscal court of the county from which the transfer was made at a rate set by agreement between the two (2) fiscal courts involved. If the fiscal courts are unable to reach an agreement, the Circuit Judge who ordered the transfer shall establish the rate based on prisoner and facility cost data provided by the receiving jailer. The order of transfer shall state the reasons of the transfer. </section></text><history>Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 385, sec. 41, effective July 1, 1982. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2440. </history><metadata><effective>July 1, 1982 </effective><former-codification> KRS 441.040. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19358</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>