<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.25-030</section_number><catch_line>Emergency bylaws. </catch_line><order_by>25-030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">With the approval of the commissioner, any domestic organization may, at any time, adopt, in the same manner as in the case of ordinary bylaws, emergency bylaws to become operative during a period of acute emergency. Emergency bylaws may contain provisions with respect to the number of directors capable of acting which shall constitute its board, the number of such directors which shall constitute a quorum at a meeting of the board, the number of votes necessary for action by such board, the manner in which vacancies on the board shall be filled, the line of succession of its officers, and the interim management of the affairs of the insurance organization; such provisions, if approved by the commissioner, need not comply with the requirement of the charter of such domestic organization or of the insurance or incorporation laws of this state. </section><section prefix="2">KRS 304.25-040 and subsections (2) to (6), inclusive, of KRS 304.25-050, shall not be applicable during a period of acute emergency to any domestic organization operating in accordance with and under emergency bylaws theretofore approved by the commissioner. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1363, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 25, sec. 3, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:06</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29595</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>