<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.894</section_number><catch_line>Conditions for relinquishing of ownership of low-level nuclear waste disposal site -- Commonwealth policy as to sites or facilities -- Contracts or agreements with federal government. </catch_line><order_by>894</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Governor, the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, the secretary of the Energy and Environment Cabinet or any other state agency shall not enter into a contract or an agreement of any kind with the federal government relinquishing ownership of a low-level nuclear waste disposal site located in the Commonwealth without prior approval of a majority of the members of the Kentucky House of Representatives and a majority of the members of the Kentucky Senate. </section><section prefix="2">It shall be the policy of the Commonwealth to retain final authority for approving or disapproving the locating, opening, closing, or reopening of a nuclear waste disposal site or facility within its borders. </section><section prefix="3">The Governor or appropriate state agencies may enter into contracts and agreements with the federal government relating to nuclear waste disposal sites located in the Commonwealth on July 15, 1980, that do not violate the provisions of subsections (1) and (2) of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 314, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 388, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 328, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 17, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8510</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>