<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="61" order_by="61">GENERAL PROVISIONS AS TO OFFICES AND OFFICERS -- SOCIAL SECURITY FOR PUBLIC EMPLOYEES -- EMPLOYEES RETIREMENT SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>61.409</section_number><catch_line>Law enforcement agency not to establish requirements for employees relating to residency or voter registration -- Exceptions -- Application. </catch_line><order_by>409</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No state, city, county, urban-county, charter county, or consolidated local government law enforcement agency shall set a residence requirement, except requiring residence within the Commonwealth, for any of its employees who do not possess peace officer powers. </section><section prefix="2">No state, city, county, urban-county, charter county, or consolidated local government law enforcement agency shall require that an employee, whether that employee is a peace officer or not, be a registered voter. </section><section prefix="3">The provisions of subsection (1) shall not preclude an employer or agency specified in subsection (1) from having a requirement for response to a specified location within a specified time limit for an employee or volunteer who is off-duty but who is on-call to respond for work. </section><section prefix="4">The residence requirements of subsection (1) of this section requiring residency within the Commonwealth shall not apply to an employee of a law enforcement agency employed by that agency on July 15, 2002, until that employee's employment relationship with the law enforcement agency is terminated. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 247, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002; and amended ch. 346, sec. 237, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2002).  This section was created and amended by 2002 Ky. Acts chs. 247 and 346, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22943</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>