<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="220" order_by="220">SANITATION DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>220.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 220.010 to 220.540. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in KRS 220.010 to 220.540, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Sanitary works," "improvements," "sanitary system" or "sanitary sewers," means any works constructed by a sanitation district in accordance with the purposes of KRS 220.010 to 220.540, as set forth in KRS 220.030. </section><section prefix="2">"Person" means any person, firm, copartnership, association or corporation other than a public corporation. </section><section prefix="3">"Public corporation" means any county, city, school district, water district or drainage district, and any other governmental agency or political subdivision clothed with the power of levying general or special taxes or issuing bonds payable from special funds. </section><section prefix="4">"Land" or "property" means real property. </section><section prefix="5">"Board of directors," "directors" or "board" means the governing body of a sanitation district. </section><section prefix="6">"Sanitation commissioner" or "commissioner" means the commissioner of sanitation districts, as provided for in KRS 220.020. </section><section prefix="7">"District" means a sanitation district authorized by KRS 220.010 to 220.540. </section><section prefix="8">"District area," "within the district," "corporate limits of the district" and similar terms mean that area established to be within the district in accordance with KRS 220.020 to 220.540. No construction subdistrict shall be construed to be within the district area. </section><section prefix="9">"Construction subdistrict bonds and obligations" and like phrases mean any obligation whatsoever that has been incurred by the district because of some function or activity of a construction subdistrict. Such debts are not obligations of the district, and such debts may be paid only from moneys received by the district on account of the construction subdistrict, or from the funds, if any, in the construction subdistrict, or from the funds, if any, in the construction subdistrict reserve fund. </section><section prefix="10">"Construction subdistrict facilities" are all sewage facilities within a construction subdistrict, and all sewage facilities outside the district area which join together two (2) or more construction subdistricts or lead from a construction subdistrict to the district area or lead from a construction subdistrict to a disposal plant or a treatment plant outside the construction subdistrict and outside the district area, and which are not a part of a sewer system of a municipal corporation or a sewer system of a water district organized pursuant to KRS 74.010 to 74.415. </section><section prefix="11">"District facilities" are all facilities of the district as provided for in KRS 220.020 to 220.540. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 16, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 126. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2062g-1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:37</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9767</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>