<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.435</section_number><catch_line>Adoption of lists -- Rejections -- Execution of contracts -- Publication of lists. </catch_line><order_by>435</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The State Textbook Commission shall, not later than September 20 of any year in which an adoption is to be made, select, recommend, and publish a list of books or programs in each subject and grade, taking into account the needs of the various types of students. </section><section prefix="2">The State Textbook Commission shall have the authority to reject any book which: <section prefix="a">Contains subversive material or information that is offered for listing or adoption. If the commission finds on the multiple list any book which contains subversive material or information, provided the publisher of the book has been given written notice by the secretary of the commission not less than thirty (30) days prior to the meeting, the textbook commission shall have authority to remove the book from the state multiple list; </section><section prefix="b">Is in noncompliance with standards and specifications set forth in KRS 156.410; or </section><section prefix="c">Is not of high quality in terms of the content provided, the audience addressed, the format used, the readability of material or the ancillary materials provided the teacher and students. </section></section><section prefix="3">The State Textbook Commission shall have the authority to solicit additions for the state list when the list does not contain books or materials for subjects added to the state courses of study. </section><section prefix="4">The chief state school officer shall make and execute contracts for the recommended textbooks and programs with the publishers on or before May 1 following the establishment of the state multiple list of recommended titles selected by the commission. Except as described in KRS 156.400, all contracts shall run for six (6) years. </section><section prefix="5">The chief state school officer shall prepare a multiple list of recommended textbooks or programs and publish the list along with a consumer guide and distribute the documents to the superintendents of each county and independent school district in Kentucky on or before November 15 of each adoption year. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 419, sec. 7, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 266, sec. 5, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. IV, sec. 153, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 138, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 9, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982; and ch. 154, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 7, effective March 13, 1974. -- Created 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 184, sec. 8. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3185</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>