<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="281" order_by="281">MOTOR CARRIERS </unit></structure><section_number>281.870</section_number><catch_line>Coordinated Transportation Advisory Committee. </catch_line><order_by>870</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created a Coordinated Transportation Advisory Committee, also known as the "CTAC", that is to be composed of designated members of the cabinet, the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, and the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet. </section><section prefix="2">Members of the CTAC shall serve terms as determined by each respective cabinet. The CTAC shall meet at least once a month, but may meet more frequently if desired, and shall maintain a written record of all meetings and actions taken. In all proceedings of the CTAC and in all actions taken by the CTAC, the cabinet and the Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall each have two (2) votes, and the Education Cabinet shall have one (1) vote. A quorum of the CTAC shall be required to conduct any official business. </section><section prefix="3">The staff of the cabinet's Office of Transportation Delivery shall provide administrative support to the CTAC. The executive director of the Office of Transportation Delivery shall set the agenda for meetings of the CTAC. The Office of Transportation Delivery may promulgate administrative regulations under KRS Chapter 13A governing the human service transportation delivery program on behalf of the CTAC. The cabinet shall promulgate administrative regulations under KRS Chapter 13A to specify the duties and responsibilities of the CTAC. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 65, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 127, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 63, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14440</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>