<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="227" order_by="227">FIRE PREVENTION AND PROTECTION -- ELECTRICIANS </unit></structure><section_number>227.784</section_number><catch_line>Nonapplicability of KRS 227.770 to 227.784 to cigarettes for sale outside Kentucky -- Adoption of federal standards -- Local regulation preempted. </catch_line><order_by>784</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Nothing in KRS 227.770 to 227.784 shall be construed to prohibit any person or entity from manufacturing or selling cigarettes that do not meet the requirements of KRS 227.772 if the cigarettes are or will be stamped for sale in another state or are packaged for sale outside the United States and that person or entity has taken reasonable steps to ensure that the cigarettes will not be sold or offered for sale to persons located in this state. </section><section prefix="2">KRS 227.770 to 227.784 shall no longer apply if a federal reduced cigarette ignition propensity standard is adopted and becomes effective. </section><section prefix="3">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, city, county, urban-county, charter county, or consolidated local government units of this state shall neither enact nor enforce any ordinance or other local law or regulation conflicting with, or preempted by, any provision of KRS 227.770 to 227.784 or with any policy of this state expressed by KRS 227.770 to 227.784, whether that policy be expressed by inclusion of a provision in KRS 227.770 to 227.784 or by exclusion of that subject from KRS 227.770 to 227.784. </section></text><history> Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 70, sec. 8, effective April 1, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> April 1, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10712</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>