<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="235" order_by="235">BOATS AND BOATING </unit></structure><section_number>235.220</section_number><catch_line>Manufacturer's and dealer's registration -- Suspension or revocation of license. </catch_line><order_by>220</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every manufacturer of or dealer in motorboats in this state shall register with the cabinet at Frankfort, Kentucky, and pay an annual registration fee as set by the department by administrative regulation. Upon receipt of this fee, the department shall issue to the manufacturer or dealer a certificate of number and a plate bearing the number assigned, which plate shall be so designed that it can be transferred from boat to boat. Every manufacturer or dealer registered under this section shall be furnished additional dealer certificates of number and plates upon the payment of two dollars ($2) for each additional certificate of number desired. A motorboat bearing dealer's plates and carrying a dealer's certificate of number may be used only by a member of the firm registered or by a bona fide salesman or employee of the firm for any purpose reasonably connected with the sale or demonstration for sale and delivery of the dealer's motorboat or by any manufacturer or dealer, licensed as provided above, in transporting any motorboat over the waters of this state to his place of retail business for the manufacturer or wholesale dealer in motorboats and for no other purpose. </section><section prefix="2">Every motorboat dealer or manufacturer who acquires a used motorboat for cash, trade-in, or in any other manner, shall within fifteen (15) days from date of acquisition have the registration assigned to himself. The dealer shall execute his application for assignment upon documents designated by the cabinet to the county clerk of the county in which he maintains his principal place of business and pay the transfer fee. The clerk shall enter the assignment upon the automated system. </section><section prefix="3">The dealer shall retain the properly assigned certificate of title received from his transferor and may make any reassignments thereon until the forms for dealer assignment on the certificate of title are exhausted. The cabinet may, if it deems warranted, provide a special document to allow for additional dealer assignments without requiring system generated documents. </section><section prefix="4">If the dealer assigns the motorboat to a purchaser for use, he shall deliver the properly assigned certificate of title to the purchaser, who shall make application for registration and a certificate of title thereon, pursuant to KRS 235.050. </section><section prefix="5">The cabinet shall insure that the automated system is capable of accepting instructions from the county clerk that a certificate of title shall not be produced under a dealer registration situation. </section><section prefix="6">The license of any dealer or manufacturer may be suspended or revoked by the cabinet for a violation of any section of this statute. Such persons shall be afforded a full opportunity to defend themselves against any charges at a hearing set by this department. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 275, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 163, sec. 13, effective January 1, 1990. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 404, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 446, sec. 8, effective April 12, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 295, sec. 82, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 292, sec. 23. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 68, Art. VIII, sec.  24, effective March 17, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11069</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>