<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="95" order_by="95">CITY POLICE AND FIRE DEPARTMENTS </unit></structure><section_number>95.830</section_number><catch_line>Use of fire apparatus outside city limits, cities of all classes. </catch_line><order_by>830</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any city in the state owning or controlling fire apparatus may take it to extinguish fires to any point in the county in which that city is located, into a smaller territory in that county, or into areas of another county or state, as determined by the city legislative body. The apparatus shall be so used only in conformity with reasonable terms and regulations which the city legislative body may prescribe. </section><section prefix="2">The city shall not be liable in any manner on account of the use of the apparatus at any point outside of the corporate limits of the city. The apparatus shall be deemed to be employed in the exercise of a governmental function of the city. </section><section prefix="3">All city or fire protection district firefighters, full-paid or volunteer, serving at a fire or doing fire prevention work outside the corporate limits of a city or a fire protection district shall be considered as serving in their regular line of duty, as though they were serving within the corporate limits. </section><section prefix="4">Full-paid firefighters shall receive no additional compensation, and volunteer firemen shall receive only the compensation provided by ordinance for such cases. </section><section prefix="5">All full-paid firefighters and volunteer firemen are entitled to the benefits of any firefighters' pension fund or volunteer firemen's fund, the same as if the firefighting or fire prevention work had been within the corporate limits of the city or the fire protection district. </section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 46, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 111. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2741u-3. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26071</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>