<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="139" order_by="139">SALES AND USE TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>139.200</section_number><catch_line>Imposition of sales tax. </catch_line><order_by>200</order_by><text>A tax is hereby imposed upon all retailers at the rate of six percent (6%) of the gross receipts derived from: <section prefix="1">Retail sales of: <section prefix="a">Tangible personal property, regardless of the method of delivery, made within this Commonwealth; and </section><section prefix="b">Digital property regardless of whether: <section prefix="1">The purchaser has the right to permanently use the property; </section><section prefix="2">The purchaser's right to access or retain the property is not permanent; or </section><section prefix="3">The purchaser's right of use is conditioned upon continued payment; and </section></section></section><section prefix="2">The furnishing of the following: <section prefix="a">The rental of any room or rooms, lodgings, or accommodations furnished by any hotel, motel, inn, tourist camp, tourist cabin, or any other place in which rooms, lodgings, or accommodations are regularly furnished to transients for a consideration. The tax shall not apply to rooms, lodgings, or accommodations supplied for a continuous period of thirty (30) days or more to a person; </section><section prefix="b">Sewer services; </section><section prefix="c">The sale of admissions except those taxed under KRS 138.480; </section><section prefix="d">Prepaid calling service and prepaid wireless calling service; </section><section prefix="e">Intrastate, interstate, and international communications services as defined in KRS 139.195, except the furnishing of pay telephone service as defined in KRS 139.195; and </section><section prefix="f">Distribution, transmission, or transportation services for natural gas that is for storage, use, or other consumption in this state, excluding those services furnished: <section prefix="1">For natural gas that is classified as residential use as provided in KRS 139.470(8); or </section><section prefix="2">To a seller or reseller of natural gas. </section></section></section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 73, sec. 4, effective July 1, 2009. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 4, effective July 1, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 72, effective January 1, 2006; and ch. 173, Pt. VI, sec. 2, effective June 1, 2005. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 7, effective July 1, 2004. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. VII A, sec. 617, effective July 1, 1990. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 40, Part I, sec. 4. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 5, Art. I, sec. 20. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28861</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>