<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">B MEDICAL IMAGING, RADIATION THERAPY, AND RELATED OCCUPATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>311B.030</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Board for Medical Imaging and Radiation Therapy -- Qualifications, terms, and nomination of members.   </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Board for Medical Imaging and Radiation Therapy is hereby created to promote, preserve, and protect the public health, safety, and welfare of the citizens of the Commonwealth of Kentucky by regulating and licensing individuals who use ionizing or nonionizing radiation as advanced imaging professionals, medical imaging technologists, radiographers, radiation therapists, nuclear medicine technologists, limited X-ray machine operators, or any combination of professions licensed under this chapter. The board shall consist of nine (9) members appointed by the Governor, with the following qualifications: <section prefix="a">Two (2) members shall be licensed radiographers whose primary work responsibilities are related to general diagnostic radiography; </section><section prefix="b">Two (2) members shall be licensed radiographers with a post-primary certification and whose primary work responsibilities are related to that post-primary certification; </section><section prefix="c">One (1) member shall be a licensed nuclear medicine technologist; </section><section prefix="d">One (1) member shall be a licensed radiation therapist; </section><section prefix="e">One (1) member shall be a licensed limited X-ray machine operator; </section><section prefix="f">One (1) member shall be a licensed medical imaging technologist or therapist who serves as an educator in an accredited program or as an administrator in a medical imaging or radiation therapy department; and </section><section prefix="g">One (1) member shall be an individual at-large from the general public with no family or business relation to health care but with an interest in the rights of consumers of health services. </section></section><section prefix="2">All board members, except the at-large member, shall have at least five (5) years of experience in their respective areas of certification or licensure and shall maintain active registry or certification and Kentucky licensure in medical imaging or radiation therapy during the term as a board member. Each board member shall be a resident of Kentucky or actively employed in medical imaging or radiation therapy in Kentucky, and shall be in good standing with the board. </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">By May 1 of years in which terms expire, nominations of individuals for appointment to the board shall be submitted to the Governor and may be made by citizens of the Commonwealth of Kentucky through the Kentucky Society of Radiologic Technologists, the Kentucky Society of Nuclear Medicine Technologists, the board, or other professional imaging or radiation therapy organizations that are recognized by the board. </section><section prefix="b">No two (2) board members shall be residents of the same county. </section><section prefix="c">A minimum of two (2) names per appointment shall be submitted to the Governor. </section></section><section prefix="4">The Governor shall make each appointment by September 1 for terms beginning November 1 of that same year. The initial terms of appointment shall be staggered with five (5) members appointed for four (4) years and four (4) members appointed for two (2) years. Thereafter, members shall be appointed to the board for terms of four (4) years, expiring on October 31 of the fourth year. A board member may serve two (2) consecutive appointments. After a second consecutive appointment, that individual may not be reappointed until at least one (1) full year has passed. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 50, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40197</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>