<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="246" order_by="246">DEPARTMENT OF AGRICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>246.260</section_number><catch_line>State aid for promotion of sheep industry. </catch_line><order_by>260</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="a">"Department" means the department of agriculture; </section><section prefix="b">"Commissioner" means the commissioner of agriculture; </section><section prefix="c">"Show, exhibition and sale" shall not include those held as a part of or in connection with any county or other local fair. </section></section><section prefix="2">It shall be the duty of the department to aid, encourage, foster and promote the development and improvement of the sheep industry in Kentucky. To that end, it shall be the duty of the department to promote, and assist in the promotion of shows and sales of sheep in Kentucky with the object and purpose of maintaining Kentucky's national recognition as a sheep state for breeding, producing, raising, exhibition, showing and sale of sheep and for said purposes there hereby is appropriated out of the general fund to the department the sum of three thousand dollars ($3,000) for each of the fiscal years 1951-1952 and 1952-1953. </section><section prefix="3">From the appropriation made in subsection (2) of this section, one thousand dollars ($1,000) shall be used and applied in each of said fiscal years for the payment of premiums for district shows and sales which may be held in Kentucky in each of the fiscal years, 1951-1952 and 1952-1953 which is open on equal terms and conditions to all Kentucky 4-H club members with a sheep project. One thousand dollars ($1,000) shall be used and applied in each fiscal year for the payment of premiums for district shows and sales which may be held in Kentucky in each of the fiscal years, 1951-1952 and 1952-1953 which is open on equal terms and conditions to all Kentucky future farmer members with a sheep project. One thousand dollars ($1,000) shall be used and applied in each of the fiscal years for the payment of premiums for district shows and sales which may be held in Kentucky in each of the fiscal years, 1951-1952 and 1952-1953 which is open on equal terms and conditions to all Kentucky adult sheep raisers in Kentucky. No Kentucky adult sheep raiser may show, exhibit or sell in more than one district show. </section><section prefix="4">Any show, exhibition and sale of sheep to be eligible to receive the aforesaid appropriations must provide that the entries in all classes must be open upon equal terms to all breeders of such sheep in Kentucky. The commissioner shall determine with respect to the aforesaid sheep which shows, exhibitions and sales in each year shall receive assistance and, in making such determination, he may consider such shows, exhibitions and sales as may have been held in Kentucky in any previous year and in any previous two (2) year period. </section></text><history>Created 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 166, secs. 1 to 4. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11540</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>