<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.16-115</section_number><catch_line>Discretionary groups -- Requisite findings of commissioner.   </catch_line><order_by>16-115</order_by><text>Group life insurance offered to a resident of this state under a group life insurance policy issued to a group, other than one described in KRS 304.16-030, 304.16-040, 304.16-050, 304.16-060, 304.16-070, or 304.16-080, shall be subject to the following requirements: <section prefix="1">No group life insurance policy shall be delivered in this state unless the commissioner finds that: <section prefix="a">The issuance of the group policy is not contrary to the best interests of the public; </section><section prefix="b">The issuance of the group policy would result in economies of acquisition or administration; and </section><section prefix="c">The benefits of the group policy are reasonable in relation to the premiums charged; </section></section><section prefix="2">No group life insurance coverage may be offered in this state by an insurer under a policy issued in another state unless this state or another state having requirements substantially similar to the requirements of subsection (1) of this section has made a determination that the requirements have been met; </section><section prefix="3">The premium for the policy shall be paid either from the policyholder's funds or from funds contributed by the covered persons, or from both; and </section><section prefix="4">An insurer may exclude or limit the coverage on any person as to whom evidence of individual insurability is not satisfactory to the insurer. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 4, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:11</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40549</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>