<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="342" order_by="342">WORKERS' COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>342.796</section_number><catch_line>Notice of education and training opportunities. </catch_line><order_by>796</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding any provisions of the KRS to the contrary, every employer engaged in the severance or processing of coal, as defined in KRS 342.0011, at its principal office and such other locations where employees customarily report for payroll and personnel matters, shall conspicuously post a notice advising employees of the education and training opportunities available under this chapter. The notice shall include: <section prefix="a">Toll-free telephone numbers for the: <section prefix="1">Department of Workers' Claims; </section><section prefix="2">Kentucky Community and Technical College System; and </section><section prefix="3">Kentucky Higher Education Assistance Authority; </section></section><section prefix="b">Telephone numbers for the local board of education and centers for adult education and literacy; and </section><section prefix="c">A list of approved education and training programs available to employees engaged in the severance or processing of coal. </section></section><section prefix="2">The notice shall be made available to all employers at no cost and upon request of the employer. The notice shall also be posted on the Web sites maintained by the Department of Workers' Claims and the Kentucky Community and Technical College System. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1853, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 340, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32558</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>