<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="7" order_by="7">LEGISLATIVE RESEARCH COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>7.500</section_number><catch_line>Public access to electronic form of Kentucky Constitution, statutes, acts, and administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>500</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Legislative Research Commission shall make available to the public in electronic form the following texts: <section prefix="a">The Constitution of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="b">The Kentucky Revised Statutes; </section><section prefix="c">The Kentucky Acts; and </section><section prefix="d">The administrative regulations comprising the Kentucky Administrative Regulations Service and the Administrative Register of Kentucky. </section></section><section prefix="2">The information identified in subsection (1) of this section shall be made available to the public by means of access by way of the largest nonproprietary, nonprofit cooperative public computer network. The information shall be made available in one (1) or more formats and by one (1) or more means in order to provide the greatest feasible access to the general public in this Commonwealth. Any person who accesses the information may access all or any part of the information. The information shall be made available in the shortest feasible time after the information is available to the Legislative Research Commission. </section><section prefix="3">Any documentation that describes the electronic digital formats of the information identified in subsection (1) of this section and is available to the public shall be made available by means of access by way of the computer network specified in subsection (2) of this section. </section><section prefix="4">Personal information concerning a person who accesses the information made available under this section may be maintained only for the purpose of providing service to the person. </section><section prefix="5">No fee or other charge may be imposed by the Legislative Research Commission as a condition of accessing the information that is accessible by way of the computer network specified in subsection (2) of this section. </section><section prefix="6">The information made available to the public under this section shall not be subject to the provisions of KRS 61.870 to 61.884. </section><section prefix="7">No action taken pursuant to this section shall be deemed to alter or relinquish any copyright or other proprietary interest or entitlement of the Commonwealth of Kentucky relating to any of the information made available under this section. </section><section prefix="8">In addition to the access provided by this section, the Commission may also make available any of the information identified in subsection (1) of this section by any other means of access that would facilitate public access to the information under terms and conditions established by the Commission. </section></text><history> Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 46, sec. 8, effective September 1, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> September 1, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=491</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>