<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.10-022</section_number><catch_line>Office of the Secretary -- Major organization units -- Executive directors -- Appointments. </catch_line><order_by>10-022</order_by><text>There is established in the Office of the Secretary an Office of Administrative Hearings and an Office of Legislative and Intergovernmental Affairs. Each of these offices shall be headed by an executive director appointed by the secretary with the approval of the Governor as required by KRS 12.050. There is also established in the Office of the Secretary an Office of General Counsel, headed by a general counsel appointed by the secretary with the approval of the Governor in accordance with KRS 12.050 and 12.210. The executive directors and the general counsel shall be directly responsible to the secretary and shall perform the functions, powers, and duties as provided by law and as prescribed by the secretary. The Environmental Quality Commission, which shall be headed by an executive director appointed by the secretary with the approval of the Governor, shall be attached to the Office of the Secretary. The Kentucky State Nature Preserves Commission, which shall be headed by a director, and the Mine Safety Review Commission, whose members shall be appointed by the Governor with the consent of the General Assembly, shall be attached to the Office of the Secretary. The Kentucky Public Service Commission, which shall be headed by an executive director appointed by the commission in accordance with KRS 278.100, shall be attached to the Office of the Secretary for administrative purposes. </text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 350, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 4, effective June 20, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:34</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10298</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>