<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="250" order_by="250">AGRICULTURAL SEEDS, FEEDING STUFFS, AND FERTILIZERS </unit></structure><section_number>250.511</section_number><catch_line>Registration of commercial feed manufacturing facilities. </catch_line><order_by>511</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall manufacture a commercial feed in this state, unless he has filed with the director on forms provided by the director, his name, place of business, and location of each manufacturing facility in this state. </section><section prefix="2">No person shall distribute in this state a commercial feed, except a customer-formula feed, which has not been registered pursuant to the provisions of this section. The application for registration shall be submitted in the manner prescribed by the director. Upon approval by the director, the registration shall be issued to the applicant. A registration shall continue in effect unless it is canceled by the registrant or unless it is canceled by the director pursuant to subsection (3) of this section. The director by administrative regulation may exempt the manufacturer or distributor named on the label from the requirement for registration of each feed distributed in the state. </section><section prefix="3">The director may refuse registration of any commercial feed not in compliance with the provisions of KRS 250.491 to 250.631 and may cancel any registration subsequently found not to be in compliance with any provision of KRS 250.491 to 250.631. No registration shall be refused or canceled unless the registrant shall have been given an opportunity for an informal hearing before the director and to amend the application in order to comply with the requirements of KRS 250.491 to 250.631. Any person aggrieved by a decision made as a result of an informal hearing may appeal, and upon appeal an administrative hearing shall be conducted in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 68, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996; and ch. 318, sec. 169, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 356, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 4. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/96).  This section was amended by 1996 Ky. Acts chs. 68 and 318 which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12169</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>