<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.6-145</section_number><catch_line>Minimum standards -- Operative dates. </catch_line><order_by>6-145</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The interest rates used in determining the minimum standard for the valuation of: <section prefix="a">All life insurance policies issued in a particular calendar year, on or after the effective date of KRS 304.15-342; </section><section prefix="b">All individual annuity and pure endowment contracts issued in a particular calendar year on or after January 1, 1983; </section><section prefix="c">All annuities and pure endowments purchased in a particular calendar year on or after January 1, 1983 under group annuity and pure endowment contracts; and </section><section prefix="d">The net increase, if any, in a particular calendar year after January 1, 1983, in amounts held under guaranteed interest contracts shall be the calendar year statutory valuation interest rates as defined in this section. </section></section><section prefix="2">The calendar year statutory valuation interest rates, I, shall be determined as follows and the results rounded to the nearer one-quarter of one percent (1/4 of 1%): <section prefix="a">For life insurance, </section><section prefix="b">For single premium immediate annuities and for annuity benefits involving </section><section prefix="c">For other annuities with cash settlement options and guaranteed interest </section><section prefix="d">For other annuities with no cash settlement options and for guaranteed interest </section><section prefix="e">For other annuities with cash settlement options and guaranteed interest </section></section> I = .03 + W (R1 - .03) + W/2 (R2 - .09); life contingencies arising from other annuities with cash settlement options and from guaranteed interest contracts with cash settlement options,  I = .03 + W (R - .03)  where R1 is the lesser of R and .09,   R2 is the greater of R and .09,   R is the reference interest rate defined in this section,   and W is the weighting factor defined in this section; contracts with cash settlement options, valued on an issue year basis, except as stated in paragraph (b) above, the formula for life insurance stated in paragraph (a) above shall apply to annuities and guaranteed interest contracts, with guarantee durations in excess of ten (10) years and the formula for single premium immediate annuities stated in paragraph (b) above shall apply to annuities and guaranteed interest contracts with guarantee duration of ten (10) years or less; contracts with no cash settlement options, the formula for single premium immediate annuities stated in paragraph (b) above shall apply; and contracts with cash settlement options, valued on a change in fund basis, the formula for single premium immediate annuities stated in paragraph (b) above shall apply.  However, if the calendar year statutory valuation interest rate for any life insurance policies issued in any calendar year determined without reference to this sentence differs from the corresponding actual rate for similar policies issued in the immediately preceding calendar year by less than one-half of one percent (1/2 of 1%), the calendar year statutory valuation interest rate for such life insurance policies shall be equal to the corresponding actual rate for the immediately preceding calendar year. For purposes of applying the immediately preceding sentence, the calendar year statutory valuation interest rate for life insurance policies issued in a calendar year shall be determined for 1980 (using the reference interest rate defined for 1979) and shall be determined for each subsequent calendar year regardless of when KRS 304.15-342 becomes effective. <section prefix="3">The weighting factors referred to in the formulas stated above are given in the following tables: <section prefix="a">Weighting Factors for Life Insurance: </section><section prefix="b">Weighting factor for single premium immediate annuities and for annuity </section><section prefix="c">Weighting factors for other annuities and for guaranteed interest contracts, <section prefix="1">For annuities and guaranteed interest contracts valued on an issue year </section><section prefix="2">For annuities and guaranteed interest contracts valued on a change in </section><section prefix="3">For annuities and guaranteed interest contracts valued on an issue year </section><section prefix="4">For other annuities with cash settlement options and guaranteed interest </section><section prefix="5">Plan type as used in the above tables is defined as follows: </section><section prefix="6">An insurer may elect to value guaranteed interest contracts with cash </section></section></section> Guarantee Duration   Weighting Factors   (Years)   10 or less     .50   More than 10, but not   more than 20     .45   More than 20     .35  For life insurance, the guarantee duration is the maximum number of years the life insurance can remain in force on a basis guaranteed in the policy or under options to convert to plans of life insurance with premium rates or nonforfeiture values or both which are guaranteed in the original policy; benefits involving life contingencies arising from other annuities with cash settlement options and guaranteed interest contracts with cash settlement options:        .80 except as stated in (b) above, shall be as specified in tables 1., 2., and 3. below, according to the rules and definitions in 4., 5., and 6. below: basis:  Guarantee Duration          Weighting Factor for Plan Type   (Years)   A B C   5 or less:   .80 .60 .50   More than 5, but not   more than 10   .75 .60 .50   More than 10, but not   more than 20:   .65 .50 .45   More than 20:   .45 .35 .35 fund basis, the factors shown in 1. above increased by:        Plan Type       A B C       .15 .25 .05 basis (other than those with no cash settlement options) which do not guarantee interest on considerations received more than one (1) year after issue or purchase and for annuities and guaranteed interest contracts valued on a change in fund basis which do not guarantee interest rates on considerations received more than twelve (12) months beyond the valuation date, the factors shown in 1. or derived in 2. increased by:        Plan Type       A B C       .05 .05 .05 contracts with cash settlement options, the guarantee duration is the number of years for which the contract guarantees interest rates in excess of the calendar year statutory valuation interest rate for life insurance policies with guarantee duration in excess of twenty (20) years. For other annuities with no cash settlement options and for guaranteed interest contracts with no cash settlement options, the guarantee duration is the number of years from the date of issue or date of purchase to the date annuity benefits are scheduled to commence. Plan Type A: At any time policyholder may withdraw funds only with an  adjustment to reflect changes in interest rates or asset values since  receipt of the funds by the insurer, or without such adjustment but  in installments over five (5) years or more, or as an immediate life  annuity, or no withdrawal permitted; Plan Type B: Before expiration of the interest rate guarantee, policyholder  may withdraw funds only with an adjustment to reflect changes in  interest rates or asset values since receipt of the funds by the  insurer, or without such adjustment but in installments over five  (5) years or more, or no withdrawal permitted. At the end of  interest rate guarantee, funds may be withdrawn without such  adjustment in a single sum or installments over less than five (5)  years; and Plan Type C: Policyholder may withdraw funds before expiration of interest  rate guarantee in a single sum or installments over less than five  (5) years either without adjustment to reflect changes in interest  rates or asset values since receipt of the funds by the insurer, or  subject only to a fixed surrender charge stipulated in the contract  as a percentage of the fund. settlement options and annuities with cash settlement options on either an issue year basis or on a change in fund basis. Guaranteed interest contracts with no cash settlement options and other annuities with no cash settlement options must be valued on an issue year basis. As used in this section, an issue year basis of valuation refers to a valuation basis under which the interest rate used to determine the minimum valuation standard applicable to each change in the fund held under the annuity or guaranteed interest contract is the calendar year valuation interest rate for the year of the change in the fund. <section prefix="4">The reference interest rate referred to in subsection (2) of this section shall be defined as follows: <section prefix="a">For all life insurance, the lesser of the average over a period of thirty-six (36) months and the average over a period of twelve (12) months, ending on June 30 of the calendar year next preceding the year of issue, of Moody's Corporate Bond Yield Average - Monthly Average Corporates, as published by Moody's Investors Service, Inc.; </section><section prefix="b">For single premium immediate annuities and for annuity benefits involving life contingencies arising from other annuities with cash settlement options and guaranteed interest contracts with cash settlement options, the average over a period of twelve (12) months, ending on June 30 of the calendar year of issue or year of purchase, of Moody's Corporate Bond Yield Average - Monthly Average Corporates, as published by Moody's Investors Service, Inc.; </section><section prefix="c">For other annuities with cash settlement options and guaranteed interest contracts with cash settlement options, valued on a year of issue basis, except as stated in paragraph (b) above, with guarantee duration in excess of ten (10) years, the lesser of the average over a period of thirty-six (36) months and the average over a period of twelve (12) months, ending on June 30 of the calendar year of issue or purchase, of Moody's Corporate Bond Yield Average - Monthly Average Corporates, as published by Moody's Investors Service, Inc.; </section><section prefix="d">For other annuities with cash settlement options and guaranteed interest contracts with cash settlement options, valued on a year of issue basis, except as stated in paragraph (b) above, with guarantee duration of ten (10) years or less, the average over a period of twelve (12) months, ending on June 30 of the calendar year of issue or purchase, of Moody's Corporate Bond Yield Average - Monthly Average Corporates, as published by Moody's Investors Service, Inc.; </section><section prefix="e">For other annuities with no cash settlement options and for guaranteed interest contracts with no cash settlement options, the average over a period of twelve (12) months, ending on June 30 of the calendar year of issue or purchase, of Moody's Corporate Bond Yield Average - Monthly Average Corporates, as published by Moody's Investors Service, Inc.; and </section><section prefix="f">For other annuities with cash settlement options and guaranteed interest contracts with cash settlement options, valued on a change in fund basis, except as stated in paragraph (b) above, the average over a period of twelve (12) months, ending on June 30 of the calendar year of the change in the fund, of Moody's Corporate Bond Yield Average - Monthly Average Corporates, as published by Moody's Investors Service, Inc. </section></section><section prefix="5">In the event that Moody's Corporate Bond Yield Average - Monthly Average Corporates is no longer published by Moody's Investors Service, Inc., or in the event that the National Association of Insurance Commissioners determines that Moody's Corporate Bond Yield Average - Monthly Average Corporates as published by Moody's Investors Service, Inc. is no longer appropriate for the determination of the reference interest rate, then an alternative method for determination of the reference interest rate, which is adopted by the National Association of Insurance Commissioners and approved by regulation promulgated by the commissioner, may be substituted. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1004, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 263, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-16</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:08</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=16785</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>