<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.90-015</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of corporation. </catch_line><order_by>90-015</order_by><text>The Northern Kentucky Convention Center Corporation: <section prefix="1">Shall supervise the design and construction of the Northern Kentucky Convention Center, and shall provide all management functions for the facility and for any other property acquired or leased pursuant to its powers under this section; </section><section prefix="2">May take, acquire, and hold property, and all interests therein, by deed, purchase, gift, devise, bequest, or lease, or by transfer from the State Property and Buildings Commission, and may dispose of any property so acquired in any manner provided by law. </section><section prefix="3">May issue revenue bonds, subject to procedures which shall be established by the Finance and Administration Cabinet, solely payable from the revenues and other funds pledged for their payment for the purpose of paying all or any part of the cost of any project or for the acquisition of property; </section><section prefix="4">Shall promote the growth and development of the convention trade, tourism, and the hotel, restaurant, and entertainment industry in Northern Kentucky and the Commonwealth, through utilization of the Northern Kentucky Convention Center to enhance these and the public interest; </section><section prefix="5">May adopt administrative regulations, as provided in KRS Chapter 13A, governing the operation, maintenance, or use of property under its custody and control; </section><section prefix="6">May levy a surcharge on tickets for functions held within the center to contribute to operating revenue; </section><section prefix="7">Shall have the exclusive control of all exhibitions, performances, and concessions in the Northern Kentucky Convention Center. The corporation shall have a prior lien upon the property of any private exhibitor, concessionaire, or other person holding an exhibition or performance or operating a concession in the center, and may sell the property upon ten (10) days notice to satisfy any indebtedness: </section><section prefix="8">Shall participate with local hotels and the travel industry to develop tourist packages and additional services to attract conferences and conventions to the region; </section><section prefix="9">May establish an executive committee from among its membership with full authority to act between its meetings to the extent delegated by the corporation; and </section><section prefix="10">May sue and be sued and maintain and defend legal actions in its corporate name. </section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 3, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3004</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>