<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="216" order_by="216">B LICENSURE AND REGULATION OF HEALTH FACILITIES AND SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>216B.306</section_number><catch_line>Procedures, remedies, and penalties for operation of boarding home without registration. </catch_line><order_by>306</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When the cabinet has reasonable cause to believe that any person, association, business entity, or organization is operating a boarding home without a registration, the cabinet may: <section prefix="a">Issue and deliver a notice to cease and desist from the violations; </section><section prefix="b">Issue and deliver a notice to cease and desist to any person who aids and abets the operation of a boarding home that is not registered; and </section><section prefix="c">Impose a civil penalty of at least one thousand dollars ($1,000) but not more than five thousand dollars ($5,000) upon the person, association, business entity, or organization that operates a boarding home that is not registered by the cabinet. </section></section><section prefix="2">Issuance of a notice under subsection (1) of this section shall not constitute agency action for which a hearing under KRS Chapter 13B may be sought. </section><section prefix="3">For the purpose of enforcing a cease and desist order and penalties under subsection (1) of this section, the cabinet may file a proceeding in the name of the Commonwealth seeking issuance of an injunction and enforcement of penalties against any person who violates subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="4">In addition to the remedies under subsection (1) of this section, the cabinet may impose a civil penalty of at least one thousand dollars ($1,000) but not more than five thousand dollars ($5,000) upon the person, association, business, entity, or organization who aids and abets the operation of a boarding home that is not registered. If the cabinet is required to seek enforcement of the cease and desist order, it shall be entitled to collect attorney's fees, costs, and any expenses incurred by the cabinet or local government as a consequence of and incident to the relocation of boarders to appropriate housing. </section></text><history> Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 170, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:37</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9244</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>