<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="439" order_by="439">PROBATION AND PAROLE </unit></structure><section_number>439.550</section_number><catch_line>Probation by District Court -- Supervision by Department of Corrections, or by adult misdemeanant probation and work release agency of urban-county government. </catch_line><order_by>550</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If any District Court places a person on probation following a conviction of crime, either upon verdict or plea, the court may direct that the defendant be under the supervision of the Department of Corrections. </section><section prefix="2">In counties containing an urban-county form of government, the urban-county council shall provide for supervision of a person placed on probation or work release by the District Court of the county following a conviction of crime, either upon a verdict or plea, under the supervision of an adult misdemeanant probation and work release agency of the urban-county government. The employees of the agency shall be classified civil service employees of a correctional services division created under KRS 67A.028 and shall be subject to the direction of the judges of the District Court in the performance of their duties. There shall be the number of employees of said agency, including clerical personnel, as necessary for the operation of the agency, and they shall receive reasonable salaries to be fixed by the urban-county council which salaries shall be paid out of the urban-county treasury. </section></text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 100, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 344, sec. 52, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 449, effective January 2, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. V, sec. 24(14); and ch. 406, sec. 330. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 290, sec. 1. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 256, sec. 1. -- Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 32, effective May 18, 1956. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19205</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>