<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="40" order_by="40">VETERANS </unit></structure><section_number>40.350</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Wounded or Disabled Veterans Program -- Powers and duties -- Components of program -- Data-sharing agreements -- Confidentiality of veterans' personal information -- Administrative regulations -- Authority to accept and expend moneys. </catch_line><order_by>350</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">The Kentucky Wounded or Disabled Veterans Program is hereby created in the Kentucky Department of Veterans' Affairs and shall be attached to the Office of the Commissioner for administrative purposes. </section><section prefix="b">The program shall assist wounded or disabled veterans who served in the United States Armed Forces and were discharged under conditions other than dishonorable. The program shall: <section prefix="1">Ease the transition from active service for these wounded or disabled veterans; and </section><section prefix="2">Ensure that these wounded or disabled veterans receive the federal, state, and private benefits to which they are entitled as wounded or disabled veterans. </section></section><section prefix="c">The commissioner shall designate a wounded or disabled veterans coordinator for the Commonwealth. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Wounded or Disabled Veterans Program shall: <section prefix="a">Perform outreach to improve wounded or disabled veterans' awareness of eligibility for federal, state, and private wounded or disabled veterans' services and benefits; </section><section prefix="b">Assess the needs of wounded or disabled veterans with respect to benefits and services; </section><section prefix="c">Review programs, research projects, and other initiatives that are or may be: <section prefix="1">Designed to address or meet the needs of Kentucky's wounded or disabled veterans; or </section><section prefix="2">Unresponsive or insensitive to the needs of these wounded or disabled veterans; </section></section><section prefix="d">Recommend changes, revisions, and new initiatives to the commissioner to: <section prefix="1">Address deficiencies identified through the review established in paragraph (c) of this subsection; and </section><section prefix="2">Improve benefits and services; and </section></section><section prefix="e">Incorporate wounded or disabled veterans' issues in strategic planning concerning benefits and services. </section></section><section prefix="3">The primary components of the program shall be: <section prefix="a">Advocacy and Public Awareness. The program shall advocate for wounded or disabled veterans and shall work to increase public awareness about the needs of wounded or disabled veterans. The program shall advocate legislation and policies on the local, state, and national levels to address these issues; </section><section prefix="b">Collaboration. The program shall collaborate with federal, state, and private agencies that provide services to wounded or disabled veterans; </section><section prefix="c">Research and Information Dissemination. The program shall monitor and research issues relating to wounded or disabled veterans and disseminate information and opportunities throughout its network; </section><section prefix="d">Education. The program, through conferences, seminars, and training workshops with federal, state, and private agencies, shall provide guidance and direction to wounded or disabled veterans applying for grants, benefits, or services; </section><section prefix="e">Honor and Recognition. The program shall promote events and activities that recognize and honor wounded or disabled veterans; and </section><section prefix="f">Facilities. The program, through grants and other sources of funding, shall provide facilities as appropriate in support of the program. </section></section><section prefix="4">The Kentucky Department of Veterans' Affairs shall enter into data-sharing agreements with the United States Department of Veterans Affairs and the Department of Defense to obtain timely information with regard to the address and medical status of a Kentucky wounded or disabled veteran. </section><section prefix="5">With the consent of a wounded or disabled veteran, the wounded or disabled veterans coordinator for the Commonwealth, or his or her designee, may obtain personal information concerning that veteran for the sole purpose of implementing the program. Under the provisions of KRS 61.878, the information shall not be subject to public disclosure. </section><section prefix="6">The Kentucky Department of Veterans' Affairs shall promulgate administrative regulations to carry out the provisions of this section. </section><section prefix="7">The program is authorized to accept and expend: <section prefix="a">Moneys that may be appropriated by the General Assembly; and </section><section prefix="b">Other moneys received from any other source, including donations and grants. </section></section></text><history> Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21854</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>