<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.2003</section_number><catch_line>Claims disallowed. </catch_line><order_by>2003</order_by><text>Notwithstanding KRS 65.2001, a local government shall not be liable for injuries or losses resulting from: <section prefix="1">Any claim by an employee of the local government which is covered by the Kentucky workers' compensation law; </section><section prefix="2">Any claim in connection with the assessment or collection of taxes; </section><section prefix="3">Any claim arising from the exercise of judicial, quasi-judicial, legislative or quasi-legislative authority or others, exercise of judgment or discretion vested in the local government, which shall include by example, but not be limited to: <section prefix="a">The adoption or failure to adopt any ordinance, resolution, order, regulation, or rule; </section><section prefix="b">The failure to enforce any law; </section><section prefix="c">The issuance, denial, suspension, revocation of, or failure or refusal to issue, deny, suspend or revoke any permit, license, certificate, approval, order or similar authorization; </section><section prefix="d">The exercise of discretion when in the face of competing demands, the local government determines whether and how to utilize or apply existing resources; or </section><section prefix="e">Failure to make an inspection. </section></section> Nothing contained in this subsection shall be construed to exempt a local government from liability for negligence arising out of acts or omissions of its employees in carrying out their ministerial duties. </text><history>Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 224, sec. 18, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1988 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23369</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>