<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="272" order_by="272">COOPERATIVE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>272.131</section_number><catch_line>Articles of association, contents -- Filing effect.   </catch_line><order_by>131</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The articles of incorporation of each association shall state: <section prefix="a">The name of the association that satisfies KRS 14A.3-010; </section><section prefix="b">The purposes for which it is formed; </section><section prefix="c">The place where its principal business will be transacted; </section><section prefix="d">The period of duration, which may be perpetual. When the articles of incorporation fail to state the period of duration, it shall be considered perpetual. Any association heretofore or hereafter organized for a period less than perpetual, may, by amendment to its articles of incorporation, extend the period of its duration for a specified period or perpetually; </section><section prefix="e">The names and addresses, not less than five (5), of those who are to serve as directors for the first term or until the election of their successors; </section><section prefix="f">If organized without capital stock, whether the property rights and interest of each member shall be equal or unequal; and if unequal, the articles shall set forth the general rules applicable to all members by which the property rights and interests, respectively, of each member shall be determined and fixed; and the association shall have the power to admit new members who shall be entitled to share in the property of the association with the old members in accordance with the general rules. These provisions of the articles of incorporation shall not be altered, amended, or repealed except by the affirmative vote of not less than two-thirds (2/3) of the votes entitled to be cast by members present in person, or by proxy, if permitted by the bylaws, and voting thereon at any regular or special meeting; and </section><section prefix="g">If organized with capital stock, the authorized amount of the stock and the number of shares into which it is divided and the par value thereof. Capital stock may be divided into preferred and common stock. The articles of incorporation must contain a statement of the number of shares of stock to which preference is granted and the number of shares of stock to which no preference is granted and the nature and extent of the preference and the privileges granted to each. No specific amount of the capital stock authorized is required to be subscribed before the association may transact business with other than its members; the board may determine the amount of capital stock to be issued as the business of the association may justify or demand, from time to time, within the amount of the total authorization. </section></section><section prefix="2">The articles of incorporation may contain any provision consistent with law with respect to management, regulation, government, financing, indebtedness, membership, the establishment of voting districts and the election of delegates for representative purposes, the issuance, retirement and transfer of its stock, if formed with capital stock, or any provisions relative to the way or manner in which it shall operate with respect to its members, officers, or directors, and any other provisions relating to its affairs; but nothing set forth in this section shall be construed as limiting any of the rights or powers otherwise given to such associations. </section><section prefix="3">The articles of incorporation must be subscribed by the incorporators and acknowledged by one (1) of them before an officer authorized by the laws of this state to take and certify acknowledgments of deeds and conveyances; and shall be filed and recorded in accordance with the statute relating to corporations generally; and when so filed, the articles of incorporation, or certified copies thereof, shall be received in all the courts of this state, and other places, as prima facie evidence of the facts contained therein, and of the due incorporation of the association. A copy of the articles of incorporation, indorsed by the Secretary of State with the fact and time of recording in his office, shall be filed with the dean of the College of Agriculture of the University of Kentucky and with the Commissioner of the Department of Agriculture. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 77, effective July 15, 2010; and repealed, reenacted, and amended ch. 151, sec. 57, effective January 1, 2011. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 77, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 117, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2011 </effective><lrc-note> (1/1/2011).  This section was repealed, reenacted, and amended by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 151, and repealed and reenacted by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51. Pursuant to Section 184 of Acts ch. 51, it was the intent of the General Assembly that the repeal and reenactment not serve to void the amendment, and these Acts do not appear to be in conflict, therefore, they have been codified together.  (7/15/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 183, provides, "The specific textual provisions of Sections 1 to 178 of this Act which reflect amendments made to those sections by 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137 shall be deemed effective as of June 26, 2007, and those provisions are hereby made expressly retroactive to that date, with the remainder of the text of those sections being unaffected by the provisions of this section." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36662</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>