<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="336" order_by="336">LABOR CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>336.015</section_number><catch_line>Labor Cabinet -- Organization and personnel -- Responsibility of secretary -- Agencies attached for administrative purposes. </catch_line><order_by>015</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The secretary of the Labor Cabinet shall have the duties, responsibilities, power, and authority relating to labor, wages and hours, occupational safety and health of employees, child labor, apprenticeship, workers' compensation, and all other matters previously under the jurisdiction of the Department of Labor. </section><section prefix="2">The Labor Cabinet shall consist of the Office of the Secretary, the Department of Workers' Claims, and the Department of Workplace Standards. </section><section prefix="3">The following agencies are attached to the cabinet for administrative purposes only: <section prefix="a">Kentucky Labor-Management Advisory Council; </section><section prefix="b">Kentucky Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission; </section><section prefix="c">State Labor Relations Board; </section><section prefix="d">Workers' Compensation Funding Commission; </section><section prefix="e">Occupational Safety and Health Standards Board; </section><section prefix="f">Prevailing Wage Review Board; </section><section prefix="g">Apprenticeship and Training Council; </section><section prefix="h">Employers' Mutual Insurance Authority; </section><section prefix="i">Office of General Administration and Program Support for Shared Services, which shall be headed by an executive director appointed by the Governor in accordance with KRS 12.040 upon recommendation from the secretaries of the Energy and Environment Cabinet, the Labor Cabinet, and the Public Protection Cabinet. The office is composed of the following divisions: <section prefix="1">Division of Human Resource Management; </section><section prefix="2">Division of Fiscal Management; </section><section prefix="3">Division of Budgets; and </section><section prefix="4">Division of Information Services; and </section></section><section prefix="j">Office of Inspector General for Shared Services, which shall be headed by an executive director appointed by the Governor in accordance with KRS 12.040 upon recommendation from the secretaries of the Energy and Environment Cabinet, the Labor Cabinet, and the Public Protection Cabinet. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1700, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 33, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 579, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 181, sec. 2, effective April 4, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 13, sec. 11, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1987 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 1, effective January 4, 1988. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 414, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31990</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>