<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="367" order_by="367">CONSUMER PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>367.46971</section_number><catch_line>Registration of telemarketing companies doing business in this state -- Filing fee -- Renewal -- Addendum -- Written confirmation of receipt of filing -- Posting of registration statement. </catch_line><order_by>46971</order_by><text><section prefix="1">At least ten (10) days prior to doing business in this state, a telemarketing company shall register with the division by filing the information described below and paying a filing fee of three hundred dollars ($300). A telemarketing company shall be deemed to do business in this state if the telemarketing company solicits prospective purchasers from locations in this state or solicits prospective purchasers who are located in this state. The information required by this section shall be submitted on a form provided by the Attorney General and shall be verified by a declaration signed by each principal of the telemarketing company, under penalty of perjury. The declaration shall specify the date and location of signing. Information submitted pursuant to KRS 367.46951 to 367.46999 shall be clearly identified and appended to the filing. </section><section prefix="2">Registration of a telemarketing company shall be valid for one (1) year from the effective date thereof and may be renewed annually by making the filing required by this section and paying a filing fee of fifty dollars ($50). </section><section prefix="3">If, prior to expiration of a telemarketing company's annual registration, there is a material change in the information required by KRS 367.46951 to 367.46999, the telemarketing company shall, within ten (10) days, file an addendum updating the information with the division. However, changes in salespersons soliciting on behalf of a telemarketing company shall be updated by filing addenda, if necessary, in quarterly intervals computed from the effective date of registration. The addendum shall include the required information for all salespersons currently soliciting or having solicited on behalf of the telemarketing company at any time during the period between the filing of the registration, or the last addendum, and the current addendum, and shall include information on salespersons no longer soliciting for the telemarketing company as of the date of the filing of the current addendum. </section><section prefix="4">Upon receiving the filing and the filing fee pursuant to this section, the division shall send the telemarketing company a written confirmation of receipt of the filing. If the telemarketing company has more than one (1) business location, the written confirmation shall be sent to the telemarketing company's principal business location as identified in the telemarketing company's filing in sufficient numbers so that the telemarketing company can meet the requirements of this subsection. Within ten (10) days of receipt of the confirmation, the telemarketing company shall post in a conspicuous place at each of the telemarketing company's business locations within this state a copy of the entire registration statement which has been filed with the division. Until confirmation of receipt of filing is received and posted, the telemarketing company shall post in a conspicuous place at each of the telemarketing company's business locations within this state a copy of the first page of the registration form sent to the department. The telemarketing company shall also post in close proximity to either the confirmation of receipt of filing or the first page of the submitted registration form the name of the individual in charge of each location from which the telemarketing company does business in this state. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 115, sec. 3, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 21, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 302, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 463, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/94).  This statute was created by 1994 Ky. Acts chs. 302 and 463, which are substantively identical and have been codified together. Minor variations have been resolved by giving precedence to Acts ch. 463 which was enacted last. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34976</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>