<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="309" order_by="309">MISCELLANEOUS OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS </unit></structure><section_number>309.133</section_number><catch_line>Requirements for licensure -- Licensure without examination -- Reciprocity. </catch_line><order_by>133</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall issue a license as a licensed professional art therapist to any person who files a completed application, accompanied by the required fees, and who submits satisfactory evidence that the applicant is at least twenty-one (21) years of age, demonstrates professional competency by satisfactorily passing the required examination, is a registered art therapist as defined by the Art Therapy Credentials Board, Inc., is a board certified art therapist as defined by the Art Therapy Credentials Board, Inc., and has: <section prefix="a">Received a master's degree or doctoral degree in art therapy that includes six hundred (600) hours of supervised internship experience from an accredited institution and has completed an additional one thousand (1,000) client contact hours of postgraduate experience under appropriate supervision; or </section><section prefix="b">Received a master's degree or doctoral degree in a related field, has a minimum of twenty-one (21) semester hours of sequential course work in the history, theory, and practice of art therapy, has completed seven hundred (700) hours of supervised internship experience from an accredited institution, and has completed an additional two thousand (2,000) client contact hours of postgraduate experience under appropriate supervision. </section></section><section prefix="2">The board may approve on a case-by-case basis applicants who have a master's degree or a doctoral degree from nonaccredited institutions. </section><section prefix="3">If an applicant has met all of the requirements for licensure except satisfactorily passing the required examination, the applicant shall be scheduled to take the next examination following the approval of the application. </section><section prefix="4">The board may issue a license to an applicant without examination if the person possesses a valid regulatory document issued by the appropriate examining board under the laws of any other state or territory of the United States, the District of Columbia, or any foreign nation that in the judgment of the board has requirements substantially equivalent to or exceeding the requirements in this section. </section><section prefix="5">The board may set criteria for continuing education and supervisory experience. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 5, effective June 25, 2009. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 337, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><lrc-note>(6/25/2009).  2009 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 12, provides: "Any person who is certified as a professional art therapist on the effective date of this Act [6/25/2009] shall automatically be licensed on the effective date of this Act [6/25/2009] and shall be issued a copy of the license at the time his or her certificate was next scheduled to be renewed if at that time the person complies with the provisions of Section 6 of this Act [KRS 309.1335] and has not been the subject of disciplinary action under Sections 8 [KRS 309.137] and 10 [KRS 309.1375] of this Act." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30343</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>