<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="434" order_by="434">OFFENSES AGAINST PROPERTY BY FRAUD </unit></structure><section_number>434.444</section_number><catch_line>Misrepresenting current or former military status -- Exemptions -- Penalties -- Transfer of fines revenue -- Short title.   </catch_line><order_by>444</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of misrepresenting current or former military status when he or she, for the purpose of direct or indirect monetary gain, and with intent to defraud, obtain employment, or be elected or appointed to public office, intentionally makes: <section prefix="a">A claim, orally, in writing, or by any fraudulent display, that he or she is entitled to wear military awards, military decorations, or military rank; </section><section prefix="b">A claim that he or she served in the United States Armed Forces, a Reserve Component thereof, or the National Guard; or </section><section prefix="c">A claim that he or she served in the military during a wartime era, whether or not there was a declared war, or served in a combat zone, or makes any misrepresentation of actual military service. </section></section><section prefix="2">This section shall not apply to a person who or an organization which: <section prefix="a">Is reenacting military history or a military event; </section><section prefix="b">Is playing the part of a member of the Armed Forces of the United States, a Reserve Component thereof, or the National Guard in a play, motion picture television production, or other dramatic production, or at a patriotic or civic event; </section><section prefix="c">Is a member of the Armed Forces of the United States, a Reserve Component thereof, or the National Guard and, as part of a military assignment, is representing a member of the Armed Forces in a previous war or time period for ceremonial, recruiting, or training purposes; </section><section prefix="d">Is an employee of or volunteer for a museum and, as a part of their duties, is representing a member of the Armed Forces of the United States, a Reserve Component thereof, or the National Guard for ceremonial, historical, or training purposes; </section><section prefix="e">Owns, displays, purchases, sells, or trades militaria, including but not limited to medals, ribbons, and rank insignia, and does not claim to have personally earned them unless he or she is legally entitled to do so; </section><section prefix="f">Is a natural person using his or her given name that includes a military rank, so long as he or she does not use the name to defraud another in a manner prohibited by this section; </section><section prefix="g">Uses a name or honorary military or military-like rank which has been bestowed upon him or her by a public officer, public employee, or public agency, in the name of a public officer or public agency; </section><section prefix="h">Uses a corporate, partnership, sole proprietorship, or other name for a business or product which includes a military rank, so long as the name is not used to defraud another in a manner prohibited by this section; or </section><section prefix="i">Holds a registered trademark which includes a military rank or honorary rank, so long as the trademark is not used to defraud another in a manner prohibited by this section. </section></section><section prefix="3">Misrepresenting current or former military status is: <section prefix="a">A violation of KRS 514.040 if the defendant, by the misrepresentation, obtains money or property; and </section><section prefix="b">If the defendant, by the misrepresentation, obtains a public benefit, a violation of the applicable statute that prohibits obtaining that public benefit and provides a specific penalty. </section></section><section prefix="4">If a violation of subsection (3) of this section is not involved, the defendant shall be fined an amount not to exceed five thousand dollars ($5,000) or be imprisoned in the county jail for not more than twelve (12) months, or both. </section><section prefix="5">KRS 431.100 to the contrary notwithstanding, any fine assessed as a penalty for conviction under this section shall be transferred by the circuit clerk and deposited with the veterans program trust fund established by KRS 40.460(2)(b). </section><section prefix="6">This section shall be cited as the Kentucky Stolen Valor Act. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 115, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 15, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2008).  In 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 15, sec. 1, under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(a) and (c), during codification renumbering and rearranging of parts of a section have occurred. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42401</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>