<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="197" order_by="197">PENITENTIARIES </unit></structure><section_number>197.150</section_number><catch_line>Prisoners or dependents to receive compensation for work outside prison -- Prisoners with dependents to have preference. </catch_line><order_by>150</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The administrative regulations made by the Department of Corrections shall provide some definite compensation to be paid to each prisoner or his dependents for each day he works outside of the prison. The department shall collect information concerning the number and requirements of the dependents of each prisoner, and those with families of greatest dependency shall be given preference in assignments to work outside of the prison, if the record, physical ability, and conduct of the prisoner warrants preference. </section><section prefix="2">The administrative regulations may provide that any infraction of the regulations or of the regulations governing the discipline of the prisoners, either while confined within the walls of the prison, or while engaged in employment outside the prison, shall work a forfeiture of the benefits authorized in this section, either in whole or in part, in the discretion of the department. Payments to the prisoners or their dependents as authorized by this section shall be made subject to the regulations, as other expenses of the department, but only out of the funds made available under the provisions of the particular contract under which the prisoners have been employed. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 54, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 344, sec. 28, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. V, sec. 24(14). -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 3828b-14. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6883</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>