<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIV" order_by="34">DESCENT, WILLS, AND ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="393" order_by="393">ESCHEATS </unit></structure><section_number>393.230</section_number><catch_line>Proceeding to force payment or surrender of intangible property -- To establish actual abandonment. </catch_line><order_by>230</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If any person or the agent of any court refuses to pay or surrender intangible property to the department as provided in KRS 393.060 to 393.110, an equitable proceeding may be brought on the relation of the State Treasurer to force payment or surrender. All property subject to KRS 393.060 to 393.110 may be listed and included in a single action. </section><section prefix="2">If any intangible property is turned over to the department on presumption of abandonment, in accordance with KRS 393.060 to 393.120, the State Treasurer may at any subsequent time institute proceedings to establish conclusively that it was actually abandoned, or that the owner has died and there is no person entitled to it. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 58, sec  16, effective March 10, 1994; and ch. 276, sec. 16, effective July 15, 1994. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 1619. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/94).  This section was amended by 1994 Ky. Acts chs. 58 and 276. Where these Acts are not in conflict, they have been codified together. Where a conflict exists, Acts ch. 276, which was last enacted by the General Assembly, prevails under KRS 446.250. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36224</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>