<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="262" order_by="262">SOIL AND WATER CONSERVATION </unit></structure><section_number>262.100</section_number><catch_line>Petition for district. </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any twenty-five (25) owners of land lying within the limits of the territory proposed to be organized into a district, and within counties that maintain a full-time county agricultural extension agent, may file a petition with the commission asking that a soil conservation district be organized to function in the territory described in the petition. The petition shall set forth:  <section prefix="a">The proposed name of the district;  </section><section prefix="b">A statement that there is need, in the interest of the public health, safety and welfare, for a district to function in the territory described in the petition;  </section><section prefix="c">A description of the territory proposed to be organized as a district, which description need not be given by metes and bounds or by legal subdivisions, but shall be sufficient if generally accurate;  </section><section prefix="d">A request that the commission define the boundaries for the district; that a referendum be held within the defined territory on the question of the creation of a district in that territory; and that the commission determine that a district be created.  </section></section><section prefix="2">Where more than one petition is filed covering parts of the same territory, the commission may consolidate all or any of those petitions. </section></text><history>Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 42i-5. </history><metadata><effective>October 1, 1942</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12719</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>