<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIII" order_by="33">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS AND ESTATES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>386A.3-040</section_number><catch_line>Statutory trust's liability.   </catch_line><order_by>3-040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A debt, obligation, or other liability of a statutory trust is solely a debt, obligation, or other liability of the trust. </section><section prefix="2">A debt, obligation, or other liability incurred by or otherwise existing with respect to the property of or associated with a particular series of a statutory trust is solely a debt, obligation, or liability of the particular series for which there is recourse against only the property of or associated with the particular series. </section><section prefix="3">A person is not personally liable, directly or indirectly, by way of indemnification, contribution, assessment, or otherwise, for a debt, obligation, or other liability of the statutory trust solely by reason of being or acting as a trustee, beneficial owner, agent of the trust, or agent of the trustee. </section><section prefix="4">A person is not personally liable, directly or indirectly, by way of indemnification, contribution, assessment, or otherwise, for a debt, obligation, or other liability of a series or against the property of or associated with a series of a statutory trust by reason of being associated with a series as a beneficial owner, trustee, agent of the series, or agent of the trustee. </section><section prefix="5">The property of a statutory trust not associated with a series is subject to attachment and execution to satisfy a debt, obligation, or other liability of the trust. The property of a statutory trust associated with a series is subject to attachment and execution to satisfy a debt, obligation, or other liability incurred by or with respect to the property associated with that series. The property of a series is subject to attachment and execution to satisfy a debt, obligation, or other liability incurred by or with respect to the property associated with that series. </section><section prefix="6">Subsections (3) and (4) of this section shall not affect the liability of any person for his or her own negligence, wrongful acts, or misconduct. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 19, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:37</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40361</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>