<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="214" order_by="214">DISEASES </unit></structure><section_number>214.556</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Cancer Registry -- Cancer patient data management system.   </catch_line><order_by>556</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby established within the Kentucky cancer program the Kentucky Cancer Registry and the cancer patient data management system for the purpose of providing accurate and up-to-date information about cancer in Kentucky and facilitating the evaluation and improvement of cancer prevention, screening, diagnosis, therapy, rehabilitation, and community care activities for citizens of the Commonwealth. The cancer patient data management system shall be administered by the Lucille Parker Markey Cancer Center. </section><section prefix="2">Each licensed health facility which provides diagnostic services, or diagnostic services and treatment, or treatment to cancer patients shall report to the Kentucky Cancer Registry, through the cancer patient data management system and in a format prescribed by the Kentucky Cancer Registry, each case of cancer seen at that health facility. Failure to comply may be cause for assessment of an administrative fine for the health facility, the same as for violation of KRS 216B.250. </section><section prefix="3">Each health facility shall grant to the cancer registry access to all records which would identify cases of cancer or would establish characteristics of the cancer, treatment of the cancer, or status of any identified cancer patient. Hospitals actively participating and enrolled in the cancer patient data management system of the Kentucky Cancer Program as of July 13, 1990, shall be considered to be in compliance with this section. The Lucille Parker Markey Cancer Center shall provide staff assistance in compiling and reporting required information to hospitals which treat a low volume of patients. </section><section prefix="4">No liability of any kind or character for damages or other relief shall arise or be enforced against any licensed health facility by reason of having provided the information or material to the Kentucky Cancer Registry pursuant to the requirements of this section. </section><section prefix="5">The identity of any person whose condition or treatment has been reported to the Kentucky Cancer Registry shall be confidential, except that: <section prefix="a">The Kentucky Cancer Registry may exchange patient-specific data with any other cancer control agency or clinical facility for the purpose of obtaining information necessary to complete a case record, but the agency or clinical facility shall not further disclose such personal data; and </section><section prefix="b">The Kentucky Cancer Registry may contact individual patients if necessary to obtain follow-up information which is not available from the health facility. </section></section><section prefix="6">All information, interviews, reports, statements, memoranda, or other data furnished by reason of this section, expressly including all portions, subsets, extracts, or compilations of the data as well as any findings or conclusions resulting from those studies, shall be privileged and shall not be considered public records under KRS 61.870 to 61.884. The Kentucky Cancer Registry may determine that certain extracts, subsets, or compilations of data do not reveal privileged information and may be published or otherwise shared to further the public health goals set forth herein. </section><section prefix="7">The Kentucky Cancer Registry shall make periodic reports of its data and any related findings and recommendations to the Legislative Research Commission, the Interim Joint Committees on Appropriations and Revenue and on Health and Welfare, the Governor, the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, the reporting health facility, and other appropriate governmental and nongovernmental cancer control agencies whose intent it is to reduce the incidence, morbidity, and mortality of cancer. The Kentucky Cancer Registry may conduct analyses and studies as are indicated to advance cancer control in the Commonwealth, either directly or by confidentially sharing data with third parties. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 127, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 463, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 410, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 184, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 5, effective July 1, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40580</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>