<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="275" order_by="275">LIMITED LIABILITY COMPANIES </unit></structure><section_number>275.535</section_number><catch_line>Procedure in liquidation of nonprofit limited liability company by court. </catch_line><order_by>535</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In proceedings to liquidate the assets and affairs of a nonprofit limited liability company, the court shall have the power to issue injunctions and to appoint a receiver or receivers while the action is pending. The receivers shall have those powers and duties as the court from time to time may direct, to take action to preserve the corporate assets wherever situated, and to carry on the affairs of the nonprofit limited liability company until a full hearing can be held. </section><section prefix="2">After holding a hearing, upon notice as the court may direct to be given to all parties to the proceedings and to any other parties in interest designated by the court, the court may appoint a liquidating receiver or receivers with authority to collect the assets of the nonprofit limited liability company. The liquidating receiver or receivers shall have authority, subject to the order of the court, to sell, convey, and dispose of all or any part of the assets of the nonprofit limited liability company wherever situated, either at public or private sale. The order appointing the liquidating receiver or receivers shall state their powers and duties. The powers and duties may be increased or diminished at any time during the proceedings. </section><section prefix="3">The assets of the nonprofit limited liability company or the proceeds resulting from a sale, conveyance, or other disposition thereof shall be applied and distributed as follows: <section prefix="a">All costs and expenses of the court proceedings and all liabilities and obligations of the nonprofit limited liability company shall be paid, satisfied, and discharged, or adequate provision for them shall be made; </section><section prefix="b">Assets held by the nonprofit limited liability company upon condition requiring return, transfer, or conveyance, which condition occurs by reason of the dissolution or liquidation, shall be returned, transferred, or conveyed in accordance with the condition's requirements; </section><section prefix="c">Assets received and held by the nonprofit limited liability company subject to limitations permitting their use only for a nonprofit purpose, but not held upon a condition requiring return, transfer, or conveyance by reason of the dissolution or liquidation, shall be transferred or conveyed to one (1) or more domestic or foreign nonprofit limited liability companies, societies, or organizations engaged in activities substantially similar to those of the dissolving or liquidating nonprofit limited liability company, as the court may direct; and </section><section prefix="d">Any remaining assets may be distributed to those persons, societies, organizations, or domestic or foreign limited liability companies, whether for profit or nonprofit, specified in the plan of distribution adopted or, if no plan of distribution has been adopted, as the court may direct. </section></section><section prefix="4">The court shall have power to allow, from time to time, as expenses of the liquidation, compensation to the receiver or receivers and to attorneys in the proceeding, and to direct the payment thereof out of the assets of the nonprofit limited liability company or the proceeds of any sale or disposition of the assets. </section><section prefix="5">A receiver of a nonprofit limited liability company appointed under the provisions of this section shall have authority to sue and defend in all courts in the receiver’s own name as receiver of the nonprofit limited liability company. The court appointing the receiver shall have exclusive jurisdiction of the nonprofit limited liability company and its property, wherever situated. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 12, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 12, effective June 26, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 183, provides, "The specific textual provisions of Sections 1 to 178 of this Act which reflect amendments made to those sections by 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137 shall be deemed effective as of June 26, 2007, and those provisions are hereby made expressly retroactive to that date, with the remainder of the text of those sections being unaffected by the provisions of this section." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13933</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>