<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.39-170</section_number><catch_line>Assigned claims bureau and plan. </catch_line><order_by>39-170</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Reparation obligors providing basic reparation insurance in this Commonwealth may organize and maintain, subject to approval and regulation by the commissioner of insurance, an assigned claims bureau and an assigned claims plan and adopt rules for their operation and for assessment of costs on a fair and equitable basis consistent with this subtitle. If they do not organize and continuously maintain an assigned claims bureau and an assigned claims plan in a manner considered by the commissioner of insurance to be consistent with this subtitle, the commissioner shall organize and maintain an assigned claims bureau and an assigned claims plan. Each reparation obligor providing basic reparation insurance in this Commonwealth shall participate in the assigned claims bureau and the assigned claims plan. Costs incurred shall be allocated fairly and equitably among the reparation obligors. </section><section prefix="2">The assigned claims bureau shall promptly assign each claim and notify the claimant of the identity and address of the assignee of the claim. Claims shall be assigned so as to minimize inconvenience to claimants. The assignee thereafter has rights and obligations as if he or she had issued a policy of basic reparation insurance complying with this subtitle applicable to the injury or, in case of financial inability of a reparation obligor to perform its obligations, as if the assignee had written the applicable basic reparation insurance, undertaken the self-insurance, or lawfully obligated itself to pay reparation benefits. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1530, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 385, sec. 17, effective July 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30046</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>