<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">A EMERGENCY MEDICAL SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>311A.060</section_number><catch_line>Sanctions for violations -- Disciplinary actions -- Criminal charges. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If it is determined that an entity regulated by the board, a paramedic, first responder, or emergency medical technician has violated a statute, administrative regulation, protocol, or practice standard relating to serving as an entity regulated by the board, a paramedic, first responder, or emergency medical technician, the office of the board may impose any of the sanctions provided in subsection (2) of this section. Any party to the complaint shall have the right to propose findings of fact and conclusions of law, and to recommend sanctions. </section><section prefix="2">The office of the board shall require an acceptable plan of correction and may use any one (1) or more of the following sanctions when disciplining a paramedic, emergency medical technician first responder, emergency medical technician, or any entity regulated by the board: <section prefix="a">Private reprimand that shall be shared with each of the paramedic's, first responder's, or emergency medical technician's emergency medical services or related employer and medical director; </section><section prefix="b">Public reprimand; </section><section prefix="c">Fines of fifty dollars ($50) to five hundred dollars ($500) for a natural person or fifty dollars ($50) to five thousand dollars ($5,000) for a public agency or business entity; </section><section prefix="d">Revocation of certification or licensure; </section><section prefix="e">Suspension of licensure until a time certain; </section><section prefix="f">Suspension until a certain act or acts are performed; </section><section prefix="g">Limitation of practice permanently; </section><section prefix="h">Limitation of practice until a time certain; </section><section prefix="i">Limitation of practice until a certain act or acts are performed; </section><section prefix="j">Repassing a portion of the paramedic, first responder, or emergency medical technician examination; </section><section prefix="k">Probation for a specified time; or </section><section prefix="l">If it is found that the person who is licensed or certified by the board has been convicted of, pled guilty to, entered an Alford plea to a felony offense, or has completed a diversion program for a felony offense the license or certification shall be revoked. </section></section><section prefix="3">The filing of criminal charges or a criminal conviction for violation of the provisions of this chapter or the administrative regulations promulgated thereunder shall not preclude the office of the board from instituting or imposing board disciplinary action authorized by this chapter against any person or organization violating this chapter or the administrative regulations promulgated thereunder. </section><section prefix="4">The institution or imposition of disciplinary action by the office of the board against any person or organization violating the provisions of this chapter or the administrative regulations promulgated thereunder shall not preclude the filing of criminal charges against or a criminal conviction of any person or organization for violation of the provisions of this chapter or the administrative regulations promulgated thereunder. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 243, sec. 5, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 11, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30728</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>