<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.862</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 211.861 to 211.869. </catch_line><order_by>862</order_by><text>As used in KRS 211.861 to 211.869, unless the compact requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Commission" means the Central Midwest Interstate Low-Level Radioactive Waste Commission; </section><section prefix="2">"Cabinet" means the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="3">"Compact" means the Central Midwest Interstate Low-Level Radioactive Waste Compact; </section><section prefix="4">"Disposal" means the isolation of waste from the biosphere in a permanent facility designed for that purpose; </section><section prefix="5">"Facility" means a parcel of land or site, together with the structures, equipment, and improvements on, or appurtenant to, the land or site, that is used or is being developed for the treatment, storage, or disposal of low-level radioactive waste; </section><section prefix="6">"Low-level radioactive waste" or "waste" means radioactive waste not classified as high-level radioactive waste, transuranic waste, spent nuclear fuel, or by-product material as defined in Section 11e(2) of the Federal Atomic Energy Act. This definition shall apply regardless of any declaration by the federal government or any state that any radioactive material is exempt from any regulatory control; </section><section prefix="7">"Management plan" means the plan adopted by the commission for the storage, transportation, treatment, and disposal of waste within the region; </section><section prefix="8">"Naturally-occurring radioactive material" (NORM) means naturally occurring materials not regulated under the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, as amended, whose radionuclide concentrations have been increased by or as a result of human practices. Naturally occurring radioactive material does not include the natural radioactivity of rocks or soils, or background radiation, but instead refers to materials whose radioactivity is technologically enhanced by controllable practices (or by past human practices); </section><section prefix="9">"Person" means any individual, corporation, business enterprise, or other legal entity, public or private, and any legal successor, representative, agent or agency of that individual, corporation, business enterprise, or legal entity; </section><section prefix="10">"Region" means the geographical area of the state of Illinois and the Commonwealth of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="11">"Regional facility" means any facility as defined in this section that is located in Kentucky, and established by Kentucky pursuant to designation of Kentucky as a host state by the commission; </section><section prefix="12">"Storage" means the temporary holding of radioactive material for treatment or disposal; and </section><section prefix="13">"Treatment" means any method, technique, or process, including storage for radioactive decay, designed to change the physical, chemical, or biological characteristics of the radioactive material in order to render the radioactive material safe for transport or management, amenable to recovery, convertible to another usable material, or reduced in volume. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 385, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 46, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8501</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>