<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="216" order_by="216">B LICENSURE AND REGULATION OF HEALTH FACILITIES AND SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>216B.176</section_number><catch_line>School-located health care or dental care programs provided by not-for-profit primary care centers at public school or Head Start program. </catch_line><order_by>176</order_by><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a not-for-profit primary care center licensed under KRS Chapter 216, which provides health care services to Kentucky Medicaid members pursuant to a contract between a Medicaid managed care organization and the Department for Medicaid Services, may enter into a written agreement with a board of education or a Head Start program to provide a school-located health care program or school-located dental care program on Head Start or board of education property. The agreement shall include the following provisions: <section prefix="1">The services shall include: <section prefix="a">For school-located health care services: <section prefix="1">Basic primary care; </section><section prefix="2">Episodic acute care; </section><section prefix="3">Care for chronic conditions; and </section><section prefix="4">Preventive health care for the pupils enrolled in the school; and </section></section><section prefix="b">For school-located dental care services, oral health and preventative care services using fixed dental operatories, portable equipment, or mobile units; </section></section><section prefix="2">The programs shall be located in or on the grounds of a public school or Head Start program; </section><section prefix="3">The programs shall operate as a satellite of a licensed primary care center under the supervision of the medical director of the primary care center and shall not be considered Head Start or public school programs; </section><section prefix="4">When in operation as a satellite of a primary care center: <section prefix="a">The program staff for a school-located health care program shall include a physician, physician assistant, or advanced practice registered nurse and may be staffed with additional health care professionals appropriate for the services being provided; and </section><section prefix="b">The program staff for a school-located dental care program shall include a dentist and may be staffed with additional health care professionals appropriate for the services being provided; and </section></section><section prefix="5">The programs may, under agreement with the school, participate in the school's health education program. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 68, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 40, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 127, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:37</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43283</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>