<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="439" order_by="439">PROBATION AND PAROLE </unit></structure><section_number>439.562</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Council for Interstate Adult Offender Supervision -- Membership -- Meetings – Reimbursement -- Administrative regulations.   </catch_line><order_by>562</order_by><text><section prefix="1">To oversee the intrastate affairs of the Interstate Compact for Adult Offender Supervision, the Kentucky Council for Interstate Adult Offender Supervision is created and attached to the Office of the Secretary of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet for administrative purposes. </section><section prefix="2">The membership of the council shall consist of: <section prefix="a">The commissioner of the Department of Corrections, ex officio; </section><section prefix="b">The compact administrator of the Department of Corrections, ex officio; </section><section prefix="c">The deputy commissioner of the Office of Community Services and Facilities, ex officio; </section><section prefix="d">One (1) member of the House of Representatives selected by the Speaker of the House of Representatives and appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="e">One (1) member of the Senate selected by the President of the Senate and appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="f">Two (2) members of the judiciary selected by the Chief Justice of the Kentucky Supreme Court and appointed by the Governor; and </section><section prefix="g">Six (6) at-large members, appointed by the Governor, representing victim groups and other community interest groups. </section></section><section prefix="3">Of the initial members, except those serving ex officio, three (3) members shall be appointed to serve terms of four (4) years, three (3) members shall be appointed to terms of three (3) years, three (3) members shall be appointed to terms of two (2) years, and one (1) member shall be appointed to a term of one (1) year. Thereafter, members shall be appointed to terms of four (4) years or until their successors have been duly appointed and qualified. Members may be reappointed and vacancies shall be immediately filled, in like manner, for the unexpired term. </section><section prefix="4">The Kentucky Council for Interstate Adult Offender Supervision shall meet at least annually, at the call of the chair, and shall: <section prefix="a">Advocate when seeking resources; </section><section prefix="b">Provide recommendations regarding operational improvements; </section><section prefix="c">Provide recommendations regarding dispute resolution; </section><section prefix="d">Provide recommendations regarding training needs; </section><section prefix="e">Provide recommendations regarding policy changes; and </section><section prefix="f">Serve as a support mechanism for the Kentucky Compact Office. </section></section><section prefix="5">The Governor shall designate one (1) member of the council as chairperson and one (1) member as vice chairperson, and a member so designated shall serve in that capacity at the pleasure of the Governor or until his or her term expires. </section><section prefix="6">Members of the council shall serve without compensation but shall be reimbursed for expenses actually and necessarily incurred in the performance of their duties, subject to Finance and Administration Cabinet administrative regulations. </section><section prefix="7">Except as otherwise provided in this section, the Department of Corrections may promulgate administrative regulations necessary to administer the Interstate Compact for Adult Offender Supervision. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 72, sec. 7, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 473, sec. 2, effective June 19, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><lrc-note> (6/19/2002).  Under 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 473, sec. 4, this section "takes effect the later of July 1, 2001, or upon enactment of the Interstate Compact for Adult Offender Supervision, in substantially the form set out in [KRS 439.561], by no less than thirty-five states, as that term is defined in [KRS 439.561]." On June 19, 2002, the thirty-fifth state enacted the compact, and this section took effect. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42290</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>