<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.6317</section_number><catch_line>Department for Medicaid Services to develop strategies for reimbursing and paying persons participating in the Supports for Community Living Waiver Program -- Allocation of slots -- Administrative regulations -- Funding.   </catch_line><order_by>6317</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Supports for Community Living Waiver Program" means funding from the Department for Medicaid Services to serve individuals with an intellectual disability or other developmental disabilities who qualify for intermediate care and choose to live in a community-based setting and includes funding for a self-determination model, as recommended by the Commission on Services and Supports for Individuals with an Intellectual Disability and Other Developmental Disabilities under KRS 210.577(2), that provides the ability for the individual receiving services and supports to personally control, with appropriate assistance, a targeted amount of dollars; and </section><section prefix="b">"Slots" means the dedication of provider or financial resources for services to persons with an intellectual disability or other developmental disabilities. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Department for Medicaid Services shall develop and implement flexible reimbursement and payment strategies that reflect the individually determined needs for services and supports by persons with an intellectual disability and other developmental disabilities participating in the Supports for Community Living Waiver Program. </section><section prefix="3">The Department for Medicaid Services shall allocate slots to the fourteen (14) community mental health regions based on percentage of total population. </section><section prefix="4">The Department for Medicaid Services shall reallocate underutilized slots to address statewide needs and shall reallocate slots in emergency situations to address unmet needs for services and supports. </section><section prefix="5">The Department for Medicaid Services shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to implement the requirements of this section. </section><section prefix="6">Funds for the Supports for Community Living Waiver Program shall be appropriated only for direct services to qualified individuals and any unexpended funds shall not lapse but shall be carried forward to the next fiscal year and shall be used for the same purpose. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 64, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 13, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 108, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 403, sec. 4, effective April 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40793</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>