<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="227" order_by="227">FIRE PREVENTION AND PROTECTION -- ELECTRICIANS </unit></structure><section_number>227.487</section_number><catch_line>Fees for electrical inspections. </catch_line><order_by>487</order_by><text>Except where other rules are adopted by a city or county, the following reporting and fee requirements shall apply to electrical inspections of residential buildings and single-family dwellings: <section prefix="1">The inspector shall complete a report for each inspection. One (1) copy of the report shall be given to the owner of the electrical installation or his representative at the time the inspection fees are paid. A second copy of the report shall be sent to the Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction no later than one (1) week after the inspection is completed. The report shall include, but is not limited to, the following: <section prefix="a">The address of the dwelling inspected; </section><section prefix="b">The number of rooms, number of receptacles and number of switch boxes inspected; </section><section prefix="c">Number of code violations, if any; </section><section prefix="d">A description of each code violation, and recommended change to correct the violation; </section><section prefix="e">The date and time of day the inspection commenced; </section><section prefix="f">The time, in hours and minutes, required for the inspection; </section><section prefix="g">The number of miles and hours and minutes of travel time incurred by the inspector for that inspection, if mileage and travel charges are added to the inspection fee; </section><section prefix="h">The amount charged for the inspection, separated into an amount for mileage, if any, and the amount for travel time, if any, and the amount charged for the actual inspection. </section></section><section prefix="2">The maximum inspection fee shall be an amount equal to the prevailing wage for a master electrician in the region in which the inspection is made, multiplied by the time required to conduct the inspection. This rate shall not be applied to travel time to and from the inspection. </section><section prefix="3">An inspector may charge, in addition to the inspection fee, an amount for necessary travel to and from the inspection site. The mileage rate charged shall not exceed the amount per mile allowed to state employees, and the inspector shall charge no more than ten dollars ($10) per hour for travel time. If two (2) or more inspections are made during one (1) trip, then the cost of travel shall be divided between the inspections made. In no case shall an inspector charge more than once for the same trip, or charge for mileage or time not actually expended. </section><section prefix="4">Each inspector shall furnish bond of five thousand dollars ($5,000) with surety satisfactory to the Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction. </section><section prefix="5">The Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction shall design reporting forms which meet the requirements of subsection (1) of this section, and provide these forms to electrical inspectors. The department shall adopt regulations to administer the requirements of this section. </section><section prefix="6">Nothing in this section is intended to limit the right of cities or counties to set fees or adopt rules for electrical inspections which are different from those specified in subsections (1), (2), (3) or (4) of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 405, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 218, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10668</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>