<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="176" order_by="176">DEPARTMENT OF HIGHWAYS </unit></structure><section_number>176.050</section_number><catch_line>Duties of department. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The department shall: <section prefix="a">Investigate all problems relating to the construction and maintenance of roads in the state; </section><section prefix="b">Examine all projects and ascertain the feasibility of all routes; </section><section prefix="c">Obtain information as to the proper type of road for any project; </section><section prefix="d">Examine all types of road materials which may be used in the construction or maintenance of any road to be constructed by the department or under its direction or supervision; </section><section prefix="e">Require the design plans for all road projects constructing a new route to identify, if at all feasible, one (1) or more publicly owned sites at least four (4) acres in size, along the proposed new route that will be used as waste sites during the construction phase of the project but that have the potential for a city, county, or other governmental entity to turn the site into an industrial park upon completion of the road project, regardless of whether the site currently has the infrastructure necessary to support an industrial park; </section><section prefix="f">Consult with all legislative bodies affected by a new road construction project during the design phase for the purpose of soliciting local government officials' preferences for the location of waste sites that could be turned into an industrial park; </section><section prefix="g">From time to time, examine and have examined and audited all of its books, papers and records; </section><section prefix="h">Cause to be made all necessary surveys in the establishment and construction of the system of public highways; all necessary maps, prints, plans and specifications of all work to be done on the roads; estimates of costs; advertisement for bids; contracts for construction or maintenance; and all necessary forms in connection therewith; and </section><section prefix="i">Promulgate administrative regulations under KRS Chapter 13A for the care and maintenance of roads after they have been constructed. </section></section><section prefix="2">The department may publish bulletins containing useful information concerning the construction and maintenance of roads. </section><section prefix="3">An invoice or bill to be paid out of the road or bridge funds shall not be approved by the department for payment until it has been carefully examined by the department to ascertain if the bill or invoice is in every respect a proper and legitimate charge against the road or bridge funds. The commissioner may call before him any person who may have information respecting any bill or invoice. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 181, sec. 1, effective March 27, 1998. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4356t-3e, 4356t-3f. </history><metadata><effective> March 27, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5161</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>