<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.9-495</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 304.9-495 to 304.9-497. </catch_line><order_by>9-495</order_by><text>For the purposes of KRS 304.9-495 to 304.9-497: <section prefix="1">"Limited lines self-service storage space insurance producer" means a: <section prefix="a">Licensed managing general agent, which has the same meaning as "managing general agent" in KRS 304.9-085(1); </section><section prefix="b">Licensed agent, which as the same meaning as "agent" in KRS 304.9-020; or </section><section prefix="c">Limited lines self-service storage space insurance agent licensed pursuant to KRS 304.9-230; </section> designated by the insurer as the self-service storage space insurance supervising entity; </section><section prefix="2">"Occupant" has the same meaning as in KRS 359.200; </section><section prefix="3">"Offering and disseminating" means providing general information relating to the self-service storage space insurance offered, including a description of the coverage and price, receiving applications and premiums, and performing other activities permitted by the department which do not require a license; </section><section prefix="4">"Operator" has the same meaning as in KRS 359.200; </section><section prefix="5">"Personal property" has the same meaning as in KRS 359.200; </section><section prefix="6">"Self-service storage facility" has the same meaning as in KRS 359.200; and </section><section prefix="7">"Self-service storage space insurance" means insurance that provides primary coverage to an occupant of a self-service storage facility space for the loss of or damage to tangible personal property that is contained in a self-service storage space, but does not include a homeowner's policy, renter's insurance policy, a private passenger motor vehicle insurance policy, or an insurance policy that provides coverage similar to the insurance provided by this subsection. </section></text><history> Created 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><lrc-note> (71/1514). In codification, the Reviser of Statutes has altered the numbering within this statute from the way it appeared in 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 2, under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(c). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:07</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43251</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>