<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="77" order_by="77">AIR POLLUTION CONTROL </unit></structure><section_number>77.135</section_number><catch_line>Budget -- Contingent fund -- Compliance with KRS 65A.010 to 65A.090.   </catch_line><order_by>135</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It shall be the duty of the secretary-treasurer of an air pollution control board formed pursuant to KRS 77.070, during or before the month of May of each year, to prepare and certify to the consolidated local government or fiscal court of the county and to the legislative body of the city, for their joint consideration, a preliminary budget showing the total funds which, in the judgment of the air pollution control board, will be needed for the various departments of the district, together with a statement showing the estimated balances, if any, which will be available on July 1 for expenditure during the next fiscal year following the certification of said statement, and also indicating, as nearly as may be possible, what additional funds or assets (other than appropriations) will be or will become available for expenditure during that year. The board shall also furnish to the consolidated local government or the fiscal court and the city legislative body any other information or data available to it which the consolidated local government, the fiscal court, or the city legislative body may request. </section><section prefix="2">Prior to the first day of each fiscal year, every air pollution control board shall prepare, for its own use and guidance, a financial budget setting forth the total amounts of funds available from all sources for expenditures during the said fiscal year, and also setting forth in detail the estimated expenditures of the board and the district during said fiscal year. </section><section prefix="3">A contingent fund for unanticipated expenditures may be established in order to provide for such contingent and unanticipated needs as may arise during the district's said fiscal year. </section><section prefix="4">All air pollution control boards shall comply with the provisions of KRS 65A.010 to 65A.090. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 74, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 32, effective March 21, 2013. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 83, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 53, secs. 29 and 30, effective March 14, 1952. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43659</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>