<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>362.1-905</section_number><catch_line>Merger of partnerships.   </catch_line><order_by>1-905</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Pursuant to a plan of merger approved as provided in subsection (3) of this section, a partnership may be merged with one (1) or more partnerships or limited partnerships. </section><section prefix="2">The plan of merger shall set forth: <section prefix="a">The name of each partnership or limited partnership that is a party to the merger; </section><section prefix="b">The name of the surviving entity into which the other partnerships or limited partnerships will merge; </section><section prefix="c">Whether the surviving entity is a partnership or a limited partnership and the status of each partner; </section><section prefix="d">The terms and conditions of the merger; </section><section prefix="e">The manner and basis of converting the interests of each party to the merger into interests or obligations of the surviving entity, or into money or other property in whole or part; and </section><section prefix="f">The street address of the surviving entity's chief executive office. </section></section><section prefix="3">The plan of merger shall be approved: <section prefix="a">In the case of a partnership that is a party to the merger, by all of the partners, or a number or percentage specified for merger in the partnership agreement; and </section><section prefix="b">In the case of a limited partnership that is a party to the merger, by the vote required for approval of a merger by the law of the state or foreign jurisdiction in which the limited partnership is organized and, in the absence of such a specifically applicable law, by all of the partners, notwithstanding a provision to the contrary in the partnership agreement. </section></section><section prefix="4">After a plan of merger is approved and before the merger takes effect, the plan may be amended or abandoned as provided in the plan. </section><section prefix="5">The merger takes effect on the later of: <section prefix="a">The approval of the plan of merger by all parties to the merger, as provided in subsection (3) of this section; </section><section prefix="b">The filing of all documents required by law to be filed as a condition to the effectiveness of the merger; or </section><section prefix="c">Subject to KRS 14A.2-070, any effective date specified in the plan of merger. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 127, effective January 1, 2011. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 65, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36787</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>