<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="315" order_by="315">PHARMACISTS AND PHARMACIES </unit></structure><section_number>315.335</section_number><catch_line>Reporting of robbery, theft, or missing shipment of controlled substances. </catch_line><order_by>335</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A pharmacy located in Kentucky which has a robbery or theft of a controlled substance shall immediately following the robbery or discovery of the theft report the incident to a law enforcement agency serving the geographic area in which the pharmacy is located. </section><section prefix="2">A pharmacy which has mailed or shipped a controlled substance to a location in Kentucky and learns that the mailing or shipment did not arrive shall within three </section><section prefix="3">business days report that nonreceipt to: <section prefix="a">The Department of Kentucky State Police; and </section><section prefix="b">If applicable, the United States Postal Inspection Service. <section prefix="1">The name, National Drug Code, and quantity of each controlled </section><section prefix="2">A description of the circumstances of the loss; </section><section prefix="3">The names and contact information of any witnesses; and </section><section prefix="4">The name and description of any person suspected of committing the </section></section></section>(3) (a) The reports required pursuant to subsections (1) and (2) of this section shall contain at a minimum, if known and applicable: substance involved; offense or causing the loss. (b) The Board of Pharmacy may by administrative regulation authorize a pharmacy to submit a completed DEA 106 form or a successor form in lieu of the data elements required by this subsection. </text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 5, effective March 4, 2013. -- Created 2012 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 11, effective July 20, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> March 4, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41653</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>