<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="640" order_by="640">YOUTHFUL OFFENDERS </unit></structure><section_number>640.100</section_number><catch_line>Access of Parole Board to youthful offender and reports. </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text>All officials of the Department of Juvenile Justice and the Department of Corrections shall furnish members of the Parole Board or its properly accredited representatives: <section prefix="1">Access at all reasonable times to any youthful offender over whom the board has jurisdiction under this chapter; </section><section prefix="2">Facilities for communicating with and observing the youthful offender; </section><section prefix="3">The reports the board requires concerning the conduct and character of any youthful offender in its custody; and </section><section prefix="4">Any other facts deemed pertinent by the board in determining whether the youthful offender shall be paroled. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 626, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 443, sec. 25, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 145, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 108, effective April 10, 1988. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 423, sec. 143, effective July 1, 1987. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/98).  This statute has been amended by 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 443 (making a substantive nonrevisory change) and ch. 426 (which made a name change due to reorganization and is revisory in nature). The nonrevisory change prevails. KRS 7.136(3). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20319</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>