<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="605" order_by="605">ADMINISTRATIVE MATTERS </unit></structure><section_number>605.080</section_number><catch_line>Transportation of children.</catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any child ordered to be transported, by a committing or sentencing court, shall be transported by the sheriff or the jailer of that county. Any other law enforcement agency may enter into agreements with the court, sheriff, or jailer to transport juveniles. </section><section prefix="2">Any peace officer who conveys a child from the committing court or from the detention facility of the committing court to a residential treatment facility or other facility operated by the Department of Juvenile Justice or the cabinet shall be allowed an amount prescribed by regulation adopted by the Finance and Administration Cabinet calculated by the nearest traveled route, and shall be paid for all necessary expenses for feeding, lodging, and transporting the child. The officer shall make out a full account of all expenses so incurred by him and give the distance traveled. The account shall be verified by the officer upon oath before the District Court and certified by the circuit clerk to the Department of Juvenile Justice or the cabinet, as appropriate, for payment out of funds appropriated to the Department of Juvenile Justice or the cabinet for this purpose. The child's presence shall be necessary at a postdispositional proceeding only as required by court order for good cause. Transportation shall be provided as in subsection (1) of this section and expenses for transportation of a child to a proceeding from a residential treatment facility or other facility operated by the Department of Juvenile Justice or the cabinet shall be paid out of the State Treasury. </section><section prefix="3">No child shall be transported to any residential treatment facility or other facility, pursuant to order of any court, unless accompanied by an attendant of the same gender, unless that child, when authorized in writing by the court, the Department of Juvenile Justice, or the cabinet, is transported by a parent, grandparent, or adult brother or sister. </section><section prefix="4">The agent of any residential treatment facility or other facility which receives a child transported to the facility shall report any violation of subsection (3) of this section to the Commonwealth's attorney of the judicial circuit in which the facility is located. </section><section prefix="5">The Department of Juvenile Justice or the cabinet may transport or pay the necessary traveling expenses of children committed to it for care and treatment from their homes to the residential treatment facility or other facility or home to which they are committed, and the traveling expenses of such children from the facility or home to their homes when discharged or placed on supervised placement. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 257, sec. 8, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 534, sec. 7, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 272, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 358, sec. 13, effective July 1, 1997. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 6, effective April 10, 1988. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 423, sec. 11, effective July 1, 1987. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20115</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>