<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="337" order_by="337">WAGES AND HOURS </unit></structure><section_number>337.510</section_number><catch_line>Public authority's duties as to inclusion of prevailing wage in proposals and contracts. </catch_line><order_by>510</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Before advertising for bids or entering into any contract for construction of public works, every public authority shall notify the department in writing of the specific public work to be constructed, and shall ascertain from the department the prevailing rates of wages for each classification of laborers, workmen, and mechanics for the class of work called for in the construction of such public works in the locality where the work is to be performed. This schedule of the prevailing rate of wages shall include a statement that it has been determined in accordance with the provisions of KRS 337.505 to 337.550 and shall be attached to and made part of the specifications for the work and shall be printed on the bidding blanks and made a part of every contract for the construction of public works. </section><section prefix="2">The public authority advertising and awarding the contract shall cause to be inserted in the proposal and contract a stipulation to the effect that not less than the prevailing hourly rate of wages as determined by the commissioner shall be paid to all laborers, workmen, and mechanics performing work under the contract. It shall also require in all the contractor's bonds that the contractor include such provisions as will guarantee the faithful performance of the prevailing hourly wage clause as provided by contract. It shall be the duty of the public authority awarding the contract, and its agents and officers, to take cognizance of all complaints of all violations of the provisions of KRS 337.505 to 337.550 committed in the course of the execution of the contract, and when making payments to the contractor becoming due under the contract, to withhold, and retain therefrom all sums and amounts due and owing as a result of any violation thereof. It shall be lawful for any contractor to withhold from any subcontractor under him sufficient sums to cover any penalties withheld from him by the awarding authority, on account of the subcontractor's failure to comply with the terms thereof and if payment has already been made to him or her, the contractor may recover from him or her the amount of the penalty in a suit at law. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1741, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 341, sec. 3. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 33, sec. 3. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 56, sec. 1, effective June 16, 1960. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2290c-2. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32096</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>