<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="212" order_by="212">LOCAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>212.600</section_number><catch_line>Board to control health in all cities in county containing city of first class or consolidated local government. </catch_line><order_by>600</order_by><text>All municipalities in any county of this Commonwealth in which county there is located a city of the first class or a consolidated local government are hereby made subject to the provisions of KRS 212.350 to 212.620, and it shall be the duty of the board created in KRS 212.350 to make and enforce all reasonable regulations controlling or affecting the health of citizens and residents of said county, including all municipalities therein, in conformity with the provisions of KRS 212.350 to 212.620 and the laws of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, the rules and regulations of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services of Kentucky, and the ordinances of said municipalities now or hereafter in effect and not in conflict with the provisions of KRS 212.350 to 212.620. Such regulations shall, as nearly as may be practicable, be uniform throughout the county, both within and without the said municipalities; provided, however, that nothing contained in this section shall be construed to prevent the board from making specific health regulations applying only to such section or sections of said county as may be deemed to require special treatment. The board shall have power and authority to examine into all nuisances, sources of filth, and causes or probable causes of sickness, which may in its opinion be injurious to the health of the residents of such county or of any section or sections thereof. </text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 413, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 208, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 364, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(3). -- Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 41, sec. 20. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8643</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>