<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="309" order_by="309">MISCELLANEOUS OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS </unit></structure><section_number>309.302</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Board of Interpreters for the Deaf and Hard of Hearing. </catch_line><order_by>302</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created a board to be known as the "Kentucky Board of Interpreters for the Deaf and Hard of Hearing." </section><section prefix="2">The board shall consist of seven (7) members appointed by the Governor as follows: <section prefix="a">Five (5) practicing interpreters who hold current nationally recognized certification and have at least five (5) years interpreting experience; </section><section prefix="b">One (1) deaf interpreter with past or current nationally recognized certification; and </section><section prefix="c">One (1) consumer with knowledge about interpreter issues. </section></section><section prefix="3">After the initial term of each appointment, all members shall be appointed for a term of four (4) years. </section><section prefix="4">Board members shall not be allowed to succeed themselves but a former member may be reappointed to the board if that member has not served in the preceding four (4) years. </section><section prefix="5">The members of the board shall receive no compensation for their services on the board, but they shall be reimbursed for actual and necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their official duties. </section><section prefix="6">The board shall annually elect a chairman, a vice chairman, and a secretary-treasurer from the members of the board. </section><section prefix="7">The board shall hold at least one (1) meeting annually and additional meetings as the board may deem necessary. The additional meetings may be held upon call of the chairman or upon written request of a quorum. Four (4) members of the board shall constitute a quorum to conduct business. </section><section prefix="8">Upon recommendation of the board, the Governor may remove any member of the board for neglect of duty or malfeasance in office. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30352</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>