<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXVII" order_by="37">SPECIAL PROCEEDINGS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="417" order_by="417">ARBITRATION AND AWARD </unit></structure><section_number>417.160</section_number><catch_line>Vacating an award. </catch_line><order_by>160</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon application of a party, the court shall vacate an award where:  <section prefix="a">The award was procured by corruption, fraud or other undue means;  </section><section prefix="b">There was evident partiality by an arbitrator appointed as a neutral or corruption in any of the arbitrators or misconduct prejudicing the rights of any party;  </section><section prefix="c">The arbitrators exceeded their powers;  </section><section prefix="d">The arbitrators refused to postpone the hearing upon sufficient cause being shown therefor or refused to hear evidence material to the controversy or otherwise so conducted the hearing, contrary to the provisions of KRS 417.090, as to prejudice substantially the rights of a party; or  </section><section prefix="e">There was no arbitration agreement and the issue was not adversely determined in proceedings under KRS 417.060 and the party did not participate in the arbitration hearing without raising the objection; but the fact that the relief was such that it could not or would not be granted by a court is not ground for vacating or refusing to confirm the award.  </section></section><section prefix="2">An application under this section shall be made within ninety (90) days after delivery of a copy of the award to the applicant; except that, if predicated upon corruption, fraud or other undue means, it shall be made within ninety (90) days after such grounds are known or should have been known.  </section><section prefix="3">In vacating the award on grounds other than stated in paragraph (a) of subsection (1) of this section, the court may order a rehearing before new arbitrators chosen as provided in the agreement, or in the absence thereof, by the court in accordance with KRS 417.070; or, if the award is vacated on grounds set forth in paragraphs (c) and (d) of subsection (1) of this section, the court may order a rehearing before the arbitrators who made the award or their successors appointed in accordance with KRS 417.070.  The time within which the agreement requires the award to be made is applicable to the rehearing and commences on the date of the order.  </section><section prefix="4">If the application to vacate is denied and no motion to modify or correct the award is pending, the court shall confirm the award.  </section></text><history>Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 278, sec. 12, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=18001</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>