<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="108" order_by="108">URBAN SERVICES DISTRICTS -- AMBULANCE SERVICE DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>108.140</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of directors. </catch_line><order_by>140</order_by><text>The board of directors shall provide ambulance service to inhabitants of the district and shall have the authority to: <section prefix="1">Purchase ambulance vehicles and all other necessary equipment and employ trained personnel which meet all federal and state requirements; </section><section prefix="2">Establish a civil service system for employees of the district in accordance with the plan outlined for cities of the first class under KRS 90.110 to 90.230; </section><section prefix="3">Adopt rules and regulations necessary to effectively and efficiently provide emergency ambulance service for the district; </section><section prefix="4">Employ person(s) to administer the daily operations of the emergency ambulance service; </section><section prefix="5">Compensate employees of the district at a rate determined by the board; </section><section prefix="6">Apply for and receive available funds from the state and federal government for the purpose of maintaining or improving the emergency ambulance service of the district; </section><section prefix="7">Acquire by bequest, gift, grant or purchase such real or personal property necessary to provide emergency ambulance service; </section><section prefix="8">In addition to the special ad valorem tax, establish an equitable system of service charges to be collected from persons receiving emergency ambulance service from the district. The rate of the service charge shall be fixed in such amounts as can be reasonably expected to yield revenues not in excess of the cost of operation and maintenance of the system and for an adequate depreciation fund; </section><section prefix="9">Contract with private persons, partnerships, or corporations for providing ambulance service to residents of the district as long as these services utilize vehicles, equipment and personnel which conform to all requirements of KRS 108.080 to 108.180. </section></text><history>Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 33, sec. 7. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27225</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>