<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="200" order_by="200">ASSISTANCE TO CHILDREN </unit></structure><section_number>200.658</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Early Intervention System Interagency Coordinating Council -- Membership -- Duties -- Annual report -- Conflict of interest to bar voting.   </catch_line><order_by>658</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created the Kentucky Early Intervention System Interagency Coordinating Council to be comprised of twenty-five (25) members to be appointed by the Governor to serve a term of three (3) years. The members of the council shall be geographically and culturally representative of the population of the Commonwealth and conform to the requirements of federal law and regulations. For administrative purposes, the council shall be attached to the Early Childhood Advisory Council. Pursuant to federal law and regulations, the membership shall be as follows: <section prefix="a">At least five (5) members shall be the parents, including minority parents, of a child with a disability who is twelve (12) years of age or less, with at least one (1) being the parent of a child six (6) years of age or less. Each parent shall have knowledge of or experience with programs for infants and toddlers with disabilities; </section><section prefix="b">At least five (5) members shall be public or private providers of early intervention services to infants and toddlers with disabilities; </section><section prefix="c">At least one (1) member shall be a member of the Kentucky General Assembly; </section><section prefix="d">At least one (1) member shall be representative of an entity responsible for personnel preparation and may include personnel from an institution of higher education or preservice training organization; </section><section prefix="e">At least one (1) member shall be the commissioner or individual serving in a position of equivalent authority, or the designee, from the Department for Public Health; </section><section prefix="f">At least one (1) member shall be the commissioner or individual serving in a position of equivalent authority, or the designee, from the Department for Medicaid Services; </section><section prefix="g">At least one (1) member shall be the commissioner or individual serving in a position of equivalent authority, or the designee, from the Department for Behavioral Health, Developmental and Intellectual Disabilities; </section><section prefix="h">At least one (1) member shall be the commissioner or individual serving in a position of equivalent authority, or the designee, from the Department for Community Based Services; </section><section prefix="i">At least one (1) member shall be the commissioner or designee of the Department of Education; </section><section prefix="j">At least one (1) member shall be the commissioner or designee of the Department of Insurance; </section><section prefix="k">At least one (1) member shall be a representative of the Commission for Children with Special Health Care Needs; </section><section prefix="l">At least one (1) member shall be a representative for the Head Start program; and </section><section prefix="m">At least one (1) member shall be a representative of the Education of Homeless Children and Youth program. </section></section><section prefix="2">In matters concerning the Kentucky Early Intervention System, the council shall advise and assist the cabinet in areas, including but not limited to the following: <section prefix="a">Development and implementation of the statewide system and the administrative regulations promulgated pursuant to KRS 200.650 to 200.676; </section><section prefix="b">Achieving the full participation, coordination, and cooperation of all appropriate entities in the state, including, but not limited to, individuals, departments, and agencies, through the promotion of interagency agreements; </section><section prefix="c">Establishing a process to seek information from service providers, service coordinators, parents, and others concerning the identification of service delivery problems and the resolution of those problems; </section><section prefix="d">Resolution of disputes, to the extent deemed appropriate by the cabinet; </section><section prefix="e">Provision of appropriate services for children from birth to three (3) years of age; </section><section prefix="f">Identifying sources of fiscal and other support services for early intervention programs; </section><section prefix="g">Preparing applications to Part C of the Federal Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (IDEA) and any amendments to the applications; </section><section prefix="h">Transitioning of infants and toddlers with disabilities and their families from the early intervention system to appropriate services provided under Part B of the Federal Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (IDEA) operated by the state Department of Education; and </section><section prefix="i">Developing performance measures to assess the outcomes for children receiving services. </section></section><section prefix="3">The council shall prepare no later than December 30 of each year an annual report on the progress toward and any barriers to full implementation of the Kentucky Early Intervention System for infants and toddlers with disabilities and their families. The report shall include recommendations concerning the Kentucky Early Intervention System, including recommendations of ways to improve quality and cost effectiveness, and shall be submitted to the Governor, Legislative Research Commission, and the Secretary of the United States Department of Education. </section><section prefix="4">No member of the council shall cast a vote on any matter which would provide direct financial benefit to that member or otherwise give the appearance of the existence of a conflict of interest. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 30, effective July 12, 2012; and ch. 158, sec. 23, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 302, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 180, sec. 7, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 5, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 30, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 308, sec. 7, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 176, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 313, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note>(6/25/2013). A reference to the "Early Childhood Development Authority" in this statute has been changed in codification to the "Early Childhood Advisory Council" to reflect the reorganization of certain parts of the Executive Branch, as set forth in Executive Order 2012-586 and confirmed by the General Assembly in 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 57.(7/12/2012). This statute was amended by 2012 Ky. Acts chs. 146 and 158, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40945</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>