<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">A STATEWIDE EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>39A.180</section_number><catch_line>Orders and administrative regulations of political subdivisions -- Enforcement. </catch_line><order_by>180</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The political subdivisions of the state and other agencies designated or appointed by the Governor may make, amend, and rescind orders and promulgate administrative regulations necessary for disaster and emergency response purposes, and to supplement the carrying out of the provisions of this chapter, if not inconsistent with any orders or administrative regulations promulgated by the Governor or by any state agency exercising a power delegated to it by the Governor. </section><section prefix="2">All written orders and administrative regulations promulgated by the Governor, the director, or by any political subdivision or other agency authorized by KRS Chapters 39A to 39F to make orders and promulgate administrative regulations, shall have the full force of law, when, if issued by the Governor, the director, or any state agency, a copy is filed with the Legislative Research Commission, or, if promulgated by an agency or political subdivision of the state, when filed in the office of the clerk of that political subdivision or agency. All existing laws, ordinances, and administrative regulations inconsistent with the provisions of KRS Chapters 39A to 39F, or of any order or administrative regulation issued under the authority of KRS Chapters 39A to 39F, shall be suspended during the period of time and to the extent that the conflict exists. </section><section prefix="3">The law enforcement authorities of the state and of its counties, urban-counties, charter counties, and cities shall enforce the written orders and administrative regulations issued pursuant to KRS Chapters 39A to 39F. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 17, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21712</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>