<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.490</section_number><catch_line>Causes for which licenses may be revoked. </catch_line><order_by>490</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any license issued under KRS 243.020 to 243.670 may be revoked by the state board if the licensee shall have violated any of the provisions of KRS Chapter 241, 243, or 244, or any rule or regulation of the board or of the Department of Revenue relating to the regulation of the manufacture, sale, and transportation or taxation of alcoholic beverages or if the licensee shall have violated or shall violate any Act of Congress or any rule or regulation of any federal board, agency, or commission, or any ordinance now, heretofore, or hereafter in effect relating to the regulation of the manufacture, sale and transportation or taxation of intoxicating liquors or any rules or regulations of any local alcoholic beverage authority or any similar body heretofore in existence or authorized by the terms of KRS Chapters 241, 243, and 244 to be created, or if any clerk, agent, servant, or employee of any licensee shall violate any of the laws, regulations, or ordinances above referred to, irrespective of whether the licensee knew of or permitted the violation or whether the violation was committed in disobedience of his instructions, or any license may be revoked for any cause which the Alcoholic Beverage Control Board in the exercise of its sound discretion deems sufficient. A license may be revoked for any of the reasons for which the administrator would have been required to refuse a license if the facts had been known. </section><section prefix="2">If it is determined that an applicant for a license or license renewal under the provisions of this chapter is a delinquent taxpayer as defined in KRS 131.1815, the Department of Alcoholic Beverage Control may refuse to issue or renew the license to the applicant. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 578, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, secs. 652 and 653, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 22, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 329, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 168, secs. 4 and 13. --Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2554b-141, 2554c-10. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11371</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>