<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="345" order_by="345">COLLECTIVE BARGAINING FOR FIREFIGHTERS </unit></structure><section_number>345.050</section_number><catch_line>Activities prohibited and duty to bargain in good faith. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Public employers, their representatives or their agents are prohibited from: <section prefix="a">Interfering, restraining or coercing firefighters in the exercise of the rights guaranteed in KRS 345.030; </section><section prefix="b">Dominating or interfering with the formation, existence or administration of any labor organization; </section><section prefix="c">Discriminating in regard to hiring or tenure of employment or any term or condition of employment to encourage or discourage membership in any labor organization; provided, that nothing in this chapter, or in any other statute of this state, shall preclude a public employer from making an agreement with a labor organization to require as a condition of employment membership therein on or after the thirtieth day following the beginning of such employment or on the effective date of such agreement, whichever is the later; </section><section prefix="d">Discharging or otherwise discriminating against an employee because he has signed or filed any affidavit, petition or complaint or given any information or testimony under this chapter; </section><section prefix="e">Refusing to bargain collectively in good faith with a labor organization which is the exclusive representative of employees in an appropriate unit, including but not limited to the discussing of grievances with the exclusive representative. </section></section><section prefix="2">Labor organizations or their agents are prohibited from: <section prefix="a">Restraining or coercing: <section prefix="1">Firefighters in the exercise of the right guaranteed in subsection (1) of KRS 345.030, and </section><section prefix="2">A public employer in the selection of his representative for the purposes of collective bargaining or the adjustment of grievances; </section></section><section prefix="b">Refusing to bargain collectively in good faith with a public employer, if they have been designated in accordance with the provisions of this chapter as the exclusive representative of firefighters in an appropriate unit. </section></section><section prefix="3">For the purposes of this chapter, to bargain collectively is to carry out in good faith the mutual obligation of the parties, or their representatives; to meet together at reasonable times, including meetings in advance of the budget-making process; to negotiate in good faith with respect to wages, hours and other conditions of employment; to negotiate an agreement; to negotiate any question arising under any agreement; and to execute a written contract incorporating any agreement reached, if requested by either party. The obligation shall not be interpreted to compel either party to agree to a proposal, or require either party to make a concession. </section></text><history>Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 6. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32682</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>