<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="220" order_by="220">SANITATION DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>220.040</section_number><catch_line>Petition necessary to establish district -- Requisites. </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Before the commissioner of sanitation districts shall establish a district, a petition, approved as to propriety and necessity by the county board of health of each county affected, shall be filed with the commissioner, containing valid signatures of sixty percent (60%) of those in possession claiming as freeholders within the limits of the territory proposed to be organized into a district. </section><section prefix="2">In determining when sixty percent (60%) of the landowners have signed the petition, the commissioner shall consult with the landowners whose names appear upon the county tax duplicate, which for all purposes of KRS 220.010 to 220.520 shall be prima facie evidence of such ownership. The commissioner shall further require evidence to determine the fact that all signatures on the petition are genuine, and a notification by ordinary mail sent to the respective addresses shown on the petition shall be deemed satisfactory by the commissioner if the petitioner so notified fails to report in writing within ten (10) days that he did not sign the petition. When authorized by ordinance, such a petition may be signed by the governing body of any municipality lying wholly or partly within the proposed district. When so signed by such governing body a petition on the part of the governing body shall fill all requirements of representation upon the petition of the freeholders of the municipality as they appear upon the assessment roll of the municipality, and individuals within the municipality shall not sign the petition. Such a petition may also be filed by any municipality interested in some degree in the improvement, upon proper action by its governing body, except as provided in KRS 220.520. </section></text><history>Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 217, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 195, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2062g-4. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1982</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:37</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9771</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>