<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="108" order_by="108">URBAN SERVICES DISTRICTS -- AMBULANCE SERVICE DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>108.160</section_number><catch_line>Dissolution of single city or county districts. </catch_line><order_by>160</order_by><text>Single city or county districts may be dissolved in the following manner: <section prefix="1">Upon the filing of a certified petition of a number of registered voters equal to or greater than twenty-five percent (25%) of the average of the voters living in the taxing district and voting in the last four (4) general elections or upon the determination of the fiscal court or city legislative body that the abolishment of the district is in the best interest of the inhabitants of the county or city, the fiscal court or city legislative body (as appropriate) shall adopt a resolution submitting to the qualified voters of the county or city as to whether the district should be dissolved and the imposition of the special ad valorem tax discontinued. A certified copy of the resolution of the fiscal court or city legislative body (as appropriate) shall be filed with the county clerk not later than the second Tuesday in August prior to the next regular election and thereupon the clerk shall cause the question to be placed before the voters. </section><section prefix="2">The question shall be in substantially the following form: "Are you in favor of dissolving the emergency ambulance service district for (insert name of city or county) and discontinuing the special ad valorem tax that is imposed for the maintenance and operation of the district?" </section><section prefix="3">If a majority of those voting on the question favor dissolving the district and discontinuing the imposition of the special ad valorem tax the county clerk or the collector of city taxes shall remove the levy of the special ad valorem tax from the tax bills of the property owners of the district and the district shall be dissolved by order of the fiscal court or the city legislative body. If less than a majority of those voting on the question favor dissolving the district, the district shall be continued and no future vote may be taken on the question of dissolving the district until the next regular election four (4) years later. </section><section prefix="4">A resolution for the dissolution of the district shall not be considered to have any legal effect if contractual obligations assumed prior to the time of the passage of the resolution by the board have not been met. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 195, sec. 52, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 43, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 360, sec. 35, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1980; and ch. 119, sec. 12, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 243, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 33, sec. 9. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27227</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>