<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.2329</section_number><catch_line>Prohibited conduct with respect to temporary traffic control devices in highway work zones -- Penalty -- Disposition of restitution payments. </catch_line><order_by>2329</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person shall not intentionally destroy, remove, injure, or deface a temporary traffic control device erected for the purpose of enhancing traffic safety or worker safety in a highway work zone. A temporary traffic control device shall include but not be limited to a cone, tubular marker, delineator, warning light, drum, barricade, sign, sign truck, arrow board, or other device specified in an approved traffic control plan or by an administrative regulation promulgated by the cabinet pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A. </section><section prefix="2">A person who violates the provisions of this section shall, upon conviction, in addition to any other penalty established by statute, be sentenced to pay fifty dollars ($50) for each temporary traffic control device that the person destroyed, removed, injured, or defaced, and the person shall make restitution to the owner of the temporary traffic control device. </section><section prefix="3">Restitution payments to owners of temporary traffic control devices required to be made under subsection (2) of this section shall be paid directly to the owner of the device as specified by written order of the court. The court shall not direct that the payments be made through the circuit clerk. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 183, sec. 16, effective August 1, 2002. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 37, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> August 1, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6341</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>