<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="196" order_by="196">CORRECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>196.725</section_number><catch_line>Community corrections boards -- Membership -- Meetings -- Duties. </catch_line><order_by>725</order_by><text>Each community corrections program shall establish a community corrections board to provide direction and assistance to the community corrections program in the design, implementation and evaluation of the community corrections program plan. Community corrections boards shall be organized as nonprofit corporations under KRS Chapter 273. The community corrections board shall consist of not less than eight (8) members, and shall include, insofar as possible, judges, Commonwealth's attorneys, defense attorneys, crime victims or survivors, community leaders, social workers, law-enforcement officers, probation officers, and other interested persons. Members of the board shall receive no compensation for their duties as board members. The board shall be subject to the open meetings law and the open records law as provided for in KRS Chapter 61. The community corrections board shall meet on a regular basis, and its duties shall include, but are not limited to, the following: <section prefix="1">Development and recommendation of an annual budget for the community corrections program; </section><section prefix="2">Selection of new or additional board members; </section><section prefix="3">Arranging for a private and independent annual audit; and </section><section prefix="4">Development of procedures for contracting for services. </section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 6, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6853</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>