<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="216" order_by="216">B LICENSURE AND REGULATION OF HEALTH FACILITIES AND SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>216B.160</section_number><catch_line>Requirement for a care delivery model based on patient needs for licensed health care facilities and services. </catch_line><order_by>160</order_by><text>All health care facilities and services licensed under this chapter shall include in their policies and procedures a care delivery model based on patient needs which includes, but is not limited to: <section prefix="1">Defined roles and responsibilities of licensed and unlicensed health care personnel; </section><section prefix="2">A policy that establishes the credentialing, oversight, appointment, and reappointment of the registered nurse first assistant and for granting, renewing, and revising of the registered nurse first assistant's clinical privileges; </section><section prefix="3">A policy that establishes the credentialing, oversight, appointment, and reappointment of the physician assistant and for granting, renewing, and revising of the physician assistant's clinical privileges; </section><section prefix="4">A policy that establishes the credentialing, oversight, appointment, and reappointment of the certified surgical assistant and for granting, renewing, and revising of the certified surgical assistant's clinical privileges; </section><section prefix="5">A staffing plan that specifies staffing levels of licensed and unlicensed personnel required to safely and consistently meet the performance and clinical outcomes-based standards as outlined in the facility's or service's quality improvement plan; </section><section prefix="6">A staffing model that is developed and implemented in an interdisciplinary and collaborative manner; </section><section prefix="7">A policy and method that incorporates at least four (4) components in an ongoing assessment done by the registered nurse of the severity of the patient's disease, patient condition, level of impairment or disability, and the specific unit patient census to meet the needs of the individual patient in a timely manner; and </section><section prefix="8">A staffing model that supports the delivery of patient care services with an appropriate mix of licensed health care personnel that will allow them to practice according to their legal scope of practice, and for nurses, the professional standards of practice referenced in KRS Chapter 314, and facility and service policies. </section>If a nursing facility, intermediate care facility, or skilled care facility meets the most current state or federal regulations which address safe and consistent staffing levels of licensed and unlicensed personnel, those shall suffice for compliance with the standards in this section. This section shall not be interpreted as requiring any health care facility to develop a policy or a procedure for a service not offered by the facility. </text><history> Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 36, sec. 2, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 96, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 538, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 21, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:37</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9229</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>