<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.090</section_number><catch_line>Date licenses expire -- Reduction in fee for licenses less than six months -- Renewals not to affect proceedings for violations -- Term of renewals.   </catch_line><order_by>090</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All licenses issued by the department, except special event licenses, temporary licenses, or licenses listed in subsection (4) of this section, shall be valid for a period of no more than a year. The department shall promulgate administrative regulations establishing the year-round system for renewal of licenses. The system shall be designed to distribute the workload as uniformly as possible within the offices of the local administrators and the Department of Alcoholic Beverage Control. </section><section prefix="2">When any person applies for a new license authorized under KRS Chapters 241 to 244, he or she shall be charged, if the license is issued, the full fee for the respective license if six (6) months or more remain before the license is due to be renewed and one-half (1/2) the fee if less than six (6) months remain before the license is due to be renewed. No abatement of license fees shall be permitted to any person who held a license of the same kind for the same premises in the preceding license period and who was actually doing business under the license during the last month of the preceding license period. </section><section prefix="3">The renewal by the department of the certificate or permit of any alcoholic beverage license shall not be construed to waive or condone any violation that occurred prior to the renewal and shall not prevent subsequent proceedings against the licensee. </section><section prefix="4">All alcoholic beverage producers, wholesalers, or distributors may obtain or renew their licenses for either a one (1) year term or a two (2) year term. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 57, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 568, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 518, sec. 6, effective April 13, 1998. -- Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2554b-114, 2554b-117, 2554b-197. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42492</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>