<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6">THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY </unit></structure><section_number>6.930</section_number><catch_line>Report of committee findings and recommendations. </catch_line><order_by>930</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In any instance in which a study conducted by or for the committee cites inadequate operating or administrative systems controls or procedures, inaccuracies, waste, extravagance, unauthorized or unintended activities or programs, or other deficiencies, the committee shall report such deficiencies and its recommendations for their correction to the head of the state agency or program and the secretary of the cabinet to which the report pertains. </section><section prefix="2">The secretary of the cabinet and the head of the state agency or program to which the report pertains shall give affirmative consideration to the report within sixty (60) days of the adoption of the report by: <section prefix="a">Adopting the committee's recommendations and reporting their actions to the committee; or </section><section prefix="b">Otherwise correcting the deficiency and reporting their actions, and the reasons for not adopting the committee's recommendations, to the committee. </section></section><section prefix="3">If no corrective action is taken by the secretary of the cabinet or by the head of the state agency or program in response to a committee report under subsections (1) and (2) of this section, or if the committee deems the corrective action taken to be unsuitable, the committee shall report the matter to the General Assembly, together with its recommendations. </section><section prefix="4">The committee shall report the results of each of its studies, including the committee's recommendations for any further action, to the General Assembly. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 486, sec. 38, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 7, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 254,  sec. 6, effective March 30, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=418</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>