<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171">STATE LIBRARIES -- LIBRARIANS -- STATE ARCHIVES AND RECORDS </unit></structure><section_number>171.140</section_number><catch_line>General powers and duties. </catch_line><order_by>140</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The department shall give assistance and advice to all state institutional and public libraries, and to all counties in the state which propose to establish public libraries, as to the best means of their establishment and operation and may send any of its members to aid in organizing such libraries or assist in the improvement of those already established. </section><section prefix="2">It may receive gifts which may be used or held for the purpose given, and may purchase and operate traveling libraries under such conditions and rules as it thinks necessary to protect the interests of the state and best increase the efficiency of its service to the public. </section><section prefix="3">The department may issue printed material, such as lists and circulars of information, and in the publication thereof may cooperate with other state library commissions and libraries, in order to secure the more economical administration of the work for which it was formed. It may provide for library educational opportunities in various parts of the state. </section><section prefix="4">The department shall perform such other service in behalf of public libraries as it considers for the best interests of the state. </section><section prefix="5">The department shall maintain a strong central collection of library materials in a variety of formats and assure access to those materials and to other information resources throughout the state and nation for the purposes of providing information and reference services to state government agencies and of supplementing the resources of local libraries. </section></text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. --Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2438c-4. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4757</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>