<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="531" order_by="531">PORNOGRAPHY </unit></structure><section_number>531.090</section_number><catch_line>Voyeurism. </catch_line><order_by>090</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of voyeurism when: <section prefix="a">He or she intentionally: <section prefix="1">Uses or causes the use of any camera, videotape, photooptical, photoelectric, or other image recording device for the purpose of observing, viewing, photographing, filming, or videotaping the sexual conduct, genitals, an undergarment worn without being publicly visible, or nipple of the female breast of another person without that person's consent; or </section><section prefix="2">Uses the unaided eye or any device designed to improve visual acuity for the purpose of observing or viewing the sexual conduct, genitals, an undergarment worn without being publicly visible, or nipple of the female breast of another person without that person's consent; or </section><section prefix="3">Enters or remains unlawfully in or upon the premises of another for the purpose of observing or viewing the sexual conduct, genitals, an undergarment worn without being publicly visible, or nipple of the female breast of another person without the person's consent; and </section></section><section prefix="b">The other person is in a place where a reasonable person would believe that his or her sexual conduct, genitals, undergarments, or nipple of the female breast will not be observed, viewed, photographed, filmed, or videotaped without his or her knowledge. </section></section><section prefix="2">The provisions of subsection (1) of this section shall not apply to: <section prefix="a">A law enforcement officer during a lawful criminal investigation; or </section><section prefix="b">An employee of the Department of Corrections, the Department of Juvenile Justice, a private prison, a local jail, or a local correctional facility whose actions have been authorized for security or investigative purposes. </section></section><section prefix="3">Unless objected to by the victim or victims of voyeurism, the court on its own motion or on motion of the Commonwealth's attorney shall: <section prefix="a">Order the sealing of all photographs, film, videotapes, or other images that are introduced into evidence during a prosecution under this section or are in the possession of law enforcement, the prosecution, or the court as the result of a prosecution under this section; and </section><section prefix="b">At the conclusion of a prosecution under this section, unless required for additional prosecutions, order the destruction of all of the photographs, film, videotapes, or other images that are in possession of law enforcement, the prosecution, or the court. </section></section><section prefix="4">Voyeurism is a Class A misdemeanor. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 72, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 336, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43301</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>