<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="317" order_by="317">A COSMETOLOGISTS </unit></structure><section_number>317A.060</section_number><catch_line>Administrative regulations.   </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cosmetologist board shall promulgate administrative regulations governing the operation of any schools and salons of cosmetology and nail technology including but not limited to administrative regulations to protect the health and safety of the public, to protect the public against misrepresentation, deceit, or fraud in the practice or teaching of beauty culture, to set standards for the operation of the schools and salons, and to protect the students under the provisions of this chapter. </section><section prefix="2">The administrative regulations promulgated by the board shall also address: <section prefix="a">The location and housing of beauty salons or cosmetology schools in the state. To this end, the board may make reasonable divisions and subdivisions of the state. This subsection does not apply to the instructional programs in cosmetology in the state area vocational and technical schools; </section><section prefix="b">The quantity and quality of equipment, supplies, materials, records, and furnishings required in beauty salons, nail salons, or cosmetology schools; </section><section prefix="c">The training and supervision of cosmetology apprentices; </section><section prefix="d">The qualifications of teachers of cosmetology and apprentice teachers of cosmetology; </section><section prefix="e">The hours and courses of instruction at cosmetology schools; </section><section prefix="f">The examinations of applicants for licenses; </section><section prefix="g">The proper education and training of students; and </section><section prefix="h">The course and conduct of school owners, instructors, apprentice instructors, licensed cosmetologists, nail technicians, beauty salons, nail salons, and cosmetology schools. </section></section><section prefix="3">Administrative regulations pertaining to health and sanitation shall be approved by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services before becoming effective. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 6, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 202, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 354, sec. 6. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 675, instructs the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in the Act, as it confirms the establishment of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40883</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>