<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="17" order_by="17">PUBLIC SAFETY </unit></structure><section_number>17.330</section_number><catch_line>Analysis and labeling of brake fluid. </catch_line><order_by>330</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every manufacturer of any hydraulic brake fluid sold, offered for sale, or used for service in any vehicle shall submit to the Transportation Cabinet for approval a laboratory analysis report for each product produced, sold, or used in Kentucky. The analysis shall be conducted by an independent and qualified testing laboratory and shall verify that each product meets the minimum standards of heavy duty type hydraulic brake fluid specifications, designated as S. A. E. 70-R-1. </section><section prefix="2">Any alteration or adulteration made to any approved hydraulic brake fluid by the manufacturer, dealer, or seller shall be reported to the Transportation Cabinet. An approval from the Transportation Cabinet shall be obtained before any such product shall be sold, offered for sale, or used for service in this state. </section><section prefix="3">Every can, bottle, or other type of container used for the containing of hydraulic brake fluid shall be labeled to specify the composition of the contents. Such specifications shall denote conformity of the contents with the minimum standards of heavy duty type hydraulic brake fluid specifications, designated as S. A. E. 70-R-1. </section></text><history>Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. V, sec. 24(17). -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 4, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> June 16, 1960</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1240</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>