<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="160" order_by="160">SCHOOL DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>160.445</section_number><catch_line>Sports safety course required for high school athletics coaches -- Training and education on symptoms, treatment, and risks of concussion -- Venue-specific emergency action plans.     </catch_line><order_by>445</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">The Kentucky Board of Education or organization or agency designated by the board to manage interscholastic athletics shall require each interscholastic coach to complete a sports safety course consisting of training on how to prevent common injuries. The content of the course shall include but not be limited to emergency planning, heat and cold illnesses, emergency recognition, head injuries including concussions, neck injuries, facial injuries, and principles of first aid. The course shall also be focused on safety education and shall not include coaching principles. </section><section prefix="b">The state board or its agency shall: <section prefix="1">Establish a minimum timeline for a coach to complete the course; </section><section prefix="2">Approve providers of a sports safety course; </section><section prefix="3">Be responsible for ensuring that an approved course is taught by qualified professionals who shall either be athletic trainers, registered nurses, physicians, or physician's assistants licensed to practice in Kentucky; and </section><section prefix="4">Establish the minimum qualifying score for successful course completion. </section></section><section prefix="c">A course shall be reviewed for updates at least once every thirty (30) months and revised if needed. </section><section prefix="d">A course shall be able to be completed through hands-on or online teaching methods in ten (10) clock hours or less. </section><section prefix="e"><section prefix="1">A course shall include an end-of-course examination with a minimum qualifying score for successful course completion established by the board or its agency. </section><section prefix="2">All coaches shall be required to take the end-of-course examination and shall obtain at least the minimum qualifying score. </section></section><section prefix="f">Beginning with the 2009-2010 school year, and each year thereafter, at least one (1) person who has completed the course shall be at every interscholastic athletic practice and competition. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Beginning with the 2012-2013 school year, and each year thereafter, the state board or its agency shall require each interscholastic coach to complete training on how to recognize the symptoms of a concussion and how to seek proper medical treatment for a person suspected of having a concussion. The training shall be approved by the state board or its agency and may be included in the sports safety course required under subsection (1)(a) of this section. </section><section prefix="b">The board or its agency shall develop guidelines and other pertinent information or adopt materials produced by other agencies to inform and educate student athletes and their parents or legal guardians of the nature and risk of concussion and head injury, including the continuance of play after concussion or head injury. Any required physical examination and parental authorization shall include acknowledgement of the education information required under this paragraph. </section><section prefix="c">Upon request, the board or its agency shall make available to the public any training materials developed by the board or agency used to satisfy the requirements of paragraph (a) of this subsection. The board or its agency shall not be held liable for the use of any training materials so disseminated. </section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">A student athlete suspected by an interscholastic coach, school athletic personnel, or contest official of sustaining a concussion during an athletic practice or competition shall be removed from play at that time and shall not return to play prior to the ending of the practice or competition until the athlete is evaluated to determine if a concussion has occurred. The evaluation shall be completed by a physician or a licensed health care provider whose scope of practice and training includes the evaluation and management of concussions and other brain injuries. A student athlete shall not return to play on the date of a suspected concussion absent the required evaluation. </section><section prefix="b">A student athlete may return to play if it is determined no concussion has occurred. </section><section prefix="c">A student athlete deemed to be concussed shall not return to participate in any athletic practice or competition occurring on the day of the injury. The injured student athlete shall not be allowed to participate in any subsequent practice or athletic competition unless written clearance from a physician is provided. </section></section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">The state board or its agency shall adopt rules governing interscholastic athletics conducted by local boards of education to require each school that participates in interscholastic athletics to develop a venue-specific emergency action plan to deal with serious injuries and acute medical conditions in which the condition of the patient may deteriorate rapidly. The plan shall: <section prefix="1">Include a delineation of role, methods of communication, available emergency equipment, and access to and plan for emergency transport; and </section><section prefix="2">Be in writing, reviewed by the principal of the school, distributed to all appropriate personnel, posted conspicuously at all venues, and reviewed and rehearsed annually by all licensed athletic trainers, first responders, coaches, school nurses, athletic directors, and volunteers for interscholastic athletics. </section></section><section prefix="b">Each school shall submit annual written verification of the existence of a venue-specific emergency action plan to the state board or its agency. </section></section><section prefix="5">Each school shall maintain complete and accurate records of its compliance with this section and shall make the records available for review by the state board or its agency upon request. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 30, sec. 8, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 72, sec. 1, effective April 11, 2012. -- Created 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 90, sec. 2, effective March 24, 2009. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41871</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>