<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="332" order_by="332">DRIVER TRAINING SCHOOLS AND INSTRUCTORS </unit></structure><section_number>332.095</section_number><catch_line>CDL training schools -- Curriculum -- Evaluation -- Refresher course -- Ratio of students to instructors -- Drug test.   </catch_line><order_by>095</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All CDL driver training schools, as defined in KRS 165A.310, shall offer a minimum one hundred sixty (160) hours of instruction to each student that has never been issued a CDL by any state. Each school shall be required to use the curriculum that has been approved by the Kentucky Commission on Proprietary Education in consultation with the Department of Kentucky State Police and the Kentucky Community and Technical College System. Each school shall perform an evaluation of each student and determine the student's skill level to operate a commercial motor vehicle as beginner, intermediate, or advanced. The curriculum shall require a minimum number of hours of instruction based upon a student's skill level. </section><section prefix="2">Each school may provide the one hundred sixty (160) hour approved curriculum in a manner that best utilizes the staff and equipment of the school including but not limited to nights, weekends, holidays, and hours of operation. </section><section prefix="3">All CDL driver training schools, as defined in KRS 165A.310, may offer a refresher course of instruction to a resident who has one (1) year or more verifiable experience operating a commercial motor vehicle. The schools shall verify and maintain records documenting those students attending a refresher course. A refresher course may be offered on an hourly basis. </section><section prefix="4">The ratio of students to instructors during a one hundred sixty (160) hour course shall not exceed: <section prefix="a">Thirty (30) students to one (1) instructor during classroom instruction; </section><section prefix="b">Six (6) students to one (1) instructor during off-the-road training; and </section><section prefix="c">Three (3) students to one (1) instructor during on-the-road training. </section></section><section prefix="5">All CDL driver training schools, as defined in KRS 165A.310, shall require each student to undergo a drug test at the time the person applies to enroll in the school. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 26, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 302, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 280, sec. 4, effective April 9, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40338</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>