<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="136" order_by="136">CORPORATION AND UTILITY TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>136.340</section_number><catch_line>Tax on amounts paid to stock insurance companies, other than life. </catch_line><order_by>340</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every stock insurance company, other than life, doing business in this state shall, on or before the first day of March of each year, return to the Department of Revenue a statement under oath of all amounts paid to the company or its representative, whether designated as premiums or otherwise, for insurance or services incident thereto, on property or risks in this state during the preceding calendar year or since the last returns were made, including amounts received for reinsurance on Kentucky risks from unauthorized companies, and shall at the same time pay a tax of two dollars ($2) upon each one hundred dollars ($100) of such amounts paid to the company, less amounts returned on canceled policies and policies not taken. </section><section prefix="2">The health insurance contract or contracts for state employees as authorized by KRS 18A.225 shall not be subject to taxation under this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 323, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 7, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 16, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 496, sec. 8, effective August 1, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 187, Part IV, sec. 2. -- Amended 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 1. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 155, secs. 1 and 5. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4229. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:01</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28552</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>