<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="11" order_by="11">THE GOVERNOR </unit></structure><section_number>11.160</section_number><catch_line>Procedure for General Assembly confirmation of appointments by the Governor or other appointing authority. </catch_line><order_by>160</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When a statute specifically requires Senate confirmation of an appointment by the Governor or by other appointing authority, the appointment shall be handled in the following manner: <section prefix="a">All names of persons nominated when the General Assembly is not in session shall be submitted for confirmation no later than the next regular session of the General Assembly. The Governor who makes the appointment, or other appointing authority, shall deliver the name of the nominee to the clerk of the Senate upon appointment or no later than the fifteenth legislative day of the next regular session of the General Assembly. The Governor may submit a nominee for confirmation at any special session that occurs between the date of initial appointment and the next regular session of the General Assembly. If the Governor desires to submit the name of a nominee for confirmation at a special session of the General Assembly, he shall place confirmation of the nominee on the call for special session. </section><section prefix="b">All names of persons nominated to positions during a regular session of the General Assembly shall be submitted for confirmation at that regular session. The Governor who makes the appointment, or other appointing authority, shall submit the name of the nominee, together with such accompanying information as may expedite the consideration of the appointment to the clerk of the Senate not more than three (3) legislative days after making the appointment, unless the appointment is made during the last fifteen (15) legislative days, in which case the nominee's name and information shall be submitted not more than one (1) legislative day later. </section><section prefix="c">For each nominee, the Governor who makes the appointment, or other appointing authority, shall deliver to the clerk of the Senate a letter of appointment. The letter of appointment shall be accompanied by a resume which contains at least the following information: <section prefix="1">Complete employment history of the nominee; </section><section prefix="2">Complete educational background of the nominee; and </section><section prefix="3">Current and past employment by or financial relationships with the Commonwealth of Kentucky or any of its political subdivisions held by the nominee and any member of the nominee's immediate family. </section></section><section prefix="d">When a statute requires an interim legislative committee to hold a public hearing on a particular appointment, the Governor who makes the appointment, or other appointing authority, shall deliver the letter of appointment and resume for each nominee to the Legislative Research Commission within seven (7) days after making the appointment. </section><section prefix="e">The Legislative Research Commission may utilize the services of its staff or other appropriate persons or organizations to investigate the background of nominees and to verify the information provided. The Department of Kentucky State Police shall conduct and provide a criminal record history on a nominee if requested by the Legislative Research Commission. </section><section prefix="f">During periods when the General Assembly is not in session, the Governor's or other appointing authority's power of appointment shall not be diminished, and nominees may assume the responsibilities of the position pending confirmation. During that period, they shall be considered for all purposes to have been appointed and to be lawful occupants of the post to which they have been nominated, except that they shall be subject to the confirmation process when the General Assembly is next in regular session or special session called for the purpose of confirming the nominees. </section><section prefix="g">If the Governor who makes the appointment, or other appointing authority, fails to submit the name of the nominee or if the Senate declines to consider a nominee, the position shall become vacant as of sine die adjournment of the applicable special or regular session of the General Assembly at which the appointment was to be confirmed. If the Senate declines to confirm the nominee, the position shall become vacant upon the date the Senate declined to confirm. </section><section prefix="h">Any person not confirmed by the Senate shall not be reappointed by the Governor, or other appointing authority, to the same position for which confirmation is required for a period of two (2) years from the date the Senate declined to confirm the nomination or the date of sine die adjournment if the Senate declined to consider the nomination. </section></section><section prefix="2">When a statute specifically requires Senate and House of Representatives confirmation of an appointment by the Governor or by other appointing authority, the appointment shall be handled in the following manner: <section prefix="a">All names of persons nominated when the General Assembly is not in session shall be submitted for confirmation no later than the next regular session of the General Assembly. The Governor who makes the appointment, or other appointing authority, shall deliver the name of the nominee to the clerk of the House of Representatives no later than the fifteenth legislative day of the next regular session of the General Assembly. The Governor may submit a nominee for confirmation at any special session that occurs between the date of initial appointment and the next regular session of the General Assembly. If the Governor desires to submit the name of a nominee for confirmation at a special session of the General Assembly, he shall place confirmation of the nominee on the call for special session. </section><section prefix="b">All names of persons nominated to positions during a regular session of the General Assembly shall be submitted for confirmation at that regular session. The Governor who makes the appointment, or other appointing authority, shall submit the name of the nominee to the clerk of the House of Representatives not more than three (3) legislative days after making the appointment, unless the appointment is made during the last fifteen (15) legislative days, in which case the nominee's name and information shall be submitted not more than one (1) legislative day later. </section><section prefix="c">For each nominee, the Governor who makes the appointment, or other appointing authority, shall deliver to the clerk of the House of Representatives a letter of appointment. The letter of appointment shall be accompanied by a resume which contains at least the following information: <section prefix="1">Complete employment history of the nominee; </section><section prefix="2">Complete educational background of the nominee; and </section><section prefix="3">Current and past employment by or financial relationships with the Commonwealth of Kentucky or any of its political subdivisions held by the nominee and any member of the nominee's immediate family. </section></section><section prefix="d">When a statute requires an interim legislative committee to hold a public hearing on a particular appointment, the Governor who makes the appointment, or other appointing authority, shall deliver the letter of appointment and resume for each nominee to the Legislative Research Commission within seven (7) days after making the appointment. </section><section prefix="e">The Legislative Research Commission may utilize the services of its staff or other appropriate persons or organizations to investigate the background of nominees and to verify the information provided. The Department of Kentucky State Police shall conduct and provide a criminal record history on a nominee if requested by the Legislative Research Commission. </section><section prefix="f">The confirmation shall originate in the House of Representatives. If the House of Representatives does not confirm an appointment, the Senate shall not consider the appointment. </section><section prefix="g">When both the Senate and the House of Representatives have confirmed an appointment, the Senate shall notify the House of Representatives of the final approval. The clerk of the House shall then notify the Governor, or other appointing authority, and the appointee in writing of the General Assembly's action. </section><section prefix="h">During periods when the General Assembly is not in session, the Governor's or other appointing authority's power of appointment shall not be diminished, and nominees may assume the responsibilities of the position pending confirmation. During that period, they shall be considered for all purposes to have been appointed and to be lawful occupants of the post to which they have been nominated, except that they shall be subject to the confirmation process when the General Assembly is next in regular session or special session called for the purpose of confirming the nominees. </section><section prefix="i">If the Governor who makes the appointment, or other appointing authority, fails to submit the name of the nominee or if the House of Representatives or the Senate declines to consider a nominee, the position shall become vacant as of sine die adjournment of the regular session of the General Assembly at which the appointment was to be confirmed. If the House of Representatives or the Senate declines to confirm the nominee, the position shall become vacant upon the date that a chamber of the General Assembly first declined to confirm. </section><section prefix="j">Any person not confirmed by the House of Representatives or the Senate shall not be reappointed by the Governor, or other appointing authority, to the same position for which confirmation is required for a period of two (2) years from the date that a chamber of the General Assembly first declined to confirm the nomination, or the date of sine die adjournment if the House of Representatives or the Senate declined to consider the nomination. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 4, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 26, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 415, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 505, sec. 1, effective April 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=543</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>