<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="222" order_by="222">KENTUCKY ALCOHOL AND OTHER DRUG ABUSE PREVENTION, INTERVENTION, AND TREATMENT LAW </unit></structure><section_number>222.421</section_number><catch_line>Treatment for alcohol or other drug abuse on request -- Priority access to licensed treatment services -- Statistical report. </catch_line><order_by>421</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person may request treatment from a physician or alcohol and other drug abuse program licensed or approved by the cabinet to provide alcohol and other drug abuse treatment services. Persons infected with HIV, hepatitis B, or hepatitis C shall have priority access to any licensed treatment services. </section><section prefix="2">Every alcohol and other drug abuse program that provides intervention or treatment services to a person with an alcohol and other drug abuse problem or prevention programming to any persons in the community shall, upon request of the cabinet, make a statistical report to the secretary, in a form and manner the secretary shall prescribe, of persons provided prevention, intervention, and treatment services during a specified period of time. The name or address of any person to whom prevention, intervention, or treatment services were provided shall not be reported. The secretary shall provide compilations of the statistical information to other appropriate agencies upon request. </section></text><history> Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 14, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 432, sec. 9, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 501, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 334, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9941</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>