<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17A-330</section_number><catch_line>Self-insurance reporting requirements -- Exemption. </catch_line><order_by>17A-330</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All insurers authorized to write health insurance in this state and employer-organized associations that self-insure shall transmit at least annually by July 31 to the commissioner the following information, in a format prescribed by the commissioner, on their insurance experience in this state for the preceding calendar year: <section prefix="a">Total premium by product type and market segment; </section><section prefix="b">Total enrollment by product type and market segment; </section><section prefix="c">Total cost of medical claims filed by product type and market segment; </section><section prefix="d">Total amount of medical claims paid by the insurer and insured by product type and market segment; </section><section prefix="e">Total policies canceled by type and the aggregate reasons therefor; and </section><section prefix="f">List of total health and medical services paid for, grouped by types of services and costs: <section prefix="1">Total cost per health and medical service per insured group: <section prefix="a">Cost paid by insurer; </section><section prefix="b">Cost paid by insured; and </section></section><section prefix="2">Number of insureds who received each service. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">With the approval of the commissioner, the department may exempt insurers, employer-organized associations that self-insure, and health purchasing outlets from the data reporting requirements of this section if the total number of insureds is less than five hundred (500). </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1225, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 5, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 521, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 496, sec. 41, effective April 10, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17414</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>