<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="217" order_by="217">B FERTILIZER AND PESTICIDE USE AND APPLICATION </unit></structure><section_number>217B.530</section_number><catch_line>Examinations for licenses. </catch_line><order_by>530</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Applicator licensing examinations for commercial structural pest control and commercial structural fumigation shall be given the second Tuesday in May and the second Tuesday in November unless such date shall be a holiday. In such case the examination shall be given on the third Tuesday of that month. Manager licensing examinations shall be administered by the department as needed. </section><section prefix="2">An applicant shall be allowed to take two (2) consecutive licensing examinations but if the applicant has not passed the licensing examination after two (2) attempts he must then wait one (1) year and must complete and pass a training course approved by the department before reapplying to take the examination one (1) more time. If the applicant does not pass the examination the third or subsequent time, he shall have to wait two (2) years and complete and pass an additional training course approved by the department before reapplying to take the examination. </section><section prefix="3">License testing fees shall be fifty dollars ($50) for each examination each time the examination is taken. </section><section prefix="4">Written examinations shall be given to all qualified applicants.  No oral examinations shall be given. </section><section prefix="5">The commercial structural pest control examination shall consist of no less than two hundred sixty (260) written questions and no less than forty (40) identification specimens. The commercial structural fumigation examination shall consist of no less than eighty (80) written questions and no less than twenty (20) identification specimens. The manager's licensing examination shall consist of no less than ninety (90) written questions and no less than ten (10) identification specimens. </section><section prefix="6">The licensing examination shall be a timed examination. Five (5) hours shall be allowed for the commercial structural pest control examination and two (2) hours for the commercial structural fumigation examination. Timing for the manager's licensing examinations shall be set by regulation. </section><section prefix="7">The applicant must achieve a grade of at least 70% correct on the written questions and at least 70% correct on the identification to pass the licensing examination. The license applicant must take and pass the entire examination to become licensed. </section><section prefix="8">The commercial structural pest control and the commercial structural fumigation examination shall also serve as the examination necessary to fulfill federal commercial pesticide applicator certification requirements, including industrial, institutional, structural and health related pest control. </section></text><history>Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 7, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9567</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>