<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">A EMERGENCY MEDICAL SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>311A.070</section_number><catch_line>Written notice of complaint or proposed action. </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When a complaint is filed against an ambulance service, emergency medical services provider, or an emergency medical services educational institution or an employee or volunteer thereof, or when the office of the board is contemplating action against an ambulance service, emergency medical services provider, or emergency medical services educational institution or an employee or volunteer thereof, written notice of the complaint or proposed action shall be sent to: <section prefix="a">The county judge/executive, in the event of a county-operated ambulance service, emergency medical services provider, or educational institution; </section><section prefix="b">The mayor, in the event of a city-operated ambulance service, emergency medical services provider, or educational institution; </section><section prefix="c">The mayor, in the event of an urban-county government-operated ambulance service, emergency medical services provider, or educational institution; </section><section prefix="d">The chairman of the fire protection district, in the event of a fire district-operated ambulance service, emergency medical services provider, or educational institution; </section><section prefix="e">The head of the public agency, in the event of an ambulance service, emergency medical services provider, or educational institution operated by a public agency other than specified in paragraphs (a) to (d) of this subsection; </section><section prefix="f">The president, chancellor, or other officer in charge of an educational institution operated, in the event of an ambulance service or educational institution; </section><section prefix="g">The chief operating officer or president of a nonprofit corporation, corporation for profit, limited liability company, or other business entity, in the event of an ambulance service, emergency medical services provider, or educational institution operated by the business entity; and </section><section prefix="h">Both the ambulance service, emergency medical services provider, or educational institution officials specified in this subsection and the officials of any public agency contracting for services. </section></section><section prefix="2">The notice specified in this section shall be in addition to any notice provided to any other person or organization. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 138, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 138, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 13, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 183, provides, "The specific textual provisions of Sections 1 to 178 of this Act which reflect amendments made to those sections by 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137 shall be deemed effective as of June 26, 2007, and those provisions are hereby made expressly retroactive to that date, with the remainder of the text of those sections being unaffected by the provisions of this section." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30730</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>