<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="177" order_by="177">STATE AND FEDERAL HIGHWAYS -- LIMITED ACCESS FACILITIES -- TURNPIKES -- ROAD BONDS -- BILLBOARDS -- RECYCLERS </unit></structure><section_number>177.375</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Transportation Center Advisory Board. </catch_line><order_by>375</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is created a Kentucky Transportation Center Advisory Board, hereinafter in KRS 177.375 to 177.380 called the transportation center board or the board, to assist in policy formulation for and to provide direction to the Kentucky Transportation Center which is located at the University of Kentucky. The board shall consist of nine (9) members appointed by the Governor. </section><section prefix="2">Of the nine (9) members, three (3) members shall be ex officio and include the secretary of the Transportation Cabinet, the state highway engineer and the dean of the College of Engineering at the University of Kentucky. In addition, it is recommended that three (3) of the nine (9) appointments be made in the following manner: <section prefix="a">One (1) member appointed from a list of three (3) names submitted by the executive board of the Kentucky Association of Counties; </section><section prefix="b">One (1) member appointed from a list of three (3) names submitted by the executive board of the Kentucky County Judges' Association; and </section><section prefix="c">One (1) member appointed from a list of three (3) names submitted by the executive board of the Kentucky Municipal League. </section></section> Initial appointments made pursuant to paragraphs (a), (b) and (c) of this subsection shall be for a period of one (1) year. The remaining appointments shall be for two (2) years except that ex officio members shall serve the same terms as that of their respective offices. Ex officio members and regular members shall have the same powers and voting privileges. Each appointment thereafter shall be for a period of two (2) years. <section prefix="3">The Governor shall designate one (1) member of the board as chairman, whose term shall be for two (2) years with said two (2) years being consistent with the biennium budget period. The members shall serve without pay, but shall be reimbursed for reasonable expenses from the center's budget. </section><section prefix="4">Meetings of the board shall be held at least semiannually but may be held more frequently as deemed necessary subject to call by the chairman or by request of a majority of the board members. Board meetings shall concern, among other things, policy matters relating to the transportation center's technical assistance and research programs, financial plans, and such other matters as necessary to carry out the intent of KRS 177.375 to 177.380. </section><section prefix="5">Five (5) members of the board shall constitute a quorum for doing business. Each member shall have one (1) vote and a majority vote of the members present shall control on all questions. Each regular and ex officio member may designate a proxy by written notice to the chairman prior to call to order of each meeting and such proxy shall be entitled to cast the member's vote. </section></text><history>Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 394, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5319</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>