<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="325" order_by="325">PUBLIC ACCOUNTANTS </unit></structure><section_number>325.301Firms</section_number><catch_line>required to obtain license to practice in Kentucky -- Firms exempted from licensure requirement -- Criteria for license.   </catch_line><order_by>301Firms</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The following firms shall obtain a license to practice in this state: <section prefix="a">Any firm with an office located in this state performing attest services, as defined in KRS 325.220; </section><section prefix="b">Any firm with an office in this state that uses the title "CPA" or other phrase or abbreviation in any manner described in KRS 325.410 to suggest it is a certified public accounting firm; and </section><section prefix="c">Any firm that does not have an office located in this state but performs any attest service described in KRS 325.220(1)(a), (c), or (d) for a client with his or her home office in this state or a client who is a resident of this state. </section></section><section prefix="2">The following firms shall not be required to obtain a license to practice in this state and may use the title "CPA" in the name of the firm: <section prefix="a">A firm which does not have an office in this state that performs services described in KRS 325.220(1)(b) or (e) for a client having its home office in this state or a client who is a resident of this state if: <section prefix="1">The firm complies with the requirements contained in subsections (3)(a) and (12) of this section; and </section><section prefix="2">All services provided by the firm are performed by an individual with a practice privilege granted under KRS 325.282; and </section></section><section prefix="b">A firm which does not have an office in this state and does not provide attest services, as defined in KRS 325.220, to a client having his or her home office located in this state or a client who is a resident of this state may provide other services that are regulated activities, as defined in KRS 325.220, if: <section prefix="1">The services are provided through an individual granted a practice privilege as described in KRS 325.282; and </section><section prefix="2">The firm can legally provide the services in the state where the individual with a practice privilege has his or her principal place of business. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">All firms seeking to obtain a license to practice in this Commonwealth shall meet the following requirements: <section prefix="a">Certified public accountants shall hold fifty-one percent (51%) or more of the ownership of the firm in terms of financial interests and voting rights of all partners, officers, shareholders, members, or managers of the firm; </section><section prefix="b">All owners of the firm who are not certified public accountants shall be natural persons actively engaged in the firm's operations and shall satisfy additional requirements established by the board through promulgation of an administrative regulation; </section><section prefix="c">The name of the firm shall comply with the requirements of KRS 325.380; </section><section prefix="d">All certified public accountants who are sole proprietors, partners, shareholders, members, officers, directors, or employees of a firm with an office located in this state, who regularly practice in this Commonwealth, shall maintain current licenses to practice issued by the board; </section><section prefix="e">Any individual licensee and any individual qualifying for a practice privilege under this chapter who is responsible for supervising attest services and signs or authorizes someone to sign the report on behalf of the firm shall meet the competency requirements established by the board through promulgation of an administrative regulation; and </section><section prefix="f">The firm shall comply with the provisions of this chapter, the administrative regulations promulgated by the board, and all other laws of this Commonwealth applicable to the firm's particular form of business organization. </section></section><section prefix="4">Before a firm may practice in this Commonwealth, the firm manager shall: <section prefix="a">Submit an initial application which contains information required by the board through promulgation of an administrative regulation; and </section><section prefix="b">Pay a fee not to exceed two hundred dollars ($200) established by an administrative regulation promulgated by the board. </section></section><section prefix="5">The firm license shall be renewed every two (2) years by the firm manager: <section prefix="a">Completing the renewal process according to the procedures as established in administrative regulation promulgated by the board; and </section><section prefix="b">Paying the renewal fee, which shall not exceed two hundred dollars ($200), as established by administrative regulation promulgated by the board. </section></section><section prefix="6">A firm license due to expire on July 1, 2011, shall: <section prefix="a">Be renewed by the firm manager according to the procedures established by the board through promulgation of an administrative regulation; </section><section prefix="b">Require payment of a fee not to exceed fifty dollars ($50) established by the board through promulgation of an administrative regulation; and </section><section prefix="c">Expire on August 1, 2012. </section></section><section prefix="7">A firm license that expires on or after August 1, 2012, shall: <section prefix="a">Be renewed by the firm manager prior to August 1, 2012; </section><section prefix="b">Require payment of a fee not to exceed two hundred dollars ($200) established by the board through promulgation of an administrative regulation; </section><section prefix="c">Be effective for two (2) years; and </section><section prefix="d">Be renewed by the firm manager on or before August 1 of each two (2) year period thereafter according to the procedures contained in this subsection and as established by the board through promulgation of an administrative regulation. </section></section><section prefix="8">If a firm license has been expired for a period of less than one (1) month and the firm has not violated any other provision of this chapter or the accompanying administrative regulations promulgated thereunder, the firm manager may renew the license by: <section prefix="a">Satisfying all the requirements of this subsection, including any requirements established by the board through promulgation of an administrative regulation; and </section><section prefix="b">In addition to the renewal fee, paying a late fee not to exceed one hundred dollars ($100). </section></section><section prefix="9">A firm with a license expired for a period of longer than one (1) month after the date of expiration shall cease operating immediately. The firm shall not operate until the board approves the issuance of a new license to the firm. </section><section prefix="10">Effective August 1, 2012, sole proprietors shall comply with the licensing requirements for firms under this section. </section><section prefix="11">The firm manager shall notify the board in accordance with procedures established in an administrative regulation promulgated by the board, of any change in its licensing information within thirty (30) days. Any change in the name of a firm shall require the filing of an initial application. </section><section prefix="12">All firms that perform audits, reviews, or compilations shall enroll in and complete on a regular basis an approved peer review program with standards that are equivalent to or better than the peer review program administered by the American Institute of Certified Public Accountants as determined by administrative regulations promulgated by the board. Every firm shall comply with any requirements or restrictions placed on its license as prescribed by the board in response to the results of peer reviews. </section><section prefix="13">Nothing contained in this chapter shall require a certified public accountant or firm of certified public accountants licensed by another state to obtain a license to practice in this Commonwealth if the certified public accountant or firm of certified public accountants enters this Commonwealth solely to: <section prefix="a">Conduct a peer review of a firm; or </section><section prefix="b">Perform attestation work, incidental to an engagement which was initiated with a client located outside of the Commonwealth and has extended into the Commonwealth due to common ownership or existence of a subsidiary, assets, or other operations located within the Commonwealth. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 107, sec. 5, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 31, sec. 2, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 7, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 248, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (6/24/2015). Under the authority of KRS 7.136(1), the Reviser of Statutes has changed the internal numbering of KRS 325.220 to place definitions in alphabetical order and changed references to that statute in subsections (1) and (2) of this statute to correspond. No words were changed in this process. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:54</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44597</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>