<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.231</section_number><catch_line>Appeals -- Hearing officers -- Appeal board -- Procedure. </catch_line><order_by>231</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The secretary shall appoint one (1) or more impartial hearing officers to hear and decide upon appealed decisions. </section><section prefix="2">Any applicant or recipient who is dissatisfied with the decision or delay in action on his application for public assistance or the amount granted to him may appeal to a hearing officer, except that an appeal and a hearing need not be granted if the sole issue is a federal or state law requiring an automatic change adversely affecting some or all recipients of the Kentucky medical assistance program so long as advance notice of the change, with an explanation of appeal rights, is provided to all affected recipients. However, a recipient may appeal whether the cabinet is accurately interpreting a change in federal or state law which may adversely affect the recipient. On receipt of an appeal, an administrative hearing shall be conducted in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section><section prefix="3">The secretary may appoint an Appeal Board for Public Assistance composed of the secretary and two (2) other members. The secretary shall be chairman, and he and one (1) other member constitute a quorum. </section><section prefix="4">Any applicant or recipient who is dissatisfied with the decision of a hearing officer may appeal to the appeal board in the manner and form prescribed by administrative regulation. The board may on its own motion affirm, modify, or set aside any decision of a hearing officer on the basis of the evidence previously submitted in the case, or direct the taking of additional evidence, or may permit any of the parties to the decision to initiate further appeals before it. The board may remove itself or transfer to another hearing officer the proceedings on any appeal pending before a hearing officer. The board shall promptly notify the parties to any proceedings of its findings and decisions. </section><section prefix="5">The manner in which appeals are presented and hearings and appeals conducted under subsection (4) of this section shall be in accordance with administrative regulations promulgated by the secretary. </section><section prefix="6">After a decision by the appeal board, any party aggrieved by the decision may seek judicial review of the decision by filing a petition in the Circuit Court of the county in which the petitioner resides, in accordance with KRS 13B.140, 13B.150, and 13B.160. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 96, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 436, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 194, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(21). -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 256, sec. 10. -- Created 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7667</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>