<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="150" order_by="150">FISH AND WILDLIFE RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>150.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Angling" means the taking or attempting to take fish by hook and line in hand, rod in hand, jugging, setline, or sport fishing trotline; </section><section prefix="2">"Buy" includes offering to buy, acquiring, or possessing through purchase, barter, exchange, or trade; </section><section prefix="3">"Commercial trotline" means a line to which are attached more than fifty (50) single or multibarbed baited hooks, which shall not be placed closer than eighteen (18) inches; </section><section prefix="4">"Commission" means the Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources Commission; </section><section prefix="5">"Commissioner" means the commissioner of the Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources; </section><section prefix="6">"Daylight hours" means the period from one-half (1/2) hour before sunrise to one-half (1/2) hour after sunset; </section><section prefix="7">"Device" means any article, instrument, or equipment of whatever nature or kind which may be used to take wild animals, wild birds, or fishes; </section><section prefix="8">"Department" means the Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources; </section><section prefix="9">"Fishing" means to take or attempt to take in any manner, whether the fisherman has fish in possession or not; </section><section prefix="10">"Gigging" means the taking of fish by spearing or impaling on any pronged or barbed instrument attached to the end of any rigid object; </section><section prefix="11">"Grabbing" means the taking of fish, frogs, or turtles directly by hand or with the aid of a handled hook; </section><section prefix="12">"Hunting" means to take or attempt to take in any manner, whether the hunter has game in possession or not; </section><section prefix="13">"Identification tag" means a marker made of specified material upon which a name and address or number is placed and attached to unattended gear to designate ownership or responsible operator; </section><section prefix="14">"Impounded waters" means any public waters backed up behind a dam and includes all water upstream from the dam to the first riffle or shoal; </section><section prefix="15">"Jugging" means a means of fishing by which a single baited line is attached to any floating object; </section><section prefix="16">"License" means any document issued by the department authorizing its holder to perform acts authorized by the license and includes any other form of authorization in addition to or in lieu of an actual document which may be authorized by the department by administrative regulation; </section><section prefix="17">"Migratory shore or upland game birds" means all species of migratory game birds except waterfowl; </section><section prefix="18">"Minnows" means all fish under six (6) inches in length, except basses, either largemouth, smallmouth or Kentucky; rock bass or goggle-eye; trout; crappie; walleye; sauger; pike; members of the striped bass family; and muskellunge; </section><section prefix="19">"Navigable waters" means any waters within this state under lock and dam; </section><section prefix="20">"Nonresident" means a person who has not established a permanent domicile in this state and has not resided in this state for thirty (30) days immediately prior to his application for a license; </section><section prefix="21">"Permit" means any document issued by the department authorizing its holder to perform acts authorized by the permit and includes tags which shall be affixed to wildlife or devices as evidence of holding a permit and includes any other form of authorization in addition to or in lieu of an actual document authorized by the department by administrative regulation; </section><section prefix="22">"Possess" means the act of having or taking into control; </section><section prefix="23">"Prescribed by the department" means established by an administrative regulation; </section><section prefix="24">"Processed wildlife" means any wildlife specimen or parts thereof that have been rendered into a permanently preserved state; </section><section prefix="25">"Protected wildlife" means all wildlife except those species declared unprotected by administrative regulations promulgated by the department; </section><section prefix="26">"Public roadway" includes rural roads, highways, bridges, bridge approaches, city streets, viaducts, and bridges which are normally traveled by the general public and are under the jurisdiction of a state, federal, county, or municipal agency; </section><section prefix="27">"Public waters" means all waters within the state flowing in a natural stream channel or impounded on a natural stream; </section><section prefix="28">"Raw fur" means a hide, fur, or pelt of a fur-bearing animal which has not been processed. Skinning, stretching, oiling, or coloring of the pelt of the animal shall not be considered processing; </section><section prefix="29">"Administrative regulation" means a written regulation promulgated, pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A, by the commissioner with the approval of the commission; </section><section prefix="30">"Resident" means any person who has established permanent domicile and legal residence and has resided in this state for thirty (30) days immediately prior to his application for a license. All other persons shall be classed as nonresidents, except students enrolled for at least six (6) months in an educational institution as full-time students and military personnel of the United States who are under permanent assignment, shall be classified as residents while so enrolled or assigned in this state; </section><section prefix="31">"Resist" means to point a gun at, leave the scene, intimidate or attempt to intimidate in any manner, or further interfere in any manner with any officer in the discharge of his duties; </section><section prefix="32">"Rough fish" means all species of fishes other than those species designated by administrative regulation as sport fishes; </section><section prefix="33">"Sell" includes offering to sell, having or possessing for sale, barter, exchange, or trade; </section><section prefix="34">"Setline" means a line to which is attached one (1) single or multibarbed hook. This line may be attached to a tree limb, tree trunk, bank pole, or other stationary object, on the bank of a stream or impoundment; </section><section prefix="35">"Snagging" means the taking of fish or other aquatic animals through the use of a hand-held pole and attached line with single or multiple fish hooks in which the fish is hooked by a rapid drawing motion rather than enticement by bait; </section><section prefix="36">"Sports fishing trotline" means a line to which are attached no more than fifty (50) single or multibarbed baited hooks which shall not be placed closer together than eighteen (18) inches; </section><section prefix="37">"Take" includes pursue, shoot, hunt, wound, catch, kill, trap, snare, or capture wildlife in any way and any lesser act designed to lure, attract, or entice for these purposes; and to place, set, aim, or use any device, animal, substance, or agency which may reasonably be expected to accomplish these acts; or to attempt to do these acts or to assist any other person in the doing of or the attempt to do these acts; </section><section prefix="38">"Tenant" means any resident sharecropper, lessee, or any other person actually engaged in work upon a farm or lands and residing in a dwelling on the farms or lands including noncontiguous lands, but shall not include any other employee or tenant unless actually residing on the property and engaged or employed as above mentioned; </section><section prefix="39">"Transport" means to carry, move, or ship wildlife from one place to another; </section><section prefix="40">"Waterfowl" means all species of wild ducks, geese, swans, mergansers, and coots; and </section><section prefix="41">"Wildlife" means any normally undomesticated animal, alive or dead, including without limitations any wild mammal, bird, fish, reptile, amphibian, or other terrestrial or aquatic life, whether or not possessed in controlled environment, bred, hatched, or born in captivity and including any part, product, egg, or offspring thereof, protected or unprotected by this chapter. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 512, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 268, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 474, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 365, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 265, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 178, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 273, sec. 1. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 38, sec. 1. -- Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 115, sec. 1. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 200, sec. 1. -- Amended 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 2. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 84, sec. 1. -- Amended 1944 Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 2; and ch. 124, sec. 1. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 68, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 1893d-10, 1954-2. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1926</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>