<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="210" order_by="210">STATE AND REGIONAL MENTAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>210.775</section_number><catch_line>Hart-Supported Living Council.     </catch_line><order_by>775</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created the Hart-Supported Living Council for services to persons with a disability and their families. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">The Hart-Supported Living Council shall be composed of eleven (11) members. The secretary and the executive director of the Kentucky Housing Corporation or their designees shall be ex officio members. </section><section prefix="b">Nine (9) of the members shall be volunteers and shall be appointed by the Governor from a list of nominees in the following manner: <section prefix="1">Three (3) of the appointed members shall represent family members of persons with a disability; </section><section prefix="2">Two (2) of the appointed members shall be persons with a disability; </section><section prefix="3">One (1) of the appointed members shall represent professionals and providers of services to persons with a disability; </section><section prefix="4">One (1) of the appointed members shall represent advocates for persons with a disability; and </section><section prefix="5">Two (2) of the appointed members shall represent the community at large. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">The appointed members may serve on the council for three (3) years from the date of appointment. Members may be reappointed for one (1) additional consecutive three (3) year term. The Governor shall fill any vacancy occurring in the council in the manner prescribed in subsection (2) of this section. </section><section prefix="4">The cabinet shall provide staff assistance to the Hart-Supported Living Council. </section><section prefix="5">The chairman of the Hart-Supported Living Council shall be elected from among the members. A majority of the members shall constitute a quorum. </section><section prefix="6">The Hart-Supported Living Council shall meet as often as necessary but no less frequently than every other month. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 96, effective July 12, 2012; and ch. 158, sec. 42, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 405, sec. 71, effective July 15, 1994. – Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 261, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note>(7/12/2012). This statute was amended by 2012 Ky. Acts chs. 146 and 158. Where these Acts are not in conflict, they have been codified together. Where a conflict exists, Acts ch. 146, which was last enacted by the General Assembly, prevails under KRS 446.250. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44642</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>