<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="309" order_by="309">MISCELLANEOUS OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS </unit></structure><section_number>309.0805</section_number><catch_line>Use of titles "licensed clinical alcohol and drug counselor," "licensed clinical alcohol and drug counselor associate," "certified alcohol and drug counselor," and "registered alcohol and drug peer support specialist" -- Construction.   </catch_line><order_by>0805</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall use the title "licensed clinical alcohol and drug counselor," "licensed clinical alcohol and drug counselor associate," "certified alcohol and drug counselor," or "registered alcohol and drug peer support specialist," or hold himself or herself out as a "licensed clinical alcohol and drug counselor," "licensed clinical alcohol and drug counselor associate," "certified alcohol and drug counselor," or "registered alcohol and drug peer support specialist" unless he or she is licensed, certified, or registered pursuant to KRS 309.080 to 309.089. </section><section prefix="2">Nothing in KRS 309.080 to 309.089 shall apply to persons licensed, certified, or registered under any other provision of the Kentucky Revised Statutes, including but not limited to physicians, social workers, psychologists, marriage and family therapists, art therapists, nurses, or students in accredited training programs in those professions, and nothing in KRS 309.080 to 309.089 shall be construed to limit, interfere with, or restrict the practice, descriptions of services, or manner in which they hold themselves out to the public. </section><section prefix="3">Nothing in KRS 309.080 to 309.089 shall be construed to alter, amend, or interfere with the practice of those who render counseling services, including but not limited to employment counseling, job placement counseling, vocational rehabilitation counseling, pastoral counseling based on any tenet of one's religious beliefs, or school counseling. </section><section prefix="4">Nothing in KRS 309.080 to 309.089 shall apply to the activities and services of a student intern or trainee who is pursuing a program of studies in alcohol and drug counseling at an accredited institution of higher education, if these activities are performed under the supervision or direction of an approved supervisor and the activities are part of the supervised program of studies. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2015. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 96, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44290</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>