<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="353" order_by="353">MINERAL CONSERVATION AND DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>353.730Investigation</section_number><catch_line>of abandoned wells -- Application -- Report -- Bond.   </catch_line><order_by>730Investigation</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person may investigate an abandoned well upon receipt of approval from the department. The person shall submit to the department: <section prefix="a">An application requesting approval to investigate and stating the planned methods for the investigation. In all cases where there has been a complete severance of the ownership of the oil and gas from the ownership of the surface to be disturbed, the application shall include a plan to prevent erosion and sedimentation; </section><section prefix="b">A twenty-five dollar ($25) fee; and </section><section prefix="c">A certification by the applicant that he has the authority to enter the property upon which the well is located and to conduct the investigation. </section></section><section prefix="2">The department shall review all applications for investigation. If the department approves the request for investigation, the applicant shall be allowed to produce the well without a permit as required by KRS 353.570, and the applicant shall submit a report of investigation to the department on forms provided by the department. In order to produce the well for more than sixty (60) days, the applicant must obtain a bond as required by KRS 353.590(7) or (12). Notwithstanding the provisions of KRS 353.590(2), no fee shall be required for any such well. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 21, sec. 18, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 160, sec. 4, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 359, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44257</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>