<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="154" order_by="154">A STATE LOTTERY </unit></structure><section_number>154A.070</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of corporation's president. </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The president, as chief executive officer of the corporation, shall direct and supervise all administrative and technical activities in accordance with the provisions of this chapter and with the administrative regulations adopted by the board. It shall be his duty to: <section prefix="a">Supervise and administer the operation of the lottery games; </section><section prefix="b">Employ and direct such personnel as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter and utilize such services, personnel, or facilities of the corporation as he may deem necessary. He may employ by personal service contract pursuant to KRS 45A.690 to 45A.725 and compensate such consultants and technical assistants as may be required to carry out the provisions of this chapter. The president may, by agreement, secure information and services as he may deem necessary from any department, agency, or unit of state government, and shall compensate such department, agency, or unit of state government for its services. Such agencies, departments, or units of state government shall cooperate with the corporation and provide such information and services as may be required by the corporation to assure the integrity of the lottery and the effective operation of the lottery games; </section><section prefix="c">Contract in accordance with the administrative regulations of the corporation with persons to sell lottery tickets at retail. The president shall require a bond or bank letter of credit from lottery retailers in an amount provided by administrative regulations issued by the board; </section><section prefix="d">Make available for inspection by the board or any member of the board, upon request, all books, records, files, and other information and documents of his office and to advise the board and recommend such administrative regulations and other matters he deems necessary and advisable to improve the operation and administration of the lottery; </section><section prefix="e">Enter into any contract pursuant to KRS Chapters 45 and 45A or administrative regulations promulgated by the board, and pursuant to KRS 154A.120, with any person, firm, or corporation for the promotion and any operation of the lottery, or for the performance of any of the functions as provided in this chapter; </section><section prefix="f">Attend meetings of the board or appoint a designee to attend on his behalf; and </section><section prefix="g">On the first day of the Regular Session of the General Assembly in 1990 and biennially thereafter, submit the proposed biennial budget of the corporation to the Appropriations and Revenue Committee of the House of Representatives for review and comment. The budget shall be submitted to the Director of the Legislative Research Commission within five (5) days of adoption by the board for distribution to the Appropriations and Revenue Committee of the House of Representatives for review. </section></section><section prefix="2">The president, with the approval of the board, may amend or modify the budget at any time in any manner deemed necessary for the proper operation of the corporation; however, each change shall be reported in writing to the board and to the director of the Legislative Research Commission, who shall transmit a copy of the change to the Appropriations and Revenue Committee of the House of Representatives. </section><section prefix="3">Following his confirmation, and during his entire term of office, the president shall reside in Kentucky. </section><section prefix="4">The president, and the board, may conduct an ongoing study of the operation and administration of lotteries in other states or countries, of available literature on the subject, of federal laws and regulations which may affect the operation of the lottery, and of the reaction of citizens of this state to existing or proposed features of lottery games, with a view toward implementing improvements that will tend to serve the purposes of this chapter. </section><section prefix="5">The president also may: <section prefix="a">Require bond from corporate employees with access to corporate funds or lottery funds, in such an amount as provided in the administrative regulations of the board. The president may also require bond from other employees as he deems necessary; and </section><section prefix="b">For good cause, suspend, revoke, or refuse to renew any contract entered into in accordance with the provisions of this chapter or the administrative regulations of the board. </section></section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 170, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 496, sec. 46, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1988 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 7, effective December 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3015</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>