<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="99" order_by="99">URBAN RENEWAL AND REDEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>99.550</section_number><catch_line>Power and authority of agency with respect to urban renewal. </catch_line><order_by>550</order_by><text>An agency shall have all the powers necessary or convenient to undertake and carry out urban renewal plans and urban renewal projects, including the authority to acquire and dispose of property, to issue bonds and other obligations, to borrow and accept grants from the federal government or other source and to exercise the other powers which KRS 99.330 to 99.510 confer on an agency with respect to redevelopment projects. In connection with the planning and undertaking of any urban renewal plan or urban renewal project, the agency, the community, and all public and private officers, agencies, and bodies shall have all the rights, powers, privileges, and immunities which they have with respect to a development plan or redevelopment project, in the same manner as though all of the provisions of KRS 99.330 to 99.510 applicable to a development plan or redevelopment project were applicable to an urban renewal plan or urban renewal project; Provided That for such purpose the word "redevelopment" as used in KRS 99.330 to 99.510 and KRS 99.520 to 99.590, except in this section and in the definition of "redevelopment project" in KRS 99.340, shall mean "urban renewal," the words "slum area" and the words "blighted area" as used in KRS 99.330 to 99.510 and KRS 99.520 to 99.590, except in this section and in the definitions in subsections (1) and (2) of KRS 99.340, shall mean "blighted, deteriorated, or deteriorating area," and the finding prescribed in KRS 99.370 with respect to a slum area or blighted area shall not be required; Provided further That any disaster area, referred to in KRS 99.530, shall constitute a "blighted area"; and Provided further That this section shall not change the corporate name of the agency or amend any section of KRS 99.330 to 99.510. In addition to the surveys and plans which an agency is otherwise authorized to make, an agency is hereby specifically authorized to make (1) plans for carrying out a program of voluntary repair and rehabilitation of buildings and improvements, (2) plans for the enforcement of laws, codes, and regulations relating to the use of lands and the use and occupancy of buildings and improvements, and to the compulsory repair, rehabilitation, demolition, or removal of buildings and improvements, (3) plans for the relocation of persons, including families, business concerns and others, displaced by an urban renewal project, (4) preliminary plans outlining urban renewal activities for neighborhoods to embrace two (2) or more urban renewal areas, and (5) preliminary surveys to determine if the undertaking and carrying out of an urban renewal project are feasible. The agency is authorized to make relocation payments to or with respect to persons, including families, business concerns and others, displaced by an urban renewal project, for moving expenses and losses of property for which reimbursement or compensation is not otherwise made, including the making of such payments financed by the federal government. The agency also is authorized to develop, test, and report methods and techniques, and carry out demonstrations and other activities, for the prevention and the elimination of slums and urban blight.  </text><history>Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 159, sec. 10, effective June 19, 1958. -- Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 215, sec. 4. </history><metadata><effective>June 19, 1958</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:07</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26555</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>