<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="76" order_by="76">CITY-COUNTY METROPOLITAN SEWER, SEWER CONSTRUCTION, AND SANITATION DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>76.150</section_number><catch_line>District revenue bonds.   </catch_line><order_by>150</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Subsections (2) through (4) have no application to construction subdistrict bonds or obligations. All references to revenues, rates, rentals, charges, or collections in subsections (2) and (3) exclude those derived from or made on account of construction subdistricts. District facilities referred to in subsections (2) and (3) exclude construction subdistrict facilities. </section><section prefix="2">The district may, from time to time, issue its negotiable interest-bearing revenue bonds for any of its corporate purposes, and it may also, from time to time, issue its negotiable interest-bearing revenue bonds to refund any of its bonds at maturity or pursuant to redemption provisions, or at any time before maturity with the consent of the holders. All the bonds, including interest, are payable solely from and secured only by revenues of the district realized through the collection of rates, rentals, or other charges, imposed for use of the facilities of the district. The bonds shall be authorized by resolution of the board and shall bear the dates, mature at the times not exceeding forty (40) years from their respective dates, bear interest at the rate or rates or method of determining rates, payable at least annually, be in the denominations and form, either coupon or registered, carry the registration privileges, be executed in the manner, be payable in the medium of payment at the place, and be subject to the terms of redemption, with or without premium, as the resolutions provide; except that before the issuance of bonds for any project within the corporate limits of any city forming a district pursuant to KRS 76.010, the issuance of bonds shall first be authorized by ordinance passed by the legislative body of the city and approved by the mayor of the city. The bonds shall be sold at public sale for the price as the board determines. </section><section prefix="3">Any resolution authorizing any bonds may contain provisions, which shall be a part of the contract with the holders of the bonds, as to: <section prefix="a">Pledging all or any part of the gross or net revenues of the district to secure the payment of the bonds and interest on the bonds; </section><section prefix="b">The amounts to be raised in each year by rates, rentals, and charges, and their use and disposition, and of any other revenues of the district; </section><section prefix="c">The setting aside of reserves or sinking funds and their regulation and disposition; </section><section prefix="d">Limitations on the right of the district to restrict and regulate the use of its facilities; </section><section prefix="e">Limitations on the purposes to which the proceeds of sale of any issue of bonds to be issued may be applied; </section><section prefix="f">Limitations on the issuance of additional bonds; and </section><section prefix="g">The procedure, if any, by which the term of any contract with bondholders may be amended or abrogated, the amount of bonds the holders of which must consent, and the manner in which the consent may be given. </section></section><section prefix="4">The bonds or other obligations of the district shall not constitute an obligation or indebtedness of the city or of the county and it shall be plainly stated on the face of each bond of the district that it has been issued under the provisions of KRS 76.010 to 76.210, and that it does not constitute an indebtedness of the city or of the county. All bonds authorized may be issued without a vote of the voters and without any other proceedings or happenings of any other conditions or things than those proceedings, conditions and things which are specified and required by KRS 76.010 to 76.210. The bonds shall be signed in the name of the district by the chairman or vice chairman of the board, attested by the signature of the secretary-treasurer, with corporate seal of the district attached. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 50, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 274, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 54. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 33, sec. 7. -- Created 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 13. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:12</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43635</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>