<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="148" order_by="148">PARKS AND TOURISM </unit></structure><section_number>148.870</section_number><catch_line>Legislative recognition and purpose. </catch_line><order_by>870</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The General Assembly recognizes that the ridge top of Pine Mountain is a unique area desirable for the creation of a trail. Therefore, it is hereby declared that in order to afford the citizens of the Commonwealth an opportunity to enjoy this natural area, to attract out-of-state visitors, to ensure the well-being of our tourism industry, to preserve for future generations the beauty of certain areas untrammeled by man, to provide for the ever-increasing outdoor recreation needs of an expanding population, and to promote the preservation of, public access to, travel within, and enjoyment and appreciation of the outdoor areas and historic resources of the Commonwealth, there is hereby established a certain defined area in the southeastern part of the Commonwealth for ultimate designation as the Pine Mountain State Scenic Trail, with land in the defined area owned or leased by the Commonwealth or on which the Commonwealth has obtained an easement comprising the initial state park. </section><section prefix="2">It is the intent of KRS 148.870 to 148.892 to assure preservation of the scenic, ecological, and other values within the boundaries of the trail and to provide proper management of the recreational, wildlife, water, and other resources within those boundaries. It is further the intent of KRS 148.870 to 148.892 to impose reasonable policies governing the use of land within the authorized boundaries of the trail, except for the restrictions set forth in KRS 148.870 to 148.892, for the general welfare of the people of the Commonwealth and, where necessary, to enable the Commonwealth or any of its agencies to acquire fee title or lesser interests in land within the boundaries of the trail, in order to maintain the public trust in this unique area. </section><section prefix="3">The General Assembly recognizes the valuable contributions that volunteers and private, nonprofit groups have made to the development and maintenance of trails throughout the Commonwealth. In recognition of these contributions, it is further the purpose of KRS 148.870 to 148.892 to encourage and assist volunteer citizen and nonprofit group involvement in the planning, development, maintenance, and management, where appropriate, of the trail. </section><section prefix="4">The General Assembly recognizes that the establishment of Pine Mountain State Scenic Trail is not intended to create a one hundred twenty (120) mile linear barrier around southeastern Kentucky. The General Assembly further recognizes that to ensure the continued economic development of the area, provisions shall be made for means of ingress and egress for owners of property and those with property rights affected by the creation of the trail, and for new road construction, utility facilities, and pipelines that may cross the trail. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 87, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1815</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>