<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="315" order_by="315">PHARMACISTS AND PHARMACIES </unit></structure><section_number>315.520</section_number><catch_line>Issuance and renewal of licenses -- Separate license required for each location -- Display of license -- Transfer of license prohibited.   </catch_line><order_by>520</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall refuse to renew any license to operate unless the home medical equipment and services provider meets the standards and requirements of KRS 315.510 to 315.524 and the administrative regulations of the board. The board shall act upon an application for a license within thirty (30) days after the receipt thereof. </section><section prefix="2">A separate license shall be required for each location of a home medical equipment and services provider. </section><section prefix="3">A home medical equipment and services provider shall display its license at its place of business. </section><section prefix="4">Each license as a home medical equipment and services provider, unless sooner suspended or revoked, shall expire on September 30 following its date of issuance and be renewable annually thereafter upon proper application accompanied by such reasonable renewal fee as may be set by administrative regulation of the board, not to exceed two hundred dollars ($200) initially per year nor to increase more than twenty-five dollars ($25) per year up to a maximum of four hundred dollars ($400). An additional fee not to exceed the annual renewal fee may be assessed and set by administrative regulation as a delinquent renewal penalty for failure to renew by September 30 of each year. </section><section prefix="5">Licenses to operate shall be issued only for the premises and persons named in the application and shall not be transferable. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 73, sec. 6, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40281</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>