<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="341" order_by="341">UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>341.570</section_number><catch_line>Representation in court -- Expense of suit. </catch_line><order_by>570</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In any civil action to enforce the provisions of this chapter or in which the commission or the cabinet is an interested party, the commission or the cabinet may be represented by any qualified attorney who is designated by the secretary for that purpose. The expenses and compensation of such special attorney and any experts employed in connection with such proceedings shall be considered a proper cost of the administration of this chapter. </section><section prefix="2">All criminal actions for violation of any provision of this chapter, or of any rules or regulations issued under it, shall be prosecuted by the Attorney General of this state, or, at his request and under his direction, by the county attorney or Commonwealth attorney of any county in which the employing unit has a place of business or the violator resides or has filed a claim. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 136, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 12, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(23),(31). -- Amended 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 1. -- Amended 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 216, sec. 23. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4748g-17. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32320</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>