<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="157" order_by="157">STATE SUPPORT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>157.069</section_number><catch_line>Distribution of general funds for locally operated secondary area technology centers and vocational departments.   </catch_line><order_by>069</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Secondary area technology center" or "secondary area center" means a school facility dedicated to the primary purpose of offering five (5) or more technical preparation programs that lead to skill development focused on specific occupational areas. An area center may be called a "magnet technology center" or "career center" or may be assigned another working title by the parent agency. An area center may be either state or locally operated; and </section><section prefix="b">"Vocational department" means a portion of a school facility that has five (5) or more technical preparation programs that lead to skill development focused on specific occupational areas. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Department of Education shall distribute all general funds designated for locally operated secondary area centers and vocational departments, which have been receiving state supplemental funds prior to June 21, 2001, by a weighted formula, specified in an administrative regulation promulgated by the Kentucky Board of Education. The formula shall take into account the differences in cost of operating specific programs. The commissioner of education shall determine programs to be assigned to categories based on the descriptions found in paragraphs <section prefix="a">to (c) of this subsection. Programs in Categories III and II shall be eligible for </section>funding. (a) Category III--High-cost technical programs: Programs in which students develop highly technical skills in specific occupational areas and that require high-cost equipment, materials, and facilities. This category may include selected industrial technology Level III programs as defined by the Department of Education and programs in other occupational areas as deemed appropriate; <section prefix="b">Category II--Technical skill programs: Programs in which students develop technical skills focused in occupational areas and that require technical equipment but high-cost equipment, facilities, or materials are not necessary to operate the programs. This category may include selected industrial technology Level III programs as defined by the Department of Education and programs in other occupational areas as deemed appropriate; and </section><section prefix="c">Category I--Orientation and career exploration programs: Programs that provide orientation and exploration of broad-based industries by giving students knowledge and experience regarding careers within these industries and develop some exploratory or hands-on skills used in the industry. </section></section> Notwithstanding paragraphs (a) and (b) of subsection (1) of this section, the Department of Education shall approve the combining of eligible secondary vocational programs into a single vocational department for purposes of funding for a school district that has been receiving state supplemental funds and has distributed its vocational programs, previously located in area centers, among magnet career academies. <section prefix="3">For calculation purposes and after categorizing the programs as described in subsection (2) of this section, a weight shall be applied as a percentage of the base guarantee per pupil in average daily attendance as defined by KRS 157.320 under the Support Education Excellence in Kentucky Program, which shall be applied to full-time equivalent students in Categories II and III. Category I programs shall receive no weight. The full-time equivalent students shall be calculated on the basis of the total program enrollment divided by the length of the class period divided by six (6). </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 39, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 81, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 5, effective June 21, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42218</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>