<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="235" order_by="235">BOATS AND BOATING </unit></structure><section_number>235.210</section_number><catch_line>Boats exempt from registration requirement. </catch_line><order_by>210</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A motorboat shall not be required to be numbered under this chapter if it is:  <section prefix="a">Already covered by a number in full force and effect which has been awarded to it pursuant to federal law or a federally approved numbering system of another state; provided, that such boat shall not have been within this state for a period in excess of sixty (60) consecutive days;  </section><section prefix="b">A motorboat from a country other than the United States temporarily using the waters of this state;  </section><section prefix="c">A motorboat whose owner is the United States, a state or a subdivision thereof, except when such boat is leased to the public for compensation it must be registered according to KRS 235.080(2);  </section><section prefix="d">A ship's lifeboat used or intended to be used as such;  </section><section prefix="e">A motorboat belonging to a class of boats which has been exempted from numbering by the department after said agency has found that the numbering of motorboats of such class will not materially aid in their identification; and, if an agency of the federal government has a numbering system applicable to the class of motorboats to which the motorboat in question belongs, after the department has further found that the motorboat would also be exempt from numbering if it were subject to the federal law.  </section></section><section prefix="2">Boats exempt from registration may be required by the department to apply for an official identification number to be displayed in accordance with KRS 235.110. </section></text><history>Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 295, sec. 79, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 263, sec. 14, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 292, sec. 16. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 68, Art. VIII, sec. 23, effective March 17, 1960. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1980</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11068</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>