<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.22-020</section_number><catch_line>Legislative findings. </catch_line><order_by>22-020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The General Assembly hereby finds and declares that the general welfare and material well-being of citizens of the Commonwealth, and particularly those residing in qualified counties, depends in large measure upon the development and growth of industry in the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="2">The General Assembly hereby finds and declares further that it is in the best interest of the Commonwealth to induce the location of manufacturing facilities, electric generation, and agribusiness operations within the qualified counties of the Commonwealth in order to advance the public purposes of relieving unemployment by creating new jobs within the qualified counties that but for the inducements to be offered by the authority to approved companies as herein provided would not exist and of creating new sources of tax revenues for the support of the public services provided by the Commonwealth and qualified counties. </section><section prefix="3">The General Assembly hereby finds and declares further that the authority granted by KRS 154.22-010 to 154.22-070 and the purposes to be accomplished hereby are proper governmental and public purposes for which public moneys may be expended, and that the inducement of the location of manufacturing facilities, electric generation, and agribusiness operations within qualified counties is of paramount importance, mandating that the provisions of KRS 154.22-010 to 154.22-070 be liberally construed and applied in order to advance the public purposes. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 321, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 390, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1994. – Repealed, reenacted, and amended as KRS 154.22-020, 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 23, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 392, sec. 2, effective April 8, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><former-codification> KRS 152.262 </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2742</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>