<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="199" order_by="199">PROTECTIVE SERVICES FOR CHILDREN - ADOPTION </unit></structure><section_number>199.900</section_number><catch_line>Training programs authorized -- Research assignment -- Classification -- Compensation -- Contract. </catch_line><order_by>900</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The secretary for health and family services in coordination with the Personnel Cabinet is authorized to establish formal training programs within the Cabinet for Health and Family Services or within any of the divisions or sections of the cabinet for the training of necessary personnel for the administration of the programs of the cabinet. When courses of study, applicable to the program processes of the cabinet, are not available through cabinet instruction, arrangements may be made for the training of employees in any public or private school or institution having available facilities for that purpose, and such training shall be deemed to be a part of the cabinet training program. Training of employees in public or private schools or institutions for this purpose shall be deemed a part of research assignments to be completed during the period of study, and these assignments are to relate directly to the work assignment of the employee. After consulting with the Personnel Cabinet, position classifications in the research series shall be established for employees on such work study assignments, and funds of the cabinet may be used to pay salaries commensurate with the appropriate classification while the employee is receiving training. </section><section prefix="2">Any employee who is paid a salary while receiving such training shall be required to enter into a contract, prior to receiving the training, that he will complete a specified work assignment, and that unless he continues in the employ of the cabinet for at least a period equivalent to the training period, immediately following the completion of training, the state will hold a claim against him for the amount of salary paid during the training period, and he will repay to the cabinet the sum paid to him by the cabinet during the period of his training. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 200, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 86, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 426, sec. 164, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(1), (13) and (30). -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7250</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>