<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="281" order_by="281">A COMMERCIAL DRIVER'S LICENSES </unit></structure><section_number>281A.100</section_number><catch_line>Release of information regarding commercial driving history record. </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, the Transportation Cabinet shall upon request furnish full information regarding the commercial driving history record of any person to the following: <section prefix="a">The driver licensing administrator, court official, or police agency of this or any other state or foreign jurisdiction, requesting that information; </section><section prefix="b">Any employer or prospective employer; </section><section prefix="c">The commercial driver; or </section><section prefix="d">Any other person so established by administrative regulation, pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A, of the cabinet. </section></section><section prefix="2">The cabinet may charge a fee of five dollars ($5) for this service. </section><section prefix="3">The driving history record of a commercial driver shall include, but not be limited to, convictions for any moving traffic violation, traffic accident record, and all out-of-state moving traffic convictions. </section><section prefix="4">If a person legally entitled to a commercial driving history releases information concerning the driving history record of a commercial driver, a state agency, employee, or agent shall not be held liable. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 274, sec. 3, effective April 7, 1992. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 455, sec. 10, effective July 1, 1991. </history><metadata><effective>April 7, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14469</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>