<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="529" order_by="529">PROSTITUTION OFFENSES </unit></structure><section_number>529.140</section_number><catch_line>Human trafficking victims fund.   </catch_line><order_by>140</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The "human trafficking victims fund," referred to in this section as the "fund," is created as a separate revolving fund within the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet. </section><section prefix="2">The fund shall consist of proceeds from assets seized and forfeited pursuant to KRS 529.150, proceeds from the fee in KRS 529.130, grants, contributions, appropriations, and any other moneys that may be made available for purposes of the fund. </section><section prefix="3">Moneys in the fund shall be distributed to agencies serving victims of human trafficking, including but not limited to law enforcement agencies, prosecutorial agencies, and victim service agencies in accordance with procedures developed by the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet pursuant to administrative regulation. The administrative regulation shall require that the Cabinet for Health and Family Services receive adequate funding allocation under this subsection to meet the responsibilities imposed upon it to serve minor victims of human trafficking under KRS 620.029. </section><section prefix="4">Notwithstanding KRS 45.229, any moneys remaining in the fund at the close of the fiscal year shall not lapse but shall be carried forward into the succeeding fiscal year to be used for the purposes set forth in this section. </section><section prefix="5">Any interest earnings on moneys in the fund shall become a part of the fund and shall not lapse to the general fund. </section><section prefix="6">Moneys in the fund are hereby appropriated for the purposes set forth in this section. </section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 25, sec. 9, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41840</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>