<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="321" order_by="321">VETERINARIANS </unit></structure><section_number>321.207</section_number><catch_line>Certification of animal control agencies and animal euthanasia specialists. </catch_line><order_by>207</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Board of Veterinary Examiners, upon submission of a complete application and payment of a fee established by the board, shall issue to any animal control agency that it determines to be qualified, authorization to apply to the federal Drug Enforcement Agency, including any successor entity, for a restricted controlled substance registration certificate for the purchase, possession, and use of sodium pentobarbital or other drugs as authorized by the board for administration by a certified animal euthanasia specialist to euthanize injured, sick, or abandoned animals. </section><section prefix="2">To satisfy the board's authorization, the applicant shall comply with administrative regulations promulgated by the board which contain standards for proper storage and handling of the drugs the board has authorized for use, and any other provisions as may be necessary to ensure that the drugs are used safely and solely for the purpose set forth in this section. </section><section prefix="3">If the registration certificate is granted by the federal Drug Enforcement Agency, and the applicant otherwise satisfies the requirements of the Board of Veterinary Examiners, the board shall certify the animal control agency to euthanize animals. </section><section prefix="4">Upon submission of a complete application, payment of a fee established by the board, and successful completion of a board-approved animal euthanasia specialist training course by the applicant, the Board of Veterinary Examiners shall issue to any person whom it determines to be qualified, a certificate for the person to function as a certified animal euthanasia specialist. </section><section prefix="5">Euthanasia of animals in a certified animal control agency shall be performed by a licensed veterinarian, including a registered veterinary technician or technologist employed by and functioning under the direct supervision of a licensed veterinarian, or a certified animal euthanasia specialist as provided for in subsection (4) of this section. A certified animal control agency that employs a certified animal euthanasia specialist may purchase, possess, and administer sodium pentobarbital or other drugs that the board approves for the euthanasia of animals. Sodium pentobarbital and other drugs approved by the board shall be the only drugs used for the euthanasia of animals in a certified animal control agency. </section><section prefix="6">Certified animal control agencies and certified animal euthanasia specialists shall be required to renew their certificates at intervals, upon conditions, and upon the payment of fees established by the board. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31383</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>