<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="505" order_by="505">PROTECTION AGAINST UNFAIR OR OPPRESSIVE PROSECUTION </unit></structure><section_number>505.030</section_number><catch_line>Effect of former prosecution for same offense. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text>When a prosecution is for a violation of the same statutory provision and is based upon the same facts as a former prosecution, it is barred by the former prosecution under the following circumstances:  <section prefix="1">The former prosecution resulted in:  <section prefix="a">An acquittal, or  </section><section prefix="b">A conviction which has not subsequently been set aside; or  </section></section><section prefix="2">The former prosecution resulted in a determination by the court that there was insufficient evidence to warrant a conviction; or  </section><section prefix="3">The former prosecution was terminated by a final order or judgment, which has not subsequently been set aside, and which required a determination inconsistent with any fact or legal proposition necessary to a conviction in the subsequent prosecution; or  </section><section prefix="4">The former prosecution was improperly terminated after the first witness was sworn but before findings were rendered by a trier of fact. Termination under either of the following circumstances is not improper:  <section prefix="a">The defendant expressly consents to the termination or by motion for mistrial or in some other manner waives his right to object to the termination; or  </section><section prefix="b">The trial court, in exercise of its discretion, finds that the termination is manifestly necessary.  </section></section></text><history>Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 45, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 1975</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19697</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>