<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="335" order_by="335">SOCIAL WORKERS AND PROFESSIONAL COUNSELORS </unit></structure><section_number>335.510</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Board of Licensed Professional Counselors. </catch_line><order_by>510</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Board of Licensed Professional Counselors is created and shall consist of seven (7) members who shall reside in the Commonwealth and be appointed by the Governor. One (1) of the members shall be a citizen at large and the remaining six (6) members shall be licensed professional clinical counselors. The licensed professional clinical counselor members on the board shall have been licensed as professional clinical counselors in the Commonwealth for at least two </section><section prefix="2">years preceding their appointments. The citizen at large member shall not be </section>associated with or have a relative who is associated with the practice or business of professional counseling. Neither the citizen at large nor his relatives shall have a financial interest in the practice or business of professional counseling. (2) All appointments and vacancies to the board shall be filled by the Governor. Appointments and vacancies of counselor members shall be filled by the Governor from a list of three (3) names for each position to be filled that is submitted by the Kentucky Mental Health Counseling Association. Vacancies shall be filled for the remainder of the unexpired terms and in the same manner as set out in this subsection. <section prefix="3">The length of a term of board appointment shall be four (4) years. A board member shall serve no more than two (2) consecutive terms. </section><section prefix="4">The board shall elect a chair from its membership, and a chair shall be elected annually but shall serve no more than two (2) consecutive one (1) year terms. Four (4) members of the board shall constitute a quorum. </section><section prefix="5">The board shall hold two (2) meetings annually to give examinations pursuant to KRS 335.515 and may hold additional meetings as the board deems necessary. The additional meetings may be held upon call of the chair or upon the written request of three (3) or more board members. </section><section prefix="6">The Governor shall remove a member from the board, for cause only. </section><section prefix="7">A member of the board who is a citizen at large shall be disqualified from his or her seat on the board if: <section prefix="a">He or she, a member of his or her household, or a relative becomes associated with or financially interested in the business of professional counseling; </section><section prefix="b">He or she, a member of his or her household, or a relative becomes, or is in training to become, a licensed professional clinical counselor; or </section><section prefix="c">He or she ceases to reside in the Commonwealth. </section></section><section prefix="8">A counselor member of the board shall be disqualified from his seat on the board if: <section prefix="a">He or she has been determined by the board or a court to have violated the code of professional ethics or practice standards established pursuant to KRS 335.500 to 335.599; </section><section prefix="b">He or she ceases to be a licensed professional clinical counselor; or </section><section prefix="c">He or she ceases to reside in the Commonwealth. </section></section><section prefix="9">Each board member shall receive one hundred dollars ($100) per day for each day of service actually given in carrying out his duties under KRS 335.500 to 335.599, and shall also be reimbursed the necessary traveling, hotel, and contingent expenses incurred in attending the meetings of the board and in performing the duties of the board. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 364, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2002).  This statute was amended by 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2002. Section 13 of that Act reads, "Members of the Kentucky Board of Certification for Professional Counselors as of the effective date of this Act may serve as members of the Kentucky Board of Licensed Professional Counselors created in Section 3 of this Act until the expiration of their terms. Vacancies to the Kentucky Board of Licensed Professional counselors shall be filled under the provisions of Section 3 of this Act." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31958</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>