<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="325" order_by="325">PUBLIC ACCOUNTANTS </unit></structure><section_number>325.280Qualifications</section_number><catch_line>for licensure as certified public accountant by reciprocity and for foreign accountants.   </catch_line><order_by>280Qualifications</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board may issue a license to practice by reciprocity, if the applicant submits an application for a license to practice any regulated activity, upon forms approved by the board, that includes all required fees, in the amounts as determined by administrative regulation promulgated by the board, and meets the following requirements: <section prefix="a">The applicant received a grade on the Uniform Certified Public Accountants Examination in another state that was equivalent to a passing grade at the time in this Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="b">The applicant holds a valid active license, and is in good standing as a certified public accountant, issued under the laws of any other state; and </section><section prefix="c"><section prefix="1">The applicant meets all current experience requirements in this Commonwealth at the time application is made; or </section><section prefix="2">Within the ten (10) years immediately preceding the application, had four (4) years of experience in the practice of the regulated activities acceptable to the board upon which the license was based. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">The board may issue a license to practice the regulated activities without examination to an applicant who holds a valid license to engage in the practice of the regulated activities in good standing from a foreign country if: <section prefix="a">The applicant's foreign country makes similar provisions to allow a person who holds a valid license to practice the regulated activities issued by this Commonwealth to obtain that foreign country's comparable designation; </section><section prefix="b">The authority of the foreign country that issued the designation regulates the practice of the regulated activities, including the issuance of reports; </section><section prefix="c">The foreign designation was granted upon education and examination requirements which were established by the foreign authority or law and were substantially equivalent to those in effect in this Commonwealth at the time the foreign designation was granted; </section><section prefix="d">The applicant satisfies the applicable experience requirement contained in paragraph (c) of subsection (1) of this section; </section><section prefix="e">The applicant has successfully passed a uniform qualifying examination on United States national standards approved by the board; and </section><section prefix="f">The applicant submits an application for a license to practice the regulated activities, upon forms approved by the board, that includes all required fees, in the amounts as determined by administrative regulation promulgated by the board. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 107, sec. 4, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 34, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 5, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 248, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 285, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 8, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 143, sec. 7. -- Created 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 210, secs. 3 (7), (8) and 4. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:54</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44596</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>