<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.60-115Definitions</section_number><catch_line>for KRS 224.60-120 to 224.60-150. </catch_line><order_by>60-115Definitions</order_by><text>As used in KRS 224.60-120 to 224.60-150, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Bodily injury and property damage" means only those actual economic losses to an individual or the individual's property resulting from bodily injuries and damages to property caused by a release into the environment from a petroleum storage tank. In this context, property damage includes damage to natural resources; </section><section prefix="2">"Cabinet" means the Energy and Environment Cabinet; </section><section prefix="3">"Claim" means any demand in writing for a certain sum; </section><section prefix="4">"Corrective action" means those actions necessary to protect human health and the environment in the event of a release from a petroleum storage tank. Corrective action includes initial responses taken pursuant to KRS 224.60-135, remedial actions to clean up contaminated groundwater, surface waters, or soil, actions to address residual effects after initial corrective action is taken, and actions taken to restore or replace potable water supplies. Corrective action also includes actions necessary to monitor, assess, and evaluate a release, as well as actions necessary to monitor, assess, and evaluate the effectiveness of remedial action after a release has occurred; </section><section prefix="5">"Dealer" has the same meaning as in KRS 138.210; </section><section prefix="6">"Division" means the Division of Waste Management; </section><section prefix="7">"Facility" means, with respect to any owner or operator, all petroleum storage tanks which are owned or operated by an owner or operator and are located on a single parcel of property or on any contiguous or adjacent property; </section><section prefix="8">"Federal regulations" means regulations for underground petroleum storage tanks promulgated by the United States Environmental Protection Agency pursuant to Subtitle I of the Solid Waste Disposal Act, as amended by the Resource Conservation and Recovery Act; </section><section prefix="9">"Free product" means a regulated substance that is present as a non-aqueous phase liquid; </section><section prefix="10">"Fund" means the petroleum storage tank environmental assurance fund and its subaccounts, the financial responsibility account and the petroleum storage tank account established pursuant to KRS 224.60-140; </section><section prefix="11">"Gasoline" has the same meaning as in KRS 138.210; </section><section prefix="12">"Motor fuel" means petroleum or a petroleum-based substance that is motor gasoline, aviation gasoline, No. 1 or No. 2 diesel fuel, or any grade of gasohol, that is typically used in the operation of a motor engine, jet fuel, and any petroleum or petroleum-based substance typically used in the operation of a motor vehicle, including used motor vehicle lubricants and oils; </section><section prefix="13">"Occurrence" means a release, or releases, of an accidental nature, requiring corrective action, from a petroleum storage tank or tanks located at the same facility, due to continuous or repeated exposure to conditions. An additional release or releases at the same facility in which the area requiring remedial action is separate from a previous remediation area or areas shall be considered a separate occurrence; </section><section prefix="14">"Person" means an individual, trust, firm, joint stock company, federal agency, corporation, the state, a municipality, commission, or political subdivision of the state. The term includes a consortium, a joint venture, the United States government, or a commercial entity; </section><section prefix="15">"Petroleum" and "petroleum products" means crude oil, or any fraction thereof, which is liquid at standard conditions of temperature and pressure, which means at sixty (60) degrees Fahrenheit and 14.7 pounds per square inch absolute. The term includes motor gasoline, gasohol, other alcohol-blended fuels, diesel fuel, heating oil, special fuels, lubricants, and used oil; </section><section prefix="16">"Petroleum storage tank" means an underground storage tank, as defined by KRS 224.60-100, which contains petroleum or petroleum products but, for the purpose of participation or eligibility for the fund, shall only include tanks containing motor fuels and shall not include petroleum storage tanks used exclusively for storage of fuel used in the operation of a commercial ship or vessel or tanks used exclusively for storage of fuel used for the purposes of powering locomotives or tanks owned by a federal agency or the United States government; </section><section prefix="17">"Petroleum storage tank operator" means any person in control of, or having responsibility for, the daily operation of a petroleum storage tank; </section><section prefix="18">"Petroleum storage tank owner" means the person who owns a petroleum storage tank, except that petroleum storage tank owner does not include any person who, without participation in the management of a petroleum storage tank, holds indicia of ownership primarily to protect a security interest in the tank; </section><section prefix="19">"Received" has the same meaning as in KRS 138.210; </section><section prefix="20">"Release" means any spilling, leaking, emitting, discharging, escaping, leaching, or disposing from a petroleum storage tank into groundwater, surface water, or surface or subsurface soils. The term shall not include releases that are permitted or authorized by the state or federal law; </section><section prefix="21">"Special fuels" has the same meaning as in KRS 138.210; and </section><section prefix="22">"Third party" means a person other than the owner or operator of a facility, or the agents or employees of the owner or operator, who sustains bodily injury or property damage as a result of a release from that facility. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 67, sec. 20, effective March 25, 2015. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 377, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 24, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 361, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 284, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 498, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 295, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 419, sec. 1, effective April 11, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 450, sec. 1, effective April 13, 1992. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 370, sec. 2, effective April 9, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> March 25, 2015 </effective><former-codification> KRS 224.816. </former-codification><lrc-note>(2/9/93). -- When this statute was created in 1990, the introductory phrase "As used in KRS 224.60-120 to 224.60-150, unless the context otherwise requires:" appeared before subsection (1) of the statute. See 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 370, sec. 2. The 1992 amendment to this statute, however, did not include this language. See 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 450, sec. 1. This erroneous omission has been corrected by restoring the language in question as required by KRS 446.280. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:32</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44024</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>