<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17-030</section_number><catch_line>Scope and format of policy. </catch_line><order_by>17-030</order_by><text>No policy of health insurance shall be delivered or issued for delivery to any person in this state unless it otherwise complies with this title, and complies with the following: <section prefix="1">The entire money and other considerations therefor shall be expressed therein; </section><section prefix="2">The time when the insurance takes effect and terminates shall be expressed therein; </section><section prefix="3">It shall purport to insure only one (1) person, except that a policy may insure, originally or by subsequent amendment, upon the application of an adult member of a family, who shall be deemed the policyholder, any two (2) or more eligible members of that family, including husband, wife, unmarried dependent children to age nineteen (19), unmarried children from nineteen (19) to twenty-five (25) years of age who are full-time students enrolled in and attending an accredited educational institution and who are primarily dependent on the policyholder for maintenance and support, and any other person dependent upon the policyholder as provided pursuant to KRS 304.17-310; </section><section prefix="4">The style, arrangement, and overall appearance of the policy shall give no undue prominence to any portion of the text, and every printed portion of the text of the policy and of any indorsements or attached papers shall be plainly printed in light-faced type of a style in general use, the size of which shall be uniform and not less than ten (10) point with a lower case unspaced alphabet length not less than one hundred and twenty (120) point (the "text" shall include all printed matter except the name and address of the insurer, name on title of the policy, the brief description, if any, and captions and subcaptions); </section><section prefix="5">The exceptions and reductions of indemnity shall be set forth in the policy and other than those contained in KRS 304.17-050 to 304.17-290, inclusive, shall be printed, at the insurer's option, either included with the benefit provision to which they apply, or under an appropriate caption such as "Exceptions," or "Exceptions and Reductions," except that if an exception or reduction specifically applies only to a particular benefit of the policy, a statement of the exception or reduction shall be included with the benefit provision to which it applies; </section><section prefix="6">Each form, including riders and indorsements, shall be identified by a form number in the lower left-hand corner of the first page thereof; and </section><section prefix="7">The policy shall contain no provision purporting to make any portion of the charter, rules, constitution, or bylaws of the insurer a part of the policy unless the portion is set forth in full in the policy, except in the case of the incorporation of, or reference to, a statement of rates or classification of risks, or short-rate table filed with the commissioner. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1201, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 483, sec. 18, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 17, sec. 3, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:06</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17288</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>