<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.20-045</section_number><catch_line>Insurance or guarantee by authority. </catch_line><order_by>20-045</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The authority may insure, guarantee, or issue letters of credit for all or a part of a loan or debenture of others, public or private. </section><section prefix="2">The authority may insure, guarantee, or issue letters of credit for all or a part of a lease entered into by others, public or private. </section><section prefix="3">The authority may procure insurance, a guarantee, or a letter of credit from any source for all or a part of a loan, debenture, or lease of others, public or private. The authority may procure insurance, a guarantee, or a letter of credit for either a single loan, debenture, or lease or for any combination of loans, debentures, or leases. </section><section prefix="4">The authority may insure, guarantee, or issue letters of credit for all or a part of a revenue bond issued by the authority, another state agency or authority, or another entity or authority authorized by law to issue revenue bonds. </section><section prefix="5">The authority may procure insurance, a guarantee, or a letter of credit for all or a part of a revenue bond issue of the authority, another state agency or authority, or another entity or authority authorized by law to issue revenue bonds. The authority may procure insurance, a guarantee, or a letter of credit for either all or part of a single revenue bond issue or for all or a part of any combination of revenue bond issues. </section></text><history>Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 383, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1988 </effective><former-codification> KRS 154.047 </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2669</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>