<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">C STATE AID TO LOCAL EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>39C.050</section_number><catch_line>Criteria for funding local emergency management agencies. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text>Local emergency management agencies created pursuant to KRS 39B.010 shall be eligible to apply for benefits from the fund created pursuant to KRS 39C.010 and 39C.020 if they meet the following criteria: <section prefix="1">The local emergency management agency shall have a qualified, duly appointed local director who is capable of fully executing the duties of the position pursuant to KRS 39B.030. Unless the local director has already completed an introductory emergency management course or is determined by the director to be suitably qualified, during the first year of participation in the funding program, the local director, whether serving on a voluntary or paid basis, shall have successfully completed all correspondence courses specified by the division by administrative regulation. The local director shall also participate in an emergency management workshop when offered. Unless the local director has already completed an introductory emergency management course or is determined by the director to be suitably qualified, each local director shall also attend an introductory emergency management course when offered. <section prefix="a">In each following year, each local director shall attend an emergency management workshop, when offered. </section><section prefix="b">In subsequent years, a local director shall continue his or her education by annually completing advanced instruction offered by the division, including the training courses and the Emergency Management Development Program as required by administrative regulations promulgated by the division. The requirements of this section may be met by successfully completing related courses offered by federal agencies and other organizations, as approved by the division. </section></section><section prefix="2">Each local emergency management agency employee, other than the local director, whose salary is reimbursed in part by this fund, shall attend one (1) emergency management workshop at least every other year, and shall complete other instruction offered by the division as required by administrative regulations promulgated by the division. </section><section prefix="3">The local director appointed pursuant to KRS Chapters 39A to 39F, shall develop a local emergency operations plan and appropriate annexes. This plan shall be subject to concurrence review by the director of the division. In subsequent years, the plan and all annexes shall annually be reviewed, updated, approved, and officially adopted in accordance with the provisions of KRS Chapters 39A to 39F. </section><section prefix="4">During the second and each subsequent year of participation in the program, the local director shall conduct an exercise to test the local emergency operations plan in accordance with exercise program requirements and guidelines of the Federal Emergency Management Agency or the division. </section><section prefix="5">Each local emergency management agency created pursuant to KRS Chapters 39A to 39F shall provide for an organized and designated emergency operating center in the local jurisdiction from which all operations of the local disaster and emergency services organization shall be coordinated. This center shall provide resources for communications, information management, and other operational capabilities necessary to ensure the coordination of all disaster and emergency response in the local jurisdiction. The local emergency operations center shall be a direction and control component of the integrated emergency management system of the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="6">Each local emergency management agency shall develop, and submit annually to the division, a program paper detailing agency administrative data, current staff personnel listings, a specific work plan of program objectives scheduled for accomplishment during the next fiscal year, and a budget request. Forms and guidance materials for this report shall be provided by the division. </section><section prefix="7">Each employee of a local emergency management agency created pursuant to this chapter with the exception of the local director and each deputy, if the deputy functions in a policymaking capacity, whose salary is reimbursed in part or in total with these funds, shall meet the standards of the Kentucky merit system, or the standards of the Federal Office of Personnel Management or its successor or local equivalent, when recognized by the director. </section><section prefix="8">In order for a local emergency management agency to participate in the funding program, one (1) of the following persons shall attend an annual emergency management workshop: <section prefix="a">The county judge/executive; </section><section prefix="b">The deputy county judge/executive; </section><section prefix="c">The mayor of an urban-county government, or of a consolidated local government, or of the largest city in the county, or the mayor of the city which is the county seat of the county, or the chief executive of other local government; </section><section prefix="d">The city manager; </section><section prefix="e">The local emergency management deputy director; or </section><section prefix="f">A member of the fiscal court, urban-county council, or consolidated local government of the county. </section></section><section prefix="9">The division shall determine by administrative regulation: <section prefix="a">Public officials and disaster and emergency services personnel who may be reimbursed for attendance at emergency management workshops or other activities; and </section><section prefix="b">Reimbursements for attending courses and workshops, which shall be limited as follows: <section prefix="1">Reimbursement rates for meals and travel mileage shall not exceed those for state employees. </section><section prefix="2">Reimbursement shall be made for attending the workshop or course nearest to the participant's residence. A participant may attend a workshop at a greater distance but will be reimbursed for meals and mileage equal to that of attending the nearest workshop or course. In cases of extreme hardship, the nearest course or workshop requirement may be waived, in writing, by the director. </section></section></section><section prefix="10">The division shall: <section prefix="a">Publicize all available state and federal emergency management agency training courses to mayors, county judges/executive, and local directors; and </section><section prefix="b">Assist local personnel listed in this section in gaining entrance to state and federal emergency management agency training courses. </section></section><section prefix="11">If, at any time, the director of the division determines that a local emergency management agency or a local director does not comply with the eligibility requirements of this section, the director shall notify that local director and the appointing authorities, in writing, of the intent to deny financial assistance to the local emergency management agency. The local director shall have ten (10) working days to come into compliance or otherwise provide information to the director to justify eligibility for funding. If the director continues to determine that the local emergency management agency or the local director does not meet eligibility requirements, the local emergency management agency shall be ineligible for funds and the director shall notify the local director and the appointing authorities, of the determination. A local director aggrieved by a decision of the director may appeal to the Franklin Circuit Court within twenty (20) days of the receipt of the director's decision. The court's review shall be from the record and shall not be de novo. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 10, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 44, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21755</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>