<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="70" order_by="70">SHERIFFS, CONSTABLES, AND COUNTY POLICE FORCE </unit></structure><section_number>70.293Terms</section_number><catch_line>of employment of retired police officer.   </catch_line><order_by>293Terms</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Individuals employed under KRS 70.291 to 70.293 shall: <section prefix="a">Serve for a term not to exceed one (1) year. The one (1) year employment term may be renewed annually at the discretion of the employing sheriff's office; </section><section prefix="b">Receive compensation according to the standard procedures applicable to the employing sheriff's office; and </section><section prefix="c">Be employed based upon need as determined by the employing sheriff's office. </section></section><section prefix="2">Notwithstanding any provisions of KRS 16.505 to 16.652, 18A.225 to 18A.2287, 61.510 to 61.705, or 78.510 to 78.852 to the contrary: <section prefix="a">Individuals employed under KRS 70.291 to 70.293 shall continue to receive all retirement and health insurance benefits to which they were entitled upon retiring in the applicable system administered by Kentucky Retirement Systems; </section><section prefix="b">Individuals employed under KRS 70.291 to 70.293 shall not be eligible to receive health insurance coverage through the sheriff's office or the fiscal court of the sheriff's county; </section><section prefix="c">The sheriff's office or fiscal court of the sheriff's office shall not pay any employer contributions or retiree health expense reimbursements to the Kentucky Retirement Systems required by KRS 61.637(17) for individuals employed under KRS 70.291 to 70.293; and </section><section prefix="d">The sheriff's office or fiscal court of the sheriff's office shall not pay any insurance contributions to the state health insurance plan, as provided by KRS 18A.225 to 18A.2287, for individuals employed under KRS 70.291 to 70.293. </section></section><section prefix="3">Individuals employed under KRS 70.291 to 70.293 shall be subject to any merit system, civil service, or other legislative due process provisions applicable to the sheriff's office. A decision not to renew a one (1) year appointment term under this section shall not be considered a disciplinary action or deprivation subject to due process. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 3, effective June 24, 2015. -- Created 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 96, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44502</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>