<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="223" order_by="223">SANITARIANS, WATER PLANT OPERATORS, AND WATER WELL CONSTRUCTION PRACTICES </unit></structure><section_number>223.415</section_number><catch_line>Appointments to board -- Meetings -- Payment of expenses. </catch_line><order_by>415</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall be appointed by the Governor upon the advice of the secretary after soliciting recommendations of interested parties. All members of the board shall be residents of the Commonwealth. The board shall be composed of the following: <section prefix="a">A driller who is an active member of both the National Water Well Association and the Kentucky Water Well Association and whose business is actively involved in drilling water wells. This member shall serve for an initial term of three (3) years; </section><section prefix="b">A member who is a representative of the cabinet who shall serve as the executive secretary and treasurer of the board and shall be responsible for maintaining records, to serve for an initial term of three (3) years; </section><section prefix="c">A member who is a hydrogeologist or hydrologist from the Kentucky Geological Survey to serve for an initial term of two (2) years; </section><section prefix="d">Three (3) members who are water well drillers and who are presently in the business of drilling wells, each representing a different geographic region within the Commonwealth, to serve for an initial term of two (2) years; and </section><section prefix="e">A member from the public at large, who shall not be in any way connected with a water well business, to serve for an initial term of two (2) years. </section></section><section prefix="2">Upon the expiration of the respective terms, each successor shall be appointed in the same manner as the predecessor for a term of three (3) years. </section><section prefix="3">At the first meeting of the board held in each calendar year, the board shall elect a chairperson who shall serve for one (1) year. A majority of members shall decide upon rules of procedure. </section><section prefix="4">The board shall hold as many meetings a year as are necessary to effectuate the purpose of KRS 223.405 to 223.460, but the board must hold at least quarterly meetings. Notice of a meeting shall be sent to each member at least ten (10) days prior to the meeting. Five (5) members shall constitute a quorum. Rules of procedure adopted by the board may provide for such additional meetings as are necessary. </section><section prefix="5">The members of the board shall serve without compensation but may be reimbursed for all actual and necessary expenses incurred while discharging their official duties. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 26, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 215, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9976</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>