<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="150" order_by="150">FISH AND WILDLIFE RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>150.180</section_number><catch_line>Buying, selling, or transporting protected wildlife, mussels and fishes, raw fur, or processed wildlife. </catch_line><order_by>180</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as otherwise provided for in this chapter, and subject to regulations adopted under this chapter, no person, for himself or as the agent or employee of another shall buy, or sell, or attempt to buy, or sell, barter, exchange, or trade, or have in possession for the purpose of selling, bartering, or trading any protected wildlife or part thereof, raw fur or processed wildlife, no matter where or when caught or killed, whether caught or killed in this state or in any other state or other country. </section><section prefix="2">Mussels and fishes, other than sport fishes as designated by departmental regulations, and all fishes, regardless of species, raised by licensed propagation permittees may be bought, sold, and transported, if in legal possession. </section><section prefix="3">Raw furs, if in legal possession, may be sold, transported, or shipped, by a licensed trapper or licensed hunter to a licensed fur buyer (resident or nonresident), and by a licensed fur buyer to a licensed fur processor or to another fur buyer if in legal possession. A fur processor may hold raw furs or sell to another licensed fur processor at any time. </section><section prefix="4">Subject to regulations adopted under this chapter, a person who has been issued a license under this chapter and who has the license on his person may transport anywhere as a part of his personal baggage any protected wildlife legally taken by him under such license, not in excess of the number that the law or regulation permits him to have in possession at any one (1) time. </section><section prefix="5">A person who has legally taken any protected wildlife in another state and who has in his possession the license which authorizes such taking may, if the same be dead, transport the same in this state, as part of his personal baggage at any time during the open season for the particular species in the state in which taken or within ten (10) days after the close of such season. Any person may ship dead game or dead fish so taken subject to the provisions of the laws of the state in which the same was taken and the laws and regulations of the United States relating thereto. </section><section prefix="6">No person shall import or transport into the State of Kentucky or receive shipment in the state from without the state, any live fish or wildlife without first procuring from the department a written fish transportation permit or wildlife transportation permit. If it is determined upon inspection that such fish or wildlife would not constitute a menace to the state and are free from disease and other undesirable physical characteristics, the commissioner shall issue a permit for a fee to be determined by the Fish and Wildlife Commission by administrative regulation, pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A. A fish transportation permit shall be valid for one (1) year from the date of issuance, and a wildlife transportation permit shall be valid for specific dates as indicated on the permit. </section><section prefix="7">No person may at any time stock any species of fish secured from any source into the public waters of the Commonwealth without first securing a permit from the commissioner. </section><section prefix="8">This section shall not in any way interfere with the transportation of any fish or wildlife by authorized personnel of the department. </section><section prefix="9">Federal and state regulations shall govern the transportation of all migratory wild birds. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 127, sec. 4, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 353, sec. 3, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 365, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 178, sec. 5, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 38, sec. 9. -- Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 115, sec. 12. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 200, sec. 27. -- Amended 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 4; and ch. 78, sec. 9. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 84, sec. 5. -- Amended 1944 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 3. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 68, sec. 18. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 1893d-11, 1954d-14. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1972</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>