<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="402" order_by="402">MARRIAGE </unit></structure><section_number>402.210</section_number><catch_line>Issuance of license when either party under eighteen. </catch_line><order_by>210</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If either of the parties is under eighteen (18) but over sixteen (16) years of age and not before married, no license shall issue without the consent required by KRS 402.020(1)(f), personally given or certified in writing to the clerk over the signature of the person consenting in accordance with KRS 402.020(1)(f), attested by two (2) subscribing witnesses and proved by the oath of one (1) of the witnesses, administered by the clerk. If the parties are personally unknown to the clerk, a license shall not issue until bond, with good surety, in the penalty of one hundred dollars ($100) is given to the Commonwealth, with condition that there is no lawful cause to obstruct the marriage. </section><section prefix="2">If either of the parties is under sixteen (16) years of age, no license shall issue without the permission of a District Judge, as required by KRS 402.020(1)(f)3., in the form of a certified copy of a written court order. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 122, sec. 3, effective March 26, 1998 and ch. 258, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 212, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 386, sec. 93. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 15. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2106. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/98).  This section was amended by 1998 Ky. Acts chs 122 and 258 which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36487</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>