<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.350</section_number><catch_line>General powers and duties of boards of regents. </catch_line><order_by>350</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The government of each of the state universities and the Kentucky Community and Technical College System is vested in its respective board of regents. Each board of regents, when its members have been appointed and qualified, shall constitute a body corporate, with the usual corporate powers, and with all immunities, rights, privileges, and franchises usually attaching to the governing bodies of educational institutions. Each board may: <section prefix="a">Receive grants of money and expend the same for the use and benefit of the university or college; </section><section prefix="b">Adopt bylaws, rules, and regulations for the government of its members, officers, agents, and employees, and enforce obedience to such rules; </section><section prefix="c">Require such reports from the president, officers, faculty, and employees as it deems necessary and proper from time to time; </section><section prefix="d">Determine the number of divisions, departments, bureaus, offices, and agencies needed for the successful conduct of the affairs of the university or college; and </section><section prefix="e">Grant diplomas and confer degrees upon the recommendation of the president and faculty. </section></section><section prefix="2">Each board of regents shall periodically evaluate the institution's progress in implementing its missions, goals, and objectives to conform to the strategic agenda. Officers and officials shall be held accountable for the status of the institution's progress. </section><section prefix="3">In addition to the duties required in subsections (1) and (2) of this section, the board of regents for the Kentucky Community and Technical College System, upon recommendation of the president of the system, shall: <section prefix="a">Develop and implement guidelines for the preparation of biennial budget requests by the administrators of the colleges within the system. The guidelines shall define the processes for review and approval by the boards of directors for the colleges; </section><section prefix="b">Adopt a biennial budget request for the Kentucky Community and Technical College System upon the recommendation of the president of the system; </section><section prefix="c">Adopt an allocation process for distributing funds to the colleges within the system; </section><section prefix="d">Consider recommendations from the boards of directors of the colleges to improve the overall budget planning and allocation processes; </section><section prefix="e">Designate each college with a name; </section><section prefix="f">Encourage and accept donations of land and funds to be used in the acquisition, construction, or operations of colleges in the system. The board may commemorate donations from private persons or corporations with suitable memorials; and </section><section prefix="g">Accept federal grants when deemed appropriate to be used in the acquisition, construction, or operations of colleges in the system. </section></section> The board of regents shall assure that the budget planning and implementation processes are consistent with the adopted strategic agenda and biennial budget and with the missions of the institutions within the system. </text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 56, sec. 3, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 101, effective May 30, 1997. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4527-44. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, K, 11, (6) at 659. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4268</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>