<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="235" order_by="235">BOATS AND BOATING </unit></structure><section_number>235.050</section_number><catch_line>Application for title and registration -- Accompanying documents. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, before the owner or operator of each motorboat required to be registered and numbered by KRS 235.040 may operate it or permit its operation upon the waters of this state, the owner shall apply for title and registration to the county clerk of the county in which he resides, except, if the motorboat is to be operated principally in a county other than the county of the owner's residence the owner may apply for title and registration to the county clerk of the county in which the motorboat is to be principally operated. A motorboat last titled and registered in another state and purchased by a person for operation in this state shall be first titled and registered in this state by and in the name of the purchaser and not in the name of the seller. The application for title and registration shall be accompanied by: <section prefix="a">A bill of sale, if the application is for registration of a new motorboat; or </section><section prefix="b">The owner's registration receipt if the motorboat was last registered in this state; or </section><section prefix="c">A bill of sale and the previous registration receipt if last registered in another state; and </section><section prefix="d">The annual registration fee. </section></section><section prefix="2">Motorboats shall be registered annually. If an application for title and registration is filed with the county clerk prior to the annual registration date established by the Transportation Cabinet, the registration period shall include less than twelve (12) consecutive months and registration fees shall be computed at a rate of one-twelfth (1/12) of the appropriate annual registration fee set out in KRS 235.080 per month of the remaining registration period. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 289, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 163, sec. 5, effective January 1, 1990. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 233, sec. 4, effective June 17, 1978; and ch. 263, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 292, sec. 4. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 68, Art. VIII, sec. 5, effective March 17, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11045</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>