<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">COUNTY GOVERNMENT (FISCAL COURTS AND COUNTY COMMISSIONERS) </unit></structure><section_number>67.928</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of Sections 99 and 144 constitutional offices within unified territory -- Funding responsibilities and oversight duties unaffected by unification. </catch_line><order_by>928</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided in subsection (2) of this section, all offices provided for in Sections 99 and 144 of the Constitution of Kentucky shall remain in existence upon the unification of a county and a participating city or cities pursuant to KRS 67.900 to 67.940. However, all existing powers and duties of the offices shall be assigned to the unified local government. </section><section prefix="2">Nothing in KRS 67.900 to 67.940 shall alter or affect the election or term of any county court clerk, county attorney, coroner, jailer, sheriff, surveyor, or assessor. Nor shall any provision of KRS 67.900 to 67.940 be construed to alter or affect the powers, duties, or responsibilities of these officers as prescribed by the Constitution and laws of the Commonwealth of Kentucky. Any funding responsibilities or oversight of any constitutional officers or their employees previously exercised by the county, which shall include the approval of the annual budget of the sheriff’s and the county clerk’s offices, shall be transferred to the unified local government. </section></text><history> Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 246, sec. 15, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23829</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>