<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="278" order_by="278">PUBLIC SERVICE COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>278.017</section_number><catch_line>Establishing boundaries of certified areas. </catch_line><order_by>017</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as otherwise provided in this section, the boundaries of the certified territory of each retail electric supplier are hereby set as a line or lines substantially equidistant between its existing distribution lines and the nearest existing distribution lines of any other retail electric supplier in every direction, with the result that there is hereby certified to each retail electric supplier such area which in its entirety is located substantially in closer proximity to one of its existing distribution lines than to the nearest existing distribution line of any other retail electric supplier.  </section><section prefix="2">On or before one hundred twenty (120) days after June 16, 1972, or, when requested in writing by a retail electric supplier and for good cause shown, such further time as the commission may fix by order, each retail electric supplier shall file with the commission a map or maps showing all of its existing distribution lines. The commission shall prepare or cause to be prepared within one hundred twenty (120) days thereafter a map or maps of uniform scale to show, accurately and clearly, the boundaries of the certified territory of each retail electric supplier as established under subsection (1) of this section, and shall issue such map or maps of certified territory to each retail electric supplier. Any retail electric supplier who feels itself aggrieved by reason of a certification of territory pursuant to this section may protest the certification of territory within a one hundred twenty day period after issuance of the map of certified territory by the commission; and the commission shall have the power, after hearing, to revise or vacate such certified territories or portions thereof.  </section><section prefix="3">In such hearing, the commission shall be guided by the following conditions as they existed on June 16, 1972:  <section prefix="a">The proximity of existing distribution lines to such certified territory.  </section><section prefix="b">Which supplier was first furnishing retail electric service, and the age of existing facilities in the area.  </section><section prefix="c">The adequacy and dependability of existing distribution lines to provide dependable, high quality retail electric service at reasonable costs.  </section><section prefix="d">The elimination and prevention of duplication of electric lines and facilities supplying such territory. In its determination of such protest, the commission hearing shall be de novo; and neither supplier shall bear the burden of proof.  </section></section><section prefix="4">In each area, where the commission shall determine that the existing distribution lines of two or more retail electric suppliers are so intertwined or located that subsection (1) of this section cannot reasonably be applied, the commission shall, after hearing, certify the service territory or territories for the retail electric suppliers under the provisions of subsection (3) of this section.  </section></text><history>Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 4, effective July 15,1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 379, sec. 4, effective April 1, 1979. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 83, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1982 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14040</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>