<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.3-660</section_number><catch_line>Annual report of commissioner. </catch_line><order_by>3-660</order_by><text>Each June, the commissioner shall make a report to the Governor setting forth: <section prefix="1">A summary of the condition of every bank or trust company organized and doing business under the laws of this state, subject to examination and inspection under this subtitle, and such other information relating to such banks and trust companies, as, in the commissioner's judgment, may be useful; </section><section prefix="2">A statement of every bank or trust company whose business has been closed during the year, that has failed or voluntarily retired during the year; </section><section prefix="3">The name of banks or trust companies placed in the commissioner's hands in process of liquidation, and the amount of dividends paid thereon; </section><section prefix="4">Any proposed amendment of the laws relating to banks and trust companies, by which the system, in the commissioner's judgment, may be improved, and by which the security of creditors, depositors, and stockholders may be increased. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 645, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 324, sec. 37, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 231. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 165a-21. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 287.660.</former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  In accordance with 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, secs. 38 and 39, this statute has been renumbered as a section of the Kentucky Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286, and KRS references within this statute have been adjusted to conform with the 2006 renumbering of that code. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14593</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>