<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="278" order_by="278">PUBLIC SERVICE COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>278.510</section_number><catch_line>Consolidation of telephone lines. </catch_line><order_by>510</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No telephone company doing an exchange business in a city shall consolidate with any other telephone company doing an exchange business in the same city, or purchase, lease or operate the plant or line of any such company, until the proper city authorities have found, after such investigation as they deem necessary, that no substantial public benefits result from the separate existence of the companies and that actual competitive conditions do not exist, and have stated their finding in a resolution consenting to such consolidation, lease, sale or operating arrangement. </section><section prefix="2">No telephone company doing a toll line business shall consolidate with any other company doing a like business whose lines serve the same communities or localities, or purchase, lease or operate the plant or lines of any such company until the Public Service Commission has found, after such investigation as it deems necessary, that no substantial public benefits result from the separate existence of the companies and that actual competitive conditions do not exist, and has stated its finding in a resolution consenting to such consolidation, lease, sale or operating arrangement. Whenever a joint application of two (2) or more such telephone companies requesting such finding and consent is filed with the Public Service Commission, the commission shall make such investigation, hold such hearings, examine such witnesses and require the production of such books, papers, and records as it deems pertinent to the determination of the application, and shall grant or withhold such consent as the facts warrant. </section><section prefix="3">The Public Service Commission shall have jurisdiction of those matters set out in Section 201 of the Constitution that relate to telephone companies, and shall enter in its minutes a record of its acts in relation thereto. </section></text><history>Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 48, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 379, sec. 52, effective April 1, 1979. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 4679e-1, 4679e-2, 4679e-4. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1982</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14141</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>