<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6">THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY </unit></structure><section_number>6.955</section_number><catch_line>Fiscal note required for bill or resolution of Legislature or executive order relating to local government. </catch_line><order_by>955</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No bill or resolution which relates to any aspect of local government or any service provided thereby shall be voted on by either chamber of the General Assembly unless a fiscal note has been prepared and attached to the bill pursuant to KRS 6.960, except that, if in the chamber in which the bill is being considered, two-thirds (2/3) of the members elected vote to waive the fiscal note requirement, no note shall be required. The fiscal note waiver shall be certified by the clerk of the chamber in which the bill is being considered, and such certification shall be attached to the bill. Although waived in one chamber, a fiscal note shall be required when the bill goes to the other chamber unless a majority of the members elected to such chamber vote to waive the fiscal note requirement. </section><section prefix="2">An executive order which relates to any aspect of local government or any service provided thereby shall not be issued unless a fiscal note has been prepared and made a part of the order pursuant to KRS 6.960. </section></text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2003. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 215, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=423</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>