<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="333" order_by="333">MEDICAL LABORATORIES </unit></structure><section_number>333.240</section_number><catch_line>Prohibited actions. </catch_line><order_by>240</order_by><text>No person shall: <section prefix="1">Operate, maintain or direct a medical laboratory, as herein defined, which is not exempt under KRS 333.040, unless a medical laboratory license has been obtained from the cabinet. </section><section prefix="2">Conduct, maintain, or operate a nonexempt medical laboratory unless such laboratory is under the direction of an individual authorized by KRS 333.090. </section><section prefix="3">Accept specimens for tests from and make reports to persons who are not legally qualified or authorized to submit specimens to medical laboratories and to receive such reports. However, this does not prohibit the referral of specimens from one licensed medical laboratory to another laboratory licensed or approved under this chapter providing the report indicated clearly the medical laboratory performing the test and the name of the director of such medical laboratory. </section><section prefix="4">Either personally or through an agent, solicit referral of specimens to his or any other medical laboratory or contract to perform medical laboratory examinations of specimens in a manner which offers or implies an offer or rebates to a person or persons submitting specimens, other fee-splitting inducements, participation in any fee-splitting arrangements, or other unearned remuneration. </section><section prefix="5">Violate or aid and abet in the violation of any provision of this chapter or the rules or regulations promulgated hereunder. </section></text><history>Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 180, sec. 25. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31863</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>