<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="503" order_by="503">GENERAL PRINCIPLES OF JUSTIFICATION </unit></structure><section_number>503.080</section_number><catch_line>Protection of property. </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The use of physical force by a defendant upon another person is justifiable when the defendant believes that such force is immediately necessary to prevent: <section prefix="a">The commission of criminal trespass, robbery, burglary, or other felony involving the use of force, or under those circumstances permitted pursuant to KRS 503.055, in a dwelling, building or upon real property in his possession or in the possession of another person for whose protection he acts; or </section><section prefix="b">Theft, criminal mischief, or any trespassory taking of tangible, movable property in his possession or in the possession of another person for whose protection he acts. </section></section><section prefix="2">The use of deadly physical force by a defendant upon another person is justifiable under subsection (1) only when the defendant believes that the person against whom such force is used is: <section prefix="a">Attempting to dispossess him of his dwelling otherwise than under a claim of right to its possession; or </section><section prefix="b">Committing or attempting to commit a burglary, robbery, or other felony involving the use of force, or under those circumstances permitted pursuant to KRS 503.055, of such dwelling; or </section><section prefix="c">Committing or attempting to commit arson of a dwelling or other building in his possession. </section></section><section prefix="3">A person does not have a duty to retreat if the person is in a place where he or she has a right to be. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 192, sec. 5, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 33, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19673</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>