<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.590</section_number><catch_line>Duties of Breast Cancer Research and Education Trust Fund Board. </catch_line><order_by>590</order_by><text>The Breast Cancer Research and Education Trust Fund Board created by KRS 211.585 shall: <section prefix="1">Develop a written plan for the expenditure of trust funds made available under KRS 211.580. The initial plan shall be completed on or before October 1, 2005, and shall be updated on an annual basis on or before October 1 of each year thereafter. The plan shall, at a minimum, include the following: <section prefix="a">A summary of existing breast cancer education, awareness, treatment, and screening programs provided to residents of Kentucky by type of program and by geographic area; </section><section prefix="b">A needs assessment for the Commonwealth of Kentucky that identifies additional programs that are needed by program type and geographic area, with support for why the identified programs are needed; and </section><section prefix="c">A prioritized list of programs and research projects that the board will address with funding available through the competitive grant program established under subsection (2) of this section; </section></section><section prefix="2">Promulgate administrative regulations to establish a competitive grant program to provide funding to not-for-profit entities, educational institutions, and government agencies in Kentucky offering programs or services in the areas of breast cancer research, education, awareness, treatment, and screening. <section prefix="a">The grant program shall give preference to programs proposing to serve the medically underserved population. </section><section prefix="b">The grant program shall provide funding to projects and programs in accordance with the priorities established in the plan developed under subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="c">The administrative regulations shall, at a minimum: <section prefix="1">Establish an application process and requirements; </section><section prefix="2">Set forth program and outcome measurement requirements; </section><section prefix="3">Establish an application review and award process; and </section><section prefix="4">Provide monitoring, oversight, and reporting requirements for funded programs; </section></section></section><section prefix="3">Promulgate administrative regulations necessary to carry out the provisions of KRS 211.580 to 211.590; and </section><section prefix="4">Provide to the Governor and the Legislative Research Commission an annual report by October 1 of each year. The report shall include: <section prefix="a">The plan developed under subsection (1) of this section for the expenditure of funds for the current and next fiscal year; </section><section prefix="b">A summary of the use and impact of prior year funds; </section><section prefix="c">A summary of the activities of the board during the prior fiscal year; and </section><section prefix="d">Any recommendations for future initiatives or action regarding breast cancer research, education, awareness, treatment, and screening. </section></section></text><history> Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 27, sec. 4, effective June 20, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8439</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>