<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="520" order_by="520">ESCAPE AND OTHER OFFENSES RELATING TO CUSTODY </unit></structure><section_number>520.110</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 520.120 and 520.130. </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For the purposes of KRS 520.120 and 520.130, a person renders assistance to another when he:  <section prefix="a">Harbors or conceals such person; or  </section><section prefix="b">Warns such person of impending discovery or apprehension, except that this does not apply to a warning given in connection with an effort to bring another into compliance with law; or  </section><section prefix="c">Provides such person with money, transportation, weapon, disguise or other means of avoiding discovery or apprehension; or  </section><section prefix="d">Prevents or obstructs, by means of force, deception or intimidation, anyone from performing an act that might aid in the discovery or apprehension of such person; or  </section><section prefix="e">Volunteers false information to a law enforcement officer; or  </section><section prefix="f">Suppresses by an act of concealment, alteration or destruction any physical evidence that might aid in the discovery or apprehension of such person.  </section></section><section prefix="2">In any prosecution for hindering prosecution or apprehension it is a defense that the accused is the spouse, parent, child, brother, sister, grandparent or grandchild of the person whose discovery or apprehension he sought to prevent.  </section></text><history>Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 179, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 1975</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19878</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>