<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="95" order_by="95">CITY POLICE AND FIRE DEPARTMENTS </unit></structure><section_number>95.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 95.160 to 95.290 and KRS 95.830 to 95.845.   </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in KRS 95.160 to 95.290 and in KRS 95.830 to 95.845, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="a">"Dismissal" means the discharge of an employee by the division or department head, civil service board, or other lawful authority; </section><section prefix="b">"Eligible list" means a list of names of persons who have been found qualified through suitable competitive examinations for positions or classes of positions; </section><section prefix="c">"Fire department" means the officers, firefighters, and clerical or maintenance employees, including the chief of the fire department; </section><section prefix="d">"Member" means any person in the police or fire department, other than the chief or assistant chief of the department; </section><section prefix="e">"Police department" means the officers, policemen, and clerical or maintenance employees, including the chief of police; </section><section prefix="f">"Police force" means the officers and policemen of the police department, other than the chief of police; </section><section prefix="g">"Policeman" means a member of the police department below the rank of officer, other than a clerical or maintenance employee; </section><section prefix="h">"Salary" means any compensation received for services; and </section><section prefix="i">"Suspension" means the separation of an employee from the service for a temporary or fixed period of time, by his appointing authority, as a disciplinary measure. </section></section><section prefix="2">As used in KRS 95.440 to 95.630, the following words and terms shall have the following meaning, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="a">"Dismissal" means the discharge of an employee by the division or department head, civil service board, or other lawful authority; </section><section prefix="b">"Eligible list" means a list of names of persons who have been found qualified through suitable competitive examinations for positions or classes of positions; </section><section prefix="c">"Fire department" means and includes all officers, firefighters, and clerical or maintenance employees of the fire department; </section><section prefix="d">"Police department" means and includes all officers, policemen, and clerical or maintenance employees of the police department; </section><section prefix="e">"Member" means any and all officers, firefighters, policemen, clerical or maintenance employees in the police or fire department, except as used in subsections (1) and (3) of KRS 95.440, and KRS 95.450, 95.460, 95.470, 95.550, 95.560, 95.565, 95.570 and 95.580; it shall not include the chief of police in an urban-county government; </section><section prefix="f">"Police force" means and includes all officers and policemen in the police department; </section><section prefix="g">"Policeman" means a member of the police department below the rank of officer, other than a clerical or maintenance employee; </section><section prefix="h">"Firefighter" means a member of the fire department below the rank of officer, other than a clerical or maintenance employee; </section><section prefix="i">"Salary" means any compensation received for services; </section><section prefix="j">"Suspension" means the separation of an employee from the service for a temporary or fixed period of time, by his appointing authority, as a disciplinary measure; and </section><section prefix="k">"Pension fund" shall mean the moneys derived from the members of the police and fire departments' salary or salaries and appropriations by the legislative body, or any other means derived from whatever source by gift or otherwise to be used for the retirement of members of the police and fire departments after the prescribed number of years of service, and for the benefit of disabled members of police and fire departments, and for the benefit of surviving spouses and dependent children or dependent fathers or mothers in the case of death of any member of the police or fire department within the scope of his employment. </section></section><section prefix="3">As used in KRS 95.761 to 95.785 the following words and terms shall have the following meaning: <section prefix="a">"Regular police department." For the purpose of KRS 95.761 to 95.785, a "regular police department" is defined as one having a fixed headquarters, where police equipment is maintained and where a policeman or policemen are in constant and uninterrupted attendance to receive and answer police calls, and execute regular police patrol duties; </section><section prefix="b">"Regular fire department." For the purpose of KRS 95.761 to 95.785, a "regular fire department" is defined as one having a fixed headquarters where firefighting apparatus and equipment are maintained, and where firefighters are in constant and uninterrupted attendance to receive and answer fire alarms; </section><section prefix="c">"Legislative body." Wherever in KRS 95.761 to 95.785 the term "body" or "legislative body" is employed, it shall be construed to mean the legislative branch of the city government or urban-county government; </section><section prefix="d">"Commission." The word "commission" shall mean the board of civil service commissioners, as established under the terms of KRS 95.761 to 95.785; </section><section prefix="e">"Trustees." The word "trustees" shall mean the board of pension fund trustees, as established under the terms of KRS 95.761 to 95.785; and </section><section prefix="f">"Pension fund." The term "pension fund" shall mean the moneys derived from the policeman or policemen and firefighter or firefighters salary or salaries, and appropriations by the legislative body, or any other sums derived from whatever source by gifts or otherwise to be used for the retirement of policeman or policemen and firefighter or firefighters after the prescribed number of years of service and for the benefit of disabled policeman or policemen and firefighter or firefighters, and for the benefit of surviving spouses and dependent children or dependent fathers or mothers in the case of death of a policeman or firefighter within the scope of his employment, according to the terms of KRS 95.761 to 95.785. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 105, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 54, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 80, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 18, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 248, sec. 1; and ch. 386, sec. 20. -- Amended 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 180, sec. 2. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 73, sec. 1. -- Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 9, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:08</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43690</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>