<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6">THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY </unit></structure><section_number>6.247</section_number><catch_line>Bill request files. </catch_line><order_by>247</order_by><text>The Legislative Research Commission shall maintain separate bill request files as follows: <section prefix="1">A regular session bill request file in which all requests for legislation to be enacted at a regular session are filed in serial order; </section><section prefix="2">A special session bill request file which shall be maintained from the time the Governor issues an executive order calling a special session of the General Assembly until the end of the special session in which all requests for legislation to be enacted at a special session are filed in serial order; </section><section prefix="3">Bill requests filed for a particular type of session of the General Assembly shall not be introduced in a session of a type other than that for which they are filed. This section shall not be construed as prohibiting the filing of multiple requests by the same or other sponsors for one (1) or more types of sessions of the General Assembly. </section><section prefix="4">Each bill request shall indicate on its face the type of session and the year of session of the General Assembly for which it is being filed. </section></text><history> Repealed, reenacted as KRS 6.247, and amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 136, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 443, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> June 21, 2001 </effective><former-codification>KRS 6A.110. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=292</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>