<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="241" order_by="241">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- ADMINISTRATION AND CONTROL </unit></structure><section_number>241.075</section_number><catch_line>Location of quota retail package licenses and quota retail drink licenses in cities of the first class or consolidated local governments.   </catch_line><order_by>075</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The State Alcoholic Beverage Control Board shall, for the purpose of regulating the location of quota retail package licenses and quota retail drink licenses in cities of the first class or consolidated local governments, divide such cities or consolidated local governments into "downtown business areas" and "combination business and residential areas." </section><section prefix="2">No quota retail package or quota retail drink license shall be granted or issued to any licensee who proposes to sell distilled spirits and wine by the package or by the drink at a location within seven hundred (700) feet of the location of any similar establishment in any combination business and residential area, nor shall such license be granted or issued to any licensee who proposes to operate at a location in a combination business and residential area within seven hundred (700) feet of a similar establishment located in a downtown business area. This section shall not affect location of such establishments in downtown business areas of such cities or consolidated local governments. </section><section prefix="3">The distance between locations of similar establishments as prescribed by this section shall be measured by following the shortest route of ordinary pedestrian travel along public thoroughfares from the nearest point of any present location of any such similar place of business to the nearest point of any proposed location of any such place of business. The measurement shall be taken from the entrance of the existing licensed premises to the entrance of any proposed location. </section><section prefix="4">The location of all establishments licensed to sell at retail distilled spirits by the package or by the drink, or both, on June 17, 1954, shall not be affected by the terms of this section and this section shall not apply to existing licensed locations or to the renewal of licenses therefor, or to transfers thereof. The distance limitation prescribed by this section shall not affect any existing licensed location, nor the right of the owner thereof to renew or transfer the license for such location. The location of any such existing license shall not be transferred to a new location in violation of this section, except that the location of any presently existing license or renewal thereof in case of destruction of property or loss of lease through failure of the landlord to renew such lease may be transferred to a location which is not closer than half the distance between the existing licensed premises and the nearest similar licensed premises. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 3, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 214, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 62, secs. 1, 2, 3, and 4, effective June 17, 1954. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42436</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>