<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXII" order_by="32">OWNERSHIP AND CONVEYANCE OF PROPERTY</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="382" order_by="382">CONVEYANCES AND ENCUMBRANCES </unit></structure><section_number>382.225</section_number><catch_line>Duties of county clerk as to general indexes in certain counties containing city with population of 20,000 or more.   </catch_line><order_by>225</order_by><text>The fiscal court in counties having a population of less than seventy-five thousand (75,000) and an assessed valuation of more than one hundred million (100,000,000) and containing a city with a population equal to or greater than twenty thousand (20,000) based upon the most recent federal decennial census may in its discretion direct the county clerk to have made in books proper for that purpose general indexes of all records in the office of the county clerk according to a system approved by the fiscal court. When the general indexes are thus completed they shall constitute the official indexes and the clerk of the county shall keep the indexes up to date by indexing therein the records of all property within one (1) month from the date they are lodged for record, and when they are so indexed, the alphabetical cross-index of such instruments need no longer be preserved and when such records or any part of them become defaced or injured, the clerk shall transcribe the defaced or injured records into new books, and they shall be as valid in law as the original record. The fiscal court may in its discretion require the county clerk and his deputies to make such indexes as provided by this section without additional compensation or may allow the said clerk for his services rendered by him and his deputies reasonable compensation. </text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 308, effective January 1, 2015. -- Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 207, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43893</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>