<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="178" order_by="178">COUNTY ROADS -- GRADE CROSSING ELIMINATION </unit></structure><section_number>178.333</section_number><catch_line>Addition of roads to through road system for county containing city of first class or consolidated local government -- New roads -- Relocation. </catch_line><order_by>333</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The fiscal court of a county containing a city of the first class or a consolidated local government may, at any time, add other roads, or portions of roads, to the county through road system adopted in accordance with KRS 178.330. The fiscal court or a consolidated local government shall cause the proposed addition to be marked on a map to be deposited with the county road engineer and to be open to public inspection. The same procedure set forth in KRS 178.330 for the establishment or maintenance of the county through road system shall be followed in the case of roads or portions of roads added thereto. Notice of the proposed addition to the system shall conform to KRS 424.130(1)(b). </section><section prefix="2">The fiscal court of a county containing a city of the first class or a consolidated local government may establish or maintain a new road in compliance with the provisions of KRS 178.115 to 178.125, or relocate a road in accordance with KRS 178.115, and at the same time add it to the county through road system, following the same procedure as is now set forth in KRS 178.330 and subsection (1) of this section, including notice in accordance with KRS 424.130(1)(b). </section><section prefix="3">The decisions of the fiscal court or the consolidated local government made in accordance with this section shall be final. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 187, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5455</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>