<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="62" order_by="62">OATHS AND BONDS </unit></structure><section_number>62.020</section_number><catch_line>Persons authorized to administer official oaths -- Certification and filing. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The official oath of any officer may be administered by: <section prefix="a">Any active, retired, or senior status justice or judge of the Court of Justice or active, retired, or senior status federal judge, with Kentucky jurisdiction; </section><section prefix="b">Any member of the General Assembly may administer an oath statewide; or </section><section prefix="c">Any county judge/executive, notary public, clerk of a court, or justice of the peace, within his district or county. </section></section><section prefix="2">For those officers listed in paragraphs (a), (b), (c), (d), and (e) of this subsection, the person administering the oath shall certify in writing that the oath of office was administered and the date of its administration. The person administering the oath shall file a written certification: <section prefix="a">In the Secretary of State's office for: <section prefix="1">A member of the General Assembly; </section><section prefix="2">An officer elected from the state at large; </section><section prefix="3">An officer elected from a district greater than one (1) county; or </section><section prefix="4">An officer elected from a city whose boundaries extend beyond those of a single county; </section></section><section prefix="b">In the Secretary of State's office for: <section prefix="1">An officer appointed cabinet secretary; or </section><section prefix="2">An officer appointed a deputy or assistant to an elected constitutional officer and who is required by separate statute to take the oath of office; </section></section><section prefix="c">In the Governor's office for the Secretary of State and the assistant Secretary of State; </section><section prefix="d">In the office of the county clerk for the county from which an officer is elected to countywide office or office for a district within the county. However, the requirements of this paragraph shall not apply when the requirements of paragraph (a) of this subsection apply; and </section><section prefix="e">In the office of a circuit clerk for a county clerk within the jurisdiction of that circuit clerk. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 128, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 56, sec. 3, effective March 21, 2007; and ch. 132, sec. 3, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 454, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 184, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 3754. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (6/26/2007).  This section was amended by 2007 Ky. Acts chs. 56 and 132. Where these Acts are not in conflict, they have been codified together. Where a conflict exists, Acts ch. 132, which was last enacted by the General Assembly, prevails under KRS 446.250.  (3/21/2007).  2007 Ky. Acts ch. 56, sec. 4, provides that the amendments to KRS 62.020 in 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 56, sec. 3, "shall apply retroactively to any elected officer required to take the oath of office and execute bond by the first Monday of year 2007." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23120</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>