<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.6040</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 247.6040 to 247.6070. </catch_line><order_by>6040</order_by><text>As used in KRS 247.6040 to 247.6070, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Association" means any commission, council, board, or other body; </section><section prefix="2">"Boll weevil" means Anthonomus grandis Boheman in any stage of development; </section><section prefix="3">"Commissioner" means the Commissioner of Agriculture or the Commissioner's designee; </section><section prefix="4">"Cotton" means any cotton plant or cotton plant product upon which the boll weevil is dependent for completion of any portion of its life cycle; </section><section prefix="5">"Cotton grower" means any person who is engaged in and has an economic risk in the business of producing, or causing to be produced, cotton for market; </section><section prefix="6">"Host" means any plant or plant product upon which the boll weevil is dependent for completion of any portion of its life cycle; </section><section prefix="7">"Infested" means actually infested with a boll weevil, or so exposed to infestation that it would be reasonable to believe that an infestation exists; and </section><section prefix="8">"Regulated article" means any article of any character carrying or capable of carrying the boll weevil, including but not limited to cotton plants, seed cotton, other hosts, gin trash, and mechanical cotton pickers. </section></text><history> Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11747</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>