<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="367" order_by="367">CONSUMER PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>367.150</section_number><catch_line>Functions, powers and duties of Department of Law. </catch_line><order_by>150</order_by><text>The Department of Law shall have the following functions, powers and duties: <section prefix="1">To promote the coordination of consumer protection activities of all departments, divisions and branches of state, county and city government, concerned with activities involving consumer interests; </section><section prefix="2">To assist, advise and cooperate with federal, state and local agencies and officials to protect and promote the interests of the consumer public; to advise the Governor and the legislature in all matters concerning consumer affairs; </section><section prefix="3">To conduct investigations, research, studies and analysis of matters affecting health, safety, the human environment, the marketplace and all other consumer affairs, and take appropriate action; to communicate the view of the consumer to state, county, and city agencies and officials; </section><section prefix="4">To study the operation of all laws, rules, regulations, orders, and state policies affecting consumers and to recommend to the Governor and to the Legislature, new legislation, rules, regulations, orders, and policies in the consumers' interest; </section><section prefix="5">To organize and hold conferences on problems affecting consumers; to undertake activities to encourage business, industry, the professions, and others offering goods or services to maintain high standards of honesty, fair business practices, and public responsibility in the production, promotion and sale of consumer goods and services; </section><section prefix="6">To provide a central clearing house of information for all citizens of the Commonwealth by collecting and compiling consumer complaints and inquiries, and forwarding them to the proper governmental agencies if appropriate; it shall be the further responsibility of the department to maintain records indicating the final disposition by the agency of any matter so referred; </section><section prefix="7">To organize, promote and conduct consumer education programs within the Commonwealth; to cooperate with and establish necessary liaison with consumer organizations; </section><section prefix="8"><section prefix="a">To appear before any federal, state or local governmental branch, commission, department, rate-making or regulatory body or agency, to represent and be heard on behalf of consumers' interests; and </section><section prefix="b">To be made a real party in interest to any action on behalf of consumer interests involving a quasijudicial or rate-making proceeding of any state or local governmental branch, commission, department, agency, or rate-making body whenever deemed necessary and advisable in the consumers' interest by the Attorney General. </section></section><section prefix="9">To perform such other acts as may be incidental to the exercise of the functions, powers and duties set forth in KRS 367.120 to 367.300. </section></text><history>Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 4. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34911</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>