<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.6672</section_number><catch_line>Prohibition on use of system not installed in compliance with applicable codes -- Inspection scheduling. </catch_line><order_by>6672</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person, firm, or corporation shall use, continue to use, or permit the use of any heating, ventilation, or air conditioning system that an authorized inspector or the inspector's employee or agent determines was not installed in accordance with the Uniform State Building Code, the Uniform State Residential Code, and the referenced standards contained in the respective codes. </section><section prefix="2">If a permit is required by KRS 198B.6671 for the installation of a heating, ventilation, or air conditioning system, no firm, person, or corporation shall use, continue to use, or permit the use of the heating, ventilation, or air conditioning system unless the permit has been obtained or applied for. </section><section prefix="3">Any inspection required by KRS 198B.6671 shall be scheduled with the property owner or owners or their agent or agents at least one (1) business day in advance and shall be completed within three (3) business days of the scheduled inspection. </section></text><history> Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 2, effective January 1, 2009. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2009 </effective><lrc-note> (4/18/2008).  This statute was created by 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 2, to be effective January 1, 2009, pursuant to sec. 12 of that Act. However, 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 127 (2008 HB 406, the State/Executive Branch Budget) provided in Part I, F.,16., (2) HVAC Permitting and Inspecting, that notwithstanding the delayed effective date provided in 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 12, the effective date of this statute shall be January 1, 2011. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36636</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>