<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="72" order_by="72">CORONERS, INQUESTS, AND MEDICAL EXAMINATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>72.465</section_number><catch_line>Inquiry into death under natural circumstances -- Death certificate -- Change in original certificate. </catch_line><order_by>465</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The coroner shall in his sound discretion determine the extent of inquiry to be made into any death occurring under natural circumstances and falling within the provisions of KRS 72.410 to 72.470, and if inquiry reveals that the physician of record has sufficient knowledge to reasonably state the cause of a death occurring under natural circumstances, the coroner may authorize that physician to sign the certificate of death. In all other instances, the coroner shall sign the death certificate in coroner's cases. </section><section prefix="2">In the event an autopsy is performed under the provisions of KRS 72.410 to 72.470 subsequent to the time that a death certificate has been filed with the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, Vital Statistics Branch, the coroner shall notify the Vital Statistics Branch of any change that may be necessary in the original certificate. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 113, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 96, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 88, secs. 88 and 93, effective July 1, 1992. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 93, sec. 17, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><note>  Amendment of this section by 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 88, secs. 88 and 93 became effective July 1, 1992, in compliance with 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 324, sec. 30. </note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24326</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>