<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.410</section_number><catch_line>State Board of Podiatry -- Qualifications, terms of members -- Officers -- Powers -- Meetings -- Immunity. </catch_line><order_by>410</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created in the government of the Commonwealth a State Board of Podiatry which shall consist of five (5) members, each appointed by the Governor. Four (4) members shall be appointed from lists of three (3) names for each position submitted by the Kentucky Podiatry Association. One (1) member shall be a citizen at large who is not associated with or financially interested in the practice or business regulated. Any vacancy shall be filled for the unexpired term by the Governor, as provided in the original appointment. </section><section prefix="2">A person to be eligible for appointment as a podiatrist member of the board shall be at least twenty-one (21) years of age, of good moral character, a resident of this state, and a licensed practicing podiatrist in this state for at least five (5) consecutive years next preceding the date of his appointment. No member of the board shall be a stockholder, officer or member of the faculty or board of trustees of any school, college or institution of podiatry or chiropody. </section><section prefix="3">The terms of office of each member shall be four (4) years, or until his successor shall be appointed and qualified. </section><section prefix="4">The board shall elect one (1) of its members as president and another of its members as secretary. The secretary may, subject to approval by the board, employ and fix the compensation of all personnel required for the administration of KRS 311.390 to 311.510. The board may make all rules and regulations, not inconsistent with KRS 311.390 to 311.510, as may be necessary to implement and carry out the provisions and purposes of KRS 311.390 to 311.510. </section><section prefix="5">The board shall hold meetings at least twice a year and as frequently as it deems necessary at such times and places as the board may designate. A majority of the members shall constitute a quorum. </section><section prefix="6">The board may sue and be sued in its own name. </section><section prefix="7">Members of the board shall be immune from suit in any civil or criminal action which is based upon any official act or acts performed by them in good faith as members of the board. </section></text><history>Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 166, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. --Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 3. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 225, sec. 10. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 289, sec. 3. -- Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 219, sec. 2. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 197, sec. 2. -- Created 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 176, sec. 4. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30499</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>