<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="645" order_by="645">MENTAL HEALTH ACT </unit></structure><section_number>645.220</section_number><catch_line>Notice requirements. </catch_line><order_by>220</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If a child who is at least sixteen (16) years of age is voluntarily admitted to a hospital under this chapter, the hospital shall give notice within twenty-four (24) hours to the child's parents or other person exercising custodial control or supervision, including the state, if applicable. </section><section prefix="2">Notices under this section shall advise the recipient of the following: <section prefix="a">The name, address, telephone number and name of the hospital's administrator; </section><section prefix="b">The hospital's policies concerning visitation and other communications; </section><section prefix="c">The right of the parent or other person exercising custodial control or supervision to participate in the child's treatment; and </section><section prefix="d">The right of the parent or other person exercising custodial control or supervision to participate in any proceedings under this chapter, including the right to seek discharge of the child under KRS 645.230. </section></section><section prefix="3">When a petition for certification or for emergency hospitalization is filed, the court shall immediately notify the child's parents or other person exercising custodial control or supervision, including the state, if applicable. </section><section prefix="4">Notices under this section shall be in the form most likely to reach the intended person. </section></text><history>Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 124, effective April 10, 1988. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 423, sec. 167, effective July 1, 1987. </history><metadata><effective>April 10, 1988 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20345</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>