<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.50-130</section_number><catch_line>Members to receive evidences of coverage -- Contents. </catch_line><order_by>50-130</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each member of a workers’ compensation self-insured group shall receive written evidence of coverage by the group. </section><section prefix="2">All evidences of coverage issued pursuant to this section shall contain coverage terms, conditions, and exclusions. </section><section prefix="3">All evidences of coverage issued pursuant to this section by a self-insured group shall contain the following disclosure in prominent contrasting type: THIS COVERAGE HAS BEEN PLACED WITH A WORKERS’ COMPENSATION SELF-INSURED GROUP WHICH IS REGULATED BY THE KENTUCKY DEPARTMENT OF INSURANCE AND HAS RECEIVED A CERTIFICATE OF FILING FROM THE COMMONWEALTH OF KENTUCKY. CLAIMS AGAINST GROUP MEMBERS ARE COVERED BY THE SELF-INSURED GROUP INSURANCE GUARANTY ASSOCIATION, BUT ARE NOT COVERED BY THE KENTUCKY INSURANCE GUARANTY ASSOCIATION. GROUP MEMBERS SHALL BE ASSESSED IN THE EVENT OF INSOLVENCY OF THE WORKERS’ COMPENSATION SELF-INSURED GROUP. </section><section prefix="4">All evidences of coverage issued pursuant to this section by a workers’ compensation self-insured group formed by governmental entities which have joint and several liability shall contain the following disclosure in prominent contrasting type: THIS COVERAGE HAS BEEN PLACED WITH A WORKERS’ COMPENSATION SELF-INSURED GROUP WHICH HAS RECEIVED A CERTIFICATE OF FILING FROM THE COMMONWEALTH OF KENTUCKY. CLAIMS AGAINST GROUP MEMBERS ARE NOT COVERED BY THE KENTUCKY INSURANCE GUARANTY ASSOCIATION. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1644, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 26, effective March 1, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30270</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>