<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="248" order_by="248">TOBACCO </unit></structure><section_number>248.707</section_number><catch_line>Agricultural Development Board. </catch_line><order_by>707</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Agricultural Development Board is created as a political subdivision of the Commonwealth to perform essential governmental and public functions by administering funds to provide economic assistance to the agriculture community of the Commonwealth. The board shall be a public agency within the meaning of KRS 61.805, 61.870, and other applicable statutes. </section><section prefix="2">The board shall consist of sixteen (16) members as follows: <section prefix="a">Five (5) voting members or their designees, as follows: <section prefix="1">The Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, who shall serve as chair; </section><section prefix="2">The Commissioner of the Kentucky Department of Agriculture, who shall serve as vice chair and shall serve as chair in the absence of the Governor; </section><section prefix="3">The secretary of the Cabinet for Economic Development; </section><section prefix="4">The director of the University of Kentucky Cooperative Extension Service; and </section><section prefix="5">The president of Kentucky State University; and </section></section><section prefix="b">Eleven (11) voting members appointed by the Governor, who shall be geographically distributed throughout the state and subject to confirmation by the House of Representatives and Senate as provided in KRS 11.160(2). The members shall be as follows: <section prefix="1">Seven (7) active farmers, at least four (4) of whom shall be from counties that are substantially tobacco-impacted, as determined by a formula that includes tobacco income as a percentage of total personal income in the county, and at least two (2) of whom shall have experience in agricultural diversification; </section><section prefix="2">One (1) representative of the Kentucky Farm Bureau; </section><section prefix="3">One (1) representative of the Kentucky Chamber of Commerce, who shall be an agribusiness person; </section><section prefix="4">One (1) attorney with farm experience and familiarity with agricultural policy; and </section><section prefix="5">One (1) agricultural lender. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">The members appointed under subsection (2)(b)2. and 3. of this section shall be chosen from a list of three (3) nominees submitted to the Governor by each of the respective organizations. </section><section prefix="4">Consideration shall be given to racial and gender equity in the appointment of board members. </section><section prefix="5">The majority of the voting members shall be active farmers. </section><section prefix="6">Members of the board shall be reimbursed for expenses incurred in the performance of their duties. </section><section prefix="7">Except as provided in paragraphs (a) to (d) of this subsection, the terms of the members appointed by the Governor shall be for four (4) years and until their successors are appointed and confirmed. A vacancy on the board shall be filled for the remainder of the unexpired term in the same manner as the original appointment. Members may be reappointed. The initial appointments shall be for staggered terms, as follows: <section prefix="a">Two (2) members shall be appointed for one (1) year; </section><section prefix="b">Three (3) members shall be appointed for two (2) years; </section><section prefix="c">Three (3) members shall be appointed for three (3) years; and </section><section prefix="d">Three (3) members shall be appointed for four (4) years. </section></section><section prefix="8">The Governor shall convene the first meeting of the board by August 1, 2000. </section><section prefix="9">The board shall meet monthly, or at the call of the chair or a majority of the voting members. </section><section prefix="10">A quorum of the board shall consist of nine (9) voting members. A majority of the voting members present may act upon matters before the board. </section><section prefix="11">The board shall be attached to the Office of the Governor for administrative purposes. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 182, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 530, sec. 4, effective April 26, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11971</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>