<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="212" order_by="212">LOCAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>212.380</section_number><catch_line>Membership of board -- Qualifications -- Terms -- Effect of compact or establishment of consolidated local government. </catch_line><order_by>380</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except in a county containing a consolidated local government, said board shall be composed of ten (10) members, two (2) of whom shall be the mayor of such city, and the county judge/executive of such county, as members ex officio, and four (4) of whom shall be appointed by the mayor of such city and four (4) of whom shall be appointed by the county judge/executive of such county with the approval of the fiscal court. Each appointive member shall be not less than thirty (30) years of age, intelligent, discreet, and shall have been a continuous resident of such county for at least two (2) years prior to the date of his or her appointment. At least one (1) and not more than three (3) of said appointive members shall be physicians, one (1) of said appointive members shall be a dentist, one (1) of said appointive members shall be a licensed pharmacist, and at least one (1) of said appointive members shall be a registered nurse. All appointive members shall be eligible for reappointment. </section><section prefix="2">At the expiration of each of the terms of office of said eight (8) appointive members, the successor to each member shall be appointed by said county judge/executive and said mayor for a term of office of four (4) years and until his successor is appointed and qualified. </section><section prefix="3">The two (2) appointments which increase the appointed members from six (6) to eight (8) shall both occur on July 1, 1974, one (1) of which shall be for a term expiring on June 30, 1978, the other of which shall be for a term expiring on June 30, 1975. Each subsequent appointment to the board shall be for a term of four (4) years. </section><section prefix="4">Notwithstanding subsection (2) of this section, when a city of the first class and a county containing such city have in effect a compact under KRS 79.310 to 79.330, the terms of the members on the board shall be for three (3) years and until their successors are appointed and qualified. Upon the effective date of the compact, the mayor, and county judge/executive with the approval of the fiscal court, shall adjust the terms of the sitting members so that the terms of two (2) each of their appointments expire in one (1) year, the term of one (1) each of their appointments expire in two (2) years, and the term of one (1) each of their appointments expire in three (3) years. Upon expiration of these staggered terms, successors shall be appointed for a term of three (3) years. </section><section prefix="5">Upon the establishment of a consolidated local government in a county where a city of the first class and a county containing that city have had in effect a cooperative compact pursuant to KRS 79.310 to 79.330, the board shall be composed of ten (10) members, the mayor and nine (9) members who shall be appointed to the board of health by the mayor of the consolidated local government pursuant to the provisions of KRS 67C.139 for a term of three (3) years. Incumbent board members, upon the establishment of the consolidated local government, shall continue to serve as members of the board for the time remaining of their current term of appointment and until their successors are appointed and qualified. The mayor shall serve on the board for a term which shall be coextensive with his or her term of office. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2002; and ch. 346, sec. 205, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 23, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 54, sec. 1. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 373, sec. 1. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 1. -- Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 41, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2002).  This section was amended by 2002 Ky. Acts chs. 80 and 346, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8618</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>