<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="157" order_by="157">STATE SUPPORT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>157.220</section_number><catch_line>Functions of Department of Education in special education programs. </catch_line><order_by>220</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department of Education is hereby designated as the agency for cooperation with the state and federal government agencies, the nonpublic school programs and local schools of Kentucky in carrying out the provisions of KRS 157.200 to 157.280. The Kentucky Board of Education shall make necessary rules and regulations in keeping with the provisions of KRS 157.200 to 157.280 for their proper administration, including but not limited to establishment of classes, eligibility and admission of pupils, the curriculum, class size limitations, housing, special equipment, and instructional supplies. </section><section prefix="2">The Department of Education is authorized to receive contributions and donations that may be made to carry out the provisions and requirements of KRS 157.200 to 157.280. </section><section prefix="3">Local supervision of special educational facilities for exceptional children shall be approved by the Department of Education according to rules and regulations approved by the Kentucky Board of Education. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 376, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. IV, sec. 181, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 128, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 286, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 82, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 169, sec. 2. -- Created 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3293</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>