<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="219" order_by="219">HOTEL, FOOD SERVICE, AND MOBILE HOME AND RECREATIONAL VEHICLE PARK REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>219.041</section_number><catch_line>Regulations -- State hotel code. </catch_line><order_by>041</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The secretary shall adopt regulations for the effective administration and enforcement of KRS 219.011 to 219.081. </section><section prefix="2">The secretary shall adopt a state hotel code which shall include, among other things, requirements for the issuance, suspension, and revocation of permits to operate; submission of plans for construction and equipment layout; plumbing; lighting; ventilation; water supply; sewage disposal; sanitary standards for operation; and such other matters deemed necessary to insure a safe and sanitary operation of a hotel. Standards for construction, plumbing, lighting, and ventilation shall be effective only if they are approved by the Board of Housing, Buildings and Construction and are included in the Uniform State Building Code, or if they conform to the State Plumbing Code in the case of plumbing fixtures. Any review of plans for construction, plumbing, lighting, and ventilation required before construction of a hotel shall be conducted by the Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 325, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 458, sec. 12, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 247, sec. 16, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 20, effective February 28, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(22). -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 337, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9727</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>