<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="42" order_by="42">FINANCE AND ADMINISTRATION CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>42.722</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 42.720 to 42.742.   </catch_line><order_by>722</order_by><text>As used in KRS 42.720 to 42.742: <section prefix="1">"Communications" or "telecommunications" means any transmission, emission, or reception of signs, signals, writings, images, and sounds of intelligence of any nature by wire, radio, optical, or other electromagnetic systems, and includes all facilities and equipment performing these functions; </section><section prefix="2">"Geographic information system" or "GIS" means a computerized database management system for the capture, storage, retrieval, analysis, and display of spatial or locationally defined data; </section><section prefix="3">"Information resources" means the procedures, equipment, and software that are designed, built, operated, and maintained to collect, record, process, store, retrieve, display, and transmit information, and associated personnel; </section><section prefix="4">"Information technology" means data processing and telecommunications hardware, software, services, supplies, facilities, maintenance, and training that are used to support information processing and telecommunications systems to include geographic information systems; </section><section prefix="5">"Personal information" has the same meaning as in KRS 61.931; </section><section prefix="6">"Project" means a program to provide information technologies support to functions within an executive branch state agency, which should be characterized by well-defined parameters, specific objectives, common benefits, planned activities, expected outcomes and completion dates, and an established budget with a specified source of funding; </section><section prefix="7">"Security breach" has the same meaning as in KRS 61.931; and </section><section prefix="8">"Technology infrastructure" means any computing equipment, servers, networks, storage, desktop support, telephony, enterprise shared systems, information technology security, disaster recovery, business continuity, database administration, and software licensing. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 74, sec. 5, effective January 1, 2015; ch. 89, sec. 9, effective July 15, 2014; and ch. 138, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2014. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 3, effective June 25, 2009. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 506, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 536, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><former-codification> KRS 11.503. </former-codification><lrc-note>(1/1/2015). 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 74, sec. 10 provided that "the provisions of this Act shall not impact the provisions of KRS 61.870 to 61.884." That proviso applies to this statute as amended in Section 5 of that Act. (1/1/2015). This statute was amended by 2014 Ky. Acts chs. 74, 89, and 138, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43579</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>