<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="148" order_by="148">PARKS AND TOURISM </unit></structure><section_number>148.582</section_number><catch_line>Iraq/Afghanistan War Memorial fund.   </catch_line><order_by>582</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Iraq/Afghanistan War Memorial fund is hereby created as a separate trust fund in the State Treasury. The Iraq/Afghanistan War Memorial fund shall consist of amounts received from appropriations and any other proceeds from gifts, grants, federal funds, or any other funds, both public and private, made available for the purposes of KRS 148.580 and this section. </section><section prefix="2">The Iraq/Afghanistan War Memorial fund shall be administered by the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet. </section><section prefix="3">Amounts deposited in the Iraq/Afghanistan War Memorial fund shall be used only for the purpose of the establishment of the Iraq/Afghanistan War Memorial as provided in KRS 148.580. </section><section prefix="4">Notwithstanding KRS 45.229, Iraq/Afghanistan War Memorial fund amounts not expended at the close of a fiscal year shall not lapse but shall be carried forward into the next fiscal year. </section><section prefix="5">Any interest earnings of the Iraq/Afghanistan War Memorial fund shall become a part of the Iraq/Afghanistan War Memorial fund and shall not lapse. </section><section prefix="6">Moneys deposited in the fund are hereby appropriated for the purposes set forth in this section and shall not be appropriated or transferred by the General Assembly for any other purposes. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 67, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2012). The internal numbering of this statute has been modified by the Reviser of Statutes from the way it appeared in 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 67, sec. 2, under the authority of KRS 7.136(1). The words in the text were not changed. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40257</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>