<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="80" order_by="80">LOW-COST HOUSING </unit></structure><section_number>80.270</section_number><catch_line>Public body may aid housing authority -- Declaration of policy. </catch_line><order_by>270</order_by><text>It is hereby declared that there exist in Kentucky unsafe and unsanitary housing conditions and a shortage of safe and sanitary dwelling accommodations for persons of low income; that these conditions necessitate excessive and disproportionate expenditures of public funds for crime prevention and punishment, public health and safety, fire and accident protection, and other public services and facilities; and that the public interest requires the remedying of these conditions. It is further declared that the assistance provided in KRS 80.280 to 80.300 for the remedying of such conditions constitutes a public use and purpose and an essential governmental function for which public money may be spent and other aid given; that it is a proper public purpose for any public body to aid any housing authority located or operating within its boundaries or jurisdiction, as the public body derives immediate benefits and advantages from such a housing authority or developments; and that the provisions of KRS 80.280 to 80.300 are necessary in the public interest. </text><history>Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 361, sec. 19, effective July 13, 1984. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2741x-17. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:12</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24842</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>