<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="367" order_by="367">CONSUMER PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>367.628</section_number><catch_line>Acts prohibited for roofing contractor.   </catch_line><order_by>628</order_by><text><section prefix="1">On or after July 12, 2012, a roofing contractor shall not represent, negotiate, or advertise to represent or negotiate on behalf of an owner of residential real estate on any insurance claim in connection with the repair or replacement of a roof system. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to prohibit a roofing contractor from: <section prefix="a">Providing an estimate for repair, replacement, construction, or reconstruction of the property to the owner of residential real estate; or </section><section prefix="b">Conferring with an insurance company's representative about damage to the property after a claim has been submitted by the owner of residential real estate. </section></section> This subsection shall not apply to a public adjuster licensed under Subtitle 9 of KRS Chapter 304. <section prefix="2">On or after July 12, 2012, a roofing contractor or person representing a roofing contractor shall not: <section prefix="a">Offer to pay or rebate all or any portion of an insurance deductible or claims proceeds as an inducement to the sale of goods or services related to a residential roof contract; </section><section prefix="b">Grant an allowance or discount against the fee to be charged under the contract; or </section><section prefix="c">Pay the owner of residential real estate for whom services have been performed pursuant to KRS 367.620 to 367.628, for any reason, any form of compensation in excess of one hundred dollars ($100), including but not limited to a: <section prefix="1">Bonus; </section><section prefix="2">Coupon; </section><section prefix="3">Credit; </section><section prefix="4">Gift; </section><section prefix="5">Prize; </section><section prefix="6">Referral fee; or </section><section prefix="7">Any other item having a monetary value. </section></section></section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 97, sec. 5, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40515</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>