<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="275" order_by="275">LIMITED LIABILITY COMPANIES </unit></structure><section_number>275.275</section_number><catch_line>Admission to membership in company.   </catch_line><order_by>275</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Subject to subsection (2) of this section, a person may become a member in a limited liability company: <section prefix="a">In the case of the person acquiring a limited liability company interest directly from a limited liability company, upon compliance with an operating agreement or, if an operating agreement does not so provide in writing, upon the written consent of all members; and </section><section prefix="b">In the case of an assignee of the limited liability company interest, as provided in KRS 275.255 and 275.265. </section></section><section prefix="2">The effective time of admission of a member to a limited liability company shall be the later of: <section prefix="a">The date the limited liability company is formed; </section><section prefix="b">The time provided in the operating agreement or, if no time is provided, when the person's admission is reflected in the records of the limited liability company; or </section><section prefix="c">The time the member is admitted under KRS 275.285(4). </section></section><section prefix="3">Upon becoming a member in a limited liability company, the member is bound by and a party to the operating agreement. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 108, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 14, effective June 8, 2011. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 389, sec. 55, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40447</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>