<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.842</section_number><catch_line>Duties of Cabinet for Health and Family Services -- Right of entry upon property. </catch_line><order_by>842</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services is the radiation control agency of the State of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="2">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall issue licenses pertaining to radioactive materials and require registration of other sources of ionizing radiation. </section><section prefix="3">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall develop and conduct programs for evaluation and control of hazards associated with the use of sources of ionizing, nonionizing, and electronic product radiation. </section><section prefix="4">The cabinet or its duly authorized representative may enter at a reasonable time upon the property of a licensee, registrant, or other person where sources of ionizing, nonionizing, or electronic product radiation are reasonably believed to be located for the purpose of determining whether or not such licensee, registrant, or other person is in compliance with or in violation of the provisions of KRS 211.842 to 211.852 and administrative regulations promulgated hereunder, and the owner, occupant, or person in charge of the property shall permit entry and inspection; provided, that entry into areas under the jurisdiction of an agency of the federal government or its duly designated representative shall be only upon permission of the agency or its representative. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 373, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 314, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 328, sec. 5, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 279, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8486</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>