<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="315" order_by="315">PHARMACISTS AND PHARMACIES </unit></structure><section_number>315.500</section_number><catch_line>Emergency authority for pharmacists during state of emergency -- Executive order -- Time limit -- Actions authorized -- Extension. </catch_line><order_by>500</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When the Governor declares a state of emergency pursuant to KRS 39A.100, the Governor may issue an executive order for a period of up to thirty (30) days giving pharmacists emergency authority. The executive order shall designate the geographical area to which it applies. In the executive order, the Governor may vest pharmacists with the authority to: <section prefix="a">Dispense up to a thirty (30) day emergency supply of medication; </section><section prefix="b">Administer immunizations to children pursuant to protocols established by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the National Institutes of Health, or the National Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices or determined to be appropriate by the commissioner of public health or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="c">Operate temporarily, a pharmacy in an area not designated on the pharmacy permit; and </section><section prefix="d">Dispense drugs as needed to prevent or treat the disease or ailment responsible for the emergency pursuant to protocols established by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention or the National Institutes of Health or determined to be appropriate by the commissioner of public health or his or her designee to respond to the circumstances causing the emergency. </section></section><section prefix="2">The provisions of this section may be extended, in writing, by the Governor if necessary to protect the lives or welfare of the citizens. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31049</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>