<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.500</section_number><catch_line>Causes for which licenses may be revoked or suspended. </catch_line><order_by>500</order_by><text>Any license issued under KRS 243.020 to 243.670 may be revoked or suspended for the following causes: <section prefix="1">Conviction of the licensee or his agent or employee for selling any illegal beverages on the licensed premises. </section><section prefix="2">Making any false, material statements in an application for a license or supplemental license. </section><section prefix="3">Violation of the provisions of KRS 243.670. </section><section prefix="4">Conviction of the licensee or any of his clerks, servants, agents, or employees of: <section prefix="a">Two (2) violations of the terms and provisions of KRS Chapter 241, 243, or 244 or any act regulating the manufacture, sale, and transportation of alcoholic beverages within two (2) consecutive years; </section><section prefix="b">Two (2) misdemeanors directly or indirectly attributable to the use of intoxicating liquors within two (2 ) consecutive years; or </section><section prefix="c">Any felony. </section></section><section prefix="5">Failure or default of a licensee to pay an excise tax or any part of the tax or any penalties imposed by or under the provisions of any statutes, ordinances, or Acts of Congress relative to taxation, or for a violation of any administrative regulations promulgated by the Department of Revenue made in pursuance thereof. </section><section prefix="6">Revocation of any license or permit provided in KRS 243.060, 243.070, 243.600, and 243.610, or granted under any Act of Congress relative to the regulation of the manufacture, sale, and transportation of alcoholic beverages. Any license issued under KRS 243.020 to 243.670 shall be revoked or suspended if the licensee sells the alcoholic beverages at a price in excess of the price set by federal or state regulations. </section><section prefix="7">Setting up, conducting, operating, or keeping, on the licensed premises, any gambling game, device, machine, contrivance, lottery, gift enterprise, handbook, or facility for betting or transmitting bets on horse races; or permitting to be set up, conducted, operated, kept, or engaged in, on the licensed premises, any such game, device, machine, contrivance, lottery, gift enterprise, handbook, or facility. This section shall not apply to contests in which eligibility to participate is determined by chance and the ultimate winner is determined by skill and the licensee has no direct interest, or to the sale of lottery tickets sold under the provisions of KRS Chapter 154A. </section><section prefix="8">Conviction of the licensee, his agents, servants, or employees for: <section prefix="a">The sale or use upon the licensed premises of those items described in KRS 218A.050 to 218A.130 as controlled substances, including synthetic drugs; </section><section prefix="b">Knowingly permitting the sale or use by patrons upon the licensed premises of those items described in KRS 218A.050 to 218A.130 as controlled substances, including synthetic drugs; or </section><section prefix="c">Knowingly receiving stolen property upon the licensed premises. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 108, sec. 15, effective April 11, 2012. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 654, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 522, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 254, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1988 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 26, effective December 15, 1988. - Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 18, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 1. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 1, effective February 21, 1952. -- Amended 1944 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 19. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 168, secs. 4 and 13. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2554b-134, 2554b-141. </history><metadata><effective> April 11, 2012 </effective><lrc-note>. (12/15/1988)  Although references to the sale of "shares" were deleted in the Senate committee substitute, due to a clerical error, such reference was not deleted in subsection (7) of this section. The Reviser of Statutes, pursuant to KRS 7.136, has removed the words "or shares" to conform. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40038</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>