<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="314" order_by="314">REGISTERED NURSES -- PRACTICAL NURSES </unit></structure><section_number>314.121</section_number><catch_line>Board of Nursing -- Members -- Appointment -- Terms -- Qualifications.   </catch_line><order_by>121</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Governor shall appoint a Board of Nursing consisting of sixteen (16) members: <section prefix="a">Nine (9) members shall be registered nurses licensed to practice in the Commonwealth, with the Governor ensuring that the appointees represent different specialties from a broad cross-section of the nursing profession after soliciting and receiving nominations from recognized specialty state component societies; </section><section prefix="b">Three (3) members shall be practical nurses licensed to practice in the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="c">One (1) member shall be a nurse service administrator who is a registered nurse licensed to practice in the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="d">One (1) member shall be engaged in practical nurse education who is a registered nurse licensed to practice in the Commonwealth; and </section><section prefix="e">Two (2) members shall be citizens at large, who are not associated with or financially interested in the practice or business regulated. </section></section><section prefix="2">Each appointment shall be for a term of four (4) years expiring on June 30 of the fourth year. The cycle for appointments and expiration of terms shall be as follows: <section prefix="a">The first year of the four (4) year cycle, the terms for three (3) registered nurses and one (1) licensed practical nurse shall expire; </section><section prefix="b">The second year of the four (4) year cycle, the terms for three (3) registered nurses and one (1) citizen at large shall expire; </section><section prefix="c">The third year of the four (4) year cycle, the terms for two (2) registered nurses, one (1) licensed practical nurse, and the one (1) member engaged in practical nurse education who is a registered nurse shall expire; and </section><section prefix="d">The fourth year of the four (4) year cycle, the terms for two (2) registered nurses, one (1) licensed practical nurse, and one (1) citizen at large shall expire. </section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">By March 1, the Kentucky Nurses Association shall submit to the Governor a list of members qualified for appointment as R.N. members, in number not less than twice the number of appointments to be made, from which list the Governor shall make each appointment or appointments necessary by July 1. </section><section prefix="b">By March 1, Kentucky Licensed Practical Nurses Organization Incorporated shall submit to the Governor a list of names qualified for appointment as L.P.N. members, in number not less than twice the number of appointments to be made, from which list the Governor shall make each appointment or appointments as necessary by July 1. </section><section prefix="c">By March 1 of the year in which the nurse service administrator's term shall expire, the Kentucky Organization of Nurse Executives, an affiliate of the Kentucky Hospital Association, shall submit to the Governor two (2) names of qualified individuals for appointment as the nurse service administrator from which list the Governor shall make an appointment as necessary by July 1. </section><section prefix="d">By March 1, the Kentucky Association of Nonprofit Homes and Services for the Aging, Inc., shall submit to the Governor two (2) names of qualified individuals for appointments as its R.N. representative to the board, from which the Governor shall make an appointment by July 1. </section><section prefix="e">By March 1 of the year in which the Kentucky Association of Health Care Facilities representative's term shall expire, the Kentucky Association of Health Care Facilities shall submit to the Governor two (2) names of qualified individuals for appointment as its R.N. representative to the board, from which list the Governor shall make an appointment as necessary by July 1. </section><section prefix="f">Initially, the Governor shall appoint one (1) member to serve as the registered nurse who is engaged in practical nurse education to serve the term remaining according to the cycle specified in subsection (2) of this section. By August 1, 1996, Kentucky Licensed Practical Nurses Organization Incorporated shall submit to the Governor two (2) names of qualified individuals for the appointment, from which list the Governor shall make the appointment by September 1, 1996. Thereafter, by March 1 of the year in which the practical nurse educator's term expires, Kentucky Licensed Practical Nurses Organization Incorporated shall submit to the Governor two (2) names of qualified individuals for the appointment, from which list the Governor shall make the appointment by July 1. </section><section prefix="g">The Governor shall appoint two (2) members who shall be citizens at large, who are not associated with or financially interested in the practice or business regulated. The Governor shall make the appointments by July 1 of the year in which the citizen members' terms expire. </section></section><section prefix="4">A vacancy on the board shall be filled by the Governor as provided for under subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="5">The Governor may remove any member from the board for neglect of duty, incompetence, or unprofessional or dishonorable conduct. </section><section prefix="6">Each R.N. member of the board shall be a citizen of the United States, a resident of Kentucky, a graduate of an approved school of nursing, and a registered nurse in this state. All shall have had at least five (5) years of experience in nursing, three (3) of which shall immediately precede such appointment. Five (5) members shall be engaged in nursing practice; three (3) shall be engaged in nursing education; one (1) shall be engaged in advanced practice registered nursing; and one (1) shall be in nursing administration. </section><section prefix="7">Each L.P.N. member of the board shall be a citizen of the United States, a resident of Kentucky, a graduate of an approved school of practical nursing or its equivalent, licensed as a licensed practical nurse in this state, have at least five (5) years of experience in nursing, three (3) of which shall immediately precede this appointment, and be currently engaged in nursing practice. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 10, effective July 20, 2012. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 85, sec. 63, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 391, sec. 18, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 26, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 83, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992; ch. 128, sec. 12, effective July 14, 1992; and ch. 259, sec. 4, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 342, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 408, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 10, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 7. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 4. </history><metadata><effective> July 20, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41147</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>