<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="209" order_by="209">PROTECTION OF ADULTS </unit></structure><section_number>209.990</section_number><catch_line>Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>990</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Anyone knowingly or wantonly violating the provisions of KRS 209.030(2) shall be guilty of a Class B misdemeanor as designated in KRS 532.090. Each violation shall constitute a separate offense. </section><section prefix="2">Any person who knowingly abuses or neglects an adult is guilty of a Class C felony. </section><section prefix="3">Any person who wantonly abuses or neglects an adult is guilty of a Class D felony. </section><section prefix="4">Any person who recklessly abuses or neglects an adult is guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="5">Any person who knowingly exploits an adult, resulting in a total loss to the adult of more than three hundred dollars ($300) in financial or other resources, or both, is guilty of a Class C felony. </section><section prefix="6">Any person who wantonly or recklessly exploits an adult, resulting in a total loss to the adult of more than three hundred dollars ($300) in financial or other resources, or both, is guilty of a Class D felony. </section><section prefix="7">Any person who knowingly, wantonly, or recklessly exploits an adult, resulting in a total loss to the adult of three hundred dollars ($300) or less in financial or other resources, or both, is guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="8">If a defendant is sentenced under subsection (5), (6), or (7) of this section and fails to return the victim's property as defined in KRS 218A.405 within thirty (30) days of an order by the sentencing court to do so, or is thirty (30) days or more delinquent in a court-ordered payment schedule, then the defendant shall be civilly liable to the victim of the offense or the victim's estate for treble damages, plus reasonable attorney fees and court costs. Any interested person or entity, as defined in KRS 387.510, shall have standing to bring a civil action on the victim's behalf to enforce this section. The sentencing judge shall inform the defendant of the provisions of this subsection at sentencing. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 43, sec. 1, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 8, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 249, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 370, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 56, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 157, sec. 9. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39691</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>