<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXII" order_by="32">OWNERSHIP AND CONVEYANCE OF PROPERTY</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="382" order_by="382">CONVEYANCES AND ENCUMBRANCES </unit></structure><section_number>382.796</section_number><catch_line>Conspicuous notice of all fees and obligations to be included in real estate purchase contracts -- Civil remedies -- Buyer's waiver of rights void. </catch_line><order_by>796</order_by><text>On and after April 11, 2012: <section prefix="1">Any contract or other instrument used for the sale of real property which obligates the buyer to pay a fee to the seller upon the subsequent resale of the real property, whether the fee or charge is a fixed amount or is stated as a percentage of the value of the property, the purchase price, or other consideration given for the subsequent transfer, shall include a conspicuous provision: <section prefix="a">Disclosing the existence of the obligation; </section><section prefix="b">Describing the obligation; and </section><section prefix="c">Stating that private transfer fee obligations, as that term is defined in KRS 382.792, are prohibited under KRS 382.794; </section></section><section prefix="2">A contract or other instrument for the sale of real property subject to the provisions of this section and found not to be in compliance shall be void and shall: <section prefix="a">Not be enforceable by the seller against the buyer; </section><section prefix="b">Not subject the buyer to any liability to the seller for any damages; and </section><section prefix="c">Require the seller to return all deposits made in connection with the sale of the real property; </section></section><section prefix="3">If a private transfer fee obligation is not discovered until after title of the property has passed to the buyer, the buyer may recover any and all damages resulting from the failure to disclose the obligation, including but not limited to: <section prefix="a"><section prefix="1">The amount of any obligation paid by the buyer to the seller, including interest thereon; or </section><section prefix="2">The difference between the market value of the real property if it were not subject to a private transfer fee obligation and the market value of the real property as subject to a private transfer fee obligation; and </section></section><section prefix="b">Attorneys fees, expenses, and costs incurred by the buyer in seeking the remedies under this section; and </section></section><section prefix="4">Any provision in a contract, covenant, or other instrument that purports to waive the rights of a buyer under this section shall be void. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 3, effective April 11, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> April 11, 2012 </effective><lrc-note>(4/11/2012). The internal numbering of subsection (3) of this statute has been modified by the Reviser of Statutes from the way it appeared in 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 3, under the authority of KRS 7.136(1). The words in the text were not changed. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40068</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>