<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="407" order_by="407">INTERSTATE SUPPORT ENFORCEMENT </unit></structure><section_number>407.5502Employer's</section_number><catch_line>compliance with income-withholding order of another state.   </catch_line><order_by>5502Employer's</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon receipt of an income-withholding order, the obligator's employer shall immediately provide a copy of an order to the obligor. </section><section prefix="2">The employer shall treat an income-withholding order that has been issued in another state and that appears regular on its face as if it had been issued by a tribunal of this state. </section><section prefix="3">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (4) of this section and KRS 407.5503, the employer shall withhold and distribute the funds as directed in the withholding order by complying with terms of the order terms that specify: <section prefix="a">The duration and amount of periodic payments of current child support, stated as a sum certain; </section><section prefix="b">The person designated to receive payments and the address to which the payments are to be forwarded; </section><section prefix="c">Medical support, whether in the form of periodic cash payment, stated as a sum certain, or ordering the obligor to provide health insurance coverage for the child under a policy available through the obligor's employment; </section><section prefix="d">The amount of periodic payments of fees and costs for a support enforcement agency, the issuing tribunal, and the obligee's attorney, stated as sums certain; and </section><section prefix="e">The amount of periodic payments of arrearages and interest on arrearages, stated as sums certain. </section></section><section prefix="4">An employer shall comply with the law of the state of the obligor's principal place of employment for withholding from income with respect to: <section prefix="a">The employer's fee for processing an income-withholding order; </section><section prefix="b">The maximum amount permitted to be withheld from the obligor's income; and </section><section prefix="c">The times within which the employer must implement the withholding order and forward the child support payment. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 34, effective June 24, 2015. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 9, effective March 23, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><former-history> KRS 407.5502: Renumbered as 407.5507. </former-history><former-history-former-name></former-history-former-name><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44110</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>