<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="100" order_by="100">PLANNING AND ZONING </unit></structure><section_number>100.133</section_number><catch_line>Planning commission -- Members, appointment -- Qualifications. </catch_line><order_by>133</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Before a planning unit may engage in planning operations, a planning commission shall be appointed for the unit in conformance with an adopted agreement. </section><section prefix="2">A planning commission shall consist of at least five (5), but not more than twenty (20) members. </section><section prefix="3">The Governor shall have the privilege of appointing a member to the commission to which the capital city belongs in addition to the number of members specified for that planning commission. </section><section prefix="4">Where extraterritorial jurisdiction is exercised for subdivision regulations or other regulations, the county judge/executive of each affected county may appoint a member to the planning commission of the planning unit exercising such jurisdiction in addition to the number of members specified for that planning commission. </section><section prefix="5">At least two-thirds (2/3) of the members of every planning commission shall be citizen members. </section><section prefix="6">A regional planning commission shall include at least one (1) citizen member from each joint planning unit who is also a member of the joint planning commission. </section><section prefix="7">If one (1) city only joins with one (1) county, then each shall have equal representation. </section><section prefix="8">Except as provided in KRS 100.137, at least one (1) of the county representatives of the planning commission of a joint planning unit containing a county with an unincorporated area population exceeding one thousand (1,000) persons shall be a resident of the unincorporated area of that county. </section><section prefix="9">Whenever this chapter requires a city without its consent to belong to a joint planning unit, then KRS 100.137 shall apply. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 268, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 153, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 172, secs. 8 and 9. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:11</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26689</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>