<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.458</section_number><catch_line>Temporary accessible parking placard for person with a disability -- Display. </catch_line><order_by>458</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon application of any person who has a severe temporary visual, audio, or physical impairment, including partial paralysis, heart condition, emphysema, arthritis, rheumatism, or other debilitating condition which limits or impairs one's personal mobility or ability to walk as defined in KRS 186.042, the county clerk in the county of the person's residence shall issue the person with a disability a temporary accessible parking placard. </section><section prefix="2">The accessible parking placard issued shall be a two (2) sided hanger style placard and shall on each side bear the international symbol of access adopted by Rehabilitation International in 1969, the date of expiration of the placard, a seal or other identification of the Kentucky Transportation Cabinet, and shall contain the accessible parking placard identification number and other information the Transportation Cabinet may by administrative regulation require. The international symbol of access shall be at least three (3) inches in height, be centered on the placard and in a white color on a red shield. </section><section prefix="3">A temporary accessible parking placard shall be issued at no charge by the county clerk, and the placard shall be valid for a period of not more than three (3) months. </section><section prefix="4">The application shall be made on a form prepared by the Transportation Cabinet. Placards shall be printed at cabinet expense and distributed to the county clerk of each county who shall keep a record of applications filed and placards issued. </section><section prefix="5">For every person seeking a temporary accessible parking placard, proof of the disability shall be required by a statement from a licensed physician, chiropractor, or advanced practice registered nurse that the applicant is a person whose mobility, flexibility, coordination, respiration, or perceptiveness is significantly reduced by a temporary disability to that person's arms, legs, lungs, heart, ears, or eyes. </section><section prefix="6">The temporary accessible parking placard, when the vehicle is parked in a parking space designated as accessible to and for the use of a person with a disability, shall be displayed so that it may be viewed from the front and rear of the vehicle by hanging it from the front windshield rear view mirror. When there is no rear view mirror, the placard shall be displayed on the dashboard. </section><section prefix="7">The Transportation Cabinet may promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A to implement or administer this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 5, effective January 1, 2007. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 131, sec. 2, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 405, sec. 41, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 416, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1994. – Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 60, sec. 5, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43313</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>