<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="352" order_by="352">MINING REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>352.320</section_number><catch_line>Mine foreman -- Assistants. </catch_line><order_by>320</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All commercial coal mines shall employ a certified mine foreman therein to properly carry out the plans and rules when approved by the commissioner of the department and to be responsible for compliance with the provisions of KRS Chapter 351 and this chapter. </section><section prefix="2">When the mine workings become so extensive that the mine foreman is unable personally to carry out the duties required of him by law, the operator, superintendent, or mine manager shall employ a sufficient number of persons holding suitable certificates of qualifications to act as assistants to the mine foreman, and under his instructions. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 185, sec. 21, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 23, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 41, effective April 9, 1996. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 301, sec. 10, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 303, sec. 30. --Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 31, effective March 5, 1952. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2739-1, 2739-42. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><lrc-note> (4/9/96).  The action taken with respect to this statute by 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 308 was to have become effective April 8, 1996, under Section 51 of that Act. The Act, however, did not become effective until April 9, 1996, when the Governor's signed copy of the Act was filed with the Secretary of State. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33012</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>