<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="35" order_by="35">MILITARY JUSTICE </unit></structure><section_number>35.355</section_number><catch_line>Restoration.   </catch_line><order_by>355</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Under such regulations as may be prescribed, all rights, privileges, and property affected by an executed part of a court-martial sentence which has been set aside or disapproved, except an executed dismissal or discharge, shall be restored unless a new trial or rehearing is ordered and such executed part is included in a sentence imposed upon the new trial or rehearing. </section><section prefix="2">If a previously executed sentence of dishonorable or bad-conduct discharge is not imposed on a new trial, the Governor may substitute therefor a form of discharge authorized for administrative issuance unless the accused is to serve out the remainder of the accused's enlistment. </section><section prefix="3">If a previously executed sentence of dismissal is not imposed on a new trial, the Governor may substitute therefor a form of discharge authorized for administrative issuance, and the commissioned officer dismissed by that sentence may be reappointed by the Governor alone to such commissioned grade and with such rank as in the opinion of the Governor that former officer would have attained had he not been dismissed. The reappointment of such a former officer shall be without regard to the existence of a vacancy and shall affect the promotion status of other officers only insofar as the Governor may direct. All time between the dismissal and the reappointment shall be considered as actual service for all purposes, including the right to pay and allowances. </section></text><history>Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 77, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 56, sec. 50. -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 70, effective July 1, 1954. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41953</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>