<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.140</section_number><catch_line>Functions of fair board. </catch_line><order_by>140</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The State Fair Board: <section prefix="a">Shall have the custody and control of such property as now is under its custody and control, and of such property as may hereafter be placed under its control or transferred to it by the State Property and Buildings Commission, for any purposes mentioned in this section and the physical properties so under its custody and control or transferred to it are hereinafter referred to in this section, and in KRS 247.150 and 247.160, as the "state fairgrounds and an area in a city of the first class to be used as an exhibition center." </section><section prefix="b">May erect and repair buildings on the state fairgrounds and exhibition center, make any and all necessary or proper improvements, and generally carry on a program of development and extension of facilities designed to accomplish the objectives defined in this section. </section><section prefix="c">Shall promote the progress of the state and stimulate public interest in the advantages and development of the state by providing the facilities of the state fairgrounds for agricultural and industrial exhibitions, public gatherings, cultural activities, and other functions calculated to advance the educational, physical, and cultural interests of the public and by providing the facilities of the exhibition center for conventions, trade shows, public gatherings, and other functions calculated to advance and enhance the visitor industry, economy, entertainment, cultural and educational interests of the public. </section><section prefix="d">May hold an annual fair on the state fairgrounds, for the exhibition of agricultural, mechanical, horticultural, dairy, forestry, poultry, livestock, mineral, and all other industrial interests of the state, and prepare premium lists and establish rules of exhibition for the fair. </section><section prefix="e">May purchase liability insurance for the members and executive officers exempted from the classified service of the state by KRS 18A.115. </section><section prefix="f">Shall operate the North American International Livestock Exposition, which shall be under the direction of a director appointed by the Governor upon the recommendation of the North American International Livestock Exposition Executive Committee. </section></section><section prefix="2">The State Fair Board may take, acquire and hold property, and all interest therein, by deed, gift, devise, bequest, lease, or eminent domain, or by transfer from the State Property and Buildings Commission, and may dispose of any property so acquired in the manner provided by law. In the exercise of its power of eminent domain it shall proceed in the manner provided in the Eminent Domain Act of Kentucky. </section></text><history>Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 404, sec. 35, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 448, sec. 70, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 133, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 140, sec. 96. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 1. -- Amended 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 217, sec. 3. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 5. -- Amended 1944 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4618i-5. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11592</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>