<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.30-165</section_number><catch_line>Prohibitions. </catch_line><order_by>30-165</order_by><text>It is unlawful for any person to: <section prefix="1">Violate or fail to comply with KRS 224.30-100 to 224.30-190 or any regulation adopted pursuant to it, or the terms or conditions of any variance or order issued pursuant to KRS 224.30-100 to 224.30-190 or pursuant to any regulation adopted hereunder. </section><section prefix="2">Refuse, hinder or interfere with by force or otherwise, the performance by the secretary or by any duly authorized agent or employee of the cabinet or their assistants, of any duty under the provisions of KRS 224.30-100 to 224.30-190; or to refuse to such agent, employee, or assistant entrance to any premises upon proper identification and presentation of a search warrant, or to hinder or interfere with the conduct of an inspection, test, or taking of a sample by such authorized agent, employee or assistant where entry to the premises was obtained by consent, or by presentation of proper identification, and search warrant. </section><section prefix="3">On any property or premises owned or leased by such person, allow the creation, continuance, or maintenance of any noise, or allow the installation, use or operation of any noise source, which noise or source violates or fails to comply with KRS 224.30-100 to 224.30-190, or any regulation adopted pursuant to KRS 224.30-100 to 224.30-190, or the terms or conditions of any variance or order issued pursuant to KRS 224.30-100 to 224.30-190 or pursuant to any regulation adopted hereunder. </section><section prefix="4">Intentionally remove or render inoperable, other than for purposes of maintenance, repair or replacement, any device or element of design incorporated, in compliance with KRS 224.30-100 to 224.30-190, into any product, structure, machine, equipment, vehicle or appliance for the control, abatement, or prevention of noise emissions, either prior or subsequent to its sale or delivery to the ultimate purchaser; or to use such product, structure, machine, equipment, vehicle or appliance after such device or element of design has been removed or rendered inoperable with knowledge of the removal or rendering inoperable of such device or element of design. </section><section prefix="5">Remove any notice affixed to a product or container pursuant to regulations prescribed under KRS 224.30-115(1)(c), prior to sale of the product to the ultimate purchaser. </section><section prefix="6">Attempt to obtain a registration or variance required or permitted under KRS 224.30-100 to 224.30-190 or any regulations adopted pursuant hereto by misrepresentation or failure to disclose all relevant facts. </section></text><history>Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. III, secs. 1 and 13, effective June 21, 1974; and ch. 99, sec. 15, effective June 21, 1974. </history><metadata><effective>June 21, 1974</effective><former-codification> KRS 224.775. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10390</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>