<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="533" order_by="533">PROBATION AND CONDITIONAL DISCHARGE </unit></structure><section_number>533.040</section_number><catch_line>Calculation of periods of probation and conditional discharge. </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A period of probation or conditional discharge commences on the day it is imposed. Multiple periods, whether imposed at the same or different times, run concurrently. </section><section prefix="2">If a court, as authorized by law, determines that a defendant violated the conditions of his probation or conditional discharge but reinstates probation or conditional discharge, the period between the date of the violation and the date of restoration of probation or conditional discharge shall not be computed as a part of the period of probation or conditional discharge. </section><section prefix="3">A sentence of probation or conditional discharge shall run concurrently with any federal or state jail, prison, or parole term for another offense to which the defendant is or becomes subject during the period, unless the sentence of probation or conditional discharge is revoked. The revocation shall take place prior to parole under or expiration of the sentence of imprisonment or within ninety (90) days after the grounds for revocation come to the attention of the Department of Corrections, whichever occurs first. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 138, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 331, sec. 61, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 288, effective January 1, 1975; and ch. 74, Art. V, sec. 24(14). </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20079</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>