<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="18" order_by="18">A STATE PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>18A.032</section_number><catch_line>Applicants to and eligibles for the classified service -- Examination -- Placement on and removal from registers -- Certification for employment. </catch_line><order_by>032</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided by the provisions of this chapter, the secretary may refuse to examine an applicant; or, after examination, may disqualify an applicant, remove his name from a register, refuse to certify any eligible on a register, or may consult with the appointing authority in taking steps to remove such person already appointed if: <section prefix="a">It is found that he does not meet any one (1) of the preliminary requirements established for the examination for the class of position; </section><section prefix="b">He is unable to perform the duties of the class; </section><section prefix="c">He has made a false statement of material fact in his application; </section><section prefix="d">He has used or attempted to use political pressure or bribery to secure an advantage in the examination; </section><section prefix="e">He has directly or indirectly obtained information regarding the examination to which, as an applicant, he was not entitled; </section><section prefix="f">He has failed to submit his application correctly or within the prescribed time limits; </section><section prefix="g">He has taken part in the compilation, administration, or correction of the examination for which he is an applicant; </section><section prefix="h">He has previously been dismissed from a position in the state service for cause or has resigned while charges for dismissal for cause of which he had knowledge were pending; </section><section prefix="i">He has been convicted of a felony within the preceding five (5) years and his civil rights have not been restored or he has not been pardoned by the Governor; </section><section prefix="j">He has been convicted of a job related misdemeanor, except that convictions for violations of traffic regulations shall not constitute grounds for disqualification; or </section><section prefix="k">He has otherwise willfully violated the provisions of this chapter. </section></section><section prefix="2">An eligible may be removed from a register: <section prefix="a">If the eligible cannot be located by postal authorities at the last address provided by the eligible; </section><section prefix="b">If the eligible responds in writing that he no longer desires consideration for position in that class; </section><section prefix="c">If the eligible declines an offer of probationary appointment to the class for which the register was established; </section><section prefix="d">If it is shown that the eligible is not qualified or is unsuitable for appointment to the class for which the register is established; </section><section prefix="e">If the eligible fails to reply within a period of ten (10) calendar days of the receipt of the written request of the appointing authority for an interview, or fails to appear for an interview which he has scheduled with the appointing authority without good cause; </section><section prefix="f">If the eligible accepts an appointment and fails to present himself for duty at the time and place agreed to without giving reasons for the delay satisfactory to the appointing authority; or </section><section prefix="g">If the eligible states in writing that he is not available for appointment or does not wish to be considered for appointment. </section></section><section prefix="3">When an eligible notifies the cabinet in writing that he is unavailable for employment or employment consideration, the cabinet may remove the name of that eligible from the appropriate register without further notification to the person. </section><section prefix="4">When the cabinet is notified in writing by an appointing authority that an eligible has accepted a bona fide offer of probationary appointment to any position, effective on a specified date, his name may be removed from the register for all classes for which the maximum salary is the same or less than that of the class to which he has been appointed. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 15, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 190, sec. 1, effective April 4, 1988. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 494, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, C, 2, (2) at 628.  See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, D, 10, (1) at 636. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1343</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>