<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="7" order_by="7">LEGISLATIVE RESEARCH COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>7.136</section_number><catch_line>Alterations permitted in maintaining official version of KRS. </catch_line><order_by>136</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Commission, in maintaining the official version of the Kentucky Revised Statutes, shall not alter the sense, meaning, or effect of any act of the General Assembly, but may: <section prefix="a">Renumber sections and parts of sections of the acts of the General Assembly; </section><section prefix="b">Change the wording of headnotes; </section><section prefix="c">Divide or rearrange sections and parts of sections; </section><section prefix="d">Change words when directed by law; </section><section prefix="e">Change reference numbers to agree with renumbered chapters or sections, or to make corrections in reference numbers when sections referred to are repealed or amended and the correction can be made without change in the law; </section><section prefix="f">Substitute the proper section or chapter numbers for the terms "this act," "the preceding section," and the like; </section><section prefix="g">Change capitalization, spelling, and punctuation for the purpose of uniformity and consistency; and </section><section prefix="h">Correct manifest clerical or typographical errors. </section></section><section prefix="2">In maintaining the official version of the Kentucky Revised Statutes, the reviser of statutes may substitute the name of any agency, officer, or instrumentality of the Commonwealth or of a political subdivision whose name is changed by law or to which powers, duties, and responsibilities have been transferred by law, for the name which the agency, officer, or instrumentality previously used or of the agency which was previously vested with the same powers and charged with the same duties and responsibilities. </section><section prefix="3">If any section or part of a section of a statute or of any act of the General Assembly is amended by more than one (1) act at the same session of the General Assembly, the Commission may incorporate in the statute the section as amended or altered by the several acts, if each of the amendments, changes, or alterations can be given effect and incorporated in the section in a manner which will make the section intelligible. If a conflict appears between any section amended in an act to revise and amend the Kentucky Revised Statutes and the same section in any other act adopted at the same session of the General Assembly, the change or alteration effected by the nonrevisory act shall be inserted in the section as incorporated in the statute publication. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 46, sec. 5, effective January 1, 1997. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 431, sec. 1, effective April 13, 1992. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 15, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 85, secs. 1(2), and 2(3); and ch. 255, sec. 282(1), effective June 16, 1966. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 1997 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=474</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>