<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="118" order_by="118">CONDUCT OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>118.165</section_number><catch_line>Filing of nomination papers -- Certification -- Ineligibility of Senior Status Special Judge.   </catch_line><order_by>165</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided in KRS Chapters 116 to 121, candidates for offices to be voted for by the electors of one (1) county or of a district less than one (1) county, except members of Congress and members of the General Assembly, shall file their nomination papers with the county clerk of the county not earlier than the first Wednesday after the first Monday in November of the year preceding the year the office will appear on the ballot and not later than the last Tuesday in January preceding the day fixed by law for holding the primary. Candidates for offices to be voted for by the electors of more than one (1) county, and for members of Congress and members of the General Assembly, shall file their nomination papers with the Secretary of State not earlier than the first Wednesday after the first Monday in November of the year preceding the year the office will appear on the ballot and not later than the last Tuesday in January preceding the day fixed by law for holding the primary. Signatures for nomination papers shall not be affixed on the document to be filed prior to the first Wednesday after the first Monday in November of the year preceding the year in which the office will appear on the ballot. All nomination papers shall be filed no later than 4 p.m. local time at the place of filing when filed on the last date on which the papers may be filed. </section><section prefix="2">The Secretary of State or the county clerk shall examine the notification and declaration form of each candidate to determine whether it is regular on its face. If there is an error, the proper officer shall notify the candidate by certified mail within twenty-four (24) hours of filing. </section><section prefix="3">A judge who elected to retire as a Senior Status Special Judge in accordance with KRS 21.580 shall not become a candidate or a nominee for any elected office during the five (5) year term prescribed in KRS 21.580(1)(a)1., regardless of the number of days served by the judge acting as a Senior Status Special Judge. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 66, sec. 3, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 11, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 296, sec. 8, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 40, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 17, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1988; and ch. 238, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 185, sec. 1, effective January 1, 1987. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 185, sec. 10, effective July 13, 1984; and ch. 185, sec. 11, effective January 1, 1985. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 394, sec. 20, effective July 15, 1982; and ch. 402, sec. 4, effective January 1, 1984. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 14, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 6, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 2, effective March 10, 1976. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 106, effective June 21, 1974. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42251</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>