<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="278" order_by="278">PUBLIC SERVICE COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>278.650</section_number><catch_line>Procedures for proposals to construct antenna towers in an area outside the jurisdiction of a planning commission -- Hearing -- Building permit fee. </catch_line><order_by>650</order_by><text>If an applicant proposes construction of an antenna tower for cellular telecommunications services or personal communications services which is to be located in an area outside the jurisdiction of a planning commission, the applicant shall apply to the Public Service Commission for a certificate of public convenience and necessity pursuant to KRS 278.020(1), 278.665, and this section. The commission shall convene a local public hearing on the application upon the receipt of a request from the local governing body or from not less than three (3) interested persons that reside in a county or municipal corporation in which the tower is proposed to be constructed. In reviewing the application, the commission may take into account the character of the general area concerned and the likely effects of the installation on nearby land uses and values. A local government may charge a fee for a building permit, in connection with the construction or alteration of any structure for cellular telecommunications services or personal communication services, if the fee does not exceed that charged for any other commercial structure of comparable cost of construction. </text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 343, sec. 6, effective April 23, 2002; and ch. 346, sec. 222, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 383, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> April 23, 2002 </effective><lrc-note> (4/23/2002).  This section was amended by 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 343, sec. 6, and ch. 346, sec. 222, which appear to be in conflict. The changes made by ch. 346 are revisory in nature, while the changes made by ch. 343 are substantive. The changes of ch. 343 have been allowed to prevail. Cf. KRS 7.123. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14169</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>