<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="222" order_by="222">KENTUCKY ALCOHOL AND OTHER DRUG ABUSE PREVENTION, INTERVENTION, AND TREATMENT LAW </unit></structure><section_number>222.204</section_number><catch_line>Conditions of bail -- Liability of facility releasing defendant. </catch_line><order_by>204</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person who has been arrested and placed in jail prior to trial for violation of KRS 222.202 and has not had two (2) prior convictions in the previous twelve (12) months for violation of KRS 222.202 shall be released as set forth by the Supreme Court Rule of Criminal Procedure uniform schedule of bail: <section prefix="a">To an adult who is willing to accept responsibility for the defendant through a signature verification on a form determined by the Administrative Office of the Courts; </section><section prefix="b">If he pays the requisite amount of bail on a bail schedule issued by the court; </section><section prefix="c">At such time as he is able to safely care for himself but in no event shall he be detained for more than eight (8) hours following his arrest; </section><section prefix="d">If he is ordered released by a court of competent jurisdiction; or </section><section prefix="e">Unless such person's release is precluded by other provisions of law. </section></section><section prefix="2">The jail or facility authorized by county or city ordinance agreeing to care for the person releasing the defendant shall be considered as acting in good faith and shall not be liable for subsequent acts of the defendant upon release. </section></text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 229, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 336, sec. 5, effective July 1, 1986. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9917</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>