<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.200</section_number><catch_line>Eligibility for public assistance. </catch_line><order_by>200</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A needy aged person, a needy blind person, a needy child, a needy permanently and totally disabled person, or a person with whom a needy child lives shall be eligible to receive a public assistance grant only if he has made a proper application or an application has been made on his behalf in the manner and form prescribed by administrative regulation. No individual shall be eligible to receive public assistance under more than one (1) category of public assistance for the same period of time. </section><section prefix="2">The secretary shall, by administrative regulations, prescribe the conditions of eligibility for public assistance in conformity with the public assistance titles of the Social Security Act, its amendments, and other federal acts and regulations. The secretary shall also promulgate administrative regulations to allow for between a forty percent (40%) and a forty-five percent (45%) ratable reduction in the method of calculating eligibility and benefits for public assistance under Title IV-A of the Federal Social Security Act. In no instance shall grants to families with no income be less than the appropriate grant maximum used for public assistance under Title IV-A of the Federal Social Security Act. As used in this section, "ratable reduction" means the percentage reduction applied to the deficit between the family's countable income and the standard of need for the appropriate family size. </section><section prefix="3">The secretary may by administrative regulation prescribe as a condition of eligibility that a needy child regularly attend school, and may further by administrative regulation prescribe the degree of relationship of the person or persons in whose home such needy child must reside. </section><section prefix="4">The secretary may by administrative regulation prescribe conditions for bringing paternity proceedings or actions for support in cases of out of wedlock birth or nonsupport by a parent in the public assistance under Title IV-A of the Federal Social Security Act program. </section><section prefix="5">Public assistance shall not be payable to or in behalf of any individual who has taken any legal action in his own behalf or in the behalf of others with the intent and purpose of creating eligibility for the assistance. </section><section prefix="6">The cabinet shall promptly notify the appropriate law enforcement officials of the furnishing of public assistance under Title IV-A of the Federal Social Security Act in respect to a child who has been deserted or abandoned by a parent. </section><section prefix="7">No person shall be eligible for public assistance payments if, after having been determined to be potentially responsible, and afforded notice and opportunity for hearing, he refuses without good cause: <section prefix="a">To register for employment with the state employment service, </section><section prefix="b">To accept suitable training, or </section><section prefix="c">To accept suitable employment. </section></section> The secretary may prescribe by administrative regulation, subject to the provisions of KRS Chapter 13A, standards of suitability for training and employment. <section prefix="8">To the extent permitted by federal law, scholarships, grants, or other types of financial assistance for education shall not be considered as income for the purpose of determining eligibility for public assistance. </section><section prefix="9">To the extent permitted by federal law, any money received because of a settlement or judgment in a lawsuit brought against a manufacturer or distributor of "Agent Orange" for damages resulting from exposure to "Agent Orange" by a member or veteran of the Armed Forces of the United States or any dependent of such person who served in Vietnam shall not be considered as income for the purpose of determining eligibility or continuing eligibility for public assistance and shall not be subject to a lien or be available for repayment to the Commonwealth for public assistance received by the recipient. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 242, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1988. --Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(21) and (29). -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 256, sec. 5. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 248, sec. 4. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 134, secs. 2 and 3. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 38, sec. 1. -- Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 75, sec. 2. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 33, sec. 4. -- Created 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 6. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7648</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>