<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="117" order_by="117">A UNIFORM MILITARY AND OVERSEAS VOTERS ACT </unit></structure><section_number>117A.080</section_number><catch_line>Transmission of ballot and balloting materials to covered voters -- Electronic transmission.   </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For an election described in KRS 117A.020, not later than forty-five (45) days before the election or, if the forty-fifth day before the election is a weekend or holiday, not later than the business day preceding the forty-fifth day, the election official in each jurisdiction charged with distributing a ballot and balloting materials shall transmit a ballot and balloting materials to all covered voters who by that date submit a valid military-overseas ballot application. </section><section prefix="2">A covered voter who requests that a ballot and balloting materials be sent to the voter by electronic transmission may choose facsimile transmission or the electronic transmission system established under KRS 117A.030(4). The election official in each jurisdiction charged with distributing a ballot and balloting materials shall transmit the ballot and balloting materials to the voter using the means of transmission chosen by the voter. </section><section prefix="3">If a ballot application from a covered voter arrives fewer than forty-five (45) days before the election, the official charged with distributing a ballot and balloting materials shall transmit them to the voter not later than three (3) business days after the application arrives. </section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 131, sec. 9, effective July 1, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42729</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>