<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="367" order_by="367">CONSUMER PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>367.4913</section_number><catch_line>Duties of protection notification center -- Board of directors of Kentucky Contact Center -- Kentucky Contact Center to serve all counties.   </catch_line><order_by>4913</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each protection notification center shall: <section prefix="a">Operate the protection notification center during all working days; </section><section prefix="b">Provide a locate request identification number to the excavator for each excavation or demolition location request; </section><section prefix="c">Promptly after receiving an excavation or demolition work notification from an excavator, provide to each of its affected operator members the excavator information required by KRS 367.4911(3); </section><section prefix="d">Maintain a list of all its operator member's identities, business address and business and emergency telephone numbers and record this information in accordance with KRS 64.012 with the county clerk of each county where the operator member has underground facilities. The county clerk shall provide this information upon request for the actual cost of providing a copy, to be paid by the requesting party to the county clerk. The county clerk shall assume no liability associated with the receipt of this information from the protection notification center or for subsequent provision of this same information to the requesting party; </section><section prefix="e">Make the operator members information list available to any person for inspection at its place of business without charge or provide a copy of the list to any person for any county upon request for a fee not to exceed the actual cost of providing a copy; </section><section prefix="f">Define and adopt policies and procedures for processing design information requests; and </section><section prefix="g">Provide the person making a design information request a list of identified operators that will receive notification and notify those operators. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Contact Center shall be governed by a board of directors composed of representatives of member operators who are elected by the membership. Board seats may be filled by representatives of the following: <section prefix="a">A natural gas provider; </section><section prefix="b">An electric provider; </section><section prefix="c">A telecommunications provider; </section><section prefix="d">A water/sewer provider; </section><section prefix="e">An interstate pipeline operator; </section><section prefix="f">A municipal utility operator; and </section><section prefix="g">An advisory, nonvoting representative of one (1) of the following: <section prefix="1">Home Builders Association of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="2">National Electrical Contractors Association; </section><section prefix="3">Associated General Contractors of Kentucky; or </section><section prefix="4">Kentucky Association of Plumbing, Heating-Cooling Contractors. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">The Kentucky Contact Center's board of directors shall establish the method to calculate the cost of service provided by the center. </section><section prefix="4">The Kentucky Contact Center shall serve all Kentucky counties. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 31, sec. 4, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 5, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 222, sec. 4, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 425, sec. 7, effective January 1, 1995. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note>(7/12/2012). Under the authority of KRS 7.136(1), the Reviser of Statutes has changed the internal format of this statute from the way it appeared in 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 5, to correct a manifest clerical or typographical error. The words in the text were not changed. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44311</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>