<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="324" order_by="324">A REAL ESTATE APPRAISERS </unit></structure><section_number>324A.015</section_number><catch_line>Real Estate Appraisers Board.   </catch_line><order_by>015</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is created a Real Estate Appraisers Board consisting of five (5) members, two </section><section prefix="2">of whom shall be certified real estate appraisers, one (1) of whom shall represent </section>the public and shall not be associated with or financially interested in the practice of real estate appraisals, and two (2) of whom shall be employed in the lending industry. The board shall administer the provisions of this chapter and may promulgate administrative regulations necessary to effectuate the provisions of KRS 324A.010 to 324A.090. (2) The board members shall be appointed by the Governor. Not more than one (1) board member shall be from any one (1) county within Kentucky.Members shall be appointed by the Governor for staggered terms of three (3) years. No person shall serve more than two (2) full consecutive terms. <section prefix="3">The appraiser appointees to the board shall be certified and shall have engaged in the appraisal of real estate in Kentucky on a continuing basis for at least ten (10) years. </section><section prefix="4">A board member shall be automatically removed from the board and a vacancy shall occur when: <section prefix="a">An appraiser member of the board ceases to be certified; </section><section prefix="b">A consumer member of the board acquires a certification as an appraiser; </section><section prefix="c">A lending industry member ceases to be employed in the lending industry; </section><section prefix="d">A board member enters a plea of guilty to, or has been found guilty of, a felony and the time for appeal has passed or the judgment of conviction has been finally affirmed on appeal; or </section><section prefix="e">A board member ceases to be a bona fide resident of the Commonwealth of Kentucky. </section></section><section prefix="5">The board shall adopt a seal with the design as the board may prescribe, by which it shall authenticate its proceedings. Copies of all records and papers in the office of the board, duly certified and authenticated by the seal of the board, shall be received in evidence in all courts equally and with like effect as the original. All records kept in the office of the board under the authority of this chapter shall be open to public inspection in accordance with KRS 61.820 to 61.884 and consistent with regulations prescribed by the board. </section></text><history>Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 46, sec. 8, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 247, sec. 2, effective April 7, 1992. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 383, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42095</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>