<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.192Information</section_number><catch_line>to be provided concerning Down syndrome and spina bifida -- By whom -- When.   </catch_line><order_by>192Information</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For the purposes of this section: <section prefix="a">"Down syndrome" means a chromosomal condition caused by cell division that results in the presence of an extra whole or partial copy of chromosome 21; and </section><section prefix="b">"Spina bifida" means a neural tube defect, the most common of which is the open neural tube defect myelomeningocele. </section></section><section prefix="2">A health facility as defined in KRS 216B.015(13), physician, health care provider, nurse midwife, or genetic counselor who renders prenatal care, postnatal care, or genetic counseling, upon receipt of a positive test result from a test for Down syndrome or spina bifida, shall provide the expectant or new parent with information provided by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services under subsection (3) of this section. </section><section prefix="3">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall make available to any person who renders prenatal care, postnatal care, or genetic counseling to parents who receive a prenatal or postnatal diagnosis of Down syndrome or spina bifida and to any person who has received a positive test result from a test for Down syndrome or spina bifida the following: <section prefix="a">Up-to-date, evidence-based, written information about Down syndrome or spina bifida that has been reviewed by medical experts and Down syndrome or spina bifida organizations and includes information on physical, developmental, educational, and psychosocial outcomes, life expectancy, clinical course, intellectual and functional development, and treatment options; and </section><section prefix="b">Contact information regarding support programs and services for expectant and new parents of children with Down syndrome or spina bifida, including information hotlines specific to Down syndrome or spina bifida, resource centers or clearinghouses, national and local Down syndrome or spina bifida organizations such as Down Syndrome of Louisville, Down Syndrome Association of Central Kentucky, Down Syndrome Association of South Central Kentucky, Green River Area Down Syndrome Association, Down Syndrome Association of Greater Cincinnati Serving Northern Kentucky, Council on Developmental Disabilities, the Spina Bifida Association of Kentucky, and other education and support programs. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 42, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2015. -- Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44399</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>