<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="315" order_by="315">PHARMACISTS AND PHARMACIES </unit></structure><section_number>315.295</section_number><catch_line>Automated pharmacy system in residential hospice facilities. </catch_line><order_by>295</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section and KRS 315.300: <section prefix="a">"Automated pharmacy system" means a mechanical system that delivers prescribed over-the-counter and legend drugs, and controlled substances received from a pharmacy licensed in Kentucky that maintains transaction information; and </section><section prefix="b">"Residential hospice facility" means a facility licensed under KRS Chapter 216B that provides residential skilled nursing care, pain management, and treatment for acute and chronic conditions for terminally ill patients. </section></section><section prefix="2">A pharmacy may provide pharmacy services to a residential hospice facility through the use of an automated pharmacy system under the supervision of a licensed pharmacist pursuant to the policies, procedures, and protocol established by the Kentucky Board of Pharmacy. The supervising pharmacist shall not be required to be physically present at the location of the automated pharmacy system and supervision may be provided electronically. </section><section prefix="3">Drugs stored in bulk or unit dose in an automated pharmacy system in a residential hospice facility shall be considered the inventory of the pharmacy providing services to the facility and drugs delivered through the automated pharmacy system shall be considered dispensed by the pharmacy. </section><section prefix="4">The Kentucky Board of Pharmacy shall promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A to implement the provisions of this section that shall include but not be limited to: <section prefix="a">Accuracy of the automated pharmacy system; </section><section prefix="b">Security of the system; </section><section prefix="c">Recordkeeping, including but not limited to electronic signatures of authorized users; </section><section prefix="d">Inventory management; </section><section prefix="e">Labeling or reporting requirements that include identification of the dispensing pharmacy, the prescription number, the name of the patient, and the name of the prescriber; and </section><section prefix="f">Training for authorized users. </section></section><section prefix="5">Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit or impede pharmacy practice in Kentucky. </section></text><history> Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 153, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31036</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>