<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.40-030</section_number><catch_line>Board of directors. </catch_line><order_by>40-030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The corporation shall be governed by a board of directors consisting of seven (7) members appointed as follows: <section prefix="a">Three (3) members appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="b">Two (2) members appointed by the county judge/executive of Pike County; and </section><section prefix="c">Two (2) members appointed by the mayor of Pikeville. </section></section> Initial appointments shall be for a term expiring November 1, 2003. Thereafter, members shall serve terms of four (4) years beginning November 1, 2003. After a membership term expires, members shall serve until new members are appointed to replace them. <section prefix="2">A member may be removed by his or her appointing authority as set forth in subsection (1) of this section, for misfeasance or malfeasance and after being afforded notice, an opportunity for a hearing under KRS Chapter 13B, and a finding of facts. A copy of charges, transcripts of the records of hearings, and findings of fact shall be filed with the Secretary of State. </section><section prefix="3">Members of the board shall serve without compensation, but shall be reimbursed for actual and necessary travel expenses incurred in the performance of their duties. The reimbursement shall be in accordance with administrative regulations promulgated under KRS Chapter 13A by the Finance and Administration Cabinet. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch.85, sec.1, effective June 8, 2011. -- Created 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 27, sec. 3, effective June 21, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39841</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>