<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="81" order_by="81">CITY CLASSIFICATION, BOUNDARIES, AND ALTERNATIVE METHOD OF CONSOLIDATING GOVERNMENTAL SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>81.300</section_number><catch_line>Plan for the improvement of local government in county containing city of first class may be submitted to fiscal court -- Action by fiscal court -- Election -- Time within which fiscal court must act. </catch_line><order_by>300</order_by><text>In any county containing a city of the first class, the mayor of the city of the first class with the approval of the board of aldermen, may submit to the fiscal court a plan for the improvement of local government in the county as set out herein below. The fiscal court shall, if they approve, deliver a certified copy of the plan to the county clerk, who shall cause to be submitted to the qualified voters of the affected areas at the next general election which does not occur within less than ninety (90) days of the submission by the mayor of the plan to the fiscal court, the question set out in KRS 81.350, if the certified copy of the plan is filed with the county clerk not later than the second Tuesday in August preceding the general election. In any event the fiscal court shall express its approval or disapproval of the plan within thirty (30) days of the submission of the plan by the mayor to them. </text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 195, sec. 41, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 17, sec. 1, effective May 18, 1956. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24985</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>