<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">BUDGET AND FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION </unit></structure><section_number>45.031</section_number><catch_line>Federal funds -- State clearinghouse function. </catch_line><order_by>031</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any department, board, commission, agency, advisory council, interstate compact, corporate body, or instrumentality of the Commonwealth of Kentucky applying for federal funds, aids, loans, or grants shall file a summary notification of the intended application with the Department for Local Government in accordance with the existing A-95 procedures. </section><section prefix="2">When as a condition to receiving federal funds, the Commonwealth of Kentucky is required to match the federal funds, a statement shall be filed with the notice of intent or summary of the application stating: <section prefix="a">The amount and source of state funds needed for matching purposes; </section><section prefix="b">The length of time the matching funds shall be required; </section><section prefix="c">The growth of the program; </section><section prefix="d">How the program will be evaluated; </section><section prefix="e">What action will be necessary should the federal funds be canceled, curtailed, or restricted; and </section><section prefix="f">Any other financial and program management data required by the Finance and Administration Cabinet or by law. </section></section><section prefix="3">Any application for federal funds, aids, loans, or grants which will require state matching or replacement funds at the time of application or at any time in the future, must be approved by the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, the Legislative Research Commission, and the Chief Justice for their respective branches of government or their designated agents prior to its filing with the appropriate federal agency. Any application for federal funds, aids, loans, or grants which will require state matching or replacement funds at the time of application or at any time in the future, when funds have not been appropriated for that express purpose, must be approved by the General Assembly, if in session. When the General Assembly is not in session, the application shall be reported to and reviewed by the Interim Joint Committee on Appropriations and Revenue, as provided by KRS 48.500(3). </section><section prefix="4">When any federal funds, aids, loans, or grants are received by any department, board, commission or agency of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, a report of the amount of funds received shall be filed with the Finance and Administration Cabinet; and this report shall specify the amount of funds which would reimburse an agency for indirect costs as provided for under OMB Circular A-87. </section><section prefix="5">The secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet may refuse to issue his warrant for the disbursement of any state or federal funds from the State Treasury as the result of any application which is not approved as provided by this section, or in regard to which the statement or reports required by this section were not filed. </section><section prefix="6">The secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet shall be responsible for the orderly administration of this section and for issuing the appropriate guidelines and regulations from each source of fund used. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 73, sec. 5, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 33, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 27, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 16, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 508, sec. 14, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 450, sec. 49, effective July 1, 1983. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39785</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>