<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="645" order_by="645">MENTAL HEALTH ACT </unit></structure><section_number>645.030</section_number><catch_line>Voluntary admission to hospital. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text>An authorized staff physician may admit for observation, diagnosis, and treatment at a hospital any child who is mentally ill or has symptoms of mental illness: <section prefix="1">Upon written application of a parent or other person exercising custodial control or supervision, if the child is under sixteen (16) years of age. At or before the child's admission, the child, parent or other person shall be informed of his rights under KRS 645.230 and 645.240. Any child admitted under this subsection who reaches his sixteenth birthday while hospitalized shall consent to his continued hospitalization or shall request his release. If the child fails to choose, the hospital shall advise the court-designated worker and the parent or other person exercising custodial control or supervision; </section><section prefix="2">Upon written application by a child who is at least sixteen (16) years of age and one of his parents or a person exercising custodial control or supervision. At or before admission, the child shall be informed of his right to give notice of his intent to leave under KRS 645.190 and his right to consult an attorney or his court-designated worker under KRS 645.130. The child may consult an attorney prior to his admission; or </section><section prefix="3">Upon written application by a child who is at least sixteen (16) years of age. At or before admission, the child shall be informed of his rights under KRS 645.190 and his parents' rights under KRS 645.220, 645.230 and 645.240. </section></text><history>Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 110, effective April 10, 1988. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 423, sec. 148, effective July 1, 1987. </history><metadata><effective>April 10, 1988 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20324</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>