<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="151" order_by="151">B WORKFORCE EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>151B.195</section_number><catch_line>Authority of the executive director of the Office of Vocational Rehabilitation. </catch_line><order_by>195</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The executive director of the Office of Vocational Rehabilitation shall prescribe administrative regulations governing the services, personnel, and administration of the State Vocational Rehabilitation Agency; may enter into reciprocal agreements with other states to provide for the vocational rehabilitation of residents of the states concerned; may establish and supervise the operation of small businesses established pursuant to KRS 151B.180 to 151B.210 to be conducted by eligible individuals with severe disabilities; and may establish state funded special programs for vocational rehabilitation in the state vocational rehabilitation agency. </section><section prefix="2">Except as provided in KRS 151B.190, the executive director may prescribe administrative regulations to establish fees for services provided to individuals or entities, public or private. </section><section prefix="3">The executive director is authorized to provide liability insurance or an indemnity bond against the negligence of drivers of motor vehicles owned or operated by the office for the transportation of applicants or clients of the office. If the transportation is let out under contract, the contract shall require the contractor to carry an indemnity bond or liability insurance against negligence to such amounts as the executive director designates. In either case, the indemnity bond or insurance policy shall be issued by a surety or insurance company authorized to transact business in this state, and shall bind the company to pay any final judgment not to exceed the limits of the policy rendered against the insured for loss or damage to property of any applicant or client or other person, or death or injury of any applicant or client or other person. </section><section prefix="4">The provisions of any other statute notwithstanding, the executive director is authorized to use receipt of funds from the Social Security reimbursement program for a direct service delivery staff incentive program. Incentives may be awarded if case service costs are reimbursed for job placement of Social Security or Supplemental Security Income recipients at the Substantial Gainful Activity (SGA) level for nine (9) months pursuant to 42 U.S.C. sec. 422 and under those conditions and criteria as are established by the federal reimbursement program. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 45, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 33, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended as KRS 151B.195 by 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 470, sec. 38, effective July 1, 1990, which prevailed over an amendment to KRS 163.140 by 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. IV, sec. 271, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 316, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 83, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 377, sec. 5. -- Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 4. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><former-codification> KRS 163.140. </former-codification><lrc-note> (7/13/90).  The subsequent repeal, with reenactment and amendment, of this section prevails over its amendment by a prior Act of the 1990 Regular Session pursuant to KRS 446.260. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2219</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>