<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="635" order_by="635">PUBLIC OFFENDERS </unit></structure><section_number>635.085</section_number><catch_line>Imposition of fines. </catch_line><order_by>085</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In lieu of commitment to the Department of Juvenile Justice, if a child is adjudicated a public offender, the court may in its discretion impose a fine. The imposition of a fine for an offense committed by a child shall be based upon a determination that such disposition is in the best interest of the child and to aid in his rehabilitation. Any such order shall include a finding that the child is financially able to pay the fine. Fines shall be levied consistent with the schedule set forth below: <section prefix="a">For a felony, not to exceed five hundred dollars ($500); </section><section prefix="b">For a misdemeanor, not to exceed two hundred fifty dollars ($250); and </section><section prefix="c">For a violation, not to exceed one hundred dollars ($100). </section></section><section prefix="2">When a child is directed by the court to pay a fine, the court may provide for payment to be made within a specified period of time or in specified installments. If such provision is not made a part of the court's disposition, the fine shall be payable immediately. Nothing contained herein shall be construed as limiting the court's inherent contempt powers. </section><section prefix="3">Any public offender detained for failure to comply with the court order shall not be scheduled for a time that would interfere with the educational, occupational, or religious obligations of the child, and shall be in a secure juvenile detention facility or approved detention program authorized by the Department of Juvenile Justice in accordance with KRS Chapter 15A. Any portion of a day a child is detained pursuant to the court's exercising its contempt powers shall be deemed as one (1) day for purposes of serving a detention term. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 49, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 183, sec. 40, effective August 1, 2002; and ch. 257, sec. 17, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 358, sec. 45, effective July 15, 1997. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 101, effective April 10, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/96).  Under 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 358, sec. 67(1), the amendment of this statute by Section 45 of that Act becomes effective July 15, 1997. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43507</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>