<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.706</section_number><catch_line>Duties and powers of board. </catch_line><order_by>706</order_by><text>The board shall: <section prefix="1">Through the promulgation of administrative regulations: <section prefix="a">Determine the requirements for and prescribe the form of licenses, applications, and other documents that are required by KRS 198B.700 to 198B.738; and </section><section prefix="b">Require that a home inspection report include a statement that the home inspection report does not address environmental hazards and list all other exclusions with specificity; </section></section><section prefix="2">Grant, deny, suspend, and revoke approval of examinations and courses of study regarding home inspections; </section><section prefix="3">Issue or deny applications for licensure and renewals; </section><section prefix="4">Investigate complaints concerning licensees, or persons the board has reason to believe should be licensees, including complaints concerning failure to comply with KRS 198B.700 to 198B.738 or administrative regulations promulgated under KRS 198B.700 to 198B.738, and, when appropriate, take action in accordance with KRS 198B.728 and 198B.730; </section><section prefix="5">Bring actions in the name of the state in an appropriate court in order to enforce compliance with KRS 198B.700 to 198B.738 or the administrative regulations promulgated under KRS 198B.700 to 198B.738; </section><section prefix="6">Establish license fees in an amount not to exceed two hundred fifty dollars ($250) annually; </section><section prefix="7">Inspect the records of a licensee in accordance with administrative regulations promulgated by the board; </section><section prefix="8">Conduct or designate a member or other representative to conduct public hearings on any matter for which a hearing is required under KRS 198B.728 and 198B.730; </section><section prefix="9">Adopt a seal containing the words "Kentucky Board of Home Inspectors" and, through the board's secretary, certify copies and authenticate all acts of the board; </section><section prefix="10">Use counsel, consultants, and other persons, enter into contracts, and authorize expenditures that are reasonably necessary or appropriate to administer and enforce KRS 198B.700 to 198B.738 and administrative regulations promulgated thereunder; </section><section prefix="11">Establish continuing education requirements for licensed home inspectors in accordance with KRS 198B.722 and 198B.724; </section><section prefix="12">Conduct disciplinary actions against licensees to include: <section prefix="a">Suspension, probation, or permanent revocation of a license; </section><section prefix="b">Requiring a licensee to obtain additional continuing education; and </section><section prefix="c">Issuance of a written reprimand; </section></section><section prefix="13">Require all fee-paid home inspections to be conducted in accordance with the standards of practice of: <section prefix="a">The American Society of Home Inspectors; </section><section prefix="b">The National Association of Home Inspectors; or </section><section prefix="c">Any other approved standards of practice that are equal to the standards of practice of the organizations in paragraphs (a) and (b) of this subsection as determined by the board. </section></section> The board may establish standards of practice for home inspectors licensed in Kentucky at a later date, which will supersede any other standards of practice previously adopted by the board and, if adopted by regulation, the standards in paragraphs (a) and (b) of this subsection; <section prefix="14">Exercise all other powers specifically conferred on the board under KRS 198B.700 to 198B.738; and </section><section prefix="15">Promulgate administrative regulations to carry out the effective administration and the requirements of KRS 198B.700 to 198B.738. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 6, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 4, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39902</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>