<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.999</section_number><catch_line>Prepayment of fines subject to certain conditions. </catch_line><order_by>999</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All offenses under this chapter classified as violations shall be prepayable except for: <section prefix="a">Any offense that could result in license suspension or revocation by the court or the Transportation Cabinet; </section><section prefix="b">Any offense relating to KRS 189.393, 189.520, or 189.580; </section><section prefix="c">When the defendant is speeding in a restricted zone; </section><section prefix="d">When the defendant is speeding more than twenty-five (25) miles per hour over the posted speed limit under KRS 189.394; </section><section prefix="e">An offense where evidence of the offense or of commission of another offense is seized by the officer and the citation is so marked and a court date set; </section><section prefix="f">The offense is cited with another offense that is not prepayable; </section><section prefix="g">When the defendant is under the age of eighteen (18); or </section><section prefix="h">An arrest is made under KRS 431.015. </section></section><section prefix="2">In the event that a prepayable offense is cited with another offense that is not prepayable, a court appearance shall be required on all of the offenses as required by KRS 431.452. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 512, sec. 5, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2014).  2014 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 3 provided that the amendments made to this statute in Section 1 of that Act shall be known as the "Denzel Steward Act of 2014." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43319</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>