<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="61" order_by="61">GENERAL PROVISIONS AS TO OFFICES AND OFFICERS -- SOCIAL SECURITY FOR PUBLIC EMPLOYEES -- EMPLOYEES RETIREMENT SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>61.610</section_number><catch_line>Employment and medical review after disability retirement -- Filing of review forms -- Duty of system to assist in obtaining records. </catch_line><order_by>610</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Once each year following the retirement of a person on a disability retirement allowance, or less frequently as determined by the board's medical examiner but not less than once every five (5) years, the system may require the person, prior to his normal retirement date, to undergo an employment and medical staff review and, if necessary, be required to file at the retirement office on the review form prescribed by the board current employment information and current medical information for the bodily injury, mental illness, or disease for which he receives a disability retirement allowance. The person shall have one hundred eighty (180) days from the day the system mailed the review form to the person's last address on file in the retirement office to file at the retirement office the review form and the current employment and medical information. The person shall certify to the retirement office that the review form, including current employment and medical information, is ready to be evaluated by the medical examiner in accordance with KRS 61.615. </section><section prefix="2">If, after good faith efforts, the person informs the system that he has been unable to obtain the employment or medical information, the system shall assist the person in obtaining the records and may use the authority granted pursuant to KRS 61.685(1) to obtain the records. </section><section prefix="3">If the person fails or refuses to file at the retirement office the review form, including the current employment and medical information, his retirement allowance shall be discontinued or reduced on the first day of the month following the expiration of the one hundred eighty (180) days from the day the system mailed the review form to the person's last address on file in the retirement office. The system shall send notice of the discontinuance or reduction of the disability retirement allowance by United States first-class mail to the person's last address on file in the retirement office. If the person's benefits are discontinued or reduced under this section, his rights to further disability retirement allowances shall cease, except as provided by KRS 61.615. </section></text><history> Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 36, sec. 17, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 240, sec. 32, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 349, sec. 41, effective July 15, 1988; and ch. 387, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 39. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 58, sec. 13. -- Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 21. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22996</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>