<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="524" order_by="524">INTERFERENCE WITH JUDICIAL ADMINISTRATION </unit></structure><section_number>524.055</section_number><catch_line>Retaliating against a participant in the legal process. </catch_line><order_by>055</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of retaliating against a participant in the legal process when he or she engages or threatens to engage in conduct causing or intended to cause bodily injury or damage to the tangible property of a participant in the legal process or a person he or she believes may be called as a participant in the legal process in any official proceeding or because the person has participated in a legal proceeding: <section prefix="a">Attending an official proceeding, or giving or producing any testimony, record, document, or other object produced at that proceeding; </section><section prefix="b">Giving information to a law enforcement officer relating to the possible commission of an offense or a violation of conditions of probation, parole, or release pending judicial proceedings; </section><section prefix="c">Vote, decision, or opinion; or </section><section prefix="d">Performance of his or her duty. </section></section><section prefix="2">Retaliating against a participant in the legal process is a Class D felony. </section><section prefix="3">In order for a person to be convicted of a violation of this section, the act against a participant in the legal process or the immediate family of a participant in the legal process shall be related to the performance of a duty or role played by the participant in the legal process. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 251, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 212, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19909</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>