<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>271B.13-310</section_number><catch_line>Court costs and counsel fees. </catch_line><order_by>13-310</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The court in an appraisal proceeding commenced under KRS 271B.13-300 shall determine all costs of the proceeding, including the reasonable compensation and expenses of appraisers appointed by the court. The court shall assess the costs against the corporation, except that the court may assess costs against all or some of the dissenters, in amounts the court finds equitable, to the extent the court finds the dissenters acted arbitrarily, vexatiously, or not in good faith in demanding payment under KRS 271B.13-280. </section><section prefix="2">The court may also assess the fees and expenses of counsel and experts for the respective parties, in amounts the court finds equitable: <section prefix="a">Against the corporation and in favor of any or all dissenters, if the court finds the corporation did not substantially comply with the requirements of KRS 271B.13-200 to 271B.13-280; or </section><section prefix="b">Against either the corporation or a dissenter, in favor of any other party, if the court finds that the party against whom the fees and expenses are assessed acted arbitrarily, vexatiously, or not in good faith with respect to the rights provided by this subtitle. </section></section><section prefix="3">If the court finds that the services of counsel for any dissenter were of substantial benefit to other dissenters similarly situated, and that the fees for those services should not be assessed against the corporation, the court may award to these counsel reasonable fees to be paid out of the amounts awarded the dissenters who were benefited. </section></text><history>Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 136, effective January 1, 1989. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 1989 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13446</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>