<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="18" order_by="18">A STATE PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>18A.245</section_number><catch_line>Board of trustees -- Membership, terms, meetings -- Powers -- Executive director -- Annual financial report.   </catch_line><order_by>245</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The authority shall be administered by a board of trustees composed of seven (7) members, who shall be as follows: <section prefix="a">Secretary, Finance and Administration Cabinet, ex officio; </section><section prefix="b">Secretary of personnel, ex officio; </section><section prefix="c">The state controller, ex officio; and </section><section prefix="d">Four (4) at-large members appointed by the Governor, one (1) of whom shall have at least five (5) years of investment or banking experience and one (1) of whom shall be a representative of a nonstate government employer. </section></section><section prefix="2">The members of the board appointed by the Governor shall serve for a period of four (4) years and the ex officio members of the board shall serve only for the period of their term of office. Each ex officio member may designate a proxy by written notice to the authority prior to call of order of each meeting, and the proxy shall be entitled to participate as a full voting member. </section><section prefix="3">Any vacancy which may occur shall be filled in the same manner provided for the selection of the particular member for a full term. Vacancies shall be filled for the unexpired term only. </section><section prefix="4">Membership on the board of trustees shall not be incompatible with any other office unless a constitutional incompatibility exists, and no member shall be subject to removal from office, except upon conviction of a felony, or of a misdemeanor involving moral turpitude. </section><section prefix="5">Board members who do not otherwise receive a salary or compensation from the State Treasury shall receive a per diem of one hundred dollars ($100) for each day they are in session or on official duty, and they shall be reimbursed for their actual and necessary expenses in accordance with state administrative regulations and standards applicable to state employees. </section><section prefix="6">The board shall meet at least once in each quarter of the year, and may meet in special session upon the call of the chairman. It shall elect a chairman and a vice chairman. A majority of the members shall constitute a quorum, and all actions taken by the board shall be by affirmative vote of a majority of the members present. </section><section prefix="7">The authority shall be attached to the Personnel Cabinet for administrative purposes only. The board may take but is not limited to the following actions: <section prefix="a">Appoint such employees as it deems necessary and fix the compensation for all employees of the board, subject to the approval of the secretary. The authority shall be headed by an executive director who shall be appointed by the board of directors of the authority without the limitations imposed by KRS 12.040 and KRS Chapter 18A. The executive director of the authority and employees appointed by the board shall serve at its will and pleasure. All other staff of the authority shall be employed under KRS 18A.005 to 18A.200; </section><section prefix="b">Require such employees as it thinks proper to execute bonds for the faithful performance of their duties; </section><section prefix="c">Establish a system of accounting; </section><section prefix="d">Contract for such services as may be necessary for the operation or administration of deferred compensation plans authorized in KRS 18A.230 to 18A.275, including annual audits; </section><section prefix="e">Do all things, take all actions, and adopt plans for participation consistent with federal law and with the provisions of KRS 18A.230 to 18A.275, including but not limited to: <section prefix="1">Amending the board's plan for the Kentucky Public Employees 401(k) Deferred Compensation Plan or the Kentucky Employees 457 Deferred Compensation Plan, or both such plans, to adopt, maintain, and terminate a deemed IRA program under Internal Revenue Code Section 408; </section><section prefix="2">Amending the board's plan for the Kentucky Public Employees 401(k) Deferred Compensation Plan to adopt, maintain, and terminate a qualified Roth contribution program under Internal Revenue Code Section 402A; and </section><section prefix="3">Adopting, maintaining, and terminating an Internal Revenue Code Section 403(b) plan for qualified employees; and </section></section><section prefix="f">Contract with persons or companies duly licensed by the state of Kentucky and applicable federal regulatory agencies, at the cost of the trust fund, to provide investment advice to participants in the plans, with respect to their selection of permitted investments in the plans. </section></section><section prefix="8">The Attorney General, or an assistant designated by him, may act as legal adviser and attorney for the board. The board may also appoint legal counsel in accordance with KRS Chapter 12. </section><section prefix="9">The board shall prepare an annual financial report showing all receipts, disbursements, assets, and liabilities and shall submit a copy to the Governor and the Legislative Research Commission. All board meetings and records shall be open for inspection by the public. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 5, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 181, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 50, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 496, sec. 25, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 234, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1984. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended as KRS 18A.245, 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 448, sec. 49, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 143, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><former-codification> KRS 18.540. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40100</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>