<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="645" order_by="645">MENTAL HEALTH ACT </unit></structure><section_number>645.250</section_number><catch_line>Authority to promulgate administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>250</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet may promulgate administrative regulations to implement the provisions of this chapter. </section><section prefix="2">The Department of Juvenile Justice may promulgate administrative regulations to implement the provisions of this chapter. </section><section prefix="3">The cabinet shall promulgate administrative regulations to insure that necessary and appropriate treatment is provided to children hospitalized under this chapter, including the establishment of: <section prefix="a">Reasonable time periods in which an individualized written treatment plan shall be developed, reviewed, and revised in accordance with each child's needs and progress; and </section><section prefix="b">Procedures so that a hospitalized child, his parent or other person exercising custodial control or supervision, including the state if applicable, can obtain an independent medical review of the appropriateness of decisions made to continue hospitalization or to discharge a child. </section></section><section prefix="4">The cabinet and the department shall not promulgate administrative regulations under this chapter which conflict. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 443, sec. 27, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 423, sec. 170, effective July 1, 1987. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20348</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>