<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="61" order_by="61">GENERAL PROVISIONS AS TO OFFICES AND OFFICERS -- SOCIAL SECURITY FOR PUBLIC EMPLOYEES -- EMPLOYEES RETIREMENT SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>61.876</section_number><catch_line>Agency to adopt rules and regulations. </catch_line><order_by>876</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each public agency shall adopt rules and regulations in conformity with the provisions of KRS 61.870 to 61.884 to provide full access to public records, to protect public records from damage and disorganization, to prevent excessive disruption of its essential functions, to provide assistance and information upon request and to insure efficient and timely action in response to application for inspection, and such rules and regulations shall include, but shall not be limited to: <section prefix="a">The principal office of the public agency and its regular office hours; </section><section prefix="b">The title and address of the official custodian of the public agency's records; </section><section prefix="c">The fees, to the extent authorized by KRS 61.874 or other statute, charged for copies; </section><section prefix="d">The procedures to be followed in requesting public records. </section></section><section prefix="2">Each public agency shall display a copy of its rules and regulations pertaining to public records in a prominent location accessible to the public. </section><section prefix="3">The Finance and Administration Cabinet may promulgate uniform rules and regulations for all state administrative agencies. </section></text><history>Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 273, sec. 4. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23063</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>