<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.390</section_number><catch_line>Sworn information to be contained in applications. </catch_line><order_by>390</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In addition to other information as the board may by administrative regulation require, every application for a license under KRS 243.020 to 243.670 shall contain the following information, given under oath: <section prefix="a">The name, age, Social Security number, address, residence, and citizenship of each applicant; </section><section prefix="b">If the applicant is a partner, the name, age, Social Security number, address, residence, and citizenship of each partner and the name and address of the partnership; </section><section prefix="c">The name, age, Social Security number, address, residence, and citizenship of each person interested in the business for which the license is sought, together with the nature of that interest, and, if the applicant is a corporation, limited partnership company, or limited liability company, the name, age, Social Security number, address, and residence of each officer, director, member, partner, and managerial employee and the citizenship of each, and the state under the laws of which the corporate applicant is incorporated or organized. The department may require the names of all the stockholders and the percentage of stock held by each; </section><section prefix="d">The premises to be licensed, stating the street and number, if the premises has a street number, and otherwise such a description that will reasonably indicate the location of the premises; </section><section prefix="e">A statement that neither the applicant nor any other person referred to in this section has been convicted of; any misdemeanor directly or indirectly attributable to alcoholic beverages; any violation of KRS 218A.050, 218A.060, 218A.070, 218A.080, 218A.090, 218A.100, 218A.110, 218A.120, or 218A.130 within the two (2) years immediately preceding the application; any felony, within five (5) years from the later of the date of parole or the date of conviction; or providing false information to the department preceding the application; and that the applicant or any other person referred to in this section has not had any license that has been issued to him under any alcoholic beverage statute revoked for cause within two (2) years prior to the date of the application; and </section><section prefix="f">A statement that the applicant will in good faith abide by every state and local statute, regulation, and ordinance relating to the manufacture, sale, use of, and trafficking in alcoholic beverages. </section></section><section prefix="2">If, after a license has been issued, there is a change in any of the facts required to be set forth in the application, a verified supplemental statement in writing giving notice of the change shall be filed with the board within ten (10) days after the change. </section><section prefix="3">In giving any notice or taking any action in reference to a license, the board may rely upon the information furnished in the application or in the supplemental statement connected with the application. This information, as against the licensee or applicant, shall be conclusively presumed to be correct. The information required to be furnished in the application or supplemental statement shall be deemed material in any prosecution for perjury. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 574, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 522, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1998. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2554b-134. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11361</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>