<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="181" order_by="181">COUNTY AND CITY BRIDGES, TUNNELS, AND FERRIES </unit></structure><section_number>181.570</section_number><catch_line>Bridge commission.   </catch_line><order_by>570</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any city may, by ordinance, create a bridge commission consisting of the chief executive of the city and four (4) persons appointed by such chief executive with the approval of the city legislative body. Each appointee shall be at least twenty-five (25) years of age. </section><section prefix="2">The original appointments shall be made for terms of four (4) years, and their successors shall be appointed for one (1), two (2), three (3), and four (4) years respectively. Thereafter the appointments shall be for four-year terms. Not more than two (2) appointees shall be members of the same political party, and all members shall be eligible for reappointment. Vacancies shall be filled for the unexpired term in the same manner as original appointments. </section><section prefix="3">No officer or employee of the city, whether he receives compensation or not, shall be appointed to the commission. </section><section prefix="4">Each appointee shall take, subscribe and file the constitutional oath of office, and shall execute a bond, approved by the city legislative body, in the sum of five thousand dollars ($5000). The bond shall be filed with the other official bonds of the city. </section></text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 260, effective January 1, 2015. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 3235g-9. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43845</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>