<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="213" order_by="213">VITAL STATISTICS </unit></structure><section_number>213.111</section_number><catch_line>Loan of unclaimed bodies to hospital or institution of higher learning. </catch_line><order_by>111</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding the provisions of KRS 311.300 to 311.350, any hospital or institution of higher learning may make application to any medical school incorporated within the Commonwealth for the loan of unclaimed whole dead bodies or parts thereof for educational or scientific purposes if the approval of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services has first been obtained. Approval shall be granted or denied by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services on the basis of proposed use, need, qualification of personnel, and adequacy of equipment and facilities. </section><section prefix="2">A special transit permit shall be obtained for the transportation of the dead bodies or parts thereof from the state registrar. Transportation and the ultimate burial of all the bodies or parts thereof shall be in accordance with the provisions of this chapter and KRS 311.340. </section><section prefix="3">All approved recipients shall keep a record of all bodies received by them and comply with all other regulations of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 439, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 388, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 369, sec. 21, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8738</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>