<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.12-207</section_number><catch_line>Grants-in-aid. </catch_line><order_by>12-207</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The corporation may, subject to appropriation from the General Assembly or from funds made available to the corporation from any other public or private source, provide grants-in-aid to educational institutions, and business and industry, not in excess of two hundred thousand dollars ($200,000) per grant-in-aid. Such grants-in-aid shall be used exclusively for programs which are consistent with the provisions of this chapter. </section><section prefix="2">To qualify for a grant-in-aid in which an educational institution will provide training, an educational institution and a business or industry shall submit a joint application to the corporation that contains a proposal for a program of skills training and education; a description of the program; the type of skills training or education to be provided; a statement of the total cost of the program and breakdown of the costs associated with equipment, personnel, facilities, and materials; and with respect to educational institutions only, a statement of the technical assistance and financial support for the program received or pledged from business and industry. To qualify for a grant-in-aid in which a provider other than an educational institution will provide training, the business or industry may independently submit a proposal to the corporation containing the same information as set forth in this subsection. </section><section prefix="3">Approval of the grant-in-aid application by the board shall be based upon the following criteria: <section prefix="a">The program must be within the scope of KRS 154.12-204 to 154.12-208; </section><section prefix="b">Participants in the program must be limited to a Kentucky resident, as the term is defined in KRS 141.010; </section><section prefix="c">The program must involve an area of skills training and education which is needed by business and industry and for which a shortage of qualified individuals exists within the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="d">The grant-in-aid must be essential to the success of the program as the resources of the educational institution are inadequate to attract the technical assistance and financial support necessary from business and industry; </section><section prefix="e">The educational institution must have obtained a firm commitment from business and industry for the information, technical assistance, and financial support which, together with the grant-in-aid, the resources of the applicant, and support from any other source, is sufficient to ensure the success of the program. In addition, the commitment of financial support from business and industry shall be equal to or greater than the amount of the requested grant-in-aid; </section><section prefix="f">The educational institution must have established adequate auditing procedures and reporting methods for the submission of information and data as required by the corporation; and </section><section prefix="g">Ninety percent (90%) of the participants receive a base hourly wage which is one hundred fifty percent (150%) of the federal minimum wage plus employee benefits equal to at least fifteen percent (15%) of the applicable base hourly wage, if the business and industry is located in a county of Kentucky which has had an average countywide rate of unemployment of fifteen percent (15%) or greater in the most recent twelve (12) consecutive months for which unemployment figures are available, on the basis of the final unemployment figures calculated by the Office of Employment and Training within the Department of Workforce Investment within the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 33, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 65, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 300, sec. 6, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 466, sec. 1, effective April 21, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 20, effective July 15, 1996. -- Repealed and reenacted 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 393, effective July 13, 1990. -- 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 437, Part XI, sec. 1, effective April 15, 1988. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><former-codification> KRS 157.740 </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2621</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>