<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17A-098</section_number><catch_line>Rewards or incentives to participate in voluntary wellness or health improvement program. </catch_line><order_by>17A-098</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An insurer issuing a group or individual health benefit plan may offer a voluntary wellness or health improvement program that allows for rewards or incentives to encourage participation or to reward members for participation, including but not limited to: <section prefix="a">Merchandise; </section><section prefix="b">Gift cards; </section><section prefix="c">Debit cards; </section><section prefix="d">Premium discounts or rebates; </section><section prefix="e">Contributions toward a member's health savings account; </section><section prefix="f">Modification to copayment, deductible, or coinsurance amounts; or </section><section prefix="g">Any combination of the incentives authorized by paragraphs (a) to (f) of this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any reward or incentive established under this section shall not be deemed an inappropriate inducement to obtain or retain insurance, in violation of KRS 304.12-090 and 304.12-110, if disclosed in the policy or certificate of coverage. </section><section prefix="3">The health plan member may be required to provide verification, such as a statement from his or her physician, that a medical condition makes it unreasonably difficult or medically inadvisable for the member to participate in the wellness or health improvement program. </section><section prefix="4">Nothing in this section shall prohibit an insurer from offering incentives or rewards to members for adherence to a voluntary wellness or health improvement program, if otherwise allowed by state or federal law. </section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 93, sec. 1, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39859</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>