<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="196" order_by="196">CORRECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>196.701</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky State Corrections Commission -- Membership.   </catch_line><order_by>701</order_by><text><section prefix="1">To develop and implement a statewide strategic plan for the state and community corrections programs, the Kentucky State Corrections Commission is created and is attached to the Office of the Secretary of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet. The commission shall consist of twenty-three (23) members as follows: <section prefix="a">The secretary of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet or his or her designee in writing; </section><section prefix="b">The commissioner of the Department of Corrections or his or her designee in writing; </section><section prefix="c">The deputy commissioner of the Office of Community Services and Facilities; </section><section prefix="d">The deputy commissioner of the Office of Adult Institutions; </section><section prefix="e">The director of the Division of Parole and Victim Services or his or her designee in writing; </section><section prefix="f">The executive director of the Office of Legislative and Intergovernmental Services of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet or his or her designee in writing; </section><section prefix="g">Two (2) Circuit Court Judges appointed by the Chief Justice; </section><section prefix="h">A county judge/executive appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="i">A county jailer appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="j">A Commonwealth's attorney appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="k">A practicing attorney appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="l">A victim, as that term is defined in KRS 346.020, appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="m">Four (4) service providers from the field of mental health, substance abuse treatment, or vocational and educational training, appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="n">A public member who is qualified to express the views of organized labor, appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="o">A public member who is qualified to express the views of business and industry, appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="p">The public advocate or his or her designee in writing; and </section><section prefix="q">Three (3) at-large members appointed by the Governor. </section></section><section prefix="2">The terms of those members appointed by the appointing authority shall be three (3) years. These members shall serve at the pleasure of the appointing authority and shall be eligible for reappointment. The appointed members may be removed for cause. All others serve during their terms of office. If there is a vacancy, the appointing authority shall immediately make an appointment effective for the unexpired term. </section><section prefix="3">The chairperson of the commission shall be the secretary of justice and public safety. The commissioner of the Department of Corrections shall serve as the vice chairperson who shall preside and exercise the functions of the chairperson during absence or disability of the chairperson. </section><section prefix="4">Regular meetings of the commission shall be held at least once every four (4) months at a place, day, and hour determined by the commission. Special meetings shall be held when needed as determined by the chairperson. If five (5) or more members of the commission request in writing that the chairperson call a special meeting, then the chairperson shall call a special meeting. </section><section prefix="5">Members of the commission shall receive reimbursement for necessary expenses for attendance at official commission meetings or public hearings. The administrative functions of the commission shall be performed by a full-time employee of the department who is selected by the commissioner. All public members of the commission shall, in addition to expenses, receive twenty-five dollars ($25) per day for attending each meeting. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 72, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 227, effective June 26, 2007. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 58, sec. 18, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 16, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 129, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 227, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 24, effective July 14, 1992; and ch. 255, sec. 9, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 497, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><former-codification>KRS 196.081. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42286</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>