<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.572</section_number><catch_line>Order to show cause -- Hearing. </catch_line><order_by>572</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board may issue an order directing an applicant for a license or the holder of a license to show cause why the applicant should be granted a license or the licensee should not be disciplined, respectively, when: <section prefix="a">An applicant admits or is otherwise found to have committed an act which constitutes a violation of the provisions of this chapter; or </section><section prefix="b">A licensee admits or is otherwise found to have committed an act in violation of the provisions of this chapter in any document relating to the registration or reregistration of a license. </section></section><section prefix="2">The order shall be signed by an officer of the board and shall state those violations which the board believes to have been committed. The matter shall be assigned to a hearing panel and shall proceed in accordance with KRS 311.591. The burden of proof shall lie with the charged physician. </section><section prefix="3">The board may issue a provisional permit to practice medicine as provided in KRS 311.550(27) and the board shall not approve any application for licensure or application for reregistration of an inactive license or provisional permit until a final order on the matter has been issued. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 8, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 190, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 302, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30526</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>