<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="199" order_by="199">PROTECTIVE SERVICES FOR CHILDREN - ADOPTION </unit></structure><section_number>199.595</section_number><catch_line>Legislative finding and purpose. </catch_line><order_by>595</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The General Assembly finds that: <section prefix="a">Finding adoptive families for children, for whom state assistance is desirable pursuant to KRS 199.555, and assuring the protection of the interests of the children affected during the entire assistance period, require special measures when the adoptive parents move to other states or are residents of another state; and </section><section prefix="b">Provision of medical and other necessary services for children, with state assistance, encounters special difficulties when the provision of services takes place in other states. </section></section><section prefix="2">The purposes of KRS 199.5951 to 199.5955 are to: <section prefix="a">Authorize the Cabinet for Health and Family Services to enter into interstate agreements with agencies of other states for protection of children on behalf of whom adoption assistance is being provided by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; and </section><section prefix="b">Provide procedures for interstate children's adoption assistance payments, including medical payments. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 186, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 149, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7198</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>