<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="177" order_by="177">STATE AND FEDERAL HIGHWAYS -- LIMITED ACCESS FACILITIES -- TURNPIKES -- ROAD BONDS -- BILLBOARDS -- RECYCLERS </unit></structure><section_number>177.830</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 177.830 to 177.890. </catch_line><order_by>830</order_by><text>As used in KRS 177.830 to 177.890, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Limited-access highway" means a road or highway or bridge constructed pursuant to the provisions of KRS 177.220 to 177.310; </section><section prefix="2">"Interstate highway" means any highway, road, street, access facility, bridge, or overpass which is designated as a portion of the national system of interstate and defense highways as may be established by law, or as may be so designated by the Transportation Cabinet in the joint construction of the system by the Transportation Cabinet and the United States Department of Transportation, Bureau of Public Roads; </section><section prefix="3">"Federal-aid primary highway" means any highway, road, street, appurtenant facility, bridge, or overpass which is designated as a portion of the federal-aid primary highway system as may be established by law or as may be so designated by the Transportation Cabinet and the United States Department of Transportation; </section><section prefix="4">"Turnpike" means any road or highway or appurtenant facility constructed pursuant to the provisions of KRS 177.390 to 177.570, or pursuant to the provisions of any other definition of "turnpike" in the Kentucky Revised Statutes, or any other highway, road, parkway, bridge, or street upon which a toll or fee is charged for the use of motor vehicular traffic; </section><section prefix="5">"Advertising device" means any billboard, sign, notice, poster, display, or other device intended to attract the attention of operators of motor vehicles on the highways, and shall include a structure erected or used in connection with the display of any device and all lighting or other attachments used in connection therewith. However, it does not include directional or other official signs or signals erected by the state or other public agency having jurisdiction; </section><section prefix="6">"Highway or highways" as used in KRS 177.830 to 177.890 means limited access highway, interstate highway, federal-aid primary highway, or turnpike as defined in KRS 177.830 to 177.890; </section><section prefix="7">"Commercial or industrial zone" adjacent to a federal-aid primary highway means an area zoned to permit business, commerce or trade pursuant to lawful ordinance or regulation; </section><section prefix="8">"Unzoned commercial or industrial area" adjacent to a federal-aid primary highway means an area which is not zoned by state or local law, regulation, or ordinance and on which either a commercial or industrial activity is conducted or a permanent structure therefor is located together with the area extending along the highway for such distances as may be determined by regulation promulgated by the secretary of the Transportation Cabinet. Each side of the highway will be considered separately in applying this definition--all measurements shall be from the outer edges of the regularly used buildings, parking lots, storage or processing areas of the activities, not from the property lines of the activities, and shall be along or parallel the edge of the pavement of the highway; </section><section prefix="9">"Commercial or industrial activities" for purposes of unzoned industrial and commercial areas means those activities generally recognized as commercial or industrial by zoning authorities in this state, except that none of the following activities shall be considered commercial or industrial: <section prefix="a">Outdoor advertising structures; </section><section prefix="b">Agricultural, forestry, ranching, grazing, farming, and related activities, including, but not limited to, wayside fresh produce stands; </section><section prefix="c">Activities normally or regularly in operation less than three (3) months of the year; </section><section prefix="d">Transient or temporary activities; </section><section prefix="e">Activities not visible from the main traveled way; </section><section prefix="f">Activities more than 300 feet from the nearest edge of the right-of-way; </section><section prefix="g">Activities conducted in a building principally used as a residence; </section><section prefix="h">Railroad tracks and minor sidings. </section></section><section prefix="10">"Urban areas" means those areas having a population of five thousand (5,000) or more which have been designated by the United States Department of Commerce, Bureau of the Census, as an urban area. A list of cities which have designated urban areas shall be maintained by the Transportation Cabinet, Division of Planning, Frankfort, Kentucky 40622. The Transportation Cabinet shall maintain maps indicating the boundaries of the designated areas. The maps shall be available from the Transportation Cabinet for a fee not to exceed five dollars ($5.00). </section></text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 398, sec. 1, effective April 9, 1990. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 2, effective March 29, 1976. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 178, sec. 1. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 1. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 175, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective>April 9, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5374</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>