<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="196" order_by="196">CORRECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>196.030</section_number><catch_line>Functions of Department of Corrections. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The department shall, unless otherwise provided by law, exercise all functions of the state in relation to: <section prefix="a">Management of penal, reform, and correctional institutions; </section><section prefix="b">Supervision of probation and parole; </section><section prefix="c">The giving of assistance to other departments, agencies, and institutions of the state and federal government when requested by performing services in conformity with this section; </section><section prefix="d">Acting as the agent of the federal government in matters of mutual concern, and in the administration of any federal funds granted to the state to aid in the performance of any function of this department; </section><section prefix="e">Administration and enforcement of the provisions of KRS Chapter 441 relating to the development and enforcement of jail standards, training of jailers and jail personnel, and jail planning and construction. </section></section><section prefix="2">Notwithstanding other provisions to the contrary, the Department of Corrections may contract with a county fiscal court or local or regional correctional authority to house misdemeanants and persons awaiting trial or sentencing. </section><section prefix="3">The provisions of this section shall not apply to any institution, home, or agency which does not receive aid from the state, a county, or municipality. </section></text><history> Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 19, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 497, sec. 15, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 344, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982; and ch. 385, sec. 29, effective July 1, 1982. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. V, sec. 24(14). -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 106, Art. X, sec. 3. -- Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 157, sec. 6. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4618-101. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6779</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>