<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">A AUTOMATED MOTOR VEHICLE REGISTRATION SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>186A.240</section_number><catch_line>Cancellation of title erroneously issued. </catch_line><order_by>240</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When any certificate of registration or certificate of title has been issued in error to a person not entitled to the certificate, or contains incorrect information or information has been omitted from the certificates, the Department of Vehicle Regulation shall notify in writing the person to whom the certificates have been issued or delivered and such person shall immediately return such certificate within forty-eight (48) hours, together with any other information necessary for the adjustment of the records related to it, to the county clerk of the county in which the title was originally applied for, or as otherwise directed by the Department of Vehicle Regulation. </section><section prefix="2">Upon receipt of the certificates and information requested, the county clerk and the Department of Vehicle Regulation shall coordinate the production of a corrected certificate of registration and certificate of title, and the cancellation of the erroneous documents by the Department of Vehicle Regulation, and ensure that corrected documents are sent to the appropriate party. </section><section prefix="3">Production of corrected documents shall be carried out under procedures similar to those applicable to production of an original certificate of title. The Department of Vehicle Regulation shall supply to the county clerk such forms as may be needed to assure documentation of corrective action in accordance with this section. </section></text><history>Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 45, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1982 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6184</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>