<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIII" order_by="33">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS AND ESTATES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>386A.4-070</section_number><catch_line>Effect of dissolution of a series.   </catch_line><order_by>4-070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A dissolved series continues its existence as a series, but may not carry on any activities except as is appropriate to wind up and liquidate its activities and affairs, including: <section prefix="a">Collecting the assets of or associated with the series; </section><section prefix="b">Disposing of the assets of or associated with the series that will not be distributed in kind to beneficial owners associated with the series or the statutory trust; </section><section prefix="c">Discharging or making provision for discharging the liabilities of or associated with the series or the assets of or associated therewith, including entering into new agreements with creditors having claims on assets of or associated with the series for the satisfaction thereof; </section><section prefix="d">Distributing the remaining property of or associated with the series in accordance with KRS 386A.4-110; and </section><section prefix="e">Doing every other act necessary to wind up and liquidate the series's activities and affairs. </section></section><section prefix="2">Except as otherwise provided in the governing instrument, dissolution of a series shall not: <section prefix="a">Transfer title to the property of or associated with the series; </section><section prefix="b">Prevent transfer of a beneficial interest associated with a series; </section><section prefix="c">Subject its trustees associated with the series to standards of conduct different from those applicable prior to the dissolution; or </section><section prefix="d">Amend the governing instrument or terminate contribution obligations existing thereunder. </section></section><section prefix="3">Dissolution of a series does not: <section prefix="a">Prevent the commencement of a proceeding by or against the series in the series's name; </section><section prefix="b">Abate or suspend a proceeding by or against the series pending on the effective date of dissolution; </section><section prefix="c">Transfer title to property of or associated with the series; or </section><section prefix="d">Terminate, as to the series, the authority of the registered agent of the statutory trust. </section></section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 28, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40370</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>