<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="137" order_by="137">LICENSE TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>137.115</section_number><catch_line>Permissive county license taxes. </catch_line><order_by>115</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The fiscal court of each county is hereby given the authority to impose with respect: <section prefix="a">To each restaurant serving meals, a license fee not to exceed ten dollars ($10) per annum; </section><section prefix="b">To each retail outlet of soft drinks or ice cream, a license fee not to exceed five dollars ($5) per annum. In cases where ice cream and soft drinks are sold by the same retail outlet, one (1) license tax not to exceed ten dollars ($10) per annum; </section><section prefix="c">To each billiard or pool table or bowling alley, irrespective of size, where a fee is charged and collected, directly or indirectly, a license fee not to exceed thirty dollars ($30) per annum for the first table or alley and not to exceed five dollars ($5) per annum for each additional table or alley; </section><section prefix="d">To each place where tobacco products are sold at retail, a license fee not to exceed ten dollars ($10) per annum. </section></section><section prefix="2">All license fees shall be payable to the county clerk and be credited to the general fund of the county to be used for county purposes only. </section><section prefix="3">The fiscal court of any county may allow the county clerk a commission not to exceed five percent (5%) on the license fees collected and accounted for by him under this section in addition to the fee provided in KRS 64.012. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 36, effective January 1, 2007. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 104, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 198, sec. 1. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 5, Art. IV, sec. 4. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:02</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28628</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>