<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.610</section_number><catch_line>License as proof of competency -- Power of local officials regarding regulation. </catch_line><order_by>610</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If a licensed fire protection sprinkler contractor desires to do business in any part of the state, he shall be required by KRS 198B.560 and 198B.565 to deliver to the local building official a copy of his fire protection sprinkler contractor's license. The local building official shall require a copy of the license before issuing a license or building license and no local official shall impose any other competency requirements on the licensed fire protection sprinkler contractor. </section><section prefix="2">Nothing in KRS 198B.560 and 198B.565 limits the power of a city, urban-county, county or state to regulate the quality and character of work performed by contractors, through a system of permits, fees and inspections which are designed to assure compliance with, and aid in the implementation of state and local building laws or to enforce other local laws for the protection of the public health and safety. Nothing in KRS 198B.560 and 198B.565 limits the power of a city, urban-county, county or the state to adopt any system of permits requiring submission to and approval by the city, urban-county, county or the state of plans and specifications for work to be performed by contractors before commencement of the work. The official authorized to issue building or other related permits shall ascertain that the fire protection sprinkler contractor is duly licensed by requiring evidence of a valid fire protection sprinkler contractor's license as a prerequisite to that contractor beginning design, installation, repair, alteration, extension, maintenance, or inspection of fire protection sprinkler systems. </section><section prefix="3">KRS 198B.560 and 198B.565 apply to any fire protection sprinkler contractor performing work for any city, urban-county, special district, county, or the state. Officials of any city, urban-county, special district, county or the state are required to determine compliance with KRS 198B.560 and 198B.565 before awarding any contracts for the installation, repair, alteration, addition, or inspection of a fire protection sprinkler system. Bids for such work shall be accompanied by a copy of a valid fire protection sprinkler contractor's license. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 383, sec. 13, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7036</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>