<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="77" order_by="77">AIR POLLUTION CONTROL </unit></structure><section_number>77.265</section_number><catch_line>Hearing on revocation or modification of variance -- Notice. </catch_line><order_by>265</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The hearing board may revoke or modify by written order, after a public hearing held upon not less than ten (10) days' notice, any order permitting a variance.  </section><section prefix="2">The hearing board shall serve, by personal service or by certified mail, return receipt requested, notice of the time and place of a hearing to revoke or modify any order permitting a variance not less than ten (10) days prior to such hearing upon the air pollution control officer, upon all persons who will be subjected to greater restrictions if such order is revoked or modified as proposed and upon all other persons interested or likely to be affected who have filed with the hearing board or air pollution control officer a written request for such notification.  </section><section prefix="3">If either the identity or address of any person entitled to such notice is unknown, the hearing board shall serve such person by publication of notice once in a newspaper of general circulation published within the district if such newspaper is published therein, otherwise by posting at a public place at the county seat within the district. </section></text><history>Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 315, sec. 6. -- Created 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 53, sec. 68, effective March 14, 1952. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1980</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24654</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>