<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="351" order_by="351">DEPARTMENT FOR NATURAL RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>351.110</section_number><catch_line>Examination prerequisites -- Fees -- Moneys from licenses and examination fees for use of department. </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall not admit any applicant for certification as a mine inspector, mine safety analyst, electrical inspector, mine safety instructor, mine foreman, or assistant mine foreman to take an examination given by it unless the applicant has the experience required by this chapter, and has submitted proof that he or she is drug and alcohol free in accordance with KRS 351.182 and 351.183, and has presented to the examiner at the time of registration for the examination a United States postal money order or certified check in the amount of fifty dollars ($50). All money orders or certified checks required herein shall be made payable to the State Treasurer, Frankfort, Kentucky. </section><section prefix="2">All money paid to the State Treasurer for licenses and fees required by this chapter shall be for the sole use of the department and shall be in addition to any moneys appropriated by the General Assembly for the use of the department. </section><section prefix="3">The board may refuse to examine any applicant who cannot readily understand the written English language or cannot express himself intelligently in English, or who is obviously intoxicated. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 241, sec. 14, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 11, effective April 9, 1996. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 301, sec. 5, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 8, sec. 10. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 298, sec. 8-- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 8, effective March 5, 1952. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739-45. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><lrc-note> (4/9/96).  The action taken with respect to this statute by 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 308 was to have become effective April 8, 1996, under Section 51 of that Act. The Act, however, did not become effective until April 9, 1996, when the Governor's signed copy of the Act was filed with the Secretary of State. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32914</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>