<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.120</section_number><catch_line>Nonresident pupils -- Tuition. </catch_line><order_by>120</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any board of education may charge a reasonable tuition fee per month for each child attending its schools whose parent, guardian, or other legal custodian is not a bona fide resident of the district. Any controversy as to the fee shall be submitted to the Kentucky Board of Education for final settlement. The fee shall be paid by the board of education of the school district in which the pupil resides, except in cases where the board makes provision for the child's education within his district. If a board of education is required to pay a pupil's tuition fee, the pupil shall be admitted to a school only upon proper certificate of the board of education of the district in which he resides. </section><section prefix="2">When it appears to the board of education of any school district that it is convenient for a pupil of any grade residing in that district to attend an approved public school in another district, the board of education may enter into a tuition contract with the public school authorities of the other school district for that purpose, but before a contract is entered into with public school authorities in another state the school shall have been approved by the state school authorities of that state through the grades in which the pupil belongs. When a district undertakes, under operation of a tuition contract or of law, to provide in its school for pupils residing in another district, the district of their residence shall share the total cost of the school, including transportation when furnished at public expense, in proportion to the number of pupils or in accordance with contract agreement between the two (2) boards. </section></text><history>Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended  1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. IV, sec. 202, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 82, effective June 17, 1978. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4399-51. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3443</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>