<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="117" order_by="117">REGULATION OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>117.345</section_number><catch_line>Cost of elections -- Payment. </catch_line><order_by>345</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cost of all elections held in any county shall be allowed by the fiscal court and paid by the county treasurer, except as otherwise provided by law. </section><section prefix="2">When the cost of any election has been allowed by the fiscal court and paid by the county treasurer, and within sixty (60) days following the date of the election, the county treasurer shall certify a statement of the number of precincts in the county, the date, and kind of election to the State Board of Elections, including an election that was delayed or postponed in accordance with KRS 39A.100. The certification shall be filed within ninety (90) days after the election. Upon receipt of the certification and upon being satisfied as to the correctness thereof, the State Board of Elections shall issue its warrant upon the State Treasurer in favor of the county treasurer for the amount of two hundred fifty-five dollars ($255) for each precinct in the county. </section><section prefix="3">Payments to any county under the provisions of subsection (2) of this section shall be terminated if and whenever it fails to renew a lease, contract, or lease and option with the State Property and Buildings Commission executed in connection with the acquisition of voting machines by the commission for the use of the county; and payments to any county shall be terminated whenever the county fails to pay any part of the rentals required for any effective period of the lease or if a county board of elections fails to provide training to precinct election officers required by KRS 117.187(2). </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 3, effective March 8, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 5, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 195, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 394, sec. 18, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 341, sec. 33, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 470, sec. 18, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 235, sec. 18, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 5, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 48, effective June 21, 1974. </history><metadata><effective> March 8, 2006 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, A, 17, (2) at 616. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:10</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27436</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>