<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="335" order_by="335">SOCIAL WORKERS AND PROFESSIONAL COUNSELORS </unit></structure><section_number>335.610</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Board of Licensure for Pastoral Counselors. </catch_line><order_by>610</order_by><text>The Kentucky Board of Licensure for Pastoral Counselors is hereby created. <section prefix="1">The board shall be composed of five (5) members who shall be appointed by the Governor to serve four (4) year terms. <section prefix="a">Four (4) members shall be Kentucky licensed pastoral counselors actively engaged in the practice or teaching of pastoral counseling. </section><section prefix="b">One (1) member shall be a citizen at large who is not associated with, or financially interested in, the practice or business of pastoral counseling. </section></section><section prefix="2">All reappointments to the board and vacancies on the board shall be filled by the Governor from a list of three (3) nominees for each vacancy, submitted by the executive committee of the Kentucky Association of Pastoral Counselors. In selecting the three (3) nominees to be submitted to the Governor, the executive committee shall consider all nominations, including self-nominations, from all pastoral counselors licensed under the provisions of KRS 335.600 to 335.699. </section><section prefix="3">No member shall serve more than two (2) consecutive terms. </section><section prefix="4">The chair of the board may not serve more than two (2) years. </section><section prefix="5">Each member shall serve until his or her successor is appointed and qualified. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 64, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2014. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 525, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43263</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>