<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="12" order_by="12">ADMINISTRATIVE ORGANIZATION </unit></structure><section_number>12.505</section_number><catch_line>Legislative findings for KRS 12.500 to 12.520. </catch_line><order_by>505</order_by><text>The General Assembly finds and declares that: <section prefix="1">Faith-based and community nonprofit organizations are indispensable in meeting the needs of our poor and disadvantaged citizens, and by embracing and partnering with these organizations, the capacity of government to respond to its citizens is strengthened; </section><section prefix="2">Faith-based and community nonprofit organizations should have full opportunity to participate in federal and state government funding for services directed at reducing poverty, improving the lives of low-income and vulnerable adults and children, self-sufficiency, and rehabilitation; </section><section prefix="3">It is necessary to ensure that: <section prefix="a">The rights and protections granted by the United States Constitution, the Constitution of Kentucky, and all amendments thereto are respected and preserved by all entities that receive government funding; </section><section prefix="b">Faith-based and community nonprofit organizations have equal opportunity to seek government funding for social service programs and that these social service programs remain separate from other inherently religious activities, including but not limited to worship, religious instruction, and proselytization; </section><section prefix="c">Faith-based and community nonprofit organizations do not discriminate against beneficiaries or potential beneficiaries of government-funded social service programs on any basis prohibited by law, including but not limited to discrimination based on religion, religious practices, or beliefs; and </section><section prefix="d">Faith-based and community nonprofit organizations have the capacity to effectively and efficiently manage government funds for social service programs, to perform program and service evaluations, and to report outcomes similar to any entity that receives government funding; and </section></section><section prefix="4">Communication, coordination, and technical assistance at the highest level of state government is needed to enhance the opportunities for faith-based and community nonprofit organizations to provide needed social services to our citizens. </section></text><history> Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 2, effective June 20, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:13</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=684</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>