<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">B MEDICAL IMAGING, RADIATION THERAPY, AND RELATED OCCUPATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>311B.070</section_number><catch_line>Executive director -- Qualifications -- Duties -- Bond.   </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The executive director shall have demonstrated administrative experience relative to budget, management, organizational abilities, and professional communication. The executive director shall: <section prefix="a">Be a licensed medical imaging technologist or radiation therapist; </section><section prefix="b">Have a minimum of a bachelor’s degree; and </section><section prefix="c">Meet the qualifications of a board member as required under KRS 311B.030(2). </section></section><section prefix="2">The executive director shall implement and oversee the licensure process of advanced imaging professionals, medical imaging technologists, radiographers, radiation therapists, nuclear medicine technologists, and limited X-ray machine operators as defined by the board. The executive director shall, at a minimum: <section prefix="a">Receive and evaluate applications for licenses; </section><section prefix="b">Document continuing education by licensees; </section><section prefix="c">Report suspected allegations of violations of this chapter to the board; </section><section prefix="d">Serve as corresponding secretary for the board; </section><section prefix="e">Supervise and evaluate administrative assistants and other office staff hired or contracted by the board; </section><section prefix="f">Assist the board chair in coordinating regular and special meetings and agendas; </section><section prefix="g">Maintain records of the actions of the board; </section><section prefix="h">Obtain an annual audit of the funds received and disbursed; </section><section prefix="i">Prepare and submit reports as needed; </section><section prefix="j">Serve as liaison between educational programs and the board; and </section><section prefix="k">Serve as liaison between the board and: <section prefix="1">State and national professional and accrediting organizations; and </section><section prefix="2">Other Kentucky boards and agencies. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">The executive director and other persons designated by the board shall be bonded by the state in an amount as determined by the board to be approved by the State Treasurer for the faithful performance of related duties. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 50, sec. 7, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40201</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>