<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="322" order_by="322">PROFESSIONAL ENGINEERS AND LAND SURVEYORS </unit></structure><section_number>322.045</section_number><catch_line>Requirements for licensure as a professional land surveyor -- Education, experience. </catch_line><order_by>045</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person shall qualify for licensure as a professional land surveyor if he or she has: <section prefix="a">Passed the Fundamentals of Land Surveying Examination and is thereby designated a land surveyor in training according to the conditions set forth in either paragraph (c) of this subsection or KRS 322.047(1)(a); </section><section prefix="b">Passed the Principles and Practice of Land Surveying Examination; and </section><section prefix="c">Met one (1) of the following requirements set out in this paragraph: <section prefix="1">Graduation from a board-approved program of four (4) years or more in land surveying from a college or university and not less than three (3) years of progressive experience in land surveying under the direct supervision of a practicing professional land surveyor. The experience shall be of a grade and character to indicate to the board that the applicant is competent to practice land surveying. Applicants shall be eligible to take the Fundamentals of Land Surveying Examination during the final year of the program; </section><section prefix="2">Graduation from a program of four (4) years or more in other than land surveying from a college or university of recognized standing, completion of a twenty-four (24) semester credit hour core curriculum in land surveying, and not less than four (4) years of progressive experience in land surveying under the direct supervision of a practicing professional land surveyor. The experience shall be of a grade and character to indicate to the board that the applicant is competent to practice land surveying; <section prefix="a">The core curriculum in land surveying may be completed as part of the four (4) year program or may be taken in addition to that program; and </section><section prefix="b">Applicants shall be eligible to take the Fundamentals of Land Surveying Examination upon completion of the core curriculum in land surveying or during the final year in the program if twelve (12) hours or more of the core curriculum in land surveying have been completed; or </section></section><section prefix="3">Graduation from a civil, mining, or agricultural engineering program of four (4) years or more accredited by the Engineering Accreditation Commission of the Accreditation Board for Engineering and Technology or any engineering program deemed equivalent by the board, completion of twelve (12) semester credit hours of the core curriculum in land surveying referenced in subparagraph 2. of this paragraph, and not less than four (4) years of progressive experience in land surveying under the direct supervision of a practicing professional land surveyor. The experience shall be of a grade and character to indicate to the board that the applicant is competent to practice land surveying; <section prefix="a">The twelve (12) hours of the core curriculum in land surveying may be completed as part of the engineering program or may be taken in addition to that program; and </section><section prefix="b">Applicants shall be eligible to take the Fundamentals of Land Surveying Examination upon graduation from the engineering program or during the final year in the program if twelve (12) hours of the core curriculum in land surveying have been completed. </section></section></section></section><section prefix="2">Any person having the necessary qualifications prescribed in subsection (1) of this section or any applicable qualifications prescribed in KRS 322.047(1)(a) shall be eligible to apply for licensure, even if the applicant is not practicing the profession at the time of application. </section><section prefix="3">The board shall promulgate administrative regulations to establish requirements for consideration of experience gained prior to graduation from programs as described in subsection (1)(c)1., 2., and 3. of this section, and for the surveying core curriculum described in subsection (1)(c)2. and 3. of this section. </section></text><history> Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 2, effective June 20, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31422</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>