<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">A AUTOMATED MOTOR VEHICLE REGISTRATION SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>186A.060</section_number><catch_line>Department of Vehicle Regulation to develop forms -- Reduction of paperwork required.   </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department of Vehicle Regulation is directed to develop, in cooperation with county clerks, auto dealers, and the Department of Revenue, Department of Insurance, and Department of Kentucky State Police, the forms required to record all information pertinent to the initial registration, or titling and taxation, or transfer of registration or title of a vehicle. </section><section prefix="2">The Department of Vehicle Regulation shall make every effort to minimize and reduce the amount of paperwork required to apply for, or transfer, a vehicle title. When possible, the title document itself shall be used as the primary form used to effect a transfer of vehicle ownership. The title document shall contain space exclusively reserved for a minimum of two (2) dealer assignments. </section><section prefix="3">When no in-state title exists, forms shall be designed by the department that require only the appropriate and essential information to effect the application for title. </section><section prefix="4">The department shall constantly review the information needs of government agencies and other organizations with the goal of reducing or eliminating unnecessary documentation. Information being sought for application for title relevant to, but not limited to, vehicle identification, owner, buyer, usage tax, county clerk, or inspector shall be set forth by the cabinet in such a way as to promote flexibility in reaching this goal, except that an applicant for a motor vehicle title shall not be required to provide his or her Social Security number as part of the application process. </section><section prefix="5">The use of an electronic medium shall be employed so that forms can be printed by the automated system. Existing statutory language in this chapter and KRS Chapter 186 pertaining to application, signature, forms, or application transfer record may be construed to be electronic in nature at the discretion of the cabinet as provided for by administrative regulation. </section><section prefix="6">Any person who knowingly enters, or attests to the entry of, false or erroneous information in pursuit of a certificate of title shall be guilty of forgery in the second degree. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 1, effective January 1, 2014. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 239, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 203, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 612, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 128, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 35, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 405, sec. 38, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41135</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>