<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.981</section_number><catch_line>Disposal of sewage and sewage sludge. </catch_line><order_by>981</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All sewage or sewage sludge hauled pursuant to the provisions of KRS 211.970 to 211.982 shall be disposed of by landspreading at an approved site or in a publicly-owned sewage treatment plant, unless it is demonstrated to the satisfaction of the cabinet that a publicly-owned sewage treatment plant does not exist within a reasonable hauling distance from the site at which the sewage or sewage sludge is received, or the publicly-owned sewage treatment plant refuses to accept the sewage or sewage sludge. </section><section prefix="2">If the cabinet determines that no publicly-owned sewage treatment plant is available for use by a licensed hauler, the cabinet may approve an alternative mode of disposal including, but not limited to, landspreading. The cabinet shall promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A governing landspreading and other acceptable modes of disposal which insure: <section prefix="a">That no contamination threat is posed to surface waters from any run-off; and </section><section prefix="b">That all reasonable protection is afforded to prevent contamination of groundwater. </section></section><section prefix="3">Trenching of sewage and sewage sludge shall be prohibited except where specifically authorized by the cabinet. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 570, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 248, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/98).  This section was amended by 1998 Ky. Acts chs. 71 and 570 which are identical and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8558</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>