<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>355.9-501</section_number><catch_line>Filing office. </catch_line><order_by>9-501</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (2) of this section, if the local law of this Commonwealth governs perfection of a security interest or agricultural lien, the office in which to file a financing statement to perfect the security interest or agricultural lien is: <section prefix="a">The office designated for the filing or recording of a record of a mortgage on the related real property, if: <section prefix="1">The collateral is as-extracted collateral or timber to be cut; or </section><section prefix="2">The financing statement is filed as a fixture filing and the collateral is goods that are or are to become fixtures; or </section></section><section prefix="b">The office of the Secretary of State, in all other cases, including a case in which the collateral is goods that are or are to become fixtures and the financing statement is not filed as a fixture filing. </section></section><section prefix="2">The office in which to file a financing statement to perfect a security interest in collateral, including fixtures, of a transmitting utility is the office of the Secretary of State. The financing statement also constitutes a fixture filing as to the collateral indicated in the financing statement which is or is to become fixtures. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 408, sec. 92, effective July 1, 2001. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 82, effective July 1, 1987. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 83, sec. 14. -- Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 9-501. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33806</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>