<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="439" order_by="439">PROBATION AND PAROLE </unit></structure><section_number>439.330</section_number><catch_line>Duties of board. </catch_line><order_by>330</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall: <section prefix="a">Study the case histories of persons eligible for parole, and deliberate on that record; </section><section prefix="b">Conduct reviews and hearings on the desirability of granting parole; </section><section prefix="c">Impose upon the parolee or conditional releasee such conditions as it sees fit; </section><section prefix="d">Order the granting of parole; </section><section prefix="e">Issue warrants for persons charged with violations of parole and postincarceration supervision and conduct hearings on such charges, subject to the provisions of KRS 439.341, 532.043, and 532.400; </section><section prefix="f">Determine the period of supervision for parolees, which period may be subject to extension or reduction after recommendation of the cabinet is received and considered; and </section><section prefix="g">Grant final discharge to parolees. </section></section><section prefix="2">The board shall adopt an official seal of which the courts shall take judicial notice. </section><section prefix="3">The orders of the board shall not be reviewable except as to compliance with the terms of KRS 439.250 to 439.560. </section><section prefix="4">The board shall keep a record of its acts, an electronic record of its meetings, a written record of the votes of individual members, and the reasons for denying parole to inmates. These records shall be public records in accordance with KRS 61.870 to 61.884. The board shall notify each institution of its decisions relating to the persons who are or have been confined therein, and shall submit to the Governor a report with statistical and other data of its work at the close of each fiscal year. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch.2, sec. 87, effective March 3, 2011; and ch.2, sec.101, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 129, sec. 3, effective March 18, 2005. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 179, sec. 4, effective April 4, 1994. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 344, sec. 43, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 259, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. V, sec. 24(16). -- Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 9, effective May 18, 1956. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><lrc-note> (6/8/2011).  This section was amended by 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 2, secs. 87 and 101, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39611</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>