<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="174" order_by="174">TRANSPORTATION CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>174.130</section_number><catch_line>Cabinet's duty to transmit information concerning abandonment of railroad corridors to Department of Parks and Railtrail Development Office -- Records and maps of railroad lines. </catch_line><order_by>130</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Transportation Cabinet, including any agency or other unit of government attached to the cabinet, shall immediately transmit to the Department of Parks and to the Commonwealth's Railtrail Development Office in the Department for Local Government any information received from a railroad or other person having an ownership interest in a railroad corridor pertaining to a proposed or pending action or proceeding to obtain federal authority for the regulatory abandonment of that railroad corridor. </section><section prefix="2">The Transportation Cabinet shall keep a record of railroad lines in the Commonwealth of Kentucky, including both lines that have been abandoned through the federal government's regulatory abandonment process and those where any railroad property interest in the railroad corridor itself has been abandoned under Kentucky law. The cabinet shall annually publish an updated map showing the location and as much information as to the status of these lines as practicable. The record shall include, inasmuch as possible: <section prefix="a">A description of the line and its location; </section><section prefix="b">The current or last railroad owner of the line; </section><section prefix="c">The operator of the line; </section><section prefix="d">The addresses and phone numbers for the owners and operators of the lines; </section><section prefix="e">Whether the owner of the line has received authority from the Federal Government to discontinue service over the line; </section><section prefix="f">Whether the owner of the line has received authority from the Federal Government to abandon the line; </section><section prefix="g">Whether the owner of the line has consummated any authority granted by the Federal Government to discontinue service over the line or to abandon the line; </section><section prefix="h">Whether the line has been railbanked under either federal or state law; and </section><section prefix="i">Any other information the cabinet deems pertinent and useful to the public. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 77, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 81, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 338, sec. 6, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5016</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>