<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.846</section_number><catch_line>Examination -- Educational and training programs. </catch_line><order_by>846</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The examination of the National Commission on Certification of Physician Assistants for licensure as a physician assistant shall be approved by the board. </section><section prefix="2">Educational and training programs approved by the board shall include physician assistant programs that are accredited by the Accreditation Review Commission on Education for Physician Assistants or its predecessor or successor agencies. </section><section prefix="3">Training programs for the provision of general or regional anesthesia shall be accredited by the Committee on Allied Health Education and Accreditation or the Commission on Accreditation of Allied Health Education Programs. </section><section prefix="4">A trainee enrolled in an approved program shall be supervised and the training program shall be responsible for the services provided by the trainee. A trainee shall have the same scope of practice as a physician assistant and shall not be considered to be practicing without authorization while enrolled in a training program. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 5, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 26, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2006).  2006 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 11, provides: "A physician assistant who is certified in Kentucky and in good standing on the effective date of this Act [July 12, 2006] shall automatically be licensed under Sections 1 to 10 of this Act [KRS 311.840, 311.842, 311.844, 311.845, 311.846, 311.848, 311.850, 311.852, 311.856, and 311.862] and shall be issued a physician assistant license upon annual renewal." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30651</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>