<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="196" order_by="196">CORRECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>196.180</section_number><catch_line>Duties of warden -- Removal -- Expungement of dismissed or voided disciplinary reports. </catch_line><order_by>180</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The warden shall have the general management of the institution, and the inmates thereof, subject to the administrative regulations of the Department of Corrections, and he or she shall devote his or her entire time to the duties of his or her office. </section><section prefix="2">The warden of each institution shall be held responsible for the management of his or her institution and shall be subject to removal at any time by the commissioner. </section><section prefix="3">The warden of each Department of Corrections institution shall expunge inmate prison disciplinary reports that have been dismissed or otherwise ordered void, and shall further remove any reference to dismissed or voided disciplinary reports from inmate records. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 107, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 34, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 401, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 344, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. V, sec. 24(14). -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 50, sec. 32. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 216aa-11, 216aa-20. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6810</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>