<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.0064</section_number><catch_line>Equivalents to standard high school diploma -- Diploma through examination -- External diploma program.   </catch_line><order_by>0064</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For purposes of any public employment, a high school equivalency diploma or a regular high school diploma obtained through participation in the external diploma program shall be considered equal to a high school diploma issued under the provisions of KRS 158.140. <section prefix="a">A high school equivalency diploma shall be issued without charge upon successfully passing the test given by the Kentucky Adult Education Program's approved testing centers in conformance with requirements of the General Educational Development Testing Service of the American Council on Education. A fee may be assessed by the Kentucky Adult Education Program for the issuance of a duplicate high school equivalency diploma and for issuance of a duplicate score report. All fees collected for duplicate diplomas and score reports shall be used to support the adult education program. </section><section prefix="b">As an alternative to receiving a high school equivalency diploma, persons who are twenty-five (25) years or older may obtain a high school diploma through participation in the external diploma program. The diploma shall be issued upon achieving one hundred percent (100%) mastery on the competencies established by the American Council on Education. The Kentucky Adult Education Program may enter into agreements with local school districts to confer the high school diploma on successful participants in the external diploma program. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Adult Education Program is authorized to contract annually with an institution of higher education or other appropriate agency or entity for scoring the GED examination essay. </section></text><history> Repealed, reenacted, and renumbered 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 32, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 36, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 13, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 63, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 145, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 363, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 469, sec. 23, effective July 15, 1994. -- Repealed, reenacted and amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 470, sec. 23, effective July 1, 1990; amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, sec. 167. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 361, sec. 12, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 311, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 192, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><former-codification> KRS 156.485 KRS 151B.125. </former-codification><former-codification-former-code>151B.125</former-codification-former-code><lrc-note> (7/15/94).  This section was amended by 1994 Ky. Acts chs. 363 and 469. Where these Acts are not in conflict, they have been codified together. Where a conflict exists, Acts ch. 469, which was last enacted by the General Assembly, prevails under KRS 446.250.  (7/13/90).  This section was amended by two 1990 Acts which are in conflict. Pursuant to KRS 446.250, the Act which was last enacted by the General Assembly prevails. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42209</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>