<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="439" order_by="439">PROBATION AND PAROLE </unit></structure><section_number>439.250</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 439.250 to 439.560. </catch_line><order_by>250</order_by><text>As used in KRS 439.250 to 439.560, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Secretary" means the secretary of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet; </section><section prefix="2">"Commissioner" means the commissioner of the Department of Corrections; </section><section prefix="3">"Department" means the Department of Corrections; </section><section prefix="4">"Deputy commissioner" means the deputy commissioner of the Office of Adult Institutions or the deputy commissioner of the Office of Community Services and Facilities of the Department of Corrections; </section><section prefix="5">"Board" means the Parole Board created by KRS 439.320; </section><section prefix="6">"Community supervision" means: <section prefix="a">The placement of a defendant under supervision with conditions imposed by a court for a specified period during which: <section prefix="1">Criminal proceedings are deferred without an adjudication of guilt; or </section><section prefix="2">A sentence of imprisonment or confinement, imprisonment and fine, or confinement and fine, is probated and the imposition of sentence is suspended in whole or in part; or </section></section><section prefix="b">The placement of an individual under supervision after release from prison or jail, with conditions imposed by the board for a specified period; </section></section><section prefix="7">"Compliance credit" means a credit on a paroled individual's sentence for program credit, work-for-time credit, educational accomplishment, or meritorious service and shall be calculated pursuant to the applicable provisions in KRS 197.045 and 197.047; </section><section prefix="8">"Positive reinforcement" means any of a wide range of rewards and incentives, including but not limited to awarding certificates of achievement, reducing reporting requirements, deferring a monthly supervision fee payment, removing supervision conditions such as home detention or curfew, or asking the supervised individual to be a mentor to others; </section><section prefix="9">"Probation and parole district supervisor" means the highest ranking field probation or parole administrator in each district; and </section><section prefix="10">"Supervised individual" means an individual placed on probation by a court or serving a period of parole or post-release supervision from prison or jail. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 29, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 318, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 90, July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 344, sec. 37, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. V, secs. 24(16), 28. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 275. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 106, Art. X, sec. 10. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 42. -- Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39549</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>