<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.076</section_number><catch_line>Price contracts information to be furnished district boards -- Purchase conditions. </catch_line><order_by>076</order_by><text>The chief state school officer shall furnish full information on established price contracts to each district board of education. Any board of education may purchase supplies and equipment from the vendor to whom the contract has been awarded, under the terms of the contract. Any board of education may advertise for its own bids on supplies and equipment which meet the specifications of the contracts awarded by the Office of Material and Procurement Services in the Office of the Controller. Any board of education, after advertising for bids, may award contracts if the chief state school officer certifies that the bid offers supplies and equipment which meet the standards and specifications fixed by the Kentucky Board of Education and that the bid price is lower than that established by the price contract agreement. If supplies and equipment that meet the specifications of the contracts awarded by the Office of Material and Procurement Services or a federal, local, or cooperative agency are available for purchase elsewhere, a board of education may purchase those supplies and equipment without advertising for bids. However, prior to making the purchases, the board of education shall obtain certification from: <section prefix="1">The Department of Education for technology components defined in the master plan for education technology for which standards have been established by the Kentucky Board of Education. The department shall certify that the items to be purchased meet or exceed, at a lower cost, the specifications of the components of the original equipment of manufacturers currently holding Kentucky education technology system price contracts; and </section><section prefix="2">The district's finance officer for supplies and equipment other than that described in subsection (1) of this section. He shall certify that the items to be purchased meet the standards and specifications fixed by state price contract, federal (GSA) price contract, the local school district's bid, or the bid of another school district whose bid specifications allow other districts to utilize their bids, and that the sales price is lower than that established by the price contract agreement or available through the bidding process and the price does not exceed two thousand five hundred dollars ($2,500). </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 590, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 9, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1996; and ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. IV, sec. 129, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 82, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 244, Art. II, sec. 7. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3112</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>