<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171">STATE LIBRARIES -- LIBRARIANS -- STATE ARCHIVES AND RECORDS </unit></structure><section_number>171.820</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Native American Heritage Commission -- Members -- Officers -- Meetings -- Funding. </catch_line><order_by>820</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Native American Heritage Commission is hereby established to promote, in partnership with the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet, awareness of significant Native American influences within the historical and cultural experiences of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="2">The membership of the commission shall consist of seventeen (17) members who derive from geographically diverse areas of the state and who represent various heritage interests as follows: <section prefix="a">The secretary of the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet, or the secretary's designee; </section><section prefix="b">Three (3) members from institutions of higher learning; </section><section prefix="c">Two (2) members from the preservation or archeological communities; </section><section prefix="d">One (1) member from the arts community; and </section><section prefix="e">Ten (10) members from the public at large, eight (8) of whom shall be of Native American heritage. </section></section><section prefix="3">Members listed in paragraphs (b) to (e) of subsection (2) of this section shall be appointed by the Governor and shall serve for terms of four (4) years. Any vacancy shall be filled by appointment of the Governor for the remainder of the unexpired term. </section><section prefix="4">Commission members shall receive no compensation for their services but may be reimbursed for actual and necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their duties. </section><section prefix="5">From the commission membership, the Governor shall appoint a chair and vice chair of the commission. The commission may elect by majority vote other officers deemed necessary. </section><section prefix="6">The commission shall meet at least three (3) times per year. Notice of the time and location of each meeting shall be provided in writing to each member at least ten (10) days in advance of the meeting. </section><section prefix="7">A majority of the members present shall constitute a quorum. </section><section prefix="8">Committees may be formed at the discretion of the chair. </section><section prefix="9">The commission may seek and accept grants or raise funds from any available source, public or private, to accomplish its duties and responsibilities. </section><section prefix="10">The commission shall be attached for administrative purposes to the Kentucky Heritage Council, whose responsibilities shall include but not be limited to designating a staff person to coordinate commission staff needs and providing other staff and services as needed for the commission to perform its duties under KRS 171.822. </section></text><history>Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 49, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><lrc-note>(6/25/2009).  2009 Ky. Acts ch.16, relating to the creation and organization of the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet, instructs the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in that Act. Such a correction has been made in this section.  (6/20/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 95, 97, 98, 99, 123, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-16</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4869</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>