<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.12-2088</section_number><catch_line>Guidelines -- Application -- Preliminary approval -- Final authorizing resolution. </catch_line><order_by>12-2088</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Bluegrass State Skills Corporation shall establish guidelines and standards for approving skills training investment credits for occupational upgrade training and skills upgrade training. The guidelines and standards may include, but are not limited to: required hours of classroom instruction; required courses; certification of teachers or instructors, whether independent contractors or employees of a qualified company; certification of providers; progressive levels of instruction; and standardized measures of employee evaluation to determine successful completion of a course of study. </section><section prefix="2">To apply for skills training investment credits under KRS 154.12-2084 to 154.12-2089, a qualified company shall submit an application to the Bluegrass State Skills Corporation before commencing its program of occupational upgrade training or skills upgrade training. The application submitted by the qualified company shall contain information the Bluegrass State Skills Corporation requires including, but not limited to: <section prefix="a">A proposal for a program of occupational upgrade training or skills upgrade training; </section><section prefix="b">A description of each component of the proposed training program and the number of employee training hours requested; </section><section prefix="c">A statement of all anticipated costs and expenses of the training program, including the costs and expenses associated with employee wages, equipment, personnel, facilities, and materials; and </section><section prefix="d">Auditing procedures and reporting methods for the submission of information and data to the Bluegrass State Skills Corporation. </section></section><section prefix="3">After a review of applications for skills training investment credits, the Bluegrass State Skills Corporation may designate the qualified company as a preliminarily approved company and preliminarily approve the amount of skills training investment credits that the qualified company shall be eligible to receive. The maximum amount of skills training investment credits preliminarily approved for all qualified companies by the Bluegrass State Skills Corporation for fiscal year 1998-1999 and fiscal year 1999-2000 shall not exceed one million dollars ($1,000,000) and shall not exceed two million five hundred thousand dollars ($2,500,000) for each fiscal year thereafter. Skills training investment credits shall be allocated to qualified companies in the same order preliminary approval is granted by the Bluegrass State Skills Corporation. Skills training investment credits that remain unallocated by the Bluegrass State Skills Corporation at the end of its fiscal year shall lapse and shall not be carried forward to a new fiscal year. </section><section prefix="4">The preliminarily approved company shall complete all programs of occupational upgrade training or skills upgrade training within one (1) year from the date of the preliminary approval of the skills training investment credits by the Bluegrass State Skills Corporation and shall certify the completion of these programs to the Bluegrass State Skills Corporation. </section><section prefix="5">The preliminarily approved company shall maintain in its employment the employees receiving occupational upgrade or skills upgrade training for a minimum of ninety (90) days following the completion of the program of occupational upgrade training or skills upgrade training and shall certify to the Bluegrass State Skills Corporation the number of employees who remained in the employment of the preliminarily approved company for the full ninety (90) day period. </section><section prefix="6">If a qualified company concludes its training program within the prescribed one (1) year and receives the required certifications described in subsections (4) and (5) of this section, then the Bluegrass State Skills Corporation shall adopt a final authorizing resolution approving the amount of skills training investment credits awarded to the preliminarily approved company in accordance with KRS 154.12-2084 to 154.12-2089. The adoption of a final authorizing resolution shall be contingent upon the Bluegrass State Skills Corporation's approval of documentation submitted by the preliminarily approved company supporting all incurred approved costs. If one (1) or more of the employees of the preliminarily approved company failed to continue in the employment of the company for ninety (90) days following the completion of the prescribed one (1) year, then the amount of the skills training investment credits preliminarily approved for a qualified company shall be reduced on a pro rata basis for each employee who failed to continue employment with the preliminarily approved company through the ninety (90) day period. The final amount of the skills training investment credits awarded to the approved company shall not exceed the amount of skills training investment credits that the approved company was preliminarily approved for by the Bluegrass State Skills Corporation prior to commencement of the training program. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 300, sec. 8, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 499, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2625</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>