<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="324" order_by="324">A REAL ESTATE APPRAISERS </unit></structure><section_number>324A.035</section_number><catch_line>Administrative regulations to establish requirements for certification or licensure.   </catch_line><order_by>035</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to the provisions of this chapter and KRS Chapter 13A for certification or licensure of appraisers who perform appraisals of real property in federally related transactions. Requirements established by the board relating to appraisers of federally related transactions shall not exceed the minimum requirements established by federal law or regulation; </section><section prefix="2">The board shall promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A for certification or licensure of appraisers of real property in nonfederally related transactions. <section prefix="a">Appraisers who wish to be limited to appraisals of nonfederally related transactions, and who have engaged in the appraisal of real estate for at least ten (10) years prior to April 7, 1992, shall be certified or licensed as appraisers of nonfederally related transactions. </section><section prefix="b">Appraisers who wish to be limited to appraisals of nonfederally related transactions, and who have not engaged in the appraisal of real estate for at least ten (10) years prior to April 7, 1992, shall be certified or licensed as appraisers of nonfederally related transactions if they meet the certification or licensure requirements established by the board. </section></section><section prefix="3">The board shall establish by administrative regulations requirements for: <section prefix="a">Classifications of appraisers; </section><section prefix="b">Certification and licensure; </section><section prefix="c">Renewal, suspension, or revocation of certification or licensure; </section><section prefix="d">Standards of professional appraisal practice, including experience, education, and ethics; </section><section prefix="e">Examination of applicants for certification or licensure; and </section><section prefix="f">Continuing education of appraisers. </section></section></text><history>Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 46, sec. 10, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 247, sec. 4, effective April 7, 1992. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 383, sec. 6, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42097</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>