<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="351" order_by="351">DEPARTMENT FOR NATURAL RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>351.182</section_number><catch_line>Drug-and alcohol-free status required for miner certification -- Proof -- Costs of testing -- Breath alcohol device at examination site -- Ten panel urine test.   </catch_line><order_by>182</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All applicants for certification as new miners and all initial applicants for all other certifications provided for in this chapter shall provide proof of drug- and alcohol-free status prior to certification in accordance with the provisions of this section. </section><section prefix="2">Proof of drug- and alcohol-free status shall be provided in one (1) of two (2) methods: <section prefix="a">By participation in a drug and alcohol testing program offered by the division and paid for by the applicant, in accordance with this section and KRS 351.183; or </section><section prefix="b">By the submission of drug and alcohol test results from other sources, as provided in KRS 351.183(2). </section></section><section prefix="3">If a newly certified miner gains employment in the coal industry, the initial employer shall reimburse the certified miner for the cost of one (1) drug and alcohol test required by this section and KRS 351.183, 351.184, and 351.185. </section><section prefix="4">If the applicant is currently certified in any category other than that for which he is applying by the division and the applicant is currently employed in the coal industry, the applicant's employer shall reimburse the applicant for the cost of one (1) drug and alcohol test required by this section and KRS 351.183, 351.184, and 351.185. </section><section prefix="5">The fee charged to an applicant for the drug and alcohol tests offered by the division shall not exceed the actual cost of collection, analysis, and medical review officer (MRO) review. </section><section prefix="6">The division shall provide, at each site of examinations for the certifications provided for in Chapter 351, a breath alcohol testing device and a person certified in the operation of the breath alcohol testing device. The breath alcohol test shall be administered prior to examination to determine the applicant's alcohol-free status. The division may satisfy the requirement to furnish an alcohol testing device and certified personnel by: <section prefix="a">The use of equipment and appropriately certified personnel of the division; </section><section prefix="b">A memorandum of agreement with state or local police agencies for the provision of equipment and appropriately trained personnel at the examination site; or </section><section prefix="c">Inclusion of breath alcohol testing as part of the contract to provide drug testing and collection services set out in KRS 351.183(1). </section></section><section prefix="7">A breath alcohol concentration of .04 shall be the maximum acceptable level of concentration for participation in the examination and subsequent certification. </section><section prefix="8">Except for an alternative testing protocol provided for post-accident victims under KRS 352.180(5) to (7), the minimum testing protocol acceptable for the establishment of drug-free status for certification under KRS Chapter 351 shall be at least a ten (10) panel urine test that shall include testing for the following substances: <section prefix="a">Amphetamines; </section><section prefix="b">Cannabanoids/THC; </section><section prefix="c">Cocaine; </section><section prefix="d">Opiates; </section><section prefix="e">Phencyclidine (PCP); </section><section prefix="f">Benzodiazepines; </section><section prefix="g">Propoxyphene; </section><section prefix="h">Buprenorphine; </section><section prefix="i">Methadone; </section><section prefix="j">Barbiturates; and </section><section prefix="k">The remaining panels to be used in the urine test shall be set by order of the Mine Safety Review Commission no later than June 1 of each year. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 87, sec. 21, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 4, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 241, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2006).  2006 Ky. Acts ch. 241, sec. 2, subsec. (7), provides: "A breath alcohol concentration of four tenths of a percent (.04) shall be the maximum acceptable level of concentration for participation in the examination and subsequent certification." The words "four tenths of a percent" and the parentheses around ".04" were removed during codification to correct a manifest clerical error that occurred in the drafting process. Materials in the bill folder for House Bill 572 (which became 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 241) show that the bill was drafted to be an exact copy of a bill requested and later introduced as Senate Bill 201, the initial proposed draft of which provided: "A breath alcohol concentration of .04 shall be the maximum acceptable level of concentration for participation in the examination(s) and subsequent certification(s)." Materials in the bill folder for Senate Bill 201 indicate that the erroneous phrase was inserted during the drafting process to conform with the rules for cardinal numbers set forth in the Bill Drafting Manual of the Kentucky General Assembly. The Reviser of Statutes has made this correction under the authority of KRS 7.136(1). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44538</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>