<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="183" order_by="183">AVIATION </unit></structure><section_number>183.090</section_number><catch_line>Licensing of airports -- Inspection. </catch_line><order_by>090</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet shall cause all airport facilities in the state to be inspected to determine the safety and adequacy of such facilities. No person shall operate any aircraft from an airport declared unfit by the cabinet. </section><section prefix="2">In determining whether it shall issue a certificate of approval or license for the use or operation of any airport, the cabinet shall take into consideration its location, size, layout, safety of operations, the relationship of the airport to a comprehensive plan for statewide and nationwide development, whether the adjoining area is free from obstructions based on a proper glide ratio, the nature of the terrain, the nature of the uses to which the airport will be put, and the possibilities for future development. </section><section prefix="3">The cabinet is empowered to temporarily or permanently revoke any certificate of approval or license issued by it when it shall determine that an airport or other navigation facility is not being maintained or used in accordance with the provisions of this chapter and the rules and regulations promulgated pursuant thereto. </section></text><history>Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 179, sec. 12. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 153, sec. 9. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 6. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 165-54. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5726</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>