<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">A URBAN-COUNTY GOVERNMENT </unit></structure><section_number>67A.075</section_number><catch_line>Safety officers -- Appointment -- Duties -- Compensation. </catch_line><order_by>075</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The legislative body of urban-county governments may appoint as needed safety officers. Safety officers shall have duties as prescribed by ordinance, which may include but not be limited to: <section prefix="a">Issuance of citations for violation of motor vehicle offenses as provided for in KRS Chapters 186 and 189, provided that safety officers shall not have the authority to issue citations for moving violations. </section><section prefix="b">Issuance of citations for violation of any motor vehicle or traffic safety ordinance of the urban-county government. </section><section prefix="c">Control and direction of traffic on public thoroughfares. </section><section prefix="d">Removal of vehicles in violation of state or local law consistent with those laws. </section></section><section prefix="2">The ordinance prescribing the duties of safety officers shall set out the urban-county ordinances and the sections of KRS Chapters 186 and 189 for which citation authority will exist. </section><section prefix="3">A safety officer may issue a citation for a misdemeanor or a violation committed in his presence as provided in this section. The procedures for citations shall be the same as provided in KRS 431.015. </section><section prefix="4">Safety officers appointed by authority of this section shall have only the limited powers as provided by this section and shall not have the powers of peace officers to make arrests or carry deadly weapons. </section><section prefix="5">Safety officers shall successfully complete one hundred twenty (120) hours of appropriate training certified by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council prior to being appointed as a safety officer. </section><section prefix="6">Safety officers shall be compensated and receive employment benefits as provided by urban-county ordinance. </section><section prefix="7">While in the process of securing information to complete accident reports and notwithstanding any statute to the contrary, safety officers may issue citations for violations of KRS 186.430, 186.450, 186.510, and 186.540. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 46, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 166, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1978; and ch. 173, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23848</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>