<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.670</section_number><catch_line>Notice as to deduction required -- Disposition of collections -- Records. </catch_line><order_by>670</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In the event a majority of the eligible producers in such referendum who vote therein shall vote in favor of the assessment, then the Commissioner shall notify forthwith, by certified mail, every person licensed to operate a livestock market in the state, as well as every person who operates a meat packing or slaughter establishment which buys bovine animals directly from the producer and every order buyer, that on and after the date designated in the notice, which shall be not less than thirty (30) days nor more than sixty (60) days after the mailing of the notice by the Commissioner, the amount of the assessment shall be deducted by all such sales markets or purchasers of bovine animals, or by their agents or representatives, from the purchase price paid the seller of bovine animals. </section><section prefix="2">On or before the fifteenth day of each month all assessments deducted shall be remitted to the association certified by the assessment referendum, less three percent (3%) which may be retained to compensate the stockyard operator, meat packer, order buyer, or slaughter establishment operator for the expense of collecting and remitting the assessment. </section><section prefix="3">The books and records of all stockyard operators, meat packers, order buyers, and slaughter establishment operators shall at all times during regular business hours be open for inspection by the Commissioner or his duly authorized agents for the purpose of ascertaining the accuracy of the amounts remitted. </section></text><history>Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 49, effective July 15, 1980; and ch. 213, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 9, sec. 13.</history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1980</effective><lrc-note>.This section was amended by two 1980 acts which do not appear to be in conflict and have been compiled together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11776</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>