<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171">STATE LIBRARIES -- LIBRARIANS -- STATE ARCHIVES AND RECORDS </unit></structure><section_number>171.520</section_number><catch_line>Supervision of state and local agencies -- Plan for comprehensive records management system for state government -- Rules and regulations. </catch_line><order_by>520</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The department shall, with due regard to the program activities of the state and local agencies concerned, prescribe the policies and principles to be followed by state and local agencies in the conduct of their records management programs, and make provisions for the economical and efficient management of records by state and local agencies by analyzing, developing, promoting, and coordinating standards, procedures, and techniques designed to improve the management of records, to insure the maintenance and security of records deemed appropriate for preservation, and to facilitate the segregation and disposal of records of temporary value and by promoting the efficient and economical utilization of space, equipment, and supplies needed for the purpose of creating, maintaining, storing, and servicing records.  The department may accept, administer and grant any money appropriated or granted to it, in addition to appropriations from the general fund, for providing and improving records management programs of state and local agencies. </section><section prefix="2">To effect the purposes of subsection (1) of this section, the department shall prepare a plan for a comprehensive records management system for Kentucky state government. This plan shall include a proposal for funding through cost allocation or other methods in lieu of a general fund appropriation. The plan shall provide for a records management certification program, to identify state agencies in compliance with records management practices implemented by the department, and shall be completed by July 1, 1987. The plan shall be submitted to the Office of Policy and Management and the Legislative Research Commission for evaluation. </section><section prefix="3">The department shall promulgate necessary rules and regulations for the furtherance of this section. </section></text><history>Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 66, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 39. -- Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 49, sec. 12, effective June 19, 1958. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4830</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>