<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IV" order_by="4">JUDICIAL BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="31" order_by="31">DEPARTMENT OF PUBLIC ADVOCACY </unit></structure><section_number>31.060</section_number><catch_line>Local office in jurisdiction with ten or more Circuit Judges required -- Funding by governmental unit required in amount set by department.   </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each county, urban-county, charter county, and consolidated local government with a judicial circuit containing ten (10) or more Circuit Judges, excluding judges of family court divisions as designated by the Supreme Court, shall establish and maintain an office of public advocacy and submit a plan for the operation thereof to the Department of Public Advocacy. If the plan submitted is approved by the Department of Public Advocacy, the public advocate shall grant to the county, urban-county, charter county, or consolidated local government the amount to which it would be entitled under KRS 31.050(2) which shall be used as the Commonwealth's share in defraying the expenses of the program in that county, urban-county, charter county, or consolidated local government. </section><section prefix="2">A county, urban-county, charter county, or consolidated local government identified in subsection (1) of this section shall contribute to the funding of the plan selected and approved in such amounts as the Department of Public Advocacy shall deem reasonable and necessary. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 5, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 283, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 23, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 358, sec. 3. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 353, sec. 6. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40876</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>