<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.3-862</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of receiver. </catch_line><order_by>3-862</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A receiver shall have the following powers:  <section prefix="a">To take possession of all books, records and assets of the bank;  </section><section prefix="b">To collect all debts, claims and judgments belonging to the bank, and to do such other acts as are necessary to preserve and liquidate its assets;  </section><section prefix="c">To execute in the name of the bank any instrument necessary or proper to effectuate its powers or perform its duties as receiver;  </section><section prefix="d">To initiate, pursue and defend litigation involving any right, claim, interest or liability of the bank;  </section><section prefix="e">To exercise any and all fiduciary functions of the bank as of the date of appointment as receiver;  </section><section prefix="f">Subject to the approval of the receivership court, to borrow money as necessary in the liquidation of the bank, and to secure such borrowings by the pledge or mortgage of bank assets; the repayment of money borrowed under this subsection and interest thereon shall be considered an expense of administration under KRS 286.3-872;  </section><section prefix="g">Subject to the approval of the receivership court, to abandon or convey title to any holder of a mortgage, security deed, security interest or lien against property in which the bank has an interest, whenever the receiver determines that to continue to claim such interest is burdensome and of no advantage to the bank, its depositors, creditors or shareholders;  </section><section prefix="h">Subject to the approval of the receivership court, to sell any and all real and personal property, to compromise any debt, claim or judgment due to the bank and to discontinue any action or other proceeding pending therefor; and  </section><section prefix="i">Subject to the approval of the receivership court, to avoid preferential transfers as defined in KRS 286.3-864.  </section></section><section prefix="2">A receiver shall have the following duties:  <section prefix="a">To collect, preserve, and liquidate the bank's assets as expeditiously as is compatible with the best interests of the bank and its depositors, creditors and shareholders;  </section><section prefix="b">To file with the receivership court:  <section prefix="1">A detailed statement of the assets and liabilities of the bank within thirty (30) days of confirmation; and  </section><section prefix="2">A report of its actions in the administration of the liquidation proceedings, together with such other information as the receivership court may require, every ninety (90) days thereafter;  </section></section><section prefix="c">To examine claims and reject any claim that is improper; and  </section><section prefix="d">Unless the receivership court orders otherwise, furnish such information concerning the bank and the administration of the liquidation proceedings as is requested by a depositor, creditor or shareholder.  </section></section></text><history>Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 324, sec. 47, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984 </effective><former-codification> KRS287.862. </former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  In accordance with 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, secs. 38 and 39, this statute has been renumbered as a section of the Kentucky Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286, and KRS references within this statute have been adjusted to conform with the 2006 renumbering of that code. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14612</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>