<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="199" order_by="199">PROTECTIVE SERVICES FOR CHILDREN - ADOPTION </unit></structure><section_number>199.017</section_number><catch_line>Finance and Administration Cabinet to implement "Code Adam" program -- Training -- Signs -- Drills -- Annual report. </catch_line><order_by>017</order_by><text>The secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, in consultation with the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet through the Department of Kentucky State Police, shall: <section prefix="1">Be responsible for coordinating implementation of the "Code Adam" program throughout the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="2">Provide training to administrators of state buildings and employees designated by those administrators in the implementation of the "Code Adam" program; </section><section prefix="3">Provide training in procedures for the search of state buildings and grounds for lost and missing children; </section><section prefix="4">Print and distribute signs to each public agency for use in each state building relating to the "Code Adam" program and how to initiate a "Code Adam." The signs shall be not less than twelve (12) inches square and have white letters and a purple background containing the information specified by the cabinet by administrative regulation; </section><section prefix="5">Provide for annually conducting a "Code Adam" drill at each facility covered by the provisions of KRS 199.013 to 199.019; </section><section prefix="6">Provide for the collection of statistics from each facility covered by the provisions of KRS 199.013 to 199.019 on each "Code Adam" within the state building; </section><section prefix="7">Provide an annual report to the Governor, the Department of Kentucky State Police, the Legislative Research Commission, and the General Assembly on each "Code Adam" within the Commonwealth during the previous calendar year and the results of each "Code Adam" incident. The annual report shall be a public record and shall not include the name or other identifying information, other than gender and age, of the child; and </section><section prefix="8">Promulgate administrative regulations necessary for the implementation of the "Code Adam" program as required by KRS 199.013 to 199.010. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 237, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 21, sec. 3, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7105</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>