<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="200" order_by="200">ASSISTANCE TO CHILDREN </unit></structure><section_number>200.595</section_number><catch_line>Effect of furnishing and acceptance of family preservation services. </catch_line><order_by>595</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The provision of family preservation services to a family shall constitute a reasonable effort by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services to prevent the removal of a child from the child's home under KRS 620.140, provided that the family has received timely access to other services from the Cabinet for Health and Family Services for which the family is eligible. </section><section prefix="2">Acceptance of family preservation services shall not be considered an admission of any allegation that initiated the investigation of the family, nor shall refusal of family preservation services be considered as evidence in any proceeding except where the issue is whether the Cabinet for Health and Family Services has made reasonable efforts to prevent removal of a child. </section><section prefix="3">No family preservation services program shall compel any family member to engage in any activity or refrain from any activity which is not reasonably related to remedying a condition or conditions that gave rise or which could reasonably give rise to any finding of child abuse, neglect, or dependency. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 207, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 171, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 265, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7318</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>