<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="7" order_by="7">LEGISLATIVE RESEARCH COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>7.134</section_number><catch_line>Contents of certified versions of KRS -- Format -- Requirements for certificate. </catch_line><order_by>134</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Certified versions of the Kentucky Revised Statutes shall contain: <section prefix="a">The Constitution of the United States; </section><section prefix="b">The Constitution of this Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="c">The text of all laws contained in the official version of the Kentucky Revised Statutes; </section><section prefix="d">A full and accurate index of the statute laws and Constitution of this Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="e">The rules of the Supreme Court of Kentucky, the Kentucky Rules of Civil Procedure, the Kentucky Rules of Criminal Procedure, and any other judicial materials specified by the Commission; and </section><section prefix="f">Any annotations, historical notes, and other information that the Commission deems appropriate to include. </section></section><section prefix="2">A certified version of the Kentucky Revised Statutes may be in a printed or electronic format and shall be updated in a manner and frequency acceptable to the Commission to provide prompt notice to its users of the texts of newly-created and newly-amended statutes, the repeals of existing statutes, and any technical corrections, renumberings, or notes issued by the Commission. If a publisher produces more than one (1) version of the Kentucky Revised Statutes, a separate certification may be required for each version. </section><section prefix="3">Each new complete certified version of the Kentucky Revised Statutes and each new volume, unit, supplement, supplemental pocket part, or electronic release of a certified version shall include a certificate issued by the director of the Legislative Research Commission and attested to by the reviser of statutes that the particular material being certified has been prepared in a manner acceptable to the Legislative Research Commission so as to ensure the identity of its text with the official version of the Kentucky Revised Statutes. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 46, sec. 4, effective January 1, 1997. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 2, effective June 19, 1976. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 2(1), and (2), effective June 16, 1966. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 1997 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=473</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>