<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.170</section_number><catch_line>Powers of secretary. </catch_line><order_by>170</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In the discharge of the duties imposed by this chapter the secretary or his duly authorized representative may administer oaths and affirmations, take depositions, certify official acts, and issue subpoenas to compel the attendance of witnesses and production of books, papers, correspondence, memoranda and other records considered necessary and relevant as evidence in connection with the administration of the cabinet. Such subpoena shall be served in the same manner as a subpoena issued out of a Circuit Court. </section><section prefix="2">No person shall be excused from attending and testifying or from producing books, papers, correspondence, memoranda or other records in response to such subpoena on the grounds that the evidence required of him may tend to incriminate him or subject him to a penalty, or forfeiture. No person shall be prosecuted or subjected to any suit, penalty, or forfeiture on account of any transaction, matter, or thing concerning which he or his agent or worker is compelled, after having claimed privilege against self-incrimination, to give evidence except that such witness so testifying shall not be exempt from punishment for perjury. </section></text><history>Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(21) and (29). -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 256, sec. 3. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 33, sec. 2. -- Created 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 3. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7642</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>