<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.3-350</section_number><catch_line>When dividends may be declared. </catch_line><order_by>3-350</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board of directors of any bank or trust company organized under the laws of this state may declare a dividend of so much of the net profits as they deem expedient. The net profits shall be computed by deducting all expenses, losses, and interest and taxes accrued or due from the bank. </section><section prefix="2">The approval of the commissioner shall be required if the total of all dividends declared by such institution in any calendar year shall exceed the total of its net profits of that year combined with its retained net profits of the preceding two (2) years, less any required transfers to surplus or a fund for the retirement of preferred stock or debt. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 636, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 183, sec. 10, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 196, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 251, sec. 11, effective April 1, 1982. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 596. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 287.350. </former-codification><lrc-note> (7/12/2006).  This section was amended in 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 183. In that same session, 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, sec. 38 required that all sections of KRS Chapters 287, 288, 290, 291, 294, 366, 366A, and 368 be renumbered as sections of a single KRS chapter entitled the "Kentucky Financial Services Code." Therefore, the Statute Reviser, acting under KRS 7.136(1), has changed the number of this section and codified it as a section of KRS Chapter 286. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14579</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>