<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="43" order_by="43">AUDITOR OF PUBLIC ACCOUNTS </unit></structure><section_number>43.060</section_number><catch_line>Monthly investigation of accounts of Treasurer and Finance and Administration Cabinet. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text>The Auditor shall make audits of the accounts of the State Treasurer and the Finance and Administration Cabinet not less than once each month. He shall ascertain, by personal examination of the books, accounts, and papers in the office of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, the money received by it each month, the sources from which received, and the money paid by it into the State Treasury each month. He shall carefully examine into the books, accounts, and papers in the office of the State Treasury, and ascertain the amounts of money paid into and out of the State Treasury each month, and shall ascertain the amount of money on hand by counting it and by personal inquiry of the cashier of each bank or depository in which any state money has been placed or deposited. The Auditor shall compare the vouchers and receipts of the Finance and Administration Cabinet and the State Treasurer, and state the accounts of each, and make a thorough investigation of their offices. The investigations and audits required by this section shall be made between the first day and the tenth day of each month, and at any other time the Auditor thinks necessary. </text><history>Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. II sec. 9(1). -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 1992b-60, 4630. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22115</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>