<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.848</section_number><catch_line>Agreements for training workers.   </catch_line><order_by>848</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The vice president of the Kentucky Adult Education Program in the Council on Postsecondary Education and the commissioner of education may enter into agreements to train workers for new manufacturing jobs in new or expanding industries characterized by one (1) or more of the following criteria: a high average skill, a high average wage, rapid national growth, or jobs feasible and desirable for location in rural regions. Such agreements shall not be subject to the requirements of KRS 45A.045 and KRS 45A.690 to 45A.725 when awarded on the basis of a detailed training plan approved by the appropriate agency head. Reimbursement to the industry shall be made upon submission of documents validating actual training expenditure not to exceed the amount approved by the training plan. </section><section prefix="2">The vice president and the commissioner of education may approve authorization for his or her agency to enter into agreements with industries whereby the industry may be reimbursed directly for the following services: <section prefix="a">The cost of instructors' salaries when the instructor is an employee of the industry to be served; </section><section prefix="b">Cost of only those supplies, materials, and equipment used exclusively in the training program; and </section><section prefix="c">Cost of leasing a training facility should a vocational education school or the industrial plant not be available. </section></section></text><history> Repealed, reenacted, renumbered, and amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 25, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 18, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 35, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 526, sec. 6, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 469, sec. 22, effective July 15, 1994. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 470, sec. 22, effective July 1, 1990; amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, sec. 141; and ch. 496, sec. 48. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 361, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 90, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 31, sec. 1, effective March 12, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><former-codification> KRS 156.253 KRS 151B.120. </former-codification><former-codification-former-code>151B.120</former-codification-former-code><lrc-note> (7/13/90).  The repeal, with reenactment and amendment, of this section prevailed over its amendment by two other Acts of the 1990 Regular Session pursuant to KRS 446.260. The Reviser has changed internal numbering references pursuant to KRS 7.136(1). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42195</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>