<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="351" order_by="351">DEPARTMENT FOR NATURAL RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>351.183</section_number><catch_line>Contracts for specimen collection and laboratory testing services -- Standards, procedures, and protocol -- Criteria for proof from other sources -- Annual publication of certified collection and testing providers.     </catch_line><order_by>183</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The division may contract with qualified companies to provide the collection of samples and administer the required drug and alcohol tests. The contract may provide that the collection of samples or testing be subcontracted, except that the contract shall require: <section prefix="a">The contractor and any subcontractors to follow all standards, procedures, and protocols set forth by the United States Department of Health and Human Services' Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAMHSA) for the collection and testing required by KRS 351.182 and this section; </section><section prefix="b">The contractor's or subcontractor's drug-testing protocol shall be a ten (10) panel test described in KRS 351.182(8) and any other test required by order of the Mine Safety Review Commission; and </section><section prefix="c">The contractor or the subcontractor shall provide a medical review officer (MRO) who shall: <section prefix="1">Possess the ability and medical training necessary to verify positive confirmed test results and evaluate those results in relation to an applicant's medical history or other biomedical information; and </section><section prefix="2">Follow all procedures outlined in the SAMHSA Medical Review Officer Manual. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">The director of the Division of Mine Safety may accept proof of drug- and alcohol-free status from other sources whose tests conform to the requirements set forth in KRS 351.182(7) and (8) and in accordance with KRS 351.182(2)(b) under the following conditions: <section prefix="a">An applicant shall submit a request for acceptance of his or her drug-and alcohol-free status to the director accompanied by pass/fail results of a drug and alcohol test taken within thirty (30) days prior to the request; and </section><section prefix="b">The test results shall have been performed by laboratories certified in accordance with the National Laboratory Certification Program (NLCP) by the United States Department of Health and Human Services Administration's SAMHSA and in accordance with subsection (1) of this section. </section></section><section prefix="3">The division shall maintain and publish annually a list of certified specimen collection services and testing laboratories from which it will accept data. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 87, sec. 22, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 5, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 241, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (6/24/2015). In codifying subsection (2)(a) of this statute, the Reviser of Statutes has changed the term "executive director" to "director." This substitution is consistent with amendments adopted in 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 87 reorganizing the Department for Natural Resources. The Reviser has made this change under the authority of KRS 7.136(2). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44539</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>