<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="175" order_by="175">B KENTUCKY PUBLIC TRANSPORTATION INFRASTRUCTURE AUTHORITY </unit></structure><section_number>175B.090</section_number><catch_line>Maintenance and repair of projects -- Restoration of or compensation for damaged private property -- Permitted leases. </catch_line><order_by>090</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each project constructed or operated under this chapter shall be maintained and kept in good condition and repair by the developing authority, which may contract with the department or with any local highway department for maintenance of a project. </section><section prefix="2">All private property damaged or destroyed in carrying out the powers granted by this chapter shall be restored or repaired and placed in its original condition as nearly as practicable or adequate compensation shall be made out of funds provided under this chapter. </section><section prefix="3">All counties, cities, towns, and other political subdivisions and all public agencies and commissions of the Commonwealth, notwithstanding any contrary provision of law, may lease, lend, grant, or convey to an authority any real property which may be necessary or convenient to the effectuation of the authorized purposes of the authority, including public roads and other real property already devoted to public use. </section><section prefix="4">In obtaining property under this chapter, an authority shall pursue the acquisition under the procedures and mandates of KRS 416.540 to 416.670. </section></text><history> Created 2009 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 92, effective June 26, 2009. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5151</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>