<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.294</section_number><catch_line>Use of personal communication device by minor prohibited while operating motor vehicle, motorcycle, or moped in motion on traveled portion of roadway -- Exclusions -- Administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>294</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, "personal communication device" shall have the same meaning as defined in KRS 189.292. </section><section prefix="2">Any person under the age of eighteen (18) who has been issued an instruction permit, intermediate license, or operator's license shall not operate a motor vehicle, motorcycle, or moped that is in motion on the traveled portion of a roadway while using a personal communication device, except to summon medical help or a law enforcement or public safety agency in an emergency situation. </section><section prefix="3">Use of a personal communication device does not include a stand-alone global positioning system, a global positioning or navigation system that is physically or electronically integrated into the motor vehicle, or an in-vehicle security, diagnostics, and communications system, but does include manually entering information into the global positioning system feature of a personal communication device. </section><section prefix="4">This section shall not apply to the use of a citizens band radio or an amateur radio by a motor vehicle operator. </section><section prefix="5">The secretary of the Transportation Cabinet may promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A to implement the provisions of this section, including but not limited to updates or advances in the automotive and information technology industries. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 4, effective June 8, 2011. -- Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39751</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>