<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>355.8-404</section_number><catch_line>Wrongful registration. </catch_line><order_by>8-404</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as otherwise provided in KRS 355.8-406, an issuer is liable for wrongful registration of transfer if the issuer has registered a transfer of a security to a person not entitled to it, and the transfer was registered: <section prefix="a">Pursuant to an ineffective indorsement or instruction; </section><section prefix="b">After a demand that the issuer not register transfer became effective under KRS 355.8-403(1) and the issuer did not comply with KRS 355.8-403(2); </section><section prefix="c">After the issuer had been served with an injunction, restraining order, or other legal process enjoining it from registering the transfer, issued by a court of competent jurisdiction, and the issuer had a reasonable opportunity to act on the injunction, restraining order, or other legal process; or </section><section prefix="d">By an issuer acting in collusion with the wrongdoer. </section></section><section prefix="2">An issuer that is liable for wrongful registration of transfer under subsection (1) of this section on demand shall provide the person entitled to the security with a like certificated or uncertificated security, and any payments or distributions that the person did not receive as a result of the wrongful registration. If an overissue would result, the issuer's liability to provide the person with a like security is governed by KRS 355.8-210. </section><section prefix="3">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (1) of this section or in a law relating to the collection of taxes, an issuer is not liable to an owner or other person suffering loss as a result of the registration of a transfer of a security if registration was made pursuant to an effective indorsement or instruction. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 150, effective January 1, 1997. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 49, effective July 1, 1987. -- Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 8-404, effective July 1, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 1997 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33712</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>