<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="336" order_by="336">LABOR CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>336.040</section_number><catch_line>Functions and duties of Labor Cabinet. </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Labor Cabinet shall exercise all administrative functions of the state concerned with employer-employee relationships, including the safety of workers and workers' compensation. </section><section prefix="2">The cabinet shall: <section prefix="a">Promote friendly and cooperative relations between employers and employees; </section><section prefix="b">Accumulate and publish industrial statistics and aid and encourage the development of new industries and the expansion of existing industries in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="c">Encourage, promote, and develop fair practices both by employers and employees; discourage and eliminate as far as practicable all unfair practices by either; and enforce laws relating to unfair practices; </section><section prefix="d">Foster, promote, and develop the welfare of both wage earners and industries in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="e">Improve working and living conditions of employees, and advance their opportunities for profitable employment; and </section><section prefix="f">Inquire into the causes of accidental injuries and occupational diseases arising out of and in the course of employment, and advance measures for the prevention of accidents and occupational diseases and for the improvement of sanitary conditions in places of employment. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1703, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 181, sec. 4, effective April 4, 1994. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 253. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 1599c-7, 4618-110. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31993</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>