<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="403" order_by="403">DISSOLUTION OF MARRIAGE -- CHILD CUSTODY </unit></structure><section_number>403.7527</section_number><catch_line>Filing of foreign protective order and affidavit -- Certification byissuing court official -- Entry into Law Information Network of Kentucky.  </catch_line><order_by>7527</order_by><text>(1)A copy of a foreign protective order may be filed in the office of the clerk of anycourt of competent jurisdiction of this state. A foreign protective order so filedshall have the same effect and shall be enforced in the same manner as anorder of protection issued by a court of this state.(2)(a)At the time of the filing of the foreign protective order, the person filing theorder shall file with the clerk of the court an affidavit on a form prescribedand provided by the Administrative Office of the Courts. The affidavit shallset forth the name, city, county, and state or other jurisdiction of theissuing court. The person shall certify in the affidavit the validity andstatus of the foreign protective order, and attest to the person's belief thatthe order has not been amended, rescinded, or superseded by any ordersfrom a court of competent jurisdiction. All foreign protective orderspresented with a completed and signed affidavit shall be accepted andfiled.(b)The affidavit signed by the applicant shall have space where thereviewing judge shall place information necessary to allow the order'sentry into the Law Information Network of Kentucky in the same manneras a Kentucky order.(3)(a)If the person seeking to file the order presents a copy of the foreign orderwhich is current by the terms of the order and has been certified by theclerk or other authorized officer of the court which issued it, the circuitclerk shall present it to the District Judge or Circuit Judge, who shall readthe order and enter on the affidavit the information necessary to allow theorder's entry into the Law Information Network of Kentucky. The ordershall not be subject to further verification and shall be accepted asauthentic, current, and subject to full faith and credit.(b)If the order presented is current by the terms of the order but is notcertified in the manner specified in paragraph (a) of this subsection, thecircuit clerk shall present the order and the affidavit to the District Judgeor Circuit Judge, who shall read the order and enter on the affidavit theinformation necessary to allow the order's entry into the Law InformationNetwork of Kentucky. The order shall be subject to full faith and credit inthe same manner as a Kentucky order of protection, but shall be subjectto verification by the circuit clerk. The order shall be valid for a period offourteen (14) days and may be renewed once for a period of fourteen (14)days if the circuit clerk has not received a certified copy of the order fromthe issuing jurisdiction. The clerk shall treat the foreign protective order inthe same manner as an order of protection issued pursuant to KRS403.740, except that no service on the adverse party shall be requiredpursuant to 18 U.S.C. sec. 2265.(c)Upon the filing of an uncertified foreign protective order, the circuit clerkshall, within two (2) business days, contact the issuing court to request acertified copy of the order. If the certified copy of the order is received bythe circuit clerk within the initial fourteen (14) day period, the clerk shallcause the information that certification has been received to be enteredinto the Law Information Network of Kentucky and shall notify theapplicant for the order of the fact of its certification. A facsimile copy of acertified foreign protective order shall be grounds for the issuance of anorder of protection.(d)If the clerk has not received a certified copy of the foreign protective orderwithin ten (10) days, the clerk shall notify the court and the applicant thatthe order has not been received. The notice to the applicant, on a formprepared by the Administrative Office of the Courts, shall state that theforeign protective order will be extended for another fourteen (14) days,but will be dismissed at the expiration of that time. If the clerk informs thejudge in writing that the certified foreign protective order has beenrequested but has not yet been received, the judge shall extend theforeign protective order for a period of fourteen (14) days. If certification ofthe foreign protective order is not received within twenty-eight (28) days,the foreign protective order shall expire and shall not be reissued. If theapplicant meets the qualifications for the issuance of a Kentucky domesticviolence order, the court may, upon proper application and showing ofevidence, issue a Kentucky order in accordance with this chapter.(4)The right of a person filing a foreign protective order to bring an action toenforce the order instead of proceeding under this chapter remains unimpaired.</text><history>Repealed and reenacted 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 12, effective January1, 2016. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 606, sec. 189, effective July 15, 1998. --Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:32</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44760</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>