<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="329" order_by="329">A PRIVATE INVESTIGATORS </unit></structure><section_number>329A.045</section_number><catch_line>Renewal -- Fee -- Grace period -- Termination and reinstatement -- Revocation -- Evidence of continuing education -- Inactive status. </catch_line><order_by>045</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A license or renewal issued under KRS 329A.010 to 329A.090 shall be valid for two (2) years from the date of issuance. No later than May 1 in the license renewal year, the board shall send a renewal application form to the address on file for each licensee. The renewal application shall indicate if the licensee is required to submit passport-sized photographs for a new identification card. </section><section prefix="2">All renewal applications shall be received by the board on or before June 30 in the year of renewal. </section><section prefix="3">Each company license renewal shall include a notarized statement sworn to by the representative prescribed in KRS 329A.035(2)(c) stating the identity and license number of each private investigator employed by or affiliated with the company. </section><section prefix="4">The fee for the timely renewal of a license shall be not less than fifty dollars ($50) and not more than two hundred fifty dollars ($250), as established by the board by promulgation of administrative regulations. </section><section prefix="5">For individual licensees, the board shall, at its discretion, issue either a new identification card or a renewal stamp or sticker to be affixed to the existing card. </section><section prefix="6">A grace period shall be allowed until September 1 of the license renewal year, during which time licensees may continue to practice and may renew their licenses upon payment of the renewal fee plus a late fee as promulgated by administrative regulation of the board. </section><section prefix="7">All licenses not renewed by September 1 of the renewal year shall terminate based on the failure to renew in a timely manner. Upon termination, the licensee is no longer eligible to practice in this state. </section><section prefix="8">After September 1 of the renewal year, former licensees with a terminated license may have their licenses reinstated upon payment of the renewal fee plus a reinstatement fee as promulgated by administrative regulation of the board. If the reinstatement application is made within five (5) years from the date of termination, applicants shall not be required to submit to any examination as a condition for reinstatement. </section><section prefix="9">A revoked license may not be renewed. If it is reinstated, the licensee shall pay the reinstatement fee as set forth in subsection (8) of this section and the renewal fee as set forth in subsection (4) of this section. </section><section prefix="10">A former licensee who fails to reinstate a license within five (5) years after termination may not have it renewed, restored, or reinstated. A person may apply for and obtain a new license by meeting the current requirements for licensure. </section><section prefix="11">The board may require that a person applying for a renewal or reinstatement of licensure show evidence of completion of continuing professional education as prescribed by the board in administrative regulations. </section><section prefix="12">A valid license may be put on inactive status by the licensee at the time of renewal, at a cost to be determined by the board. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 269, sec. 8, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31765</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>