<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="99" order_by="99">URBAN RENEWAL AND REDEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>99.530</section_number><catch_line>Urban renewal projects. </catch_line><order_by>530</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In addition to its authority under KRS 99.330 to 99.510, an agency is hereby authorized to plan and undertake urban renewal projects. As used in KRS 99.520 to 99.590, an urban renewal project may include undertakings and activities for the prevention of the development or spread of slums or blighted, deteriorated, or deteriorating areas, or the elimination thereof, and may involve any work or undertaking for such purpose constituting a redevelopment project or any rehabilitation or conservation work, or any combination of such undertaking or work. For this purpose, "rehabilitation or conservation work" may include: <section prefix="a">Carrying out plans for a program of voluntary or compulsory repair and rehabilitation of buildings or other improvements; </section><section prefix="b">Acquisition of real property and demolition, removal, relocation, historic preservation, or rehabilitation of buildings and improvements thereon where necessary to eliminate unhealthful, unsanitary, or unsafe conditions; lessen density; reduce traffic hazards; eliminate obsolete or other uses detrimental to the public welfare; remove or prevent the spread of blight or deterioration; or provide land or buildings, and improvements thereon, for needed public facilities; </section><section prefix="c">Installation, construction, or reconstruction of streets, utilities, parks, playgrounds, and other improvements necessary for carrying out the objectives of the urban renewal project; and </section><section prefix="d">The disposition, for uses in accordance with the objectives of the urban renewal project, of any property or part thereof acquired in the area of such project; provided that such disposition shall be in the manner prescribed in KRS 99.450 for the disposition of property in a redevelopment project area. </section></section><section prefix="2">Notwithstanding any other provisions of KRS 99.330 to 99.510 and KRS 99.520 to 99.590, where the local governing body certifies that an area is in need of redevelopment or rehabilitation as a result of a flood, fire, hurricane, earthquake, storm, or other catastrophe respecting which the Governor of the State has certified the need for disaster assistance under Public Law 875, Eighty-First Congress, or other federal law, the local governing body may approve an urban renewal plan and an urban renewal project with respect to such area without regard to any provisions of KRS 99.330 to 99.510 and KRS 99.520 to 99.590, requiring public hearings or requiring that the urban renewal plan conform to a general or master plan for the community as a whole, or that the urban renewal area be a slum area, or a blighted, deteriorated, or deteriorating area, or that the urban renewal area be predominantly residential in character or be developed or redeveloped for residential uses. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 307, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 159, sec. 8, effective June 19, 1958. -- Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 215, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:07</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26553</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>