<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="70" order_by="70">SHERIFFS, CONSTABLES, AND COUNTY POLICE FORCE </unit></structure><section_number>70.280</section_number><catch_line>Court security officers -- Duties -- Prohibited conduct. </catch_line><order_by>280</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A certified court security officer shall be charged with the following duties: <section prefix="a">Attending sessions of any court of the Court of Justice in the county in which he or she is sworn; </section><section prefix="b">Keeping order in the courts; </section><section prefix="c">Providing security services to the courts within the court facility or immediate area of the court facility; </section><section prefix="d">Guarding prisoners during court appearances; </section><section prefix="e">Serving warrants and other court papers on individuals physically present in the courtroom; </section><section prefix="f">Transporting prisoners; </section><section prefix="g">Arresting and taking individuals into custody who are in the court facility or immediate area of the court facility, or while transporting prisoners; and </section><section prefix="h">Service of process and other papers relating to civil matters on individuals physically present in the courtroom. </section></section><section prefix="2">A certified court security officer shall not: <section prefix="a">Go outside the immediate area of the court facility in which he or she is providing security services to make an arrest or take an individual into custody, except when transporting prisoners; </section><section prefix="b">Patrol the roads, streets, or highways; </section><section prefix="c">Issue traffic citations, except to enforce parking regulations around the court facility; or </section><section prefix="d">Perform general law enforcement duties outside that of providing court security. </section></section></text><history> Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 54, sec. 10, effective June 26, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24224</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>