<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.32-050</section_number><catch_line>Certificate of authority. </catch_line><order_by>32-050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Whenever any number of persons shall associate to form a corporation for any of the purposes in KRS 304.32-030, they shall submit proposed articles of incorporation in triplicate to the commissioner for examination. After being approved by the commissioner and the Attorney General, the articles shall be filed in the office of the Secretary of State, who shall issue a certificate of incorporation pursuant to the provisions of KRS Chapter 273. </section><section prefix="2">When not less than the amount required by KRS 304.32-140 is deposited with the commissioner, he or she shall cause an examination to be made either by the commissioner or some disinterested person, especially appointed by him or her for the purpose, who shall certify that the corporation has complied with the provisions of this subtitle. The certificate shall be filed in the office of the commissioner, who shall issue a certificate of authority to the corporation. </section><section prefix="3">Whenever any such corporation shall desire to amend its articles of incorporation, it shall file its articles of amendment with the commissioner before filing them with the Secretary of State. When the commissioner shall find the articles of amendment to have been legally adopted, the articles of amendment shall be filed with the Secretary of State. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1414, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 32, sec. 5, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:06</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29763</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>