<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">A HIGHER EDUCATION FINANCE </unit></structure><section_number>164A.020</section_number><catch_line>Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text>The following words and terms, unless the context clearly indicates a different meaning, shall have the following respective meanings: <section prefix="1">"Board" means the board of directors of the corporation. </section><section prefix="2">"Bonds" or "notes" means the bonds or bond anticipation notes authorized to be issued by the corporation pursuant to this chapter. </section><section prefix="3">"Corporation" means the Kentucky Higher Education Student Loan Corporation, an independent de jure municipal corporation and political subdivision of the Commonwealth of Kentucky created to perform essential governmental services. </section><section prefix="4">"Eligible institution" means any educational institution described as an eligible institution in the federal act which has, if required by the guarantee agency, a contract in force with the guarantee agency pursuant to the federal act and this chapter. </section><section prefix="5">"Eligible lender" means the Kentucky Higher Education Assistance Authority, a de jure political subdivision of the Commonwealth of Kentucky and the corporation and all other entities described as eligible lenders in the federal act which have in force a contract with the guarantee agency providing for loan guarantees to be issued by the guarantee agency to the subject lender under the federal act and this chapter. </section><section prefix="6">"Federal act" means the Higher Education Act of 1965, as from time to time amended, codified as 20 U.S.C. secs. 1001 et seq. </section><section prefix="7">"Guarantee agency" means the Kentucky Higher Education Assistance Authority duly organized and existing pursuant to the statutory laws of the Commonwealth of Kentucky or any agency authorized as a guarantor pursuant to the federal act. </section><section prefix="8">"Qualified student" means a student who qualifies for an insured student loan under the federal act. </section><section prefix="9">"Insured student loan" means a loan to a qualified student on which the payment of principal and interest is at least ninety-five percent (95%) insured by the guarantee agency and reinsured by the Secretary of Education of the United States in accordance with the requirements of the federal act, or at least ninety-five percent (95%) insured as to principal amount by the United States under the federal act or the Health Professions Educational Assistance Act of 1976, codified as 42 U.S.C. secs. 294 et seq. as from time to time amended. As used in connection with the purchase, making, or acquisition of insured student loans by the corporation, the term insured student loan shall further mean and refer to any contingent interest, security interest, pledge, commitment, chose in action, or other property interest in any such loan. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 35, sec. 1, effective March 8, 1994; and ch. 53, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 272, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 387, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4531</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>