<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="118" order_by="118">CONDUCT OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>118.255</section_number><catch_line>Fees.   </catch_line><order_by>255</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Secretary of State shall receive a fee of five hundred dollars ($500) for a candidate for statewide elected state office or the Congress, two hundred dollars ($200) for a candidate for Commonwealth's attorney, the General Assembly, or the District Court, Circuit Court, Court of Appeals, or Supreme Court, twenty dollars ($20) for candidates for a city office, fifty dollars ($50) for other candidates who file with the Secretary of State for each notification and declaration and petition filed with him, and fifty dollars ($50) for a write-in candidate for office, to be paid by the candidate, or the candidate's representative, when the notification and declaration and petition or declaration of intent is filed. </section><section prefix="2">The county clerk shall receive a fee pursuant to KRS 64.012 for each notification and declaration and petition filed with him to be paid by the candidate at the time of the filing. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 212, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 1, effective March 16, 2005. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 88, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 34, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 195, sec. 16, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 288, sec. 58, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 394, sec. 24, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 84, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 3. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 115, effective June 21, 1974. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43797</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>