<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="250" order_by="250">AGRICULTURAL SEEDS, FEEDING STUFFS, AND FERTILIZERS </unit></structure><section_number>250.391</section_number><catch_line>Analysis of fertilizers. </catch_line><order_by>391</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It shall be the duty of the director to sample, inspect, make analyses of, and test fertilizers distributed within this state at any time and place and to the extent he may deem necessary to determine whether the fertilizers are in compliance with the provisions of KRS 250.361 to 250.451. The director may enter upon any public or private premises or carriers during regular business hours in order to have access to fertilizer subject to the provisions of KRS 250.361 to 250.451 and the administrative regulations pertaining thereto, and to the records relating to their distribution. </section><section prefix="2">The methods of sampling and analysis shall be those adopted by the AOAC International, 2200 Wilson Boulevard, Suite 400, Arlington, VA 22201-3301. In cases not covered by such methods, or in cases where methods are available in which improved applicability has been demonstrated, the director may adopt appropriate methods from other sources. </section><section prefix="3">The director, in determining for administrative purposes whether any fertilizer is deficient in plant food, shall be guided by the official sample as defined in KRS 250.366(9), and obtained and analyzed as provided for in subsection (2) of this section. </section><section prefix="4">The results of official analysis of fertilizers and portions of official samples shall be distributed by the director as provided by administrative regulation and in KRS 250.416. Official samples establishing a penalty for nutrient deficiency shall be retained for a minimum of ninety (90) days from issuance of a deficiency report. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 331, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 7, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12132</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>