<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="13" order_by="13">A ADMINISTRATIVE REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>13A.250</section_number><catch_line>Consideration of costs to local and state government -- Fiscal note.  </catch_line><order_by>250</order_by><text>(1)Each administrative body that promulgates an administrative regulation shallconsider the cost that the administrative regulation may cause state or localgovernment to incur. The cost analysis shall include the projected cost or costsavings to the Commonwealth of Kentucky and each of its affected agencies,and the projected cost or cost savings to affected local governments, includingcities, counties, fire departments, and school districts. Agencies affected by theadministrative regulation may submit comments in accordance with KRS13A.270(1) to the promulgating administrative body or to a subcommitteereviewing the administrative regulation.(2)Each administrative body that promulgates an administrative regulation shallprepare and submit with the administrative regulation a fiscal note. The fiscalnote shall state:(a)The number of the administrative regulation;(b)The name and telephone number of the contact person of theadministrative body;(c)The unit, part, or division of state or local government the administrativeregulation will affect;(d)In detail, the aspect or service of state or local government to which theadministrative regulation relates, including identification of the applicablestate or federal statute or regulation that mandates the aspect or serviceor authorizes the action taken by the administrative regulation; and(e)The estimated effect of the administrative regulation on the expendituresand revenues of a state or local government agency for the first full yearthe administrative regulation will be in effect. If specific dollar estimatescannot be determined, the administrative body shall provide a briefnarrative to explain the fiscal impact of the administrative regulation.(3)Any administrative body may request the advice and assistance of theCommission in the preparation of the fiscal note.</text><history>Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 138, sec. 9, effective July 12, 2012. --Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 166, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006; and ch. 197,sec 1, effective July 12 2006. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 12,effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 410, sec. 18, effectiveJuly 15, 1994. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 417, sec. 25, effective April 13,1984.</history><metadata><effective>July 12, 2012</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40715</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>