<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="61" order_by="61">GENERAL PROVISIONS AS TO OFFICES AND OFFICERS -- SOCIAL SECURITY FOR PUBLIC EMPLOYEES -- EMPLOYEES RETIREMENT SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>61.706</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Retirement Systems unfunded liability trust fund.   </catch_line><order_by>706</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Retirement Systems unfunded liability trust fund is created and shall be administered by the Finance and Administration Cabinet. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">The trust fund shall consist of: <section prefix="1">Contributions, gifts, and donations; </section><section prefix="2">Any moneys designated by the General Assembly for deposit into the fund; and </section><section prefix="3">Any other proceeds from grants, appropriations, or other moneys made available for the purposes of the trust fund. </section></section><section prefix="b">Any donor may designate to which system within the Kentucky Retirement Systems the donation shall benefit, including: <section prefix="1">The Kentucky Employees Retirement System nonhazardous fund; </section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Employees Retirement System hazardous fund; </section><section prefix="3">The County Employees Retirement System nonhazardous fund; </section><section prefix="4">The County Employees Retirement System hazardous fund; or </section><section prefix="5">The State Police Retirement System. </section></section><section prefix="c">Checks submitted for donations shall be made payable to the Kentucky State Treasurer. </section></section><section prefix="3">Moneys in the trust fund: <section prefix="a">Shall be disbursed quarterly to the Kentucky Retirement Systems; </section><section prefix="b">Shall be used to eliminate any unfunded liability and supplement the investible assets of the Kentucky Retirement Systems; and </section><section prefix="c">Are hereby appropriated for the purposes set forth in paragraph (b) of this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="4">Notwithstanding KRS 45.229, any moneys remaining in the fund at the close of the fiscal year shall not lapse but shall be carried forward into the succeeding fiscal year to be used for the purposes provided by subsection (3) of this section. </section><section prefix="5">Interest earned on any moneys in the trust fund shall accrue to the trust fund. </section><section prefix="6"><section prefix="a">The Finance and Administration Cabinet shall separately account for each contribution, gift, or donation made to the trust fund and shall publish on its Web site a listing of each contribution, gift, or donation made and a cumulative total of the value of all contributions, gifts, or donations, including the cumulative total, since the creation of the fund, for each donor or association of donors or entities, other than those wishing to remain anonymous. </section><section prefix="b">Information listed on the Web site related to each contribution may include all information set out in this paragraph, as reported by the donor: <section prefix="1">The name of donor; </section><section prefix="2">The location of the donor by county, if the donor is located in Kentucky, or by state, if the donor is located outside Kentucky; and </section><section prefix="3">The title or position of the donor, or the association of the donor with any other entity. </section></section><section prefix="c">Anonymous donations shall be accepted without requiring any of the information provided in paragraph (b) of this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="7">The Finance and Administration Cabinet may work in conjunction with management consultants and others willing to give of their time and talents to create a strategic plan to encourage individuals, foundations, associations, corporations, and other entities to make donations to the fund. </section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 22, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42432</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>