<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.2-020</section_number><catch_line>Commissioner of insurance -- Appointment, term -- Divisions within department. </catch_line><order_by>2-020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commissioner is the head of the Department of Insurance. </section><section prefix="2">The commissioner shall be appointed by the Governor with the consent of the Senate, for a term not to exceed four (4) years on the basis of his or her merit and fitness to perform the duties of the office as provided in KRS 12.040. If the Senate is not in session when a term expires or a vacancy occurs, the Governor shall make the appointment to take effect at once, subject to the approval of the Senate when convened. Nothing contained in this subsection shall prohibit the commissioner of the Department of Insurance from being reappointed. </section><section prefix="3">The following divisions are established within the Department of Insurance and shall be headed by directors appointed by the secretary of the Public Protection Cabinet with the approval of the Governor in accordance with KRS 12.050: <section prefix="a">Property and Casualty Division; </section><section prefix="b">Health and Life Division; </section><section prefix="c">Division of Financial Standards and Examination; </section><section prefix="d">Division of Agent Licensing; </section><section prefix="e">Division of Insurance Fraud Investigation; </section><section prefix="f">Consumer Protection Division; and </section><section prefix="g">Division of Kentucky Access. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 914, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 30, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 496, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 2, sec. 2, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=16646</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>