<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="147" order_by="147">A PROGRAM DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>147A.002</section_number><catch_line>Department for Local Government -- Organization -- Commissioner. </catch_line><order_by>002</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department for Local Government shall be headed by a commissioner and shall consist of the: <section prefix="a">Office of Financial Management and Administration, which shall be headed by an executive director appointed by the commissioner and shall be responsible for duties including but not limited to local government financial assistance; county budget approval; performance of various recordkeeping requirements for the Commonwealth's cities, counties, and special districts; provision of administrative support for the state local debt officer and the state local finance officer; administration of the county officials training incentive program set forth in KRS 64.5275; and provision of financial analysis and guidance related to the internal budgetary processes of the Department for Local Government; </section><section prefix="b">Office of Federal Grants, which shall be headed by an executive director appointed by the commissioner and shall be responsible for the administration of all federal grant programs; </section><section prefix="c">Office of State Grants, which shall be headed by an executive director appointed by the commissioner and shall be responsible for the administration of all state grant programs, including the Renaissance on Main Program, the area development fund, the body armor program set forth in KRS 16.220, the cemetery fund program, single county coal severance grants, and any state grant programs or individually funded projects awarded by statute or budget; </section><section prefix="d">Office of Legal Services, which shall be headed by an executive director appointed by the commissioner and shall be responsible for legal services within the Department for Local Government and for its constituencies around the Commonwealth; and </section><section prefix="e">Office of Field Services, which shall be headed by an executive director appointed by the commissioner and shall be responsible for duties including but not limited to staffing regional offices to assist local governments. </section></section><section prefix="2">The commissioner, with the approval of the Governor, shall appoint necessary deputies, assistants, attorneys, and other employees and shall fix their compensation and authorize payment of their expenses according to law. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 69, sec. 48, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 70, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984; and ch. 404, sec. 38, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 70, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1634</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>