<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="176" order_by="176">DEPARTMENT OF HIGHWAYS </unit></structure><section_number>176.431</section_number><catch_line>Transportation Cabinet's authorization for maximum of five demonstration road and bridge related projects in each fiscal year -- Bidding process and basis of selection for projects -- Annual report to Interim Joint Committee on Appropriations and Revenue.   </catch_line><order_by>431</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding any conflicting provisions of this chapter and KRS Chapters 45A and 177, the Transportation Cabinet is authorized to utilize design/build procurement methods for up to five (5) demonstration road and bridge related projects in each fiscal year. The projects shall be identified in the biennial highway construction plan and shall be limited to those with a construction phase not greater than thirty million dollars ($30,000,000). </section><section prefix="2">For procurement purposes, the Transportation Cabinet shall utilize a qualifications-based bidding process within the context of the provisions of this chapter. The projects shall be selected based on engineering factors that determine a design/build process will provide the best value for the Commonwealth. Factors to consider may include but not be limited to the following: project delivery schedule, technical complexity, constructability, and estimated project cost. </section><section prefix="3">The secretary of the Transportation Cabinet shall determine the nature and scope of each design/build project, and shall submit a report identifying and detailing the demonstration road and bridge related projects, including the estimated cost savings, to the Interim Joint Committee on Appropriations and Revenue by December 1 of each fiscal year. </section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 67, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><lrc-note> (6/25/2013). Under the authority of KRS 7.136(1), the Reviser of Statutes has inserted subsection designations into this statute. The words in the text were not changed. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42258</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>