<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>355.7-102</section_number><catch_line>Definitions and index of definitions.   </catch_line><order_by>7-102</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In this article, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="a">"Bailee" means a person that by a warehouse receipt, bill of lading, or other document of title acknowledges possession of goods and contracts to deliver them; </section><section prefix="b">"Carrier" means a person that issues a bill of lading; </section><section prefix="c">"Consignee" means a person named in a bill of lading to which or to whose order the bill promises delivery; </section><section prefix="d">"Consignor" means a person named in a bill of lading as the person from which the goods have been received for shipment; </section><section prefix="e">"Delivery order" means a record that contains an order to deliver goods directed to a warehouse, carrier, or other person that in the ordinary course of business issues warehouse receipts or bills of lading; </section><section prefix="f">Reserved; </section><section prefix="g">"Goods" means all things that are treated as movable for the purposes of a contract for storage or transportation; </section><section prefix="h">"Issuer" means a bailee that issues a document of title or, in the case of an unaccepted delivery order, the person that orders the possessor of goods to deliver. The term includes a person for which an agent or employee purports to act in issuing a document if the agent or employee has real or apparent authority to issue documents, even if the issuer did not receive any goods, the goods were misdescribed, or in any other respect the agent or employee violated the issuer’s instructions; </section><section prefix="i">"Person entitled under the document" means the holder, in the case of a negotiable document of title, or the person to which delivery of the goods is to be made by the terms of, or pursuant to instructions in a record under, a nonnegotiable document of title; </section><section prefix="j">Reserved; </section><section prefix="k">"Sign" means, with present intent to authenticate or adopt a record: <section prefix="1">To execute or adopt a tangible symbol; or </section><section prefix="2">To attach to or logically associate with the record an electronic sound, symbol, or process; </section></section><section prefix="l">"Shipper" means a person that enters into a contract of transportation with a carrier; and </section><section prefix="m">"Warehouse" means a person engaged in the business of storing goods for hire. </section></section><section prefix="2">Definitions in other articles applying to this article and the sections in which they appear are: <section prefix="a">"Contract for sale," KRS 355.2-106; </section><section prefix="b">"Lessee in ordinary course," KRS 355.2A-103; and </section><section prefix="c">"‘Receipt’ of goods," KRS 355.2-103. </section></section><section prefix="3">In addition, Article 1 of KRS Chapter 355 contains general definitions and principles of construction and interpretation applicable throughout this article. </section></text><history>Repealed and reenacted 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 7-102, effective July 1, 1960.  </history><metadata><effective>July 12, 2012</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40603</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>