<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="337" order_by="337">WAGES AND HOURS </unit></structure><section_number>337.100</section_number><catch_line>Volunteer firefighter, rescue squad member, emergency medical technician, peace officer, or emergency management agency member absent from employment due to emergency or injury incurred in the line of duty. </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No employer shall terminate an employee who is a volunteer firefighter, rescue squad member, emergency medical technician, peace officer, or a member of an emergency management agency because that employee, when acting as a volunteer firefighter, rescue squad member, emergency medical technician, peace officer, or a member of an emergency management agency, is absent or late to the employee's employment in order to respond to an emergency prior to the time the employee is to report to his or her place of employment. </section><section prefix="2">An employer may charge any time that an employee who is a volunteer firefighter, rescue squad member, emergency medical technician, peace officer, or a member of an emergency management agency loses from employment because of the employee's response to an emergency against the employee's regular pay. </section><section prefix="3">An employer may request an employee who loses time from the employee's employment to respond to an emergency to provide the employer with a written statement from the supervisor or acting supervisor of the volunteer fire department, rescue squad, emergency medical services agency, law enforcement agency, or the director of the emergency management agency stating that the employee responded to an emergency and listing the time and date of the emergency. </section><section prefix="4">No employer shall terminate an employee who is a volunteer firefighter, rescue squad member, emergency medical technician, peace officer, or member of an emergency management agency who is absent for a period of no more than twelve (12) months from the employee's employment because of injuries incurred in the line of duty. The volunteer firefighter, rescue squad member, emergency medical technician, peace officer, or member of an emergency management agency shall provide, at the request of his or her employer: <section prefix="a">A written statement from the supervisor, acting supervisor, or director of the volunteer fire department, rescue squad, emergency medical services agency, law enforcement agency, or emergency management agency under whose command the employee was on active duty and on assignment with that fire department, rescue squad, emergency medical services agency, law enforcement agency, or emergency management agency when the injury occurred; and </section><section prefix="b">A written statement from at least one (1) licensed and practicing physician stating that the volunteer firefighter, rescue squad member, emergency medical technician, peace officer, or member of an emergency management agency is injured and a date for the employee's return to work. </section></section><section prefix="5">Any employee that is terminated in violation of the provisions of this section may bring a civil action against his or her employer. The employee may seek reinstatement to the employee's former position, payment of back wages, reinstatement of fringe benefits, and where seniority rights are granted, the reinstatement of seniority rights. In order to recover, the employee shall file this action within one (1) year of the date of the violation of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 30, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 17, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32055</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>