<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.90-010</section_number><catch_line>Northern Kentucky Convention Center Corporation -- Board. </catch_line><order_by>90-010</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Northern Kentucky Convention Center Corporation is hereby established to develop and manage the Northern Kentucky Convention Center. The corporation shall be attached to the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet for administrative purposes. The corporation shall be directed by a board consisting of seven (7) members appointed as follows: <section prefix="a">The county judge/executives of Kenton, Campbell and Boone Counties, with the approval of their respective fiscal courts, shall each appoint one (1) member to the board. An appointee under this subsection shall have demonstrated successful business experience in a field related to the convention business; </section><section prefix="b">The mayor of the city within which the convention center is located shall appoint one (1) member, with the approval of the city commission; and </section><section prefix="c">The Governor shall appoint three (3) members. </section><section prefix="d">One (1) of the initial appointees of the Governor shall have a one (1) year term, one (1) shall have a two (2) year term, and one (1) shall have a three (3) year term. All other appointments, and all subsequent appointments by the Governor, shall be for four (4) year terms. </section><section prefix="e">Members may be removed by the appointing authority only for cause and after being afforded notice, a hearing, and a finding of fact by the appointing authority. A copy of charges, transcript of the record of the hearings, and findings of fact shall be filed with the Secretary of State. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Northern Kentucky Convention Center Corporation shall be a body corporate with full corporate powers. A quorum of the corporation shall consist of four (4) members, with a majority of members present authorized to act upon any matter legally before the corporation. Minutes and records shall be kept of all meetings of the corporation and all official actions shall be recorded. </section><section prefix="3">The corporation may enact bylaws concerning the election of officers and other administrative procedures it deems necessary. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 42, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 7, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3003</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>