<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>272A.16-070</section_number><catch_line>Articles of merger -- Effective date.   </catch_line><order_by>16-070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">After each constituent entity has approved a merger, articles of merger shall be signed on behalf of each constituent entity by an authorized representative. </section><section prefix="2">The articles of merger shall include: <section prefix="a">The name and form of each constituent entity and the jurisdiction of its governing statute; </section><section prefix="b">The name and form of the surviving entity, the jurisdiction of its governing statute, and, if the surviving entity is created by the merger, a statement to that effect; </section><section prefix="c">The date the merger is effective under the governing statute of the surviving entity; </section><section prefix="d">If the surviving entity is to be created by the merger, the limited cooperative association’s articles of association; </section><section prefix="e">If the surviving entity is not created by the merger, any amendments provided for in the plan of merger to its articles of association; </section><section prefix="f">A statement as to each constituent entity that the merger was approved as required by the entity’s governing statute; and </section><section prefix="g">Any additional information required by the governing statute of any constituent entity. </section></section><section prefix="3">The limited cooperative association that is the surviving entity to a merger shall deliver the articles of merger to the Secretary of State for filing. </section><section prefix="4">A merger becomes effective upon the articles of merger being effective as provided in KRS 14A.2-070. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 160, sec. 116, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41092</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>