<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="44" order_by="44">CLAIMS UPON THE TREASURY </unit></structure><section_number>44.073</section_number><catch_line>State institutions of higher education declared agencies of state government -- Jurisdiction of Board of Claims -- Sovereign immunity. </catch_line><order_by>073</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For purposes of KRS 44.072, state institutions of higher education under KRS Chapter 164 are agencies of the state. </section><section prefix="2">The Board of Claims shall have primary and exclusive jurisdiction over all negligence claims for the negligent performance of ministerial acts against the Commonwealth, any of its cabinets, departments, bureaus, or agencies, or any officers, agents, or employees thereof while acting within the scope of their employment by the Commonwealth or any of its cabinets, departments, bureaus, or agencies. </section><section prefix="3">The Board of Claims shall have primary and exclusive jurisdiction to make findings of fact, conclusions of law, and legal determinations with regard to whether the alleged negligent act was on the part of the Commonwealth or any of its cabinets, departments, bureaus, or agencies or any officers, agents, or employees thereof. </section><section prefix="4">The Board of Claims shall have primary and exclusive jurisdiction to make findings of fact, conclusions of law, and legal determinations with regard to whether the alleged negligent act was on the part of the Commonwealth or any of its cabinets, departments, bureaus, or agencies, or any of its officers, agents, or employees while acting within the scope of their employment by the Commonwealth or any of its cabinets, departments, bureaus, or agencies. </section><section prefix="5">No action for negligence against the Commonwealth, any of its cabinets, departments, bureaus, or agencies, or any officers, agents, or employees thereof may be brought initially in any other court or forum in the Commonwealth except the Board of Claims until the Board of Claims makes a determination, that has become final, that the Board of Claims has or does not have primary and exclusive jurisdiction over the claim. </section><section prefix="6">The determination by the Board of Claims becomes final only after all appellate rights have been finalized or waived. </section><section prefix="7">Any applicable statute of limitations for bringing negligence actions in any court or forum other than the Board of Claims shall be tolled pending the final determination that the Board of Claims does not have primary and exclusive jurisdiction of the negligence claim. </section><section prefix="8">No action for negligence may be brought in any court or forum other than the Board of Claims against the Commonwealth, any of its cabinets, departments, bureaus, or agencies or any of its officers, agents, or employees while acting within the scope of their employment by the Commonwealth or any of its cabinets, departments, bureaus, or agencies. </section><section prefix="9">Negligence as used herein includes negligence, gross negligence, or wanton negligence. </section><section prefix="10">The defense of contributory negligence is not a complete bar to recovery of plaintiff's claim in the Board of Claims, and the doctrine of comparative negligence shall be utilized by the board. </section><section prefix="11">Except as otherwise provided by this chapter, nothing contained herein shall be construed to be a waiver of sovereign immunity or any other immunity or privilege maintained by the Commonwealth, its cabinets, departments, bureaus, and agencies and its officers, agents, and employees. </section><section prefix="12">Except as otherwise specifically set forth by statute and in reference to subsection (11) of this section, no action for damages may be maintained in any court or forum against the Commonwealth, any of its cabinets, departments, bureaus, or agencies or any of its officers, agents, or employees while acting within their official capacity and scope of their employment by the Commonwealth or any of its cabinets, departments, bureaus, or agencies. </section><section prefix="13">The preservation of sovereign immunity referred to in subsections (11) and (12) of this section includes, but is not limited to, the following: <section prefix="a">Discretionary acts or decisions; </section><section prefix="b">Executive decisions; </section><section prefix="c">Ministerial acts; </section><section prefix="d">Actions in the performance of obligations running to the public as a whole; </section><section prefix="e">Governmental performance of a self-imposed protective function to the public or citizens; and </section><section prefix="f">Administrative acts. </section></section><section prefix="14">The filing of an action in court or any other forum or the purchase of liability insurance or the establishment of a fund for self-insurance by the Commonwealth, its cabinets, departments, bureaus, or agencies or its agents, officers, or employees thereof for a government-related purpose or duty shall not be construed as a waiver of sovereign immunity or any other immunity or privilege thereby held. Except as specifically set forth by statute, no counterclaim, set-off, recoupment, cross-claim, or other form of avoidance of the claim for damages may be asserted by any person when suit is brought against said person by the Commonwealth or any of its cabinets, departments, bureaus, or agencies thereof. </section><section prefix="15">Neither the Commonwealth nor any of its cabinets, departments, bureaus, or agencies or any officers, agents, or employees thereof shall be liable under a respondeat superior theory or any other similar theory for the acts of independent contractors, contractors, or subcontractors thereof or anyone else doing work or providing services for the state on a volunteer basis or pursuant to a contract therewith. </section></text><history>Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 499, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1986 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22137</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>