<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="161" order_by="161">SCHOOL EMPLOYEES -- TEACHERS' RETIREMENT AND TENURE </unit></structure><section_number>161.760</section_number><catch_line>Notice of salary to be paid to teacher -- Increases -- Reductions in responsibility. </catch_line><order_by>760</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The superintendent of schools shall give notice not later than forty-five (45) days before the first student attendance day of the succeeding school year or June 15, whichever occurs earlier, to each teacher who holds a contract valid for the succeeding school year, stating the best estimate as to the salary to be paid the teacher during the year. The salary shall not be lower than the salary paid during the preceding school year, unless the reduction is a part of a uniform plan affecting all teachers in the entire district, or unless there is a reduction of responsibilities. Nothing herein shall prevent increases of salary after the superintendent's annual notice has been given. All teachers who refuse assignment shall notify the superintendent in writing not later than thirty (30) days before the first student attendance day of the school year. </section><section prefix="2">Transfer or change in appointment of teachers later than thirty (30) days before the first student attendance day of the school year shall be made only to fill vacancies created by illness, death, or resignations; to reduce or increase personnel because of a shift in school population; to make personnel adjustments after consolidation or merger; or to assign personnel according to their certification pursuant to KRS 161.010 to 161.120 provided, in the latter instance, that the teacher was appointed to a position outside his or her field of certification in the previous year. </section><section prefix="3">Reduction of responsibility for a teacher may be accompanied by a corresponding reduction in salary provided that written notification stating the specific reason for the reduction shall be furnished to the teacher not later than ninety (90) days before the first student attendance day of the school year or May 15, whichever occurs earlier. </section><section prefix="4">Employment of a teacher, under either a limited or a continuing contract, is employment in the school district only and not in a particular position or school. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 5, effective April 14, 2008. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. II, sec. 84, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 338, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982; and ch. 362, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 169, sec. 2. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 41, sec. 5. -- Amended 1944 Ky. Acts ch. 98, sec. 1. -- Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective> April 14, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3996</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>