<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.162</section_number><catch_line>Mandatory adoption of emergency management response plan in each public school.   </catch_line><order_by>162</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Emergency management response plan" or "emergency plan" means a written document to prevent, mitigate, prepare for, respond to, and recover from emergencies; and </section><section prefix="b">"First responders" means local fire, police, and emergency medical personnel. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Each local board of education shall require the school council or, if none exists, the principal in each public school building in its jurisdiction to adopt an emergency plan to include procedures to be followed in case of fire, severe weather, or earthquake, or if a building lockdown as defined in KRS 158.164 is required. </section><section prefix="b">Following adoption, the emergency plan, along with a diagram of the facility, shall be provided to appropriate first responders. </section><section prefix="c">The emergency plan shall be reviewed following the end of each school year by the school council, the principal, and first responders and shall be revised as needed. </section><section prefix="d">The principal shall discuss the emergency plan with all school staff prior to the first instructional day of each school year and shall document the time and date of any discussion. </section><section prefix="e">The emergency plan and diagram of the facility shall be excluded from the application of KRS 61.870 to 61.884. </section></section><section prefix="3">Each local board of education shall require the school council or, if none exists, the principal in each public school building to: <section prefix="a">Establish primary and secondary evacuation routes for all rooms located within the school and shall post the routes in each room by any doorway used for evacuation; </section><section prefix="b">Identify the best available severe weather safe zones, in consultation with local and state safety officials and informed by guiding principles set forth by the National Weather Service and the Federal Emergency Management Agency, and post the location of safe zones in each room of the school; </section><section prefix="c">Develop practices for students to follow during an earthquake; and </section><section prefix="d">Develop and adhere to practices to control the access to each school building. Practices may include but not be limited to: <section prefix="1">Controlling outside access to exterior doors during the school day; </section><section prefix="2">Controlling the front entrance of the school electronically or with a greeter; </section><section prefix="3">Controlling access to individual classrooms. If a classroom is equipped with hardware that allows the door to be locked from the outside but opened from the inside, the door should remain locked during instructional time; </section><section prefix="4">Requiring all visitors to report to the front office of the building, provide valid identification, and state the purpose of the visit; and </section><section prefix="5">Providing a visitor's badge to be visibly displayed on a visitor's outer garment. </section></section></section><section prefix="4">Each local board of education shall require the principal in each public school building in its jurisdiction to conduct, at a minimum, emergency response drills to include one (1) severe weather drill, one (1) earthquake drill, and one (1) lockdown drill within the first thirty (30) instructional days of each school year and again during the month of January. Required fire drills shall be conducted according to administrative regulations promulgated by the Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction. Whenever possible, first responders shall be invited to observe emergency response drills. </section><section prefix="5">No later than November 1 of each school year, a local district superintendent shall send verification to the Kentucky Department of Education that all schools within the district are in compliance with the requirements of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 38, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2015. -- Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2013; and ch. 133, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (6/25/2013). This statute was created by 2013 Ky. Acts chs. 126 and 133, which were companion bills and are substantively identical. Where these Acts are not in conflict, they have been codified together. Where a conflict exists, Acts ch. 126 prevails under KRS 446.250 as the Act which passed the General Assembly last. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44393</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>