<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.43-330</section_number><catch_line>Records and reporting requirements. </catch_line><order_by>43-330</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It shall be the responsibility of the owner or operator of each municipal solid waste disposal facility to keep an accurate written record of all amounts of solid waste measured in tons received at the facility. Measurement in tons of solid waste received shall be accomplished by the provision of stationary or portable scales at the disposal facility for weighing incoming waste. </section><section prefix="2">The owner or operator of each municipal solid waste disposal facility shall report quarterly to the cabinet, the county in which the facility is located, and the waste management district in which the facility is located the amount of household, commercial, and industrial solid waste measured in tons received at the facility and the geographical source of the waste. </section><section prefix="3">Persons operating solid waste management facilities or engaged in the collection or transportation of solid waste shall provide upon request of the cabinet information on fees charged for the collection, transportation, or disposal of solid waste. Information on fees collected by the cabinet shall be included in the annual report to the Governor and the General Assembly required by KRS 224.43-310(4). </section></text><history> Created 1991 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 3, effective February 26, 1991. </history><metadata><effective> February 26, 1991 </effective><former-codification> KRS 224.833. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10417</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>