<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.18-140</section_number><catch_line>Treatment of alcoholism -- Required provisions -- Minimum benefits.   </catch_line><order_by>18-140</order_by><text>Group contracts providing major medical or outpatient care benefits issued pursuant to KRS 304.18-130 for treatment of alcoholism shall require: <section prefix="1">That the patient be under the supervision of a physician licensed to practice in the Commonwealth or a professional designated by such physician, and who is a recognized staff member of a treatment facility licensed by the department or accredited by the Joint Commission; </section><section prefix="2">That the patient receive appropriate emergency detoxification treatment, residential treatment and outpatient treatment at facilities licensed by the department or accredited by the Joint Commission, for alcoholism treatment; and </section><section prefix="3">That the following minimum benefits per patient be provided: <section prefix="a">Emergency detoxification - 3 days, $40 per day </section><section prefix="b">Residential treatment - 10 days, $50 per day </section><section prefix="c">Outpatient treatment - 10 visits, $10 per visit. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 9, sec. 9, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1300, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 290, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 131, sec. 2, effective January 1, 1979. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44051</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>