<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="322" order_by="322">A PROFESSIONAL GEOLOGISTS </unit></structure><section_number>322A.040</section_number><catch_line>Requirements for registration.   </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In order to qualify for registration, an applicant shall meet all of the following requirements: <section prefix="a">Successful completion of a minimum of thirty (30) semester hours or forty-five (45) quarter hours of course work in geology, culminating in a baccalaureate or advanced degree in geology, geophysics, geochemistry, or geological/geotechnical engineering from an accredited college or university. At the discretion of the board, courses dealing with applied geological science that are given under the auspices of an academic department other than geology may be considered toward the fulfillment of this requirement. </section><section prefix="b">Five (5) years of experience in professional geologic work. Professional geologic work may include the instruction of geology at the college or university level, the geological research of persons at the college or university level, and geological work performed while in the employment of the United States, state, or local governments. In counting years of experience, the board may give one (1) year of credit each for a master's degree or doctoral degree in geology, geophysics, geochemistry, or geological/geotechnical engineering. </section><section prefix="c">A passing score on an examination required by the board that has been designed to demonstrate that the applicant has the necessary knowledge and skill to exercise the responsibilities of the public practice of geology. </section><section prefix="d">Enrollment by the board as a geologist-in-training. </section></section><section prefix="2">Until July 31, 2015, any individual who serves in a geologic position or performs geologic work for a local or state government in this state may become a registered geologist under this chapter if the individual submits the proper application to the board and meets the requirements of subsection (1)(a), (b), and (c) of this section. </section><section prefix="3">Credit toward the experience and education requirements shall be subject to evaluation and approval by the board. </section><section prefix="4">Documentation of competency and integrity may be required by the board. </section><section prefix="5">Upon application, registration may be provided to those registered or certified as geologists in another state having standards at least equal to those provided in this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 140, sec. 4, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 159, sec. 2, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 64, sec. 4, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40731</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>