<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="216" order_by="216">HEALTH FACILITIES AND SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>216.803</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Health and Geriatric Authority. </catch_line><order_by>803</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Health and Geriatric Authority shall be composed of five (5) members who shall be the Governor, secretary for health and family services or his designee, commissioner of public health, Attorney General, and the commissioner of revenue. These five (5) persons and their successors in office are a body corporate and politic constituting a public corporation and governmental agency and instrumentality of the Commonwealth by the name of the "Kentucky Health and Geriatric Authority," with perpetual succession and with power in that name to contract and be contracted with, to convey property, to sue and be sued, to have and use a corporate seal, and to exercise, in addition to the powers and functions conferred by KRS 216.800 to 216.853, all of the usual powers of corporations not inconsistent with specifically enumerated powers. </section><section prefix="2">The members of the authority shall receive no compensation for their services, but are entitled to reimbursement for all reasonable expenses necessarily incurred in connection with performance of their duties and functions as members. </section><section prefix="3">Three (3) members of the authority shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business. The Governor shall be the chairman of the authority and the secretary for health and family services or his designee shall be the vice chairman. The authority shall elect a secretary and a treasurer who shall serve at the pleasure of the authority and receive such compensation as may be determined by the authority. The treasurer shall give bond to the authority for a faithful accounting for all funds coming into his custody, in such amount as the authority may prescribe, drawn upon a surety company qualified to do business in the Commonwealth, premium therefor to be paid by the authority. The authority shall establish and maintain an office and the secretary of the authority shall maintain therein complete records of the authority's actions and proceedings, as public records open to inspection. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 492, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 438, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 210, sec. 5. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 257, sec. 6. -- Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 2, effective June 13, 1968. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><lrc-note>(7/15/98).  References in this statute to the former commissioner of health services have been changed to the commissioner of public health under 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 629, and KRS 7.136(2).  (6/20/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 95, 97, 98, 99, 123, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9117</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>