<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="152" order_by="152">ENERGY DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>152.212</section_number><catch_line>Appointment of Kentucky board members -- Terms  (NOT YET EFFECTIVE; SEE NOTE FOLLOWING TEXT). </catch_line><order_by>212</order_by><text>The Governor shall appoint three (3) persons to represent Kentucky on the Southern States Energy Board. One (1) member shall be chosen from a list of three (3) state representatives submitted by the Speaker of the House of Representatives; one (1) shall be chosen from a list of three (3) state senators submitted by the President of the Senate, and one (1) shall be appointed by the Governor to represent his office on the board. The member appointed to represent the Governor shall serve at his pleasure. The members appointed from the General Assembly shall serve a term of two (2) years and until a successor has been appointed in the manner prescribed above, except that if a member loses his seat in the General Assembly the Governor shall, in consultation with the Speaker of the House of Representatives or the President of the Senate, respectively, appoint a successor for the remainder of his term. </text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 486, sec. 23, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 3, effective upon contingency. </history><metadata><effective> Upon contingency. </effective><note>This version of KRS 152.212 "shall become effective at such time as all party states to the Southern Interstate Nuclear Compact approve changes in the compact which are substantially the same as those of this Act, and the Congress of the United States consents to the compact, substantially as amended in this Act." 1982 Ky. Acts, ch. 76, sec. 4. </note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2279</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>