<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>362.1-903</section_number><catch_line>Conversion of limited partnership to partnership.   </catch_line><order_by>1-903</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A limited partnership may be converted to a partnership pursuant to this subsection. <section prefix="a">Notwithstanding a provision to the contrary in a limited partnership agreement, the terms and conditions of a conversion of a limited partnership to a partnership shall be approved by all of the partners. </section><section prefix="b">After the conversion is approved by the partners, the limited partnership shall cancel its certificate of limited partnership and any certificate of assumed name filed with the Secretary of State. </section><section prefix="c">The conversion takes effect when the certificate of limited partnership is canceled. </section><section prefix="d">A limited partner who becomes a general partner as a result of the conversion remains liable only as a limited partner for an obligation incurred by the limited partnership before the conversion takes effect. Except as otherwise provided in KRS 362.1-306, the partner is liable as a general partner for an obligation of the partnership incurred after the conversion takes effect. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">A limited liability company may be converted to a limited liability partnership pursuant to this subsection. </section><section prefix="b">Notwithstanding a provision to the contrary in the operating agreement, the terms and conditions of a conversion of a limited liability company to a limited liability partnership shall be approved by all of the members. </section><section prefix="c">After the conversion is approved by the members, the limited liability company shall file with the Secretary of State a statement of qualification satisfying the requirements of KRS 362.1-931(3) and including as well the name of the predecessor limited liability company and a statement that the predecessor limited liability company was converted to a limited liability partnership. </section><section prefix="d">The conversion takes effect upon the effective time and date of the statement of qualification as provided for in KRS 14A.2-070. </section><section prefix="e">A member who becomes a general partner as a result of a conversion remains liable only as a member for an obligation incurred by the limited liability company before the conversion takes effect. Except as otherwise provided in KRS 362.1-306, a partner is liable as a general partner for an obligation of the partnership incurred after the conversion takes effect. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 118, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 63, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40457</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>