<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="95" order_by="95">A FIRE PROTECTION PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>95A.430</section_number><catch_line>Duties of commission. </catch_line><order_by>430</order_by><text>The commission shall: <section prefix="1">Create the necessary application forms, any necessary supporting documents, compliance documents, or reporting documents for the thermal vision grant program as may be necessary by promulgating administrative regulations under KRS Chapter 13A; </section><section prefix="2">Make a determination of the characteristics of the most cost-effective thermal vision systems for use by fire departments participating in the thermal vision grant program; </section><section prefix="3">Make a determination of the manufacturer or manufacturers of thermal vision devices to be purchased by the thermal vision grant program; </section><section prefix="4">Make a determination of the most cost-effective purchase mechanism and price, under KRS Chapter 45A, for thermal vision systems; </section><section prefix="5">Accept and process applications for the purchase of thermal vision systems through the thermal vision grant program; </section><section prefix="6">Award eligible fire departments grants equal to fifty percent (50%), but not to exceed the sum of five thousand dollars ($5,000), of the agreed price for the purchase of thermal vision systems; </section><section prefix="7">Require recipients of thermal vision devices purchased through the thermal vision grant program to file any reports deemed necessary by the commission concerning usage, maintenance, or property accounting or loss with the commission; and </section><section prefix="8">Maintain these reports for evaluation by the commission. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 292, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:08</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26155</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>