<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="317" order_by="317">A COSMETOLOGISTS </unit></structure><section_number>317A.155</section_number><catch_line>Cosmetologists and nail technicians must practice in licensed establishments -- Services to hospice patients and to deceased persons in the care of funeral establishments.     </catch_line><order_by>155</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, "funeral establishment" means funeral establishment as defined in KRS 316.010. </section><section prefix="2">Every person practicing as a cosmetologist, apprentice, or nail technician, with the exception of a nail technician or cosmetologist exclusively practicing manicuring in a licensed barber shop, shall practice in an establishment licensed by the board. </section><section prefix="3">Notwithstanding the provisions in subsection (2) of this section, persons holding an active license from the board as a cosmetologist or nail technician and who practice in salons licensed by the board shall be permitted to render services for pay, free, or otherwise, to: <section prefix="a">A person suffering from a terminal illness, whose death is anticipated, and who is receiving the services of a hospice program either at home or at a hospice inpatient unit; or </section><section prefix="b">Persons who are deceased and in the care of funeral establishments. </section></section><section prefix="4">Cosmetologists and nail technicians who render services authorized in subsection (3) of this section shall have the permission of the owner or administrator of the establishment where the services are rendered. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 53, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 15, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 178, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42136</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>