<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="132" order_by="132">LEVY AND ASSESSMENT OF PROPERTY TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>132.660</section_number><catch_line>Emergency assessments. </catch_line><order_by>660</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department of Revenue shall have authority to order an emergency assessment of all or any part of the taxable property in any taxing district to be made by one (1) or more persons appointed for that purpose by the department, whenever: there has been no regular assessment; the records of an assessment have been destroyed, mutilated or lost; complaint is made by the owners of not less than ten percent (10%) in value of the taxable property in the taxing district; or investigation of the department discloses that the assessment of property in such taxing district is so grossly inequitable or fiscally infeasible that an emergency exists. The order directing such emergency assessments shall state the reasons therefor and a copy shall be filed in the office of the county clerk where the property lies. Such order, when filed, shall void any assessment for the assessment year for which the emergency assessment is made. Any person appointed to make such an emergency assessment shall have the same powers and duties as the property valuation administrator. Whenever the tax roll has been completed under an emergency assessment and the tentative valuations have been determined, the department shall cause to be published pursuant to KRS Chapter 424, a notice as to the date when the tax roll will be ready for inspection and the time available for such purpose; also a copy of the notice shall be posted at the courthouse door. If any property is assessed at a greater value than that listed by the taxpayer or unlisted property is assessed, the taxpayer shall be charged with notice of such action by reason of the inspection period, and no further notice need be given of such action taken before the beginning of the inspection period. At the close of the inspection period, the tax roll shall be delivered to the county clerk and the county judge/executive shall immediately convene the board of assessment appeals to hear and determine any appeals from such emergency assessment. The board shall remain in session for the time and shall receive the compensation as provided in KRS 133.030(3). Appeals shall be taken and heard from such emergency assessments in the same manner as appeals from regular assessments. </section><section prefix="2">The department may appoint the property valuation administrator to make an emergency assessment provided he was not at fault, and if the property valuation administrator is so appointed he shall receive reasonable compensation for his services in making this assessment, which shall not affect in any manner the payment to him of any compensation that he has received for himself or on behalf of a deputy or that may be due him, for services in making the regular assessment. Whenever through the property valuation administrator's fault an emergency assessment is ordered, the property valuation administrator shall become liable for the cost thereof as provided in KRS 132.620, such cost to be limited to the amount due or paid him in accordance with the provisions of KRS 132.590. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 216, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 262, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 6, effective January 2, 1978. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 134. -- Amended 1949 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 2. -- Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 131, secs. 10 and 32. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><lrc-note>.  A technical correction has been made in this section by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to KRS 7.136. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:00</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28310</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>