<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171">STATE LIBRARIES -- LIBRARIANS -- STATE ARCHIVES AND RECORDS </unit></structure><section_number>171.390</section_number><catch_line>Report of activities required from commission. </catch_line><order_by>390</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commission shall, within two (2) years of June 21, 1974, submit a written report to the Governor and the General Assembly. The report shall set out, in such detail as may be necessary; the property, historic sites, and buildings to be incorporated into the plan; the manner and method by which the property, sites, and buildings may be restored, preserved, maintained, and operated; the amount of money which will have to be expended for the restoration and maintenance of any property; and the sources from which funds may be derived for these purposes. The commission may seek what state and federal funds are available to aid in the development of the plan and the actual restoration and preservation of Washington as a historic town.  </section><section prefix="2">The submission of the commission's report, required by subsection (1) of this section, shall not conclude the business for which it is created and the commission may continue to exist and perform its designated functions until such time as the Governor may terminate its existence. Upon termination of the commission, all real and personal property held by the commission, remaining after payment of, or provision for payment of, all debts and liabilities of the commission shall become the property of the Commonwealth of Kentucky for the purposes of the Department of Parks or the property of Old Washington, Incorporated, as determined by the commission. </section></text><history>Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 397, sec. 3. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4811</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>