<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="218" order_by="218">A CONTROLLED SUBSTANCES </unit></structure><section_number>218A.070</section_number><catch_line>Schedule II controlled substances. </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text>Unless otherwise rescheduled by regulation of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, the controlled substances listed in this section are included in Schedule II: <section prefix="1">Any material, compound, mixture, or preparation which contains any quantity of the following substances, except those narcotic drugs listed in other schedules, whether produced directly or indirectly by extraction from substances of vegetable origin, or independently by means of chemical synthesis, or by combination of extraction and chemical synthesis: <section prefix="a">Opium and opiate, and any salt, compound, derivative, or preparation of opium or opiate; </section><section prefix="b">Any salt, compound, isomer, derivative, or preparation thereof which is chemically equivalent or identical with any of the substances referred to in paragraph (a), but not including the isoquinoline alkaloids of opium; </section><section prefix="c">Opium poppy and poppy straw; </section><section prefix="d">Coca leaves and any salt, compound, derivative, or preparation of coca leaves, including cocaine and ecgonine and their salts, isomers, derivatives and salts of isomers and derivatives, and any salt, compound, isomer, derivative, or preparation thereof which is chemically equivalent or identical with any of these substances, but not including decocainized coca leaves or extractions of coca leaves which do not contain cocaine or ecgonine. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any material, compound, mixture, or preparation which contains any quantity of the following opiates, including their isomers, esters, ethers, salts, and salts of isomers, whenever the existence of these isomers, esters, ethers, and salts is possible within the specific chemical designation: Alphaprodine; Anileridine; Bezitramide; Dihydrocodeine; Diphenoxylate; Fentanyl; Isomethadone; Levomethorphan; Levorphanol; Metazocine; Methadone; Methadone-Intermediate; 4-cyano-2-dimethylamino-4; 4-diphenyl butane; Moramide-Intermediate; 2-methyl-3-morpholino-1; 1-diphenyl-propane-carboxylic acid; Pethidine; Pethidine-Intermediate-A, 4-cyano-1-methyl-4-phenylpiperidine, Pethidine-Intermediate-B, ethyl-4-phenylpiperidine-4-carboxylate; Pethidine-Intermediate-C, 1-methyl-4-phenylpiperidine-4-carboxylic acid; Phenazocine; Piminodine; Racemethorphan; Racemorphan. </section><section prefix="3">Any material, compound, mixture, or preparation which contains any quantity of the following substances having a potential for abuse associated with a stimulant effect on the central nervous system: <section prefix="a">Amphetamine, its salts, optical isomers, and salts of its optical isomers; </section><section prefix="b">Phenmetrazine and its salts; </section><section prefix="c">Methylphenidate. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 532, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 475, effective July 15, 1998 and ch. 606, sec. 67, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 412, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 441, sec. 3, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 286, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(3). -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 8. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9628</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>