<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.20-715</section_number><catch_line>Comprehensive vehicle emission control program. </catch_line><order_by>20-715</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet shall administer or provide for a comprehensive vehicle emission control program which may require the annual inspection of vehicles in counties designated by Federal Environmental Protection Agency regulation to be nonattainment for ozone, carbon monoxide, or nitrogen dioxide if a program is necessary or prudent to meet federal air quality standards and if no Federal Environmental Protection Agency approved program is being operated by an air pollution control district, county fiscal court, or combination of county fiscal courts. Provided, however, that a county legislative body not currently operating such a program has affirmatively authorized such a program to be operated either under its own or the cabinet's jurisdiction. </section><section prefix="2">The cabinet shall adopt emission standards which may vary by model year, class of vehicle, engine type or size, and may provide for the exemption of certain classes of vehicles from the requirements of KRS 224.20-710 to 224.20-765. </section><section prefix="3">The cabinet shall adopt conditions for compliance certificates and exemption certificates. </section><section prefix="4">The cabinet may administer or provide for a program to train and certify mechanics in the maintenance of control systems and techniques of engine maintenance which affect vehicle emissions, and may charge a fee for the program. </section><section prefix="5">The cabinet may administer or provide for the issuance and revocation of certificates to qualified mechanics and may charge a fee for the certificates. </section><section prefix="6">The cabinet shall adopt procedures, including inspection schedules necessary to implement the comprehensive vehicle emission control program. </section><section prefix="7">The cabinet may promulgate administrative regulations necessary to administer KRS 224.20-710 to 224.20-765. </section></text><history>Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 467, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><former-codification> KRS 224.464. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:34</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10364</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>