<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="335" order_by="335">SOCIAL WORKERS AND PROFESSIONAL COUNSELORS </unit></structure><section_number>335.100</section_number><catch_line>License, licensed clinical social worker -- Requirements -- Issuance.   </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall issue a license as "licensed clinical social worker" to an applicant who meets the following requirements: <section prefix="a">Has received a master's degree or doctoral degree in social work from an educational institution approved by the board; </section><section prefix="b">Has had a minimum of two (2) years of full time post-master's experience, consisting of at least thirty (30) hours per week, or three (3) years of part time, consisting of at least twenty (20) hours per week, post-master's degree experience acceptable to the board in the use of specialty methods and measures to be employed in clinical social work practice, the experience having been acquired under appropriate supervision as established by the board by promulgation of an administrative regulation; </section><section prefix="c">Has paid to the board an examination fee established by the board by promulgation of an administrative regulation; </section><section prefix="d">Has passed an examination prepared by the board for this purpose; </section><section prefix="e">Has not within the preceding three (3) months failed to pass an examination given by the board; and </section><section prefix="f">Has paid an initial license fee established by the board by promulgation of an administrative regulation. </section></section><section prefix="2">The license shall be displayed in the licensee's principal place of practice, and shall entitle the licensee to hold himself forth to the public as providing services as authorized by KRS 335.010 to 335.160 and KRS 335.990. </section><section prefix="3">A licensed clinical social worker may contract with a certified social worker in the practice of clinical social work as provided in KRS 335.080(3). The licensed clinical social worker shall assume responsibility for and supervise the certified social worker's practice as directed by the board by promulgation of administrative regulations. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 27, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 3, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 369, sec. 12, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 443, sec. 29, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 305, sec. 4. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 279, sec. 10. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44630</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>