<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="342" order_by="342">WORKERS' COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>342.275</section_number><catch_line>Benefit review by administrative law judge -- Determination -- Procedures -- Deadline. </catch_line><order_by>275</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commissioner shall promptly issue notice of the assignment of the claim to an administrative law judge, time for presentation of proof and of the time and place of a benefit review conference. The administrative law judge may confer informally with the parties for the purpose of defining and narrowing the issues, discussing settlement, and considering other relevant matters that may aid in the disposition of the case. </section><section prefix="2">The administrative law judge may grant continuances or grant or deny any benefits afforded under this chapter, including interlocutory relief, according to criteria established in administrative regulations promulgated by the commissioner. The administrative law judge shall render the award, order, or decision within sixty (60) days following the final hearing unless extension is mutually agreed to by all parties. The award, order, or decision, together with a statement of the findings of fact, rulings of law, and any other matters pertinent to the question at issue shall be filed with the record of proceedings, and a copy of the award, order, or decision shall immediately be sent to the parties in dispute. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1811, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 514, sec. 18, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 13, effective December 12, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 181, Part 3, sec. 15, effective April 4, 1994. -- Amended 1987 (1st Extra. Sess.).Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 32, effective January 4, 1988. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 112, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 2. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 192, sec. 20. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4933. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32460</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>