<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="160" order_by="160">SCHOOL DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>160.560</section_number><catch_line>Treasurer of board of education -- Selection -- Bond -- Duties. </catch_line><order_by>560</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each board of education shall elect a treasurer for the board. The board may elect its secretary to serve as treasurer. The board may remove the treasurer from office at any time for cause by a vote of a majority of the members of the board. </section><section prefix="2">The treasurer shall execute an official bond for the faithful performance of the duties of his office, to be approved by the local board and the commissioner of education. The bond shall be guaranteed by a surety company authorized to do business in this state, and shall be in an amount determined by the board of education in accordance with the administrative regulations promulgated by the Kentucky Board of Education. The premium on the bond shall be paid by the board of education. A copy of the bond shall be filed with the board of education and with the commissioner of education. </section><section prefix="3">The treasurer shall receive all moneys to which the board is entitled by the Constitution or by the statutes, except as otherwise provided by law, or which may in any way come into its possession, and deposit such funds in the properly designated depository. He shall withdraw such funds from the depository only upon proper order of the board. He shall keep a full and complete account of all funds in such manner and make such reports concerning them as is required by the board of education or by the Kentucky Board of Education. He shall preserve all records relating to the transactions and duties of the office and turn them over to his successor along with all public funds in his hands and all accounts and records after due and proper audit is made by a competent outside agent when he is required to do so by the board of education. </section><section prefix="4">The treasurer shall issue his check on the depository for payment of all legal claims which have been authorized for payment in accordance with policies previously adopted by the local board of education and approved by the commissioner of education. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 389, sec. 7, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. IV, sec. 235, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 54, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978; and ch. 155, sec. 82, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 173, sec. 1, effective May 18, 1956. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4399-42. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3767</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>