<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.375</section_number><catch_line>Policy statements of boards of trustees concerning "hazing" activities of campus organizations. </catch_line><order_by>375</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The boards of trustees of the University of Kentucky and the University of Louisville and the boards of regents of those state colleges set out in KRS 164.290 shall, within ninety (90) days of July 15, 1986, adopt statements of campus policy which prohibit any action or situation which recklessly or intentionally endangers mental or physical health or involves the forced consumption of liquor or drugs for the purpose of initiation into or affiliation with any organization. Such policy statements shall govern the conduct of students, faculty and other staff as well as visitors and other licensees and invitees on such campuses and property. The penalties for violations of such policy statements shall be clearly set forth therein and shall include provisions for the ejection of a violator from such campus and property, in the case of a student or faculty violator his suspension, expulsion or other appropriate disciplinary action and, in the case of an organization which authorizes such conduct, rescission of permission for that organization to operate on campus property. Such penalties shall be in addition to any penalty pursuant to the penal law or any other chapter to which a violator or organization may be subject. A copy of such policy statements which prohibit reckless or intentional endangerment to health or forced consumption of liquor or drugs for the purpose of initiation into or affiliation with any organization shall be given to all students enrolled in said college and shall be deemed to be part of the bylaws of all organizations operating on said campus. </section><section prefix="2">Nothing contained in this section is intended nor shall it be construed to limit or restrict the freedom of speech nor peaceful assembly. </section></text><history>Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 366, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4280</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>