<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="625" order_by="625">TERMINATION OF PARENTAL RIGHTS </unit></structure><section_number>625.100</section_number><catch_line>Termination orders. </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If the Circuit Court determines that parental rights are to be terminated involuntarily in accordance with the provisions of this chapter, it shall enter an order that the termination of parental rights and the transfer of custody are in the best interest of the child, and that each petitioner is fully aware of the purpose of the proceedings and the consequences of the provisions of this chapter. The order shall terminate all parental rights and obligations of such parent and release the child from all legal obligations to such parent and vest care and custody of the child in such person, agency, or cabinet as the court believes best qualified. </section><section prefix="2">Upon consent by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, the child may be declared a ward of the state and custody vested in the cabinet or in any child-placing agency or child-caring facility licensed by the cabinet or in another person, if all persons with parental rights to the child under the law have had their rights terminated voluntarily or involuntarily. If the other person is unrelated to the child, a grant of custody shall be made only with the written approval of the secretary or his designee. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 671, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 622, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 76, effective April 10, 1988. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 423, sec. 106, effective July 1, 1987. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20259</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>