<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.217</section_number><catch_line>Long-term care case management demonstration. </catch_line><order_by>217</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="a">"Case manager" means an employee of the area development district or an agency under contract with the area development district who shall assist any functionally impaired person in identifying and accessing the long-term-care services most appropriate to the individual's social and medical needs. </section><section prefix="b">"Functionally impaired person" means any person who is unable to perform without assistance any of the activities of daily living including, but not limited to dressing, bathing, toileting, transferring, or feeding, or any of the instrumental activities of daily living including but not limited to meal preparation, laundry, housecleaning, budgeting, and shopping. </section></section><section prefix="2">There shall be established within the Cabinet for Health and Family Services a Long-Term Care Case Management Demonstration Program to consolidate and coordinate all services provided or funded by the cabinet with respect to long-term care, conducted in at least three (3) area development districts. This demonstration program shall serve as the focal point for the provision of all services provided to functionally impaired persons to assure that services are consistent with the following goals: <section prefix="a">That functionally impaired persons be allowed to live independently at home or with others as long as the citizen desires without requiring inappropriate or premature institutionalization; </section><section prefix="b">That services provided or funded by the cabinet promote independent living by functionally impaired persons and prevent or minimize illness or social isolation; </section><section prefix="c">That institutional services be used only as a last resort when in-home or community-based support services are not available or are not adequate to meet the needs of functionally impaired persons; </section><section prefix="d">That a single entry point for all services for functionally impaired persons be available to all persons in need of information about or access to the services; and </section><section prefix="e">That the use of informal providers of care, such as friends and relatives of functionally impaired persons, be used as long as possible before paid services are utilized. </section></section><section prefix="3">The following programs and services shall be included in the Long-Term Care Case Management Demonstration Program: <section prefix="a">Hospital-based long-term-care services including dual-licensed beds, swing beds and physical rehabilitation services, skilled-nursing facility services, intermediate-care-facility services, nursing-facility services, home-health services, and home- and community-based waiver services funded by the Kentucky Medical Assistance Program; </section><section prefix="b">In-home and community-based services for elderly persons funded under the Older Americans Act (42 U.S.C. secs. 3001 et seq.) and Title XX of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. secs. 1397-1397f); </section><section prefix="c">Services provided under the home care program pursuant to KRS 205.460; and </section><section prefix="d">Personal-care-home services or domiciliary care funded by supplemental payments to persons receiving supplemental security income benefits pursuant to KRS 205.245. </section></section><section prefix="4">The Long-Term Care Case Management Demonstration Program shall employ a system of case management to assure that appropriate services are provided to all persons using or applying for the services set forth in subsection (3) of this section, and that the services are consistent with the goals set forth in subsection (2) of this section. All persons applying for these services shall be assigned a case manager. The duties of the case manager shall include preparation of a general plan of care, based on the person's need for services, arranging placements or other needed services or equipment, coordination and management of the applicant through the eligibility process for these services, and reviewing each case on a periodic basis to assure the plan of care is being followed. Case management shall not include the determination of eligibility for Medicaid covered services, long-term-care facility preadmission reviews, level-of-care determinations for purposes of Medicaid reimbursement, or peer review activities. The general plan of care shall not replace a daily care plan prescribed by a physician for treatment of a person in a hospital or long-term-care facility or receiving home-health services. The general plan of care shall identify the categories of services or type of placement required and the providers of the services. Case managers shall serve as advocates for applicants for the services set forth in subsection (3) of this section, and shall interact with the existing administrative structure within the Cabinet for Health and Family Services to meet the goals stated in subsection (2) of this section. Patients discharged from a hospital to a long-term-care facility shall receive case management services in the hospital on a timely basis or immediately after admission to a long-term-care facility. The goal of each case plan shall be the provision of services in the least restrictive setting designed to best meet the individual needs of the functionally impaired person. When persons are determined to need services to maintain independent living, but do not meet the financial or eligibility criteria for services, case managers shall attempt to ensure that services are provided from community resources, family member, or volunteers. </section><section prefix="5">The cabinet, through the Long-Term Care Demonstration Program, shall provide access to information, counseling, and screening as appropriate, for persons potentially in need of long-term-care services without regard to the person's income, in order to assist functionally impaired persons in accessing available services. In administering the Long-Term Care Demonstration Program, the cabinet shall provide services to meet the needs of the minority elderly as identified by the cabinet pursuant to KRS 205.201. The cabinet may charge a fee for providing information, counseling, and screening services based on the client's ability to pay. </section><section prefix="6">The secretary for health and family services may promulgate administrative regulations necessary to implement the Long-Term Care Demonstration Program. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 223, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 23, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 190, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 246, sec. 4, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 482, sec. 28, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7660</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>