<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="531" order_by="531">PORNOGRAPHY </unit></structure><section_number>531.335</section_number><catch_line>Possession or viewing of matter portraying a sexual performance by a minor -- Applicability.   </catch_line><order_by>335</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of possession or viewing of matter portraying a sexual performance by a minor when, having knowledge of its content, character, and that the sexual performance is by a minor, he or she: <section prefix="a">Knowingly has in his or her possession or control any matter which visually depicts an actual sexual performance by a minor person; or </section><section prefix="b">Intentionally views any matter which visually depicts an actual sexual performance by a minor person. </section></section><section prefix="2">The provisions of subsection (1)(b) of this section: <section prefix="a">Shall only apply to the deliberate, purposeful, and voluntary viewing of matter depicting sexual conduct by a minor person and not to the accidental or inadvertent viewing of such matter; </section><section prefix="b">Shall not apply to persons viewing the matter in the course of a law enforcement investigation or criminal or civil litigation involving the matter; and </section><section prefix="c">Shall not apply to viewing the matter by a minor or the minor's parents or guardians, or to school administrators investigating violations of subsection (1)(b) of this section. </section></section><section prefix="3">Possession or viewing of matter portraying a sexual performance by a minor is a Class D felony. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 41, sec. 5, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 39, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 201, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42077</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>