<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.47-065</section_number><catch_line>Cabinet may establish benchmarks for performance measurement -- Monitoring by Division of Forestry.   </catch_line><order_by>47-065</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet, in cooperation with the Kentucky Division of Forestry, may establish objective benchmarks to measure the performance of Kentucky's forest industries and secondary wood products manufacturers. Criteria used in establishing the benchmarks may include but are not limited to: <section prefix="a">Use of the statistical information commonly provided by governmental agencies, or specific data gathered by authorization of the cabinet; </section><section prefix="b">Comparison of regions and areas within the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="c">Comparison of Kentucky to other states; and </section><section prefix="d">Inclusion of measures of income, earnings, and employment. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Division of Forestry, with assistance from the Cabinet for Economic Development, may monitor changes in patterns of wood utilization. Information used in determining changes in wood utilization may include: time-series data on the amount of raw timber shipped out of the state in relation to the amount of timber harvested in the state; time-series data on the number of persons employed in the primary and secondary wood products sectors; and time-series data on value-added measures of Kentucky's forest products. This information may be collected and maintained and may be used to monitor the development of the state's secondary wood industry. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 49, sec. 8, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 224, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42115</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>