<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="242" order_by="242">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LOCAL OPTION </unit></structure><section_number>242.1241</section_number><catch_line>Limited sale precinct election for sale of alcoholic beverages on Sunday at licensed small farm winery in wet territory. </catch_line><order_by>1241</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">If the sale of alcoholic beverages is permitted at a licensed small farm winery located in a wet territory, a limited sale precinct election may be held to authorize the sale of alcoholic beverages on Sunday at the small farm winery. </section><section prefix="b">The election shall be held in the same manner as prescribed by KRS 242.020 to 242.040 and 242.060 to 242.120. </section><section prefix="c">The petition seeking a limited sale precinct election under this section shall state, "We the undersigned registered voters hereby petition for an election on the following question: 'Are you in favor of the sale of alcoholic beverages on Sunday at a small farm winery located in (name of territory) between the hours of 1 p.m. and (the prevailing local time for that locality)?'" </section><section prefix="d">If the precinct contains a licensed small farm winery, the proposition to be voted on in the limited sale precinct election shall state, "Are you in favor of the sale of alcoholic beverages on Sunday at a licensed small farm winery or wineries located in (name of territory) between the hours of 1 p.m. and (the prevailing time for that locality)?" </section></section><section prefix="2">Notwithstanding KRS 242.030, a limited sale precinct election to authorize Sunday sales at a small farm winery may be held less than three (3) years after a local option election held in accordance with KRS 242.124 to authorize the sale of wine at that small farm winery. </section></text><history> Created 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 115, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43441</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>