<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="36" order_by="36">DEPARTMENT OF MILITARY AFFAIRS </unit></structure><section_number>36.472</section_number><catch_line>Military family assistance trust fund board -- Membership -- Terms -- Meetings.   </catch_line><order_by>472</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">The military family assistance trust fund board is hereby created for the purpose of administering the trust fund created under KRS 36.470. The board shall be attached to the Department of Military Affairs for administrative purposes. The board shall be composed of seven (7) members as follows: <section prefix="1">Four (4) members, expert in military family matters, at least one (1) of whom shall be a member of the Kentucky National Guard, appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="2">One (1) member, expert in military family matters, appointed by the President of the Senate; </section><section prefix="3">One (1) member, expert in military family matters, appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives; and </section><section prefix="4">The adjutant general, who shall serve as a nonvoting member. </section></section><section prefix="b">Appointments referred to in paragraph (a) of this subsection shall be made within sixty (60) days of April 25, 2006. </section></section><section prefix="2">The adjutant general, or a majority of the board members, shall arrange for the first board meeting as soon as possible after all board members are appointed, but no later than June 15, 2006. </section><section prefix="3">Appointed board members shall serve without compensation but may receive reimbursement for their actual and necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their duties. </section><section prefix="4">The term of each appointed member shall be four (4) years, except any person serving on the board prior to July 15, 2012, shall serve until the expiration of his or her current term. The subsequent appointments shall be for terms as follows: <section prefix="a">The Governor shall appoint two (2) members to a term of two (2) years and two (2) members to a term of three (3) years; the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives shall each appoint one (1) member to a term of four (4) years; and </section><section prefix="b">Upon expiration of the terms established in paragraph (a) of this subsection, all appointments shall be for a term of four (4) years. </section></section><section prefix="5">An appointed member whose term has expired may continue to serve until a successor is appointed and qualifies. A member who is appointed to an unexpired term shall serve the rest of the term and until a successor is appointed and qualifies. A member may serve two (2) consecutive four (4) year terms and shall not be reappointed for four (4) years after the completion of those terms. </section><section prefix="6">A majority of the full membership of the board shall constitute a quorum. </section><section prefix="7"><section prefix="a">Except as provided in paragraph (b) of this subsection, at the first meeting, the board shall elect, by majority vote, a president who shall preside at all meetings and coordinate the functions and activities of the board. The president shall be elected or reelected each calendar year thereafter. </section><section prefix="b">The adjutant general shall not serve as the president of the board. </section></section><section prefix="8">The board shall meet at least two (2) times annually but may meet more frequently, as deemed necessary, subject to call by the president or by request of a majority of the board members. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 87, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 252, Pt. XXVIII, sec. 2, effective April 25, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40476</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>