<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.46-320</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of center. </catch_line><order_by>46-320</order_by><text>The center shall: <section prefix="1">Compile, organize, and make available for distribution information on pollution prevention technologies and procedures; </section><section prefix="2">Compile, and make available for distribution to business and industry, a list of expert private consultants on pollution prevention technologies and procedures, and a list of researchers at state universities that could provide assistance in waste reduction activities; </section><section prefix="3">Sponsor and conduct conferences and individualized workshops on pollution prevention for specific classes of business or industry; </section><section prefix="4">Conduct feasibility analyses for innovative pollution prevention technologies and procedures; </section><section prefix="5">Facilitate and promote the transfer of pollution prevention technologies and procedures between businesses and industries; </section><section prefix="6">Develop, where appropriate, and distribute for voluntary implementation, pollution prevention plans for the major classes of business or industry that generate hazardous waste or release toxic chemicals in the state; </section><section prefix="7">Develop, and make available for distribution, recommended environmental audit procedures or protocols for utilization by business and industry in conducting internal environmental audits; </section><section prefix="8">Administer loan, loan guarantee, interest subsidy, or grant programs which may be established pursuant to law for the purpose of providing moneys to a business or industry to subsidize the costs of conducting environmental audits or source reduction studies, or developing or purchasing, and implementing, source reduction technologies and procedures, or for other similar purposes; </section><section prefix="9">Provide moneys, from such funds as may be appropriated or otherwise made available, to academic institutions, businesses or industries, government agencies or private organizations located in the state to conduct demonstration or pilot programs utilizing innovative pollution prevention technologies or procedures for specific categories of industry or business; </section><section prefix="10">Provide moneys, from such funds as may be appropriated or otherwise made available, to academic institutions or private organizations located in the state for basic or applied research on pollution prevention; </section><section prefix="11">Compile, and make available for distribution, information on available tax benefits for the implementation of pollution prevention technologies and procedures by an industry or business; </section><section prefix="12">Identify governmental and nongovernmental impediments to pollution prevention; </section><section prefix="13">Develop the necessary information base and data collection programs to assist in establishing program priorities and evaluating the progress of reducing pollution; </section><section prefix="14">Develop training programs and materials for state and local regulatory personnel and private industry, designed to inform about pollution prevention practices and their applicability to industry; </section><section prefix="15">Participate in existing state, federal and industrial networks of individuals and groups actively involved in pollution prevention activities; and </section><section prefix="16">Prepare a proposed pollution prevention research and program budget request for each fiscal year, based on revenue projections and providing for the expenses of the board, the board's technical advisor, and recommendations of the university, and present it to the board for review and approval. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 460, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 166, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><former-codification> KRS 224.984. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10441</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>