<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">F LOCAL RESCUE PROGRAMS - STATE AND LOCAL SEARCH AND RESCUE PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>39F.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter.   </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>The following definitions apply in this chapter unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Developmental disability" has the same meaning as in KRS 387.510; </section><section prefix="2">"General rescue squad" means a rescue squad which performs one (1) or more of the following functions as a stated mission of the organization: <section prefix="a">Light duty rescue; </section><section prefix="b">Extrication of persons from vehicles; </section><section prefix="c">Water rescue and recovery operations not utilizing divers; </section><section prefix="d">Search for lost, trapped, or missing persons not utilizing dogs; </section><section prefix="e">Low angle rescue and recovery operations; and </section><section prefix="f">High angle rescue and recovery operations; </section></section><section prefix="3">"Impaired person" means a person who has a known or reported: <section prefix="a">Developmental disability, including but not limited to autism, or traumatic brain injury and whose disappearance poses a credible threat to the health or safety of the person, as determined by the Department of Kentucky State Police or a local law enforcement agency; or </section><section prefix="b">Physical, mental, or cognitive impairment or organic brain disorder, including but not limited to Alzheimer's disease, and whose disappearance poses a credible threat to the health or safety of the person, as determined by the Department of Kentucky State Police or a local law enforcement agency; </section></section><section prefix="4">"Reports and notification" means the reporting and notification of any search and rescue mission to the appropriate agency or person in the manner as specified by this chapter; </section><section prefix="5">"Rescue" means gaining access, rendering appropriate care, and transporting of a person or persons by whatever means, to a safe environment for appropriate care; </section><section prefix="6">"Rescue squad" means any organization which engages in the search for lost persons, rescue of persons, rescue of persons who are trapped or who are in need of rescue services, search for and recovery of drowned persons, or any other rescue related activity. "Rescue squad" shall not include the rescue of persons from a fire by a fire department, the extrication of persons from a vehicle or other activities which an emergency medical technician, emergency medical technician first responder, or paramedic is authorized to perform pursuant to applicable statutes and administrative regulations, if the activities are performed by a person for an ambulance service or in the role of a first responder. If these activities are performed other than as a first responder or in the role of an ambulance service and are involved in rescue operations, they come within the purview of activities of a rescue squad; </section><section prefix="7">"Search" means the process of looking for a person or persons whose location is not precisely known, and who may be in distress; </section><section prefix="8">"Search and rescue" ("SAR") means the process of looking for a lost, missing, or overdue person or persons who may be in distress, and rendering care with the use of appropriately trained and adequately equipped personnel; </section><section prefix="9">"Search and rescue mission" includes, but is not limited to, searching for a missing or lost person or persons, cave rescue, high angle or rough terrain rescue, urban search and rescue, dive rescue and recovery of drowning victims, inland water search, rescue, and recovery. "Search and rescue" may also include any mission permitted pursuant to this chapter. A "search and rescue mission" does not include mine rescue missions under the jurisdiction of the Department for Natural Resources pursuant to KRS Chapter 351; </section><section prefix="10">"Specialized rescue squad" means a rescue squad which performs one (1) or more of the following functions as the primary or sole mission of the organization: <section prefix="a">Cave rescue; </section><section prefix="b">Search utilizing dogs for lost, trapped or missing persons; </section><section prefix="c">Search for lost, trapped or missing persons, aircraft, or vehicles, utilizing aircraft, but does not apply to licensed air ambulances, active or reserve military organizations, the National Guard, or the Civil Air Patrol; and </section><section prefix="d">Water rescue and recovery operations utilizing divers; </section></section><section prefix="11">"Traumatic brain injury" has the same meaning as in KRS 211.470; and </section><section prefix="12">"Victim recovery" means the search for and the removal to the jurisdiction of the coroner of the remains of a person known or believed to be dead. If the person is found alive, it includes rescue of the person. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 10, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 83, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2012). 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 6, provides that Sections 2 to 5 of the Act, which included an amendment to this statute, shall be known as the "Chase McMurray Act."  (7/15/2008).  2008 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 4, provides that Sections 1 to 3 of this Act, which included an amendment to this statute, shall be known as the "Golden Alert Bill." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40534</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>