<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="344" order_by="344">CIVIL RIGHTS </unit></structure><section_number>344.015</section_number><catch_line>Implementation plans for Federal Civil Rights Act, Title VI by state agencies. </catch_line><order_by>015</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, "state agency" means any department or administrative body of state government, as defined in KRS 12.010, that is subject to the requirements of Title VI of the Federal Civil Rights Act of 1964, 42 U.S.C. secs. 2000d et seq., and regulations promulgated thereunder. </section><section prefix="2">Each state agency shall: <section prefix="a">Develop a Title VI implementation plan by January 1, 1995. If required by Title VI or regulations promulgated thereunder, the implementation plan shall: <section prefix="1">Be developed with the participation of protected beneficiaries; and </section><section prefix="2">Include Title VI implementation plans of any subrecipients of federal funds through the state agency; </section></section><section prefix="b">Submit a copy of the implementation plan to the Auditor of Public Accounts and the Human Rights Commission; and </section><section prefix="c">Submit annual Title VI compliance reports and any implementation plan updates to the Auditor of Public Accounts and the Human Rights Commission by July 1, 1995, and each July 1 thereafter. </section></section><section prefix="3">The Auditor of Public Accounts shall prepare a report on the actions which state agencies are required to take to implement Title VI, and a report summarizing and evaluating, relative to the required implementation actions, the initial state agency implementation plans and including audit findings from the Auditor of Public Accounts field reviews. The Auditor of Public Accounts shall transmit the reports to the Governor, the Human Rights Commission, the Legislative Research Commission, and each state agency. The Auditor of Public Accounts may prescribe the report format, procedure, and time frame for purposes of complying with this subsection. The prescribed format, procedure, and time frame shall be established by administrative regulation pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A. </section><section prefix="4">In addition to being available from the promulgating state agency, all implementation plans, reports, and updates required by and submitted under subsection (2) of this section shall be available for inspection and copying under KRS 61.870 to 61.884 in the offices of the Auditor of Public Accounts. </section><section prefix="5">In any annual audit made of a state agency under KRS 43.050, the Auditor of Public Accounts shall determine whether the state agency has complied with subsection (2) of this section and shall include the determination in the audit report. </section><section prefix="6">To the extent permitted by federal law or regulation, any increased costs incurred by a state agency, the Auditor of Public Accounts, or the Human Rights Commission under this section shall be paid from any available federal funds that may be used for implementation of Title VI of the Federal Civil Rights Act of 1964. </section></text><history> Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 204, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32601</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>