<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">COUNTY GOVERNMENT (FISCAL COURTS AND COUNTY COMMISSIONERS) </unit></structure><section_number>67.372</section_number><catch_line>County administration of global positioning monitoring systemprogram -- Conditions -- Agreements between counties -- Administrativefee.  </catch_line><order_by>372</order_by><text>Any county or combination of counties may operate a global positioning monitoringsystem program subject to the following conditions:(1)The program shall be assigned by ordinance to a county department or countyagency that agrees to operate or supervise the program continuously,twenty-four (24) hours per day, seven (7) days per week;(2)Each county shall identify a law enforcement agency or agencies withjurisdiction in the county to assist a petitioner, victim, or witness when a personordered to wear a monitoring device violates the provisions of the court's orderand is in need of assistance;(3)A county or counties electing to contract with an entity providing a globalpositioning monitoring system and devices shall meet not less than all of therequirements of this section and KRS 403.761 and 456.100;(4)Each county shall monitor the performance of the entity providing the globalpositioning system and devices and shall have a provision in the contract withthe monitoring entity agreeing to the termination of the contract in the event ofserious or continued violations of the contract;(5)Any system chosen shall use the most appropriate global positioningtechnology to track the person ordered to wear the monitoring device and shallinclude technology that:(a)In a domestic violence case under KRS 403.715 to 403.785 or any caseunder KRS Chapter 456:1.Notifies law enforcement or other monitors of any breach of thecourt-ordered boundaries;2.Notifies the petitioner in a timely manner of any breach; and3.Allows monitors to communicate directly with the person ordered towear the monitoring device; and(b)In other situations in which monitoring is authorized by KRS 67.374,431.517, 431.518, 431.520, 456.100, 533.030, and 533.250 thecontracting county or combination of counties shall, in the contract,specify the type and level of global positioning monitoring system servicesdesired;(6)The monitoring entity shall agree to a price for monitoring during the duration ofthe contract which shall not be increased but may be reduced during theduration of the contract. The contract shall provide that reduced payments shallbe accepted by the vendor as a full payment for all purposes from personsdetermined to be indigent by a court or other authority ordering the use ofmonitoring. In bidding for the contract the vendor may take into account thatsome monitored persons will not be able to pay the full cost of the monitoringor may not be able to pay any cost for the monitoring. The contract shallspecify that no unit of state or local government and no public officer oremployee shall be liable for the costs of monitoring under the contract.Notwithstanding the provisions of this subsection, a county or counties mayagree to pay all or a part of the monitoring fee to the monitoring entity if thecounty would have otherwise been required by a court to place a person in jailat county expense and the cost of the monitoring is less than the cost ofplacing the person in jail;(7)Agreements between counties for monitoring services may, with the approvalof their governing bodies, be consummated by a contract signed by all countiesparty thereto or by an interlocal cooperation agreement;(8)A county utilizing a global positioning monitoring system program may chargean administrative fee to a person ordered to participate in a global positioningmonitoring program to provide for the county's cost in administering themonitoring program. The fee shall be set by ordinance and shall be in additionto the fee charged by the entity contracted to provide the monitoring; and(9)KRS Chapter 456 and KRS 403.715 to 403.785 shall not apply to a personordered to participate in a global positioning monitoring system under KRS431.517, 431.518, 431.520, 533.030, and 533.250. The provisions of a courtorder that relate to a person ordered to participate in a global positioningmonitoring system pursuant to KRS 431.517, 431.518, 431.520, 533.030, and533.250 shall govern that person's conduct and any reporting or otherrequirements ordered by the court.</text><history>Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 39, effective January 1, 2016. --Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 170, sec. 9, effective July 15, 2010.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44787</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>