<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="148" order_by="148">PARKS AND TOURISM </unit></structure><section_number>148.300</section_number><catch_line>Control of activities on park grounds -- Liens against exhibitors and others -- Enforcement of liens. </catch_line><order_by>300</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commission shall have exclusive control of concessions, exhibitions, shows, entertainments and attractions at any place on the State Horse Park grounds, and may under the direction of the commission operate any or all of such activities, by law. </section><section prefix="2">The commission shall have a prior lien upon the property of any concessionaire, exhibitor or person, immediately upon its coming or being brought on the grounds to secure existing or future indebtedness. </section><section prefix="3">Any designated employee or agent of the commission may sell the property to satisfy the indebtedness after giving ten (10) days' notice to the owner or agent of the owner or, if notice cannot be given to the owner, after a notice is posted for ten (10) days in the office of the commission on the grounds, announcing that the property is to be sold. The commission through its designated agent, may bid on and buy the property offered for sale for the use and benefit of the State Horse Park. </section></text><history>Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 96, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 81, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 19, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1979 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 5, effective July 1, 1979. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1744</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>