<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="146" order_by="146">NATURAL RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>146.440</section_number><catch_line>Uses and purposes of nature preserves. </catch_line><order_by>440</order_by><text>In order to secure for the people of the Commonwealth of Kentucky of present and future generations the benefits of an environment having one or more of the characteristics of a natural area, the commission is hereby empowered to acquire in the name of the Commonwealth of Kentucky and to hold in trust for the benefit of the general public an adequate system of nature preserves in the manner herein set forth, and for the following uses and purposes:  <section prefix="1">For scientific research in such fields as, but not limited to, ecology, taxonomy, genetics, forestry, pharmacology, agriculture, soil science, geology, paleontology, ornithology, herpetology, mammalogy, biology, entomology, agronomy, conservation, and all other natural sciences;  </section><section prefix="2">For the teaching of biology, natural history, ecology, geology, conservation and other related subjects;  </section><section prefix="3">As habitats for plant and animal species and other natural objects;  </section><section prefix="4">As reservoirs of natural materials;  </section><section prefix="5">As places of natural interest and beauty;  </section><section prefix="6">As living illustrations of our natural heritage wherein one may observe and experience natural biotic and ecological systems of the earth and their processes;  </section><section prefix="7">To promote understanding and appreciation of the aesthetic, cultural, scientific and spiritual values of our unpolluted and unspoiled environment;  </section><section prefix="8">For the preservation and protection of nature preserves against modification or encroachment resulting from occupation, development or other use which would destroy their natural or aesthetic conditions;  </section><section prefix="9">As places where people may observe nature's web of life and our natural heritage, and as reminders of the vital human dependence upon unspoiled natural areas.  </section></text><history>Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 7. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1517</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>