<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.412</section_number><catch_line>License application -- Temporary license -- Personal identification card -- Child identification program -- Renewal of license by mail by citizens in military serving out-of-state -- Limited exemption for citizens with expired licenses who are returning from military -- Medical insignia -- Anatomical gift -- Limitation on number of licenses -- Married woman's name -- Witnesses for anatomical gifts -- "Veteran" designation.     </catch_line><order_by>412</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">A person who was under the age of eighteen (18) years at the time of application for an instruction permit and is eighteen (18) years of age or older may apply for an operator's license to operate a motor vehicle, motorcycle, or moped if the person has possessed the valid instruction permit for at least one hundred eighty (180) days and has completed a driver training program under KRS 186.410(4). </section><section prefix="b">A person who has attained the age of eighteen (18) years and is under the age of twenty-one (21) at the time of application for an instruction permit may apply for an operator's license to operate a motor vehicle, motorcycle, or moped if the person has possessed the valid instruction permit for at least one hundred eighty (180) days. </section><section prefix="c">A person who is at least twenty-one (21) years of age at the time of application for an instruction permit may apply for an operator's license to operate a motor vehicle, motorcycle, or moped if the person has possessed the valid instruction permit for at least thirty (30) days. </section></section><section prefix="2">Except as provided in subsection (4) of this section, a person shall apply for an operator's license in the office of the circuit clerk of the county where the person lives. Except as provided in subsection (8)(b) and (c) of this section, the application form shall require the person's: <section prefix="a">Full legal name and signature; </section><section prefix="b">Date of birth; </section><section prefix="c">Social Security number, federal tax identification number, a letter from the Social Security Administration declining to issue a Social Security number, or a notarized affidavit from the applicant to the Transportation Cabinet swearing that the person either does not have a Social Security number, or refuses to divulge his or her Social Security number, based upon religious convictions; </section><section prefix="d">Sex; </section><section prefix="e">Present Kentucky resident address, exclusive of a post office box address alone; </section><section prefix="f">Other information necessary to permit the application of United States citizens to also serve as an application for voter registration; </section><section prefix="g">A brief physical description of the applicant; </section><section prefix="h">A statement if the person has previously been licensed as an operator in another state; </section><section prefix="i">Proof of the person's Kentucky residency, including but not limited to a deed or property tax bill, utility agreement or utility bill, or rental housing agreement; and </section><section prefix="j">Other information the cabinet may require by administrative regulation promulgated under KRS Chapter 13A. </section></section><section prefix="3">A permanent resident shall present one (1) of the following documents issued by the United States Department of Homeland Security, United States Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services: <section prefix="a">An I-551 card with a photograph of the applicant; or </section><section prefix="b">A form with the photograph of the applicant or a passport with a photograph of the applicant on which the United States Department of Homeland Security, United States Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services has stamped the following: "Processed for I-551. Temporary evidence of lawful admission for permanent residence. Valid until -----. Employment authorized." </section></section><section prefix="4">If the person is not a United States citizen and has not been granted status as a permanent resident of the United States, the person's application for an original operator's license shall be submitted to either the Transportation Cabinet in Frankfort or a Transportation Cabinet field office. <section prefix="a">The application form shall be accompanied by the person's documentation issued by the United States Department of Homeland Security, United States Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services, authorizing the person to be in the United States and, if applicable, the person's international driving permit. The application form of a special status individual with a K-1 status shall be accompanied by an original or certified copy of the person's completed marriage license signed by the official who presided over the marriage ceremony and two (2) witnesses. The application form of a special status individual with a K-1 status shall also include the person's petition to enter the United States for the purpose of marriage that contains the name of the prospective spouse. If the name of the prospective spouse on the petition does not match the name of the spouse on the marriage license, the Transportation Cabinet shall not be required to issue an operator's license. </section><section prefix="b">The Transportation Cabinet shall, within fifteen (15) days of receipt of the application, review the person's documentation and determine if the person will be issued a Kentucky operator's license. If the review of an application will take longer than fifteen (15) days, the cabinet shall continue the review, but the cabinet shall be required to make a determination in all cases within thirty (30) days of receipt of the application. </section><section prefix="c">If the cabinet determines the person may be issued an operator's license, the cabinet shall issue the person an official form that the person shall take to the office of the circuit clerk of the county where the person resides. The circuit clerk shall review the person's documentation and the official form issued by the Transportation Cabinet. If the documentation is verified as accurate, and if the person successfully completes the examinations required under KRS 186.480, the circuit clerk shall issue the person a Kentucky operator's license. </section><section prefix="d">Except as provided in paragraphs (e) and (f) of this subsection, a person who is not a United States citizen and who has not been granted status as a permanent resident of the United States shall apply to renew an operator's license, or obtain a duplicate operator's license, in the office of the circuit clerk in the county in which the person resides. </section><section prefix="e">If a person is renewing an operator's license or is applying for a duplicate license after July 15, 2002, and the person's documentation issued by the United States Department of Homeland Security, United States Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services, has not been reviewed by the either the Transportation Cabinet in Frankfort or a Transportation Cabinet field office under the provisions of this subsection, the person shall be required to apply for the renewal or duplicate with either the Transportation Cabinet in Frankfort or a Transportation Cabinet field office. </section><section prefix="f">If a person has any type of change in the person's immigration status, the person shall apply to renew an operator's license with either the Transportation Cabinet in Frankfort or a Transportation Cabinet field office. </section></section><section prefix="5">The circuit clerk shall issue an operator's license bearing a color photograph of the applicant and other information the cabinet may deem appropriate. The photograph shall be taken by the circuit clerk so that one (1) exposure will photograph the applicant and the application simultaneously. When taking the photograph, the applicant shall be prohibited from wearing sunglasses or any other attire that obscures any features of the applicant's face as determined by the clerk. The clerk shall require an applicant to remove sunglasses or other obscuring attire before taking the photograph required by this subsection. Any person who refuses to remove sunglasses or other attire prohibited by this section as directed by the clerk shall be prohibited from receiving an operator's license. The operator's license issued by the cabinet shall not contain the applicant's Social Security number. The cabinet shall promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A that develop a numbering system that uses an identification system other than Social Security numbers. If an applicant does not have a Social Security number, or the applicant has submitted a notarized affidavit refusing to divulge his or her Social Security number based upon religious convictions, the Transportation Cabinet shall assign the applicant a unique identifying number. The license shall also designate by color coding and use the phrase "under 21" if the licensee is under the age of twenty-one (21); "CDL" if the license is issued pursuant to KRS Chapter 281A; or "under 21 CDL" if the licensee holds a commercial driver's license issued pursuant to KRS Chapter 281A and is under the age of twenty-one (21). </section><section prefix="6">Every applicant shall make oath to the circuit clerk as to the truthfulness of the statements contained in the form. </section><section prefix="7"><section prefix="a">Except as provided in subsection (8) of this section, the circuit clerk shall issue a color photo personal identification card to any person who is a Kentucky resident and who resides in the county who complies with the provisions of this section and who applies in person in the office of the circuit clerk. An application for a personal identification card shall be accompanied by the same information as is required for an operator's license under subsection (2) of this section, except if a person does not have a fixed, permanent address, the person may use as proof of residency a signed letter from a homeless shelter, health care facility, or social service agency currently providing the person treatment or services and attesting that the person is a resident of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="b">It shall be permissible for the application form for a personal identification card to include as a person's most current resident address a mailing address, post office box, or an address provided on a voter registration card. </section><section prefix="c">Every applicant for a personal identification card shall make an oath to the circuit clerk as to the truthfulness of the statements contained on the application form. If the applicant is not the legal owner or possessor of the address provided on the application form, the applicant shall swear that he or she has permission from the legal owner, authorized agent for the legal owner or possessor to use the address for purposes of obtaining the personal identification card. The personal identification card shall designate by color coding and by use of the phrase "under 21" if the applicant is under the age of twenty-one (21). </section><section prefix="d">A personal identification card shall be valid for a period of four (4) years from the date of issuance, except that if the personal identification card is issued to a person who does not have a fixed, permanent address, then the personal identification card shall be valid for one (1) year from the date of issuance. Except as provided in this subsection, an initial or renewal personal identification card issued to a person who is not a United States citizen and who has not been granted status as a permanent resident of the United States and who is not a special status individual, but who is a Kentucky resident, shall be valid for a period equal to the length of time the person's documentation from the United States Department of Homeland Security, United States Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services is issued, or four (4) years, whichever time period is shorter. An initial or renewal personal identification card shall be valid for a period of two (2) years if the person is not a special status individual and the person's documentation issued by the United States Department of Justice, Immigration and Naturalization Service, is issued for an indefinite period of time and does not have an expiration date. The fee shall be the same as for a regular personal identification card. </section><section prefix="e">A personal identification card may be suspended or revoked if the person who was issued the card presents false or misleading information to the cabinet when applying for the card. </section></section><section prefix="8"><section prefix="a">A person may be issued a personal identification card if the person currently holds a valid Kentucky instruction permit or operator's license. If a person's instruction permit or operator's license has been suspended or revoked, the person may be issued a temporary personal identification card. A temporary personal identification shall be renewed annually and may be surrendered when the person applies to have his or her instruction permit or operator's license reinstated. </section><section prefix="b">Upon receipt of proper documentation provided by the Department of Corrections, the circuit clerk of the county in which a released felony offender resides shall issue to any felony offender, if the felony offender is eligible, released from the Department of Corrections on home incarceration, parole, completed service of sentence, shock probation, or pardon, a personal identification card or, if the felony offender is eligible, an operator's license. Proper documentation under this paragraph shall consist of: <section prefix="1">The offender's certificate of birth, except for offenders born outside this state; </section><section prefix="2">A copy of the offender's resident record card and parole certificate or notice of discharge; </section><section prefix="3">A photograph of the offender, printed on plastic card or paper; and </section><section prefix="4">A release letter that shall contain the offender's: <section prefix="a">Full legal name, subject to the information available to the Department of Corrections; </section><section prefix="b">Discharge/release date; </section><section prefix="c">Signature; </section><section prefix="d">Social Security number; </section><section prefix="e">Date of birth; </section><section prefix="f">Present Kentucky address where he or she resides; and </section><section prefix="g">Physical description. </section></section></section> The offender shall present this documentation to the circuit clerk within thirty (30) calendar days from the date of the release letter and shall be responsible for paying the fee for the personal identification card or operator's license pursuant to KRS 186.531. The provisions of this paragraph shall apply only to persons released on or after July 15, 2010. <section prefix="c">Upon receipt of proper documentation provided by the Department of Corrections, the circuit clerk of the county in which a felony offender resides shall issue to any felony offender, if the felony offender is eligible, probated or conditionally discharged by the court and under the supervision of the Division of Probation and Parole, a personal identification card or, if the felony offender is eligible, an operator's license. Proper documentation under this paragraph shall consist of: <section prefix="1">The offender's certificate of birth, except for offenders born outside this state; </section><section prefix="2">The offender's sentencing order; </section><section prefix="3">A photograph of the offender, printed on plastic card or paper; and </section><section prefix="4">A notarized release letter, signed by the supervising officer verifying the offender's status on supervision, that shall contain the offender's: <section prefix="a">Full legal name, subject to the information available to the Division of Probation and Parole; </section><section prefix="b">Signature; </section><section prefix="c">Social Security number; </section><section prefix="d">Date of birth; </section><section prefix="e">Present Kentucky address where he or she resides; and </section><section prefix="f">Physical description. </section></section></section> The offender shall present this documentation to the circuit clerk within thirty (30) calendar days from the date of the notarized release letter. The offender shall be responsible for paying the fee for the personal identification card or operator's license pursuant to KRS 186.531. The provisions of this paragraph shall apply only to persons released on or after July 15, 2010. </section><section prefix="9">The Transportation Cabinet shall implement a voluntary statewide child identification program. The program shall issue a color photo personal identification card to a child two (2) to fifteen (15) years of age. Application for a child identification card shall be accompanied by a Social Security card and a birth certificate for the child or other proof of the child's date of birth as provided under subsection (2) of this section. The card shall contain the child's name and the toll-free number of the Kentucky Missing Persons Clearinghouse, Department of Kentucky State Police. The card shall not contain the child's Social Security number. The cabinet shall set a four dollar ($4) fee for the child identification card. Two dollars ($2) of the fee shall be used to cover the cabinet's cost for equipment and supplies. Two dollars ($2) of the fee shall be an administrative fee of the circuit clerk for issuing the card which shall be deposited by the Administrative Office of the Courts into a trust and agency account for the circuit clerks and used for the purposes of hiring additional deputy clerks and providing salary adjustments to deputy clerks. The card shall expire every four (4) years on the child's birthday. Within the time period that the child identification card is valid, the card may be updated with a new photograph and information. The fee for an updated card shall be four dollars ($4), with two dollars ($2) of the fee going to the cabinet and two dollars ($2) going to the Administrative Office of the Courts in the same manner as the fee for an initial card as described in this subsection. The descriptive data and a photo image of the child shall be stored in the Kentucky Driver's License Information System and may be retrieved and used by public agencies subject to the provisions of the Driver Privacy Protection Act, 18 U.S.C. sec. 2721, and may also be used by the Kentucky Missing Persons Clearinghouse. </section><section prefix="10">If a citizen of the Commonwealth currently serving in the United States military is stationed or assigned to a base or other location outside the boundaries of the Commonwealth, the citizen may renew a Class D operator's license issued under this section by mail. If the citizen was issued an "under 21" operator's license, upon the date of his or her twenty-first birthday, the "under 21" operator's license may be renewed for an operator's license that no longer contains the outdated reference to being "under 21." </section><section prefix="11">A citizen of the Commonwealth renewing an operator's license by mail under subsection (10) of this section may have a personal designee apply to the circuit clerk on behalf of the citizen to renew the citizen's operator's license. An operator's license being renewed by mail under subsection (10) of this section shall be issued a license without a photograph. The license shall show in the space provided for the photograph the legend "valid without photo and signature." </section><section prefix="12"><section prefix="a">If a citizen of the Commonwealth has been serving in the United States military stationed or assigned to a base or other location outside the boundaries of the Commonwealth and has allowed his or her operator's license to expire, he or she shall, within ninety (90) days of returning to the Commonwealth, be permitted to renew his or her license without having to take a written test or road test. </section><section prefix="b">A citizen who meets the criteria in paragraph (a) of this subsection shall not be convicted or cited for driving on an expired license prior to license renewal during the ninety (90) days after the person's return to the Commonwealth if the person can provide proof of his or her out-of-state service and dates of assignment. </section><section prefix="c">A citizen who meets the criteria in paragraph (a) of this subsection and who does not renew his or her license within ninety (90) days of returning to the Commonwealth shall be required to comply with the provisions of this chapter governing renewal of a license that has expired. </section><section prefix="d">If a citizen of the Commonwealth has been issued an "under 21" or "under 21 CDL" operator's license and the person is unable to renew the license on the date of his twenty-first birthday, the "under 21" or "under 21 CDL" operator's license shall be valid for ninety (90) days beyond the date of the person's twenty-first birthday. </section></section><section prefix="13">The cabinet shall provide on each license to operate motor vehicles, motorcycles, and mopeds a space for the licensed driver's: <section prefix="a">Blood type; </section><section prefix="b">Medical insignia if the person provides evidence that a medical identification bracelet noting specific physical ailments or a drug allergy is being worn or other proof as may be required by the cabinet; and </section><section prefix="c">A statement whereby the owner of the license may certify in the presence of two (2) witnesses his willingness to make an anatomical gift under KRS 311.1917. </section></section><section prefix="14">If the motor vehicle operator denotes a physical ailment or drug allergy on the operator's license, he may apply for and shall receive, for a fee of two dollars ($2) paid to the circuit clerk, two (2) medical insignia decals that may be affixed to the driver's side of the front windshield of a motor vehicle and to the driver's side of the rear window of a motor vehicle. </section><section prefix="15">An operator's license pursuant to this section shall be designated a Class D license. </section><section prefix="16">A person shall not have more than one (1) license. </section><section prefix="17">Upon marriage, a woman applying for an operator's license or a color photo personal identification card shall provide the circuit clerk with her marriage license and complete an affidavit form provided by the circuit court clerk. She shall have the following choices in regard to her full legal name as required in subsections (2) and (7) of this section: <section prefix="a">Use her husband's last name; </section><section prefix="b">Retain her maiden name; </section><section prefix="c">Use her maiden name hyphenated with her husband's last name; </section><section prefix="d">Use her maiden name as a middle name and her husband's last name as her last name; or </section><section prefix="e">In the case of a previous marriage, retain that husband's last name. </section></section><section prefix="18">Upon issuing an operator's license or personal identification card, the clerk shall draw the recipient's attention to the location on the license relating to anatomical gifts under subsection (13)(c) of this section and offer to allow personnel in the clerk's office to serve as the witnesses to the recipient's certification of willingness to make an anatomical gift if the recipient is the person to whom the license is issued. </section><section prefix="19">Any person who served in the active Armed Forces of the United States, including the Coast Guard of the United States, and was released, separated, discharged, or retired therefrom under conditions other than dishonorable, may, at the time of initial application or application for renewal or duplicate, request that an operator's license or a personal identification card issued under this section bear the word "veteran" on the face or the back of the license or personal identification card. The designation shall be in a style and format considered appropriate by the Transportation Cabinet. Prior to obtaining a designation requested under this subsection, the applicant shall present the circuit clerk with an original or copy of his or her DD-214 or DD-2 form as proof of veteran status. The circuit clerk shall not be liable for fraudulent or misread DD-214 or DD-2 forms presented. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 5, effective June 8, 2011; and ch. 79, sec. 2, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 98, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 161, sec. 32, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 46, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 192, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 4, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 55, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 96, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002; ch. 261, sec. 1, effective January 1, 2003; and ch. 264, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 535, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 52, sec. 1, effective March 16, 1998; and ch. 192, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 185, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996; and ch. 198, sec. 5, effective October 1, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994; ch. 393, sec. 9, effective January 1, 1995; and ch. 481, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 455, sec. 29, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 142, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 402, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 236, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982; ch. 243, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982; and ch. 389, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 349, sec. 4, effective June 17, 1978; and ch. 434, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 15, sec. 1, effective January 1, 1975; and ch. 124, sec. 1. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 1; and ch. 103, sec. 1. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 63, sec. 3, effective June 13, 1968. -- Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 60, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/94).  This section was amended by 1994 Ky. Acts chs. 86, 393, and 481. Where these Acts are not in conflict, they have been codified together. Where Acts chs. 86 and 481 are in conflict, Acts ch. 481, which was the last enacted by the General Assembly, prevails under KRS 446.250. 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 393 amending this section is effective January 1, 1995, according to OAG 94-42. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44695</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>