<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="605" order_by="605">ADMINISTRATIVE MATTERS </unit></structure><section_number>605.160</section_number><catch_line>Provision of information to those caring for committed children -- Show cause hearing. </catch_line><order_by>160</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet, the Department of Juvenile Justice, and the Kentucky Department of Education shall provide information to the individuals and entities contracting with the cabinet and the Department of Juvenile Justice to provide services and care to children committed to the cabinet or the Department of Juvenile Justice necessary to provide adequate care and services to the committed children they are serving. The cabinet, the Department of Juvenile Justice, and the Kentucky Department of Education shall develop a process that will result in the provision and transfer of information as required by KRS 158.137, 605.090, 605.110, 610.120, 620.145, and this section in a timely and efficient manner, including: <section prefix="a">Medical passport or history; </section><section prefix="b">Educational passport; </section><section prefix="c">Treatment history; and </section><section prefix="d">Current case plan. </section></section> If action by a court is necessary to obtain or release information that the cabinet or the Department of Juvenile Justice deems necessary for the provision of care or services to a committed child, then the cabinet or Department of Juvenile Justice, as the case may be, shall promptly petition the court for permission to receive or release the necessary information. <section prefix="2">If the cabinet, the Department of Juvenile Justice, or a school or educational facility as defined in KRS 158.137 fails to provide necessary information within the time frames established by KRS 158.137, 605.090, 605.110, 620.145, and this section, the person, agency, or entity providing care or services to a child may petition the court having jurisdiction over the child to hold a hearing, at which time the court, if the request for hearing is granted, shall require the cabinet, the Department of Juvenile Justice, or the school or educational facility as defined in KRS 158.137 to show cause as to why it has not provided the necessary information in a timely manner. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 398, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20126</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>