<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">F LOCAL RESCUE PROGRAMS - STATE AND LOCAL SEARCH AND RESCUE PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>39F.200</section_number><catch_line>Local search and rescue coordinator. </catch_line><order_by>200</order_by><text>Each local emergency management director shall assume the duties of, or appoint with the concurrence of the fiscal court, city governing body, urban-county council, consolidated local government, or governing body of other local government, a local search and rescue coordinator who shall be responsible for the coordination of all search and rescue resources and operations during all search and rescue missions within the city or county. The position of local search and rescue coordinator may be a volunteer position. The local search and rescue coordinator, if appointed by the local emergency management director, shall serve a similar term not to exceed four (4) years, but may be reappointed for a similar term upon the expiration of a previous term. The local search and rescue coordinator may be removed for cause at any time by the local director, with the concurrence of the fiscal court, city governing body, urban-county council, or governing body of other local government. The local search and rescue coordinator shall successfully complete training in search management, search techniques, and incident command required by the division by administrative regulation. </text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 11, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 102, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21813</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>