<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="261" order_by="261">STOCKYARDS </unit></structure><section_number>261.370</section_number><catch_line>Exceptions to provisions of this chapter.   </catch_line><order_by>370</order_by><text>No provision of KRS Chapter 261 shall be construed as applicable to: <section prefix="1">A person who offers for sale or trade only livestock which he has owned or has in his possession for a period of thirty (30) days or longer and who is not regularly engaged in the business of buying, selling, trading, or negotiating the transfer of livestock; </section><section prefix="2">A person who purchases only livestock for feeding or breeding purposes and retains said livestock in his possession for a period of thirty (30) days or longer and who is not regularly engaged in the business of buying, selling, trading, or negotiating the transfer of livestock; </section><section prefix="3">A person engaged in the business of buying and slaughtering livestock for food and in marketing the meat products therefrom, provided all animals purchased are slaughtered; </section><section prefix="4">A person engaged in the purchase or sale of livestock used exclusively for exhibition or entertainment purposes in the pursuit of a hobby; and </section><section prefix="5">A person engaged in sales conducted by or for FFA and 4-H groups; county, state, or private fairs or shows; and breed or livestock associations. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 28, sec. 10, effective July 12, 2012. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 225, sec. 12, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 277, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><former-codification> KRS 257.520. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40151</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>