<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="157" order_by="157">STATE SUPPORT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>157.077</section_number><catch_line>Support for summer learning programs -- Segregation and use of funds.   </catch_line><order_by>077</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section "summer learning program" and "summer learning camp" mean the program and camps established by KRS 158.865 to 158.867. </section><section prefix="2">To the extent funds are appropriated by the General Assembly to support summer learning programs, those funds shall be distributed to each local district operating a summer learning program each year based on the average daily membership of the district's summer learning camps for that year. In addition, any funds appropriated to support transportation of students to summer learning camps, shall be distributed based on the previous year per pupil calculation as determined under KRS 157.370. </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">Each school district operating a summer learning program shall establish and maintain a separate fund for each school where a summer learning camp is being held. The fund: <section prefix="1">Shall include any state appropriations specifically designated for the summer learning camp at the school, excluding Title I funds; and </section><section prefix="2">May include moneys from grants, donations from individuals and businesses, and proceeds from fundraising efforts to support the summer learning camp at the school. </section></section><section prefix="b">Funds in the accounts shall be used for personnel, field trips, and to purchase supplies, materials, and equipment for the summer learning camp. </section><section prefix="c">Any amounts remaining in an individual school fund at the end of the year shall be carried forward into the next year. If a school discontinues operation of its summer learning camp, the funds shall be transferred to another school in the district where a summer learning camp will be held. If there are no summer learning camps in the district, the funds may be used by the district to close the achievement gap between low-income and high-income students. </section></section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 131, sec. 4, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40601</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>