<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.3-218</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 286.3-219 and 286.3-220. </catch_line><order_by>3-218</order_by><text>As used in KRS 286.3-219 and 286.3-220: <section prefix="1">"Life beneficiary" means a beneficiary who is a current permissible or mandatory recipient of income or principal from the trust, or, if more than one (1), the beneficiary or beneficiaries of the oldest generation; </section><section prefix="2">"Remainder beneficiary" means a beneficiary who would have received the trust property in fee but for the continuation of the trust by the corporate trustee; </section><section prefix="3">"A portion or all of the trust" means a portion, including all, of any remainder beneficiary's share of the trust to which the remainder beneficiary would be entitled in fee following the death of the life beneficiary. The portion of each of the remainder beneficiary's share that is continued shall be held as a separate trust; </section><section prefix="4">"Trust" has the same meaning as set forth in KRS 386B.1-010; and </section><section prefix="5">"Corporate trustee" means a trust company or a bank empowered as a fiduciary. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 25, sec. 98, effective July 15, 2014. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 440, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><former-codification> KRS 287.218. </former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  In accordance with 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, secs. 38 and 39, this statute has been renumbered as a section of the Kentucky Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286, and KRS references within this statute have been adjusted to conform with the 2006 renumbering of that code. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43161</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>