<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="610" order_by="610">PROCEDURAL MATTERS </unit></structure><section_number>610.220</section_number><catch_line>Permitted purposes for holding child in custody -- Time limitation -- Extension -- Separation from adult prisoners -- Prohibition against attaching child to stationary object.   </catch_line><order_by>220</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as otherwise provided by statute, if an officer takes or receives a child into custody on an allegation of committing a public offense or into protective custody on being a suspected runaway, the child may be held at a police station, secure juvenile detention facility, youth alternative center, a nonsecure facility, or, as necessary, in a hospital or clinic for the following purposes: <section prefix="a">Identification and booking; </section><section prefix="b">Attempting to notify the parents or person exercising custodial control or supervision of the child, a relative, guardian, other responsible person, or the cabinet; </section><section prefix="c">Photographing; </section><section prefix="d">Fingerprinting; </section><section prefix="e">Physical examinations, including examinations for evidence; </section><section prefix="f">Evidence collection, including scientific tests; </section><section prefix="g">Records checks; </section><section prefix="h">Determining whether the child is subject to trial as an adult; and </section><section prefix="i">Other inquiries of a preliminary nature. </section></section><section prefix="2">A child may be held in custody pursuant to this section for a period of time not to exceed two (2) hours, unless an extension of time is granted. Permission for an extension of time may be granted by the court, trial commissioner, or court-designated worker pursuant to KRS 610.200(6)(d) and the child may be retained in custody for up to an additional ten (10) hours at a facility of the type listed in subsection (1) of this section except for an intermittent holding facility for the period of retention. </section><section prefix="3">Any child held in custody pursuant to this section shall be sight and sound separated from any adult prisoners held in secure custody at the same location, and shall not be handcuffed to or otherwise securely attached to any stationary object. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 42, effective July 1, 2015. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 160, sec. 2, effective April 21, 2004. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 193, sec. 4, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 534, sec. 9, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 358, sec. 31, effective July 15, 1997. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 29, effective April 10, 1988. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 423, sec. 41, effective July 1, 1987. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43972</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>