<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="157" order_by="157">STATE SUPPORT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>157.390</section_number><catch_line>Determination of teachers' salaries and other required public school funding components -- Additional compensation expenses. </catch_line><order_by>390</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For purposes of the state teacher salary schedule, teachers shall be placed on the schedule based on certification rank as established by the Education Professional Standards Board under KRS 161.1211 and by their years of experience as follows: 1. Zero (0) to three (3) years; 2. Four (4) to nine (9) years; 3. Ten (10) to fourteen (14) years; 4. Fifteen (15) to nineteen (19) years; and 5. Twenty (20) or more years. </section><section prefix="2">The rank and experience of the teacher shall be determined on September 15 of each year. </section><section prefix="3">The amount to be included in the base funding level for capital outlay shall be determined by multiplying the average daily attendance by the amounts set forth in the biennial budget. </section><section prefix="4">The amount to be included in the public school fund of each district for transportation shall be determined in accordance with the provisions of KRS 157.370. </section><section prefix="5">The total amount of money distributable to each district from the public school fund shall include the base funding per pupil in average daily attendance, an amount for at-risk students, an amount for the types and numbers of students with disabilities, an amount for students served in home and hospital settings, and the allotments in subsections (3) and (4) of this section, less the amount of local tax revenues generated for school purposes, up to a maximum equivalent local rate of thirty cents ($0.30) as defined by KRS 157.615(6). </section><section prefix="6">A classroom teacher or administrator may be provided additional compensation, funds for instructional and program materials, and other related costs for serving as a classroom mentor, teaching partner, or professional development leader in core discipline areas including reading, and other subject areas as appropriate to other education professionals in a state approved program or state approved activities. The Kentucky Department of Education shall administer the funds appropriated for these purposes. The Kentucky Board of Education shall promulgate administrative regulations to define the guidelines for programs and activities that qualify for funds including the application and approval process, the individual participant requirements, the amount of compensation, the timelines, and reporting requirements. The board shall solicit recommendations from the Education Professional Standards Board and staff of the Kentucky Department of Education in developing its administrative regulations. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 135, sec. 5, effective April 2, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 389, sec. 4, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 527, sec. 12, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 298, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996; and ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 195, sec. 12, effective July 14, 1992; and ch. 392, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. III, sec. 99, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 41, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1985 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 6, effective October 18, 1985. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 367, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1984; and ch. 368, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 133, sec. 4, effective July 17, 1978. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 93, sec. 28, effective July 1, 1976. </history><metadata><effective> April 2, 2002 </effective><former-history>  Repealed 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 363, sec. 18, effective June 30, 1976. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 333, sec. 1. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 1, effective June 18, 1970. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 210, sec. 1. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 24, Part 1, sec. 1. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 171, sec. 1. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 244, Art. V, sec. 1. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 145, sec. 6. -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 214, sec. 9.</former-history><former-history-former-name>KRS 157.390.</former-history-former-name><lrc-note>Former KRS 157.390 (Enact. Acts 1954, ch. 214, sec. 9; 1956, ch. 106, sec. 4; 1960, ch. 145, sec. 6; 1962, ch. 244, Art. V; 1964, ch. 171, sec. 1; 1966, ch. 24, Pt. I, sec. 1; 1968, ch. 210; 1970, ch. 116, sec. 1; 1972, ch. 333, sec. 1) was repealed by Acts 1974, ch. 363, sec. 18, effective June 30, 1976. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3322</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>