<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="230" order_by="230">HORSE RACING AND SHOWING </unit></structure><section_number>230.230</section_number><catch_line>Personnel -- Duties -- Compensation. </catch_line><order_by>230</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Governor shall appoint an executive director who shall serve at the pleasure of the Governor. The Governor shall set the qualifications and salary for the position of executive director pursuant to KRS 64.640. The executive director shall possess the powers and perform the duties imposed upon him by the Governor, and other duties as the racing commission may direct or prescribe. The executive director shall: <section prefix="a">Be responsible for the day-to-day operations of the racing commission; </section><section prefix="b">Set up appropriate organizational structures and personnel policies for approval by the racing commission; </section><section prefix="c">Appoint all staff; </section><section prefix="d">Prepare annual reports of the racing commission's program of work; </section><section prefix="e">Carry out policy and program directives of the racing commission; </section><section prefix="f">Prepare and submit to the racing commission for its approval the proposed biennial budget of the racing commission; and </section><section prefix="g">Perform all other duties and responsibilities assigned by law. </section></section> The executive director shall cause to be kept a full record of all proceedings before the racing commission and shall preserve at its general office all books, maps, records, documents, licenses, and other papers of the racing commission. All records of the racing commission shall be open to inspection by the public during regular office hours. With approval of the racing commission, the executive director may enter into agreements with any state agency or political subdivision of the state, any postsecondary education institution, or any other person or entity to enlist assistance to implement the duties and responsibilities of the racing commission. <section prefix="2">The executive director of the racing commission may employ, dismiss, or take other personnel action concerning an assistant executive director, stenographers, clerks, and other personnel as he or she may deem necessary to efficiently operate the racing commission's general office or any branch thereof. The executive director of the racing commission shall fix the compensation of all employees. Any member of the racing commission or any employee referred to in this section shall be reimbursed for expenses paid or incurred in the discharge of official business when approved by the executive director of the racing commission. The compensation of the employees referred to in this section, except for the executive director, together with reimbursement of expenses incurred by employees, a member of the racing commission, or the executive director, shall be paid from racing commission funds. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 447, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 4, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 447, sec. 5, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 14, effective March 30, 1992. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 240, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 184 sec. 3, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10834</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>