<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.29-131</section_number><catch_line>Reinsurance. </catch_line><order_by>29-131</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A domestic society may, by a reinsurance agreement, cede any individual risk or risks in whole or in part to an insurer, other than another fraternal benefit society, having the power to make reinsurance and authorized to do business in this state, or if not so authorized, one (1) which is approved by the commissioner; but no society may reinsure substantially all of its insurance in force without the written permission of the commissioner. It may take credit for the reserves on the ceded risks to the extent reinsured; but no credit shall be allowed as an admitted asset or as a deduction from liability, to a ceding society for reinsurance made, ceded, renewed, or otherwise becoming effective after January 1, 1989, unless the reinsurance is payable by the assuming insurer on the basis of the liability of the ceding society under the contract or contracts reinsured without diminution because of the insolvency of the ceding society. </section><section prefix="2">Notwithstanding the limitation in subsection (1) of this section, a society may reinsure the risks of another society in a consolidation or merger approved by the commissioner under KRS 304.29-141. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1393, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 310, sec. 13, effective January 1, 1989. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:03</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29671</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>