<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="210" order_by="210">STATE AND REGIONAL MENTAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>210.235</section_number><catch_line>Confidential nature of records -- Conditions under which records may be disclosed. </catch_line><order_by>235</order_by><text>All applications and requests for admission and release, and all certifications, records, and reports of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services which directly or indirectly identify a patient or former patient or a person whose hospitalization has been sought, shall be kept confidential and shall not be disclosed by any person, except insofar as: <section prefix="1">The person identified or his guardian, if any, shall consent; or </section><section prefix="2">Disclosure may be necessary to carry out the provisions of the Kentucky Revised Statutes, and the rules and regulations of cabinets and agencies of the Commonwealth of Kentucky; or </section><section prefix="3">Disclosure may be necessary to comply with the official inquiries of the departments and agencies of the United States government; or </section><section prefix="4">Disclosure may be necessary for: <section prefix="a">Treatment of the patient by any health care provider involved in the patient's care; </section><section prefix="b">Treatment, payment, or health care operations under the federal Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996, Pub. L. No. 104-191, including disclosure between health care providers through an electronic health information exchange or network; or </section><section prefix="c">Participation by health care providers through an electronic health information exchange or network for the purpose of meeting the requirements of the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009, Pub. L. No. 111-5, and its related federal regulations; or </section></section><section prefix="5">A court may direct upon its determination that disclosure is necessary for the conduct of proceedings before it and failure to make such disclosure would be contrary to the public interest. Nothing in this section shall preclude the disclosure, upon proper inquiry of the family or friends of a patient, of information as to the medical condition of the patient. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 317, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 262, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(1) and (9). -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 1, effective July 1, 1954. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42998</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>