<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="83" order_by="83">A ORGANIZATION OF GOVERNMENT IN CITIES </unit></structure><section_number>83A.085</section_number><catch_line>Office of city clerk required, except in city of first class -- Duties -- Combination with other nonelected city office -- Information on city and officials to Department for Local Government. </catch_line><order_by>085</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each city, except a city of the first class, shall establish the office of city clerk. </section><section prefix="2">The office of city clerk may be combined with any other nonelected city office by inclusion of the title and duties of the office in the ordinance establishing the office of city clerk. </section><section prefix="3">The duties and responsibilities of the clerk shall include but not be limited to the following: <section prefix="a">Maintenance and safekeeping of the permanent records of the city; </section><section prefix="b">Performance of the duties required of the "official custodian" or "custodian" in accordance with KRS 61.870 to 61.882; </section><section prefix="c">Possession of the seal of the city if used; </section><section prefix="d">No later than January 31 of each year, mail to the Department for Local Government a list containing current city information including but not limited to the following: <section prefix="1">The correct name of the mayor, legislative body members, and the following appointed officials who are serving as of January 1 of each year: <section prefix="a">City clerk; </section><section prefix="b">City treasurer; </section><section prefix="c">City manager; </section><section prefix="d">City attorney; </section><section prefix="e">Finance director; </section><section prefix="f">Police chief; </section><section prefix="g">Fire chief; and </section><section prefix="h">Public works director; </section></section><section prefix="2">The correct name of the city, mailing address for city hall, and telephone number of city hall; and </section><section prefix="3">The name and telephone number of either an elected or appointed official to serve as a contact person that may be reached during normal business hours of 8 a.m. to 4:30 p.m.; </section></section><section prefix="e">Performance of all other duties and responsibilities required of the city clerk by statute or ordinance; and </section><section prefix="f">The Department for Local Government shall immediately forward one (1) copy of the information received from each city clerk to the Legislative Research Commission. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 67, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 61, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 45, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 302, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:11</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=25175</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>