<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.12-223</section_number><catch_line>Department for Business Development. </catch_line><order_by>12-223</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is created within the Cabinet for Economic Development the Department for Business Development, which shall be headed by a commissioner appointed by the Governor. The department shall work with each Kentucky county in: <section prefix="a">Assisting community-based economic development agencies in creating and implementing their respective work plans; </section><section prefix="b">Developing cooperative interaction with existing industries and small and minority businesses and assisting export development; </section><section prefix="c">Providing sufficient technical resources to create and maintain a database to facilitate sales transactions between Kentucky businesses; </section><section prefix="d">Assisting minority businesses with federal, state, and local government agencies, regulations, and procurement programs; and </section><section prefix="e">Introducing entrepreneurs to individual investors and to investment capital firms interested in start-up and early-state financing. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Department for Business Development shall include the following divisions, each of which shall be headed by an executive director appointed by the secretary pursuant to KRS 12.050: <section prefix="a">The Office of Entrepreneurship shall be responsible for various forms of small business assistance, including without being limited to: <section prefix="1">Providing comprehensive information on all state business licenses and requirements; </section><section prefix="2">Assisting businesses in the identification of government procurement opportunities; </section><section prefix="3">Administering the innovation assistance set forth in KRS 154.12-278; and </section><section prefix="4">Collecting, summarizing, and disseminating information helpful to small businesses, including information on: (a) Market research; </section></section><section prefix="b">Federal, state, and local minority business programs; and </section><section prefix="c">The availability of managerial assistance. <section prefix="1">Research activities related to strategic planning, business site selection, </section><section prefix="2">Program analysis; </section><section prefix="3">Competitive analysis; </section><section prefix="4">Communications and marketing services; and </section><section prefix="5">Event planning. </section></section> The Commission on Small Business Advocacy established in KRS 11.200 shall advise the office on small business needs; and (b) The Office of Research and Public Affairs, which shall administer the following: and existing industry;  The office shall include the Division of Database and Systems Development, which shall be headed by a director appointed by the secretary pursuant to KRS 12.050. </section><section prefix="3">The following programs shall be attached to the Department for Business Development: <section prefix="a">The Kentucky port and river development program created by KRS 65.510 to 65.530, KRS 139.483, and KRS 154.80-100 to 154.80-130; </section><section prefix="b">The Waterway Marina Development Program established by KRS 154.80-310; and </section><section prefix="c">The Bluegrass State Skills Corporation established by KRS 154.12-205. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 181, sec. 6, effective June 20, 2005; and ch. 158, sec. 4, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 133, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1996; ch. 209, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996; and ch. 262, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 499, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><lrc-note> (6/20/2005). The Reviser of Statutes has renumbered the subparagraphs of subsection (2)(a) of this statute under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(a). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43341</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>