<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="342" order_by="342">WORKERS' COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>342.035</section_number><catch_line>Medical fee schedule -- Review and updating -- Action for excess fees -- Effect of failure to submit to or follow surgical or medical treatment or advice -- Fee schedule for medical testimony -- Other medical matters -- Medical fee schedule for registered nurse first assistants. </catch_line><order_by>035</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Periodically, the commissioner shall promulgate administrative regulations to adopt a schedule of fees for the purpose of ensuring that all fees, charges, and reimbursements under KRS 342.020 and this section shall be fair, current, and reasonable and shall be limited to such charges as are fair, current, and reasonable for similar treatment of injured persons in the same community for like services, where treatment is paid for by general health insurers. In determining what fees are reasonable, the commissioner may also consider the increased security of payment afforded by this chapter. On or before November 1, 1994, and on July 1 every two </section><section prefix="2">years thereafter, the schedule of fees contained in administrative regulations </section>promulgated pursuant to this section shall be reviewed and updated, if appropriate. Within ten (10) days of April 4, 1994, the commissioner shall execute a contract with an appropriately qualified consultant pursuant to which each of the following elements within the workers' compensation system are evaluated; the methods of health care delivery; quality assurance and utilization mechanisms; type, frequency, and intensity of services; risk management programs; and the schedule of fees contained in administrative regulation. The consultant shall present recommendations based on its review to the commissioner not later than sixty (60) days following execution of the contract. The commissioner shall consider these recommendations and, not later than thirty (30) days after their receipt, promulgate a regulation which shall be effective on an emergency basis, to effect a twenty-five percent (25%) reduction in the total medical costs within the program. (2) No provider of medical services or treatment required by this chapter, its agent, servant, employee, assignee, employer, or independent contractor acting on behalf of any medical provider, shall knowingly collect, attempt to collect, coerce, or attempt to coerce, directly or indirectly, the payment of any charge, for services covered by a workers' compensation insurance plan for the treatment of a work-related injury or occupational disease, in excess of that provided by a schedule of fees, or cause the credit of any employee to be impaired by reason of the employee's failure or refusal to pay the excess charge. In addition to the penalty imposed in KRS 342.990 for violations of this subsection, any individual who sustains damages by any act in violation of the provisions of this subsection shall have a civil cause of action in Circuit Court to enjoin further violations and to recover the actual damages sustained by the individual, together with the costs of the lawsuit, including a reasonable attorney's fee. <section prefix="3">Where these requirements are furnished by a public hospital or other institution, payment thereof shall be made to the proper authorities conducting it. No compensation shall be payable for the death or disability of an employee if his or her death is caused, or if and insofar as his disability is aggravated, caused, or continued, by an unreasonable failure to submit to or follow any competent surgical treatment or medical aid or advice. </section><section prefix="4">The commissioner shall, by December 1, 1994, promulgate administrative regulations to adopt a schedule of fees for the purpose of regulating charges by medical providers and other health care professionals for testimony presented and medical reports furnished in the litigation of a claim by an injured employee against the employer. The workers' compensation medical fee schedule for physicians, 803 KAR 25:089, having an effective date of February 9, 1995, shall remain in effect until July 1, 1996, or until the effective date of any amendments promulgated by the commissioner, whichever occurs first, it being determined that this administrative regulation is within the statutory grant of authority, meets legislative intent, and is not in conflict with the provisions of this chapter. The medical fee schedule and amendments shall be fair, current, and reasonable and otherwise comply with this section. </section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">To ensure compliance with subsections (1) and (4) of this section, the commissioner shall promulgate administrative regulations by December 31, 1994, which require each insurance carrier, self-insured group, and self-insured employer to certify to the commissioner the program or plan it has adopted to ensure compliance. </section><section prefix="b">In addition, the commissioner shall periodically have an independent audit conducted by a qualified independent person, firm, company, or other entity hired by the commissioner, in accordance with the personal service contract provisions contained in KRS 45A.690 to 45A.725, to ensure that the requirements of subsection (1) of this section are being met. The independent person, firm, company, or other entity selected by the commissioner to conduct the audit shall protect the confidentiality of any information it receives during the audit, shall divulge information received during the audit only to the commissioner, and shall use the information for no other purpose than the audit required by this paragraph. </section><section prefix="c">The commissioner shall promulgate administrative regulations governing medical provider utilization review activities conducted by an insurance carrier, self-insured group, or self-insured employer pursuant to this chapter. </section><section prefix="d">Periodically, or upon request, the commissioner shall report to the Interim Joint Committee on Labor and Industry of the Legislative Research Commission or to the corresponding standing committees of the General Assembly, as appropriate, the degree of compliance or lack of compliance with the provisions of this section and make recommendations thereon. </section><section prefix="e">The cost of implementing and carrying out the requirements of this subsection shall be paid from funds collected pursuant to KRS 342.122. </section></section><section prefix="6">The commissioner may promulgate administrative regulations incorporating managed care or other concepts intended to reduce costs or to speed the delivery or payment of medical services to employees receiving medical and related benefits under this chapter. </section><section prefix="7">For purposes of this chapter, any medical provider shall charge only its customary fee for photocopying requested documents. However, in no event shall a photocopying fee of a medical provider or photocopying service exceed fifty cents ($0.50) per page. In addition, there shall be no charge for reviewing any records of a medical provider, during regular business hours, by any party who is authorized to review the records and who requests a review pursuant to this chapter. </section><section prefix="8"><section prefix="a">The commissioner shall develop or adopt practice parameters or guidelines for clinical practice for use by medical providers under this chapter. The commissioner may adopt any parameters for clinical practice as developed and updated by the federal Agency for Health Care Policy Research, or the commissioner may adopt other parameters for clinical practice which are developed by qualified bodies, as determined by the commissioner, with periodic updating based on data collected during the application of the parameters. </section><section prefix="b">Any provider of medical services under this chapter who has followed the practice parameters or guidelines developed or adopted pursuant to this subsection shall be presumed to have met the appropriate legal standard of care in medical malpractice cases regardless of any unanticipated complication that may thereafter develop or be discovered. </section></section><section prefix="9"><section prefix="a">Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, the medical fee schedule adopted under subsection (4) of this section shall require all worker's compensation insurance carriers, worker's compensation self-insured groups, and worker's compensation self-insured employers to provide coverage and payment for surgical first assisting services to registered nurse first assistants as defined in KRS 216B.015. </section><section prefix="b">The provisions of this subsection apply only if reimbursement for an assisting physician would be covered and a registered nurse first assistant who performed the services is used as a substitute for the assisting physician. The reimbursement shall be made directly to the registered nurse first assistant if the claim is submitted by a registered nurse first assistant who is not an employee of the hospital or the surgeon performing the services. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1782, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 35, effective March 1, 2005. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 332, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996; and ch. 355, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 181, Part 5, sec. 19, effective April 4, 1994. -- Amended 1987 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 6, effective January 4, 1988. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4886. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/96).  This section was amended by 1996 Ky. Acts chs. 332 and 355 which are in conflict. Under KRS 446.250, Acts ch. 332, which was last enacted by the General Assembly, prevails. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32379</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>