<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.300</section_number><catch_line>Fiscal court to appropriate money for bureau, when -- Limit on amount -- Additional appropriation for agricultural extension work. </catch_line><order_by>300</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Whenever the secretary and the treasurer of a county farm bureau organized under KRS 247.240 to 247.370 have certified to the fiscal court of the county that the bureau has not less than one hundred (100) members who own or operate farms in the county and has a fund of not less than five hundred dollars ($500) in the possession of its treasurer, which fund was obtained from among its members by membership dues or otherwise, the fiscal court shall, subject to subsection (2), appropriate for county cooperative extension work out of the general fund of the county to aid in carrying on extension work in that county in agriculture and home economics and in connection with the University of Kentucky, a sum equal to twice the amount of the said fund in the hands of the bureau. </section><section prefix="2">The total sum appropriated under this section by the fiscal court shall not, in any year, exceed: <section prefix="a">Five thousand dollars ($5,000) in any county having an assessed property valuation of twenty million dollars ($20,000,000) or more; </section><section prefix="b">Four thousand dollars ($4,000) in any county having an assessed property valuation of more than fifteen million dollars ($15,000,000) but less than twenty million dollars ($20,000,000); </section><section prefix="c">Three thousand dollars ($3,000) in any county having an assessed property valuation of between ten ($10,000,000) and fifteen million dollars ($15,000,000); </section><section prefix="d">Two thousand dollars ($2,000) in any county having an assessed property valuation of between five ($5,000,000) and ten million dollars ($10,000,000) or </section><section prefix="e">One thousand five hundred dollars ($1,500) in any county having an assessed property valuation of not more than five million dollars ($5,000,000). </section></section><section prefix="3">Nothing in this section shall prevent or prohibit a fiscal court from appropriating additional funds in support of agricultural extension work under provisions of KRS 247.080 and appropriations made under either section shall be expended as provided for in KRS 247.310. </section></text><history>Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 3, effective May 18, 1956. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 42d-11. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11622</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>