<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="530" order_by="530">FAMILY OFFENSES </unit></structure><section_number>530.070</section_number><catch_line>Unlawful transaction with minor in the third degree. </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of unlawful transaction with a minor in the third degree when: <section prefix="a">Acting other than as a retail licensee, he knowingly sells, gives, purchases or procures any alcoholic or malt beverage in any form to or for a minor. The defendant may prove in exculpation that the sale was induced by the use of false, fraudulent, or altered identification papers or other documents and that the appearance and character of the purchaser were such that his age could not have been ascertained by any other means and that the purchaser's appearance and character indicated strongly that he was of legal age to purchase alcoholic beverages. This subsection does not apply to a parent or guardian of the minor; </section><section prefix="b">He knowingly induces, assists, or causes a minor to engage in any other criminal activity; </section><section prefix="c">He knowingly induces, assists or causes a minor to become a habitual truant; or </section><section prefix="d">He persistently and knowingly induces, assists or causes a minor to disobey his parent or guardian. </section></section><section prefix="2">Unlawful transaction with a minor in the third degree is a Class A misdemeanor. </section></text><history>Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 286, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 382, sec. 21, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 219, sec. 11, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 263, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20003</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>