<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.43-080</section_number><catch_line>Newsprint Recycling Task Force -- Composition -- Duties. </catch_line><order_by>43-080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">On July 15, 1994, and annually thereafter, each publisher shall submit a report to the cabinet. The report shall indicate the amount of newsprint used in the preceding year, its recycled content, along with any other information required by the cabinet. </section><section prefix="2">The Governor shall appoint a Newsprint Recycling Task Force consisting of the secretary of the Energy and Environment Cabinet or a designee; the chairman of the Kentucky Recycling and Marketing Assistance Advisory Committee or a designee; the executive director of the Kentucky Press Association or a designee; three (3) members from environmental organizations; and five (5) members representing the Kentucky newsprint publishing industry and newsprint manufacturers doing business in Kentucky. A list of names of potential task force members shall be provided by the president of the Kentucky Press Association. </section><section prefix="3">The task force members shall each serve a two (2) year term. The initial five (5) industry representatives appointments shall consist of two (2) two (2) year terms and three (3) one (1) year terms. </section><section prefix="4">The Newsprint Recycling Task Force shall meet as necessary to monitor the use of newsprint in the state for the following goals: <section prefix="a">To increase the demand for recycled newsprint in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="b">To increase the availability for the product; </section><section prefix="c">To establish Kentucky as a reliable source of old newsprint for recycling; and </section><section prefix="d">To identify, develop, and advance initiatives to recycle and reuse discarded newspapers and paper products with an emphasis on recycling these materials instead of diverting them for disposal. </section></section><section prefix="5">The Newsprint Recycling Task Force and the Kentucky Press Association shall encourage all Kentucky industries and businesses, their trade or professional organizations, and all public agencies at the state and local level to increase their use of recycled newsprint. </section><section prefix="6">The Newsprint Recycling Task Force shall take steps to attract a recycled newsprint mill or related facility to Kentucky by identifying potential sites and potential manufacturers. The task force shall also work with the Kentucky Recycling and Marketing Assistance Advisory Committee in recommending appropriate economic and tax incentives to encourage such a project. </section><section prefix="7">The Newsprint Recycling Task Force shall promote the increased recovery of old newspapers and, with the Commonwealth of Kentucky representatives, work with communities to develop processing and collection programs to provide quality material to the marketplace. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts and ch. 24, sec. 367, effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 135, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 61, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 500, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  This section was amended by Ky. Acts chs. 24 and 135, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10412</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>