<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="157" order_by="157">STATE SUPPORT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>157.921</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Geographic Education Board -- Purpose -- Membership -- Bylaws. </catch_line><order_by>921</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Geographic Education Board is established to provide leadership and planning for geography education for the population of Kentucky through the efforts of elementary, secondary, and postsecondary educators, government agencies, and public interests. The board shall be an independent agency and be attached to the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet for administrative purposes. </section><section prefix="2">The twelve (12) member board shall be appointed to two (2) year terms, initially appointed by the Governor, and composed of the following members: <section prefix="a">Three (3) representatives from postsecondary institutions; </section><section prefix="b">One (1) representative from the Council for Social Sciences; </section><section prefix="c">Six (6) representatives from elementary and secondary schools; </section><section prefix="d">One (1) representative of the Department of Education; and </section><section prefix="e">One (1) representative of the Council on Postsecondary Education. </section></section><section prefix="3">The board shall select from its membership a chair and establish bylaws, including bylaws governing board membership and length of terms. Upon expiration of the initial appointments and adoption of bylaws governing membership and length of terms by the board, the board shall be self-perpetuating, and the appointment and length of terms shall be made in accordance with the board's bylaws. Vacancies that occur before the expiration of the initial appointments shall be filled by the Governor for the remaining term of the vacancy. </section><section prefix="4">The board members shall receive no compensation but shall be reimbursed for actual expenses incurred in accordance with state procedures and policies. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 47, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 86, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 259, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3395</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>