<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="196" order_by="196">CORRECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>196.111</section_number><catch_line>Evidence-based practices to be used in treatment and intervention programs -- Standards -- Funding restrictions.   </catch_line><order_by>111</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, "evidence-based practices" means supervision policies, procedures, treatment and intervention programs, and practices that scientific research demonstrates reduce recidivism among inmates and individuals on probation, parole, or other form of post-release supervision when implemented competently. </section><section prefix="2">In order to increase the effectiveness of treatment and intervention programs funded by the state and provided by the department for inmates, probationers, and parolees, the department shall require that such programs use evidence-based practices. </section><section prefix="3">The department shall measure the effectiveness of each treatment and intervention program and demonstrate that the program has a documented evidence base and has been evaluated for effectiveness in reducing recidivism. </section><section prefix="4">The department shall promulgate administrative regulations to provide, at a minimum: <section prefix="a">A process for reviewing the objective criteria for evidence-based practices established by the agency providing the program; </section><section prefix="b">A process for auditing the effectiveness of the program; </section><section prefix="c">An opportunity for programs that do not meet the criteria based on the audit results to improve performance; and </section><section prefix="d">A mechanism to defund any program that does not meet the criteria upon a second audit. </section></section><section prefix="5">Beginning July 1, 2012, twenty-five percent (25%) of state moneys expended on programs shall be for programs that are in accordance with evidence-based practices. Beginning July 1, 2014, fifty percent (50%) of state moneys expended on programs shall be for programs that are in accordance with evidence-based practices. Beginning July 1, 2016, and thereafter, seventy-five percent (75%) of state moneys expended on programs shall be for programs that are in accordance with evidence-based practices. </section><section prefix="6">By fiscal year 2016-2017, the department shall eliminate supervision policies, procedures, programs, and practices intended to reduce recidivism that scientific research demonstrates do not reduce recidivism. However, the department may utilize a new supervision policy, procedure, program, or practice if the department determines that the new supervision policy, procedure, program, or practice has the potential for qualifying as an evidence-based practice after more scientific research is conducted. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 156, sec. 20, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 50, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40922</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>