<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXII" order_by="32">OWNERSHIP AND CONVEYANCE OF PROPERTY</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="385" order_by="385">UNIFORM TRANSFERS TO MINORS ACT </unit></structure><section_number>385.092</section_number><catch_line>Manner of creating custodial property and effecting transfer -- Designation of initial custodian -- Control. </catch_line><order_by>092</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Custodial property is created and a transfer is made whenever: <section prefix="a">An uncertificated security or a certificated security in registered form is either: <section prefix="1">Registered in the name of the transferor, an adult other than the transferor, or a trust company, followed in substance by the words: "as custodian for ------------------------------------------- (name of minor) under the Kentucky Uniform Transfers to Minors Act"; or </section><section prefix="2">Delivered if in certificated form, or any document necessary for the transfer of an uncertificated security is delivered, together with any necessary endorsement to an adult other than the transferor or to a trust company as custodian, accompanied by an instrument in substantially the form set forth in subsection (2) of this section; </section></section><section prefix="b">Money is paid or delivered to a broker or financial institution for credit to an account in the name of the transferor, an adult other than the transferor, or a trust company, followed in substance by the words: "as custodian for  </section> -------------------------------------------- (name of minor) under the Kentucky Uniform Transfers to Minors Act"; <section prefix="c">The ownership of a life or endowment insurance policy or annuity contract is either: <section prefix="1">Registered with the issuer in the name of the transferor, an adult other than the transferor, or a trust company, followed in substance by the words: "as custodian for ---------------------------------------------- (name of minor) under the Kentucky Uniform Transfers to Minors Act"; or </section><section prefix="2">Assigned in a writing delivered to an adult other than the transferor or to a trust company whose name in the assignment is followed in substance by the words: "as custodian for -------------------------------------- (name of minor) under the Kentucky Uniform Transfers to Minors Act"; </section></section><section prefix="d">An irrevocable exercise of a power of appointment or an irrevocable present right to future payment under a contract is the subject of a written notification delivered to the payor, issuer, or other obligor that the right is transferred to the transferor, an adult other than the transferor, or a trust company, whose name in the notification is followed in substance by the words: "as custodian for ------------------------------------------------------------- (name of minor) under the Kentucky Uniform Transfers to Minors Act"; </section><section prefix="e">An interest in real property is recorded in the name of the transferor, an adult other than the transferor, or a trust company, followed in substance by the words: "as custodian for ---------------------------------------------------- (name of minor) under the Kentucky Uniform Transfers to Minors Act"; </section><section prefix="f">A certificate of title issued by a department or agency of a state or of the United States which evidences title to tangible personal property is either: <section prefix="1">Issued in the name of the transferor, an adult other than the transferor, or a trust company, followed in substance by the words: "as custodian for  </section> ----------------------------------------------------- (name of minor) under the Kentucky Uniform Transfers to Minors Act"; or <section prefix="2">Delivered to an adult other than the transferor or to a trust company, endorsed to that person followed in substance by the words: "as custodian for --------------------------------------------------- (name of minor) under the Kentucky Uniform Transfers to Minors Act"; or </section></section><section prefix="g">An interest in any property not described in paragraphs (a) through (f) of this subsection is transferred to an adult other than the transferor or to a trust company by a written instrument in substantially the form set forth in subsection (2) of this section. </section></section><section prefix="2">An instrument in the following form satisfies the requirements of paragraphs (a)2. and (g) of subsection (1) of this section: "TRANSFER UNDER THE KENTUCKY UNIFORM TRANSFERS TO MINORS ACT </section> I, ------------------------------- (name of transferor or name and representative capacity if a fiduciary) hereby transfer to ----------------------------- (name of custodian), as custodian for --------------------------------- (name of minor) under the Kentucky Uniform Transfers to Minors Act, the following: (insert a description of the custodial property sufficient to identify it). Dated: -------------------------------  ------------------------------------------------- (Signature) -------------------------------------------------------- (name of custodian) acknowledges receipt of the property described above as custodian for the minor named above under the Kentucky Uniform Transfers to Minors Act. Dated: ------------------------------- -------------------------------------------------"  (Signature of Custodian) <section prefix="3">A transferor shall place the custodian in control of the custodial property as soon as practicable. </section></text><history>Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35796</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>