<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="620" order_by="620">DEPENDENCY, NEGLECT, AND ABUSE </unit></structure><section_number>620.270Scope</section_number><catch_line>of review of local citizen foster care review board.   </catch_line><order_by>270Scope</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Subject to the provisions of KRS 620.230, the local citizen foster care review board shall review the case of each child placed in the custody of the cabinet by an order of temporary custody or commitment by the court in the county or counties which the local board serves. The review shall occur at least once every six (6) months until the child is no longer in the custody of the cabinet or until an adoption proceeding becomes final. </section><section prefix="2">During each six (6) month review, the local citizen foster care review board shall review: <section prefix="a">The past, current, and future status of the child and his placement as shown through the case permanency plan, case record, case progress reports submitted by the cabinet, and other information as the board may require; </section><section prefix="b">The efforts or adjustment the parent has made in his circumstances, conduct, or conditions to make it in the child's best interest to return him to his home within a reasonable period of time considering the age of the child; </section><section prefix="c">The efforts of the cabinet to locate and provide services to the biological parents of the child; </section><section prefix="d">The efforts of the cabinet and other agencies to facilitate the return of the child to the home or to find an alternative permanent placement if reunion with the parent or previous custodian is not feasible. The cabinet shall report to the board all factors which either favor or mitigate against any decision or alternative with regard to these matters; and </section><section prefix="e">Any problems, solutions, or alternatives which may be capable of exploration, or other matters with regard to the child as the cabinet or the board determine to be explored with regard to the best interests of the state or of the child. </section></section><section prefix="3">Upon completion of a training curriculum developed and provided jointly by the Administrative Office of the Courts and by the Department for Community Based Services and approved by the state review board in regard to child sexual abuse, the local citizen foster care review board may review, at the discretion of the board, a sample of all petitions filed in the District Court of the county served by the board alleging sexual abuse of any child, not to exceed two hundred (200) petitions per year statewide, in order to determine the adequacy of the investigation, and the appropriateness of findings, adjudication, and disposition of the court. The board shall have access to all records of the cabinet, medical professionals, and law enforcement agencies pertaining to these cases. The board shall provide the cabinet and the court a full report of the findings and recommendations concerning the review. </section><section prefix="4">Notice of this review and the right to attend and participate in the review shall be provided to the child's parents, if parental rights have not been terminated or surrendered; the parent's attorney; the guardian ad litem, the attorney for the child, or both; the foster parents; the prospective adoptive parent; the relative providing care for the child; and the child who is a party to the proceeding. The cabinet and the court shall develop adequate procedures to provide notice of the review to these persons. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 63, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 59, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 278, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 301, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 412, sec. 3, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 61, effective April 10, 1988. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 423, sec. 88, effective July 1, 1987. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44469</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>