<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="96" order_by="96">UTILITIES IN CITIES </unit></structure><section_number>96.931</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 96.930 to 96.943. </catch_line><order_by>931</order_by><text>As used in KRS 96.930 to 96.943, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"City" means an incorporated municipality of any class; </section><section prefix="2">"Governing body" means the body vested by law with the legislative power of a city; </section><section prefix="3">"Sewer body" means the body vested with responsibility for the control, operation, and maintenance of a city's sewer facilities, which may be the governing body or a board, commission, or agency, created by statute or by city ordinance, or a private person, performing such functions under lawful contract with the city; </section><section prefix="4">"Water supplier" means any person supplying water intended to be used, or actually used, in any manner resulting in contamination and includes the city itself, other cities and public bodies, and private operators of water-supplying facilities; </section><section prefix="5">"Public health standards" means such standards as are lawfully prescribed from time to time by the secretary for health and family services, the United States Public Health Service, or any lawfully constituted county, city, or other public board, department, or agency, vested with responsibility in this area. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 115, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 98, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 170, sec. 2, effective June 19, 1958. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26314</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>