<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="16" order_by="16">STATE POLICE </unit></structure><section_number>16.200</section_number><catch_line>Renumbering of property having obscured numbers. </catch_line><order_by>200</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department of Kentucky State Police shall administer a program for the investigation of applications filed pursuant to KRS 514.130 and the disposition of property pursuant to KRS 500.090. </section><section prefix="2">Upon a finding by the department or a local law enforcement agency assigned by the department to investigate an application filed pursuant to KRS 514.120 that the property is lawfully owned by the applicant, the department shall issue, or cause to be issued, in consultation with any state or federal regulatory agency, a suitable identification number to be affixed to the property together with a document stating the number so issued. </section><section prefix="3">Upon a finding by the department or a local law enforcement agency assigned by the department to investigate an application filed pursuant to KRS 514.120 that the property is not lawfully owned by the applicant, the department shall seize the property or cause it to be seized by the local agency and held for disposition by a court of competent jurisdiction. </section><section prefix="4">The department shall promulgate such administrative regulations as are reasonably necessary to enforce the provisions of this section and KRS 500.090 and 514.130. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 69, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 267, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1129</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>