<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="61" order_by="61">GENERAL PROVISIONS AS TO OFFICES AND OFFICERS -- SOCIAL SECURITY FOR PUBLIC EMPLOYEES -- EMPLOYEES RETIREMENT SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>61.984</section_number><catch_line>Procurement of information technology -- Technology access contract clause -- Alternative and nonvisual access standards. </catch_line><order_by>984</order_by><text>The Finance and Administration Cabinet shall develop a technology access clause which shall be in compliance with Section 255 of the Federal Telecommunication Act of 1996 and with Section 508 of the Federal Workforce Investment Act of 1998 and shall establish alternative, including nonvisual, access standards for use in the procurement of information technology by covered entities in accordance with the following requirements: <section prefix="1">The technology access clause shall require compliance with the standards established under this section. Except as otherwise provided in KRS 61.986, the technology access clause shall be included in all contracts entered into after July 14, 2000, for the procurement of information technology by, or for the use of, covered entities. </section><section prefix="2">The alternative and nonvisual access standards shall include the specifications necessary to meet the requirements of KRS 61.982. The standards shall include the following minimum specifications: <section prefix="a">Effective, interactive control and use of technology, including the operating system, applications programs, and format of the data presented shall be readily achievable by alternative and nonvisual means; </section><section prefix="b">The technology equipped for alternative and nonvisual access shall be compatible with information technology used by other individuals with whom the person with a disability, including the blind or visually impaired individual, must interact; </section><section prefix="c">Alternative and nonvisual access technology shall be integrated into networks used to share communications among employees, program participants, and the public; and </section><section prefix="d">The technology for alternative or nonvisual access shall have the capability of providing equivalent access by nonvisual or other alternative means to telecommunications or other interconnected network services used by persons who are not disabled. </section></section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 536, sec. 34, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23113</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>