<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXI" order_by="31">DEBTOR-CREDITOR RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="376" order_by="376">STATUTORY LIENS </unit></structure><section_number>376.360</section_number><catch_line>Liens on steamboats and other vessels for work and supplies. </catch_line><order_by>360</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any officer or employee, except the captain, employed on board a steamboat, brig, schooner, sloop or model barge shall have a lien on the vessel or on the engine, tackle, furnishing and apparel for their wages, whether contracted for or earned in or out of this state, with priority therefor over any other debt due from the owner of the vessel, and over all other liens thereon. </section><section prefix="2">Mechanics, tradesmen and other persons shall have a like lien to that given by subsection (1) of this section for work, supplies, materials, stores and provisions done or furnished on the building, repairing, fitting, furnishing or equipping the vessel in this state, with priority therefor over any other debt of the owner, except that to the officers and employees, and over all other liens thereafter created. Any mechanic, tradesman or other person who does work or furnishes material or supplies out of this state shall have a like lien therefor, which shall have precedence next after that given when done or furnished in this state; but if done or furnished out of this state, subsequent to that done or furnished in this state, the liens shall be joint and equal. </section></text><history>Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2480. </history><metadata><effective>October 1, 1942</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35325</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>