<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>14A.3-030</section_number><catch_line>Registered name.   </catch_line><order_by>3-030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A foreign entity may register its real name, or its real name with any addition required by KRS 14A.3-010, if the name is distinguishable upon the records of the Secretary of State. </section><section prefix="2">A foreign entity shall register its real name, or its real name with any addition required by KRS 14A.3-010, by delivering to the Secretary of State for filing an application setting forth: <section prefix="a">Its real name, or its real name with any addition required by KRS 14A.3-010; </section><section prefix="b">The state or country of its organization; </section><section prefix="c">Its form of organization; </section><section prefix="d">Its principal office address; and </section><section prefix="e">A brief description of the nature of the business in which it is engaged. </section></section><section prefix="3">The name shall be registered for the applicant's exclusive use upon the effective date of the application. A registration not renewed as provided in subsection (4) of this section shall expire on the next January 1. </section><section prefix="4">A foreign entity whose registration is effective may renew it for successive years by delivering to the Secretary of State for filing a renewal application, which complies with the requirements of subsection (2) of this section, between October 1 and December 31 of the preceding year. The renewal application when filed shall renew the registration for the following calendar year. </section><section prefix="5">A foreign entity whose registration is effective may thereafter qualify as a foreign entity under the registered name or consent in writing to the use of that name by an entity thereafter organized under the laws of the Commonwealth or by another foreign entity thereafter authorized to transact business in this Commonwealth. The registration shall terminate when the domestic entity is organized or the foreign entity qualifies or consents to the qualification of another foreign entity under the registered name. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 25, effective January 1, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36547</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>