<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="315" order_by="315">PHARMACISTS AND PHARMACIES </unit></structure><section_number>315.191</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of board -- Advisory council.   </catch_line><order_by>191</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board is authorized to: <section prefix="a">Promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A necessary to regulate and control all matters set forth in this chapter relating to pharmacists, pharmacist interns, pharmacy technicians, pharmacies, wholesale distributors, manufacturers, and home medical equipment and services providers, to the extent that regulation and control of same have not been delegated to some other agency of the Commonwealth, but administrative regulations relating to drugs and home medical equipment and services shall be limited to the regulation and control of drugs sold pursuant to a prescription drug order or home medical equipment sold pursuant to a medical order. However, nothing contained in this chapter shall be construed as authorizing the board to promulgate any administrative regulations relating to prices or fees or to advertising or the promotion of the sales or use of commodities or services; </section><section prefix="b">Issue subpoenas, schedule and conduct hearings, or appoint hearing officers to schedule and conduct hearings on behalf of the board on any matter under the jurisdiction of the board; </section><section prefix="c">Prescribe the time, place, method, manner, scope, and subjects of examinations, with at least two (2) examinations to be held annually; </section><section prefix="d">Issue and renew all: <section prefix="1">Licenses for home medical equipment and services providers engaged in providing home medical equipment and services; and </section><section prefix="2">Licenses, certificates, and permits for all pharmacists, pharmacist interns, pharmacies, pharmacy technicians, wholesale distributors, and manufacturers engaged in the manufacture, distribution, or dispensation of drugs; </section></section><section prefix="e">Investigate all complaints or violations of the state pharmacy and home medical equipment laws and the administrative regulations promulgated by the board, and bring all these cases to the notice of the proper law enforcement authorities; </section><section prefix="f">Promulgate administrative regulations, pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A, that are necessary and to control the storage, retrieval, dispensing, refilling, and transfer of prescription drug orders within and between pharmacists and pharmacies licensed or issued a permit by it; </section><section prefix="g">Perform all other functions necessary to carry out the provisions of law and the administrative regulations promulgated by the board relating to pharmacists, pharmacist interns, pharmacy technicians, pharmacies, wholesale distributors, manufacturers, and home medical equipment and services providers; </section><section prefix="h">Establish or approve programs for training, qualifications, and registration of pharmacist interns; </section><section prefix="i">Assess reasonable fees, in addition to the fees specifically provided for in this chapter and consistent with KRS 61.870 to 61.884, for services rendered to perform its duties and responsibilities, including, but not limited to, the following: <section prefix="1">Issuance of duplicate certificates; </section><section prefix="2">Mailing lists or reports of data maintained by the board; </section><section prefix="3">Copies of documents; or </section><section prefix="4">Notices of meetings; </section></section><section prefix="j">Seize any drug or device found by the board to constitute an imminent danger to public health and welfare; </section><section prefix="k">Establish an advisory council to advise the board on administrative regulations and other matters, within the discretion of the board, pertinent to the regulation of pharmacists, pharmacist interns, pharmacy technicians, pharmacies, drug distribution, drug manufacturing, and home medical equipment and services. The council shall consist of nine (9) members selected by the board for terms of up to four (4) years. No member shall serve on the council for more than eight (8) years. Membership of the council shall include seven (7) individuals broadly representative of the profession of pharmacy and the general public, and two (2) individuals representative of the home medical equipment and services profession licensed in accordance with KRS 315.518. Members shall be selected by the board from a list of qualified candidates submitted by the association, society, or other interested parties; </section><section prefix="l">Promulgate administrative regulations establishing the qualifications that pharmacy technicians are required to attain prior to engaging in pharmacy practice activities outside the immediate supervision of a pharmacist; and </section><section prefix="m">Oversee and administer the licensure of home medical equipment and services providers pursuant to KRS 315.510 to 315.524. </section></section><section prefix="2">The board shall have other authority as may be necessary to enforce pharmacy and home medical equipment laws and administrative regulations of the board including, but not limited to: <section prefix="a">Joining or participating in professional organizations and associations organized exclusively to promote improvement of the standards of practice of pharmacy and of providing home medical equipment and services for the protection of public health and welfare or facilitate the activities of the board; and </section><section prefix="b">Receiving and expending funds, in addition to its biennial appropriation, received from parties other than the state, if: <section prefix="1">The funds are awarded for the pursuit of a specific objective which the board is authorized to enforce through this chapter, or which the board is qualified to pursue by reason of its jurisdiction or professional expertise; </section><section prefix="2">The funds are expended for the objective for which they were awarded; </section><section prefix="3">The activities connected with or occasioned by the expenditure of the funds do not interfere with the performance of the board's responsibilities and do not conflict with the exercise of its statutory powers; </section><section prefix="4">The funds are kept in a separate account and not commingled with funds received from the state; and </section><section prefix="5">Periodic accountings of the funds are maintained at the board office for inspection or review. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">In addition to the sanctions provided in KRS 315.121, the board or its hearing officer may direct any licensee, permit holder, or certificate holder found guilty of a charge involving home medical equipment, pharmacy, or drug laws, rules, or administrative regulations of the state, any other state, or federal government, to pay to the board a sum not to exceed the reasonable costs of investigation and prosecution of the case, not to exceed twenty-five thousand dollars ($25,000). </section><section prefix="4">In an action for recovery of costs, proof of the board's order shall be conclusive proof of the validity of the order of payment and any terms for payment. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 56, sec. 3, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 73, sec. 13, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 148, sec. 10, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 61, sec. 4, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 257, sec. 20, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 17, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 221, sec. 16. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 260, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note>(7/12/2012). The internal format of subsection (1)(d) of this statute has been modified by the Reviser of Statutes from the way it appeared in 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 73, sec. 13, under the authority of KRS 7.136(1). The words in the text were not changed. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44423</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>