<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="530" order_by="530">FAMILY OFFENSES </unit></structure><section_number>530.020</section_number><catch_line>Incest.   </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of incest when he or she has sexual intercourse or deviate sexual intercourse, as defined in KRS 510.010, with a person whom he or she knows to be an ancestor, descendant, uncle, aunt, brother, or sister. The relationships referred to herein include blood relationships of either the whole or half blood without regard to legitimacy, relationship of parent and child by adoption, relationship of stepparent and stepchild, and relationship of stepgrandparent and stepgrandchild. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Incest is a Class C felony if the act is committed by consenting adults. </section><section prefix="b">Incest is a Class B felony if committed: <section prefix="1">By forcible compulsion as defined in KRS 510.010(2); or </section><section prefix="2">On a victim who is: <section prefix="a">Less than eighteen (18) years of age; or </section><section prefix="b">Incapable of consent because he or she is physically helpless or mentally incapacitated. </section></section></section><section prefix="c">Incest is a Class A felony if: <section prefix="1">Committed on a victim less than twelve (12) years of age; or </section><section prefix="2">The victim receives serious physical injury. </section></section></section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 148, sec. 4, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 37, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 251, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 258, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40871</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>