<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">A DRIVING UNDER THE INFLUENCE </unit></structure><section_number>189A.005</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter -- License suspensions.   </catch_line><order_by>005</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Alcohol concentration" means either grams of alcohol per 100 milliliters of blood or grams of alcohol per 210 liters of breath; </section><section prefix="2">"Ignition interlock device" means a device, certified by the Transportation Cabinet for use in this Commonwealth under KRS 189A.500(1), that connects a motor vehicle ignition system or motorcycle ignition system to a breath alcohol analyzer and prevents a motor vehicle ignition or motorcycle ignition from starting, and from continuing to operate, if a driver's breath alcohol concentration exceeds 0.02, as measured by the device; </section><section prefix="3">"Ignition interlock certification of installation" means a certificate providing that the installed ignition interlock device is certified for use in the Commonwealth under KRS 189A.500(1); </section><section prefix="4">"Ignition interlock device provider" means any person or company engaged in the business of manufacturing, selling, leasing, servicing, or monitoring ignition interlock devices within the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="5">"Ignition interlock license" means a motor vehicle or motorcycle operator's license issued or granted by the laws of the Commonwealth of Kentucky that, with limited exceptions, permits a person to drive only motor vehicles or motorcycles equipped with a functioning ignition interlock device; </section><section prefix="6">"License" means any driver's or operator's license or any other license or permit to operate a motor vehicle issued under or granted by the laws of this state including: <section prefix="a">Any temporary license or instruction permit; </section><section prefix="b">The privilege of any person to obtain a valid license or instruction permit, or to drive a motor vehicle whether or not the person holds a valid license; and </section><section prefix="c">Any nonresident's operating privilege as defined in KRS Chapter 186 or 189; </section></section><section prefix="7">"Limited access highway" has the same meaning as "limited access facility" does in KRS 177.220; </section><section prefix="8">"Refusal" means declining to submit to any test or tests pursuant to KRS 189A.103. Declining may be either by word or by the act of refusal. If the breath testing instrument for any reason shows an insufficient breath sample and the alcohol concentration cannot be measured by the breath testing instrument, the law enforcement officer shall then request the defendant to take a blood or urine test in lieu of the breath test. If the defendant then declines either by word or by the act of refusal, he shall then be deemed to have refused if the refusal occurs at the site at which any alcohol concentration or substance test is to be administered; </section><section prefix="9">When age is a factor, it shall mean age at the time of the commission of the offense; and </section><section prefix="10">Unless otherwise provided, license suspensions under this chapter shall be imposed by the court. The court shall impose the applicable period of license suspension enumerated by this chapter and shall include in its order or judgment the length and terms of any suspension imposed. The license suspension shall be deemed effective on the date of entry of the court's order or judgment. The role of the Transportation Cabinet shall be limited to administering the suspension period under the terms and for the duration enumerated by the court in its order or judgment. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 171, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 467, sec. 1, effective October 1, 2000. -- Created 1991 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 15, sec. 1, effective July 1, 1991. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44678</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>