<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="161" order_by="161">SCHOOL EMPLOYEES -- TEACHERS' RETIREMENT AND TENURE </unit></structure><section_number>161.049</section_number><catch_line>Professional support teams -- Training program -- Alternate training program. </catch_line><order_by>049</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, "professional support team" means a school principal, an experienced teacher, a college or university faculty member, and an instructional supervisor. If an instructional supervisor or college or university faculty member is not available, the district shall assign a member with comparable experience. The school principal shall serve as the chairman of the team. </section><section prefix="2">The Education Professional Standards Board shall establish a training program for professional support teams which shall be implemented by the board or contracted with another agency. The training shall include content and procedures for the evaluation of teacher candidates. Completion of the training shall be evidenced by successfully passing the examinations prescribed by the board. </section><section prefix="3">A local school district seeking to hire a teacher pursuant to KRS 161.048(3) shall submit a plan for a local district alternative training program to the Education Professional Standards Board and have it approved in accordance with administrative regulations established by the Board. The district shall show evidence that it has sought joint sponsorship of the program with a college or university. No local school district shall employ a teacher seeking certification in a state-approved local district training program unless it has submitted a plan and received approval by the Education Professional Standards Board. </section><section prefix="4">Each state approved local district alternative training program shall provide the teacher candidate with essential knowledge and skills and include, but not be limited to, the following components: <section prefix="a">A full-time seminar and practicum of no less than eight (8) weeks' duration prior to the time the candidate assumes responsibility for a classroom. The content of the formal instruction shall be prescribed by the Education Professional Standards Board and shall include an introduction to basic teaching skills through supervised teaching experiences with students, as well as an orientation on the policies, organization, and curriculum of the employing district. </section><section prefix="b">A period of classroom supervision while the candidate assumes responsibility on a one-half (1/2) time basis for a classroom and continuing for eighteen (18) weeks. During this period, the candidate shall be visited and critiqued no less than one (1) time per week by one (1) or more members of a professional support team appointed by the local district and assigned according to the administrative regulations adopted by the Education Professional Standards Board. The candidate shall be formally evaluated at the end of five (5) weeks, at the end of the second five (5) weeks, and at the end of the last eight (8) weeks by the members of the team. During this period, the candidate shall continue formal instruction which emphasizes student assessment, child development, learning, curriculum, instruction of exceptional children, and school and classroom organization. </section><section prefix="c">An additional period of at least eighteen (18) weeks continued supervision of the teacher candidate who may be assigned full-time classroom duties. During this period the teacher candidate shall be critiqued at least once per month and shall be observed formally and evaluated at least twice. No more than two (2) months shall pass without a formal observation. Formal instruction shall also continue during this period. In addition, opportunities shall be provided for the teacher candidate to observe the teaching of experienced teachers. </section></section><section prefix="5">At least two hundred fifty (250) hours of formal instruction shall be provided in all three (3) phases of the program combined. </section><section prefix="6">At the conclusion of the alternative training program, the chair of the support team shall prepare a comprehensive evaluation report on the teacher candidate's performance. This report shall be submitted to the Education Professional Standards Board and shall contain a recommendation as to whether the teacher candidate shall be issued a one (1) year certificate of eligibility to complete the internship pursuant to KRS 161.030. The support team shall make one (1) of the following recommendations: <section prefix="a">Approved: recommends issuance of certificate to complete the internship; </section><section prefix="b">Insufficient: recommends the candidate be allowed to seek reentry into a teacher preparation program; or </section><section prefix="c">Disapproved: recommends the candidate not be allowed to enter a teacher preparation program. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 10, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 589, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. II, sec. 59, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 21, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3838</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>