<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="219" order_by="219">HOTEL, FOOD SERVICE, AND MOBILE HOME AND RECREATIONAL VEHICLE PARK REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>219.390</section_number><catch_line>State Advisory Committee on Manufactured Home, Mobile Home, and Recreational Vehicle Communities -- Membership -- Terms -- Compensation. </catch_line><order_by>390</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For the purpose of assisting in the developing and review of standards and regulations for the administration of KRS 219.310 to 219.410, there is hereby created a State Advisory Committee on Manufactured, Mobile Home, and Recreational Vehicle Communities. The committee shall be composed of twelve (12) members. The secretary for health and family services or his designee shall be an ex officio member. The other members shall be appointed by the secretary for health and family services, three (3) of whom shall represent manufactured and mobile home community owners, two (2) of whom shall represent manufactured and mobile home dealers, two (2) of whom shall represent recreational vehicle dealers or community owners, two (2) of whom shall represent local health departments, one (1) of whom shall represent the state fire marshal, and one (1) member who shall be a citizen at large. </section><section prefix="2">All appointed members shall serve for a term of four (4) years except that, of the original appointees, two (2) shall serve for one (1) year, two (2) shall serve for two (2) years, two (2) shall serve for three (3) years, and two (2) shall serve for four (4) years. All vacancies shall be filled in the manner of original appointment for the unexpired portion of the term only. </section><section prefix="3">Members of the committee shall receive no compensation for their services, but may be reimbursed for necessary travel expenses. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 328, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 556, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 242, sec. 9, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 496, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(1) and (2). -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 281, sec. 9. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9762</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>