<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IV" order_by="4">JUDICIAL BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="21" order_by="21">A SUPREME COURT OF KENTUCKY </unit></structure><section_number>21A.170</section_number><catch_line>In-service training for judges, domestic relations commissioners, and trial commissioners on child sexual abuse, domestic violence, and crimes against the elderly. </catch_line><order_by>170</order_by><text>The Supreme Court shall provide, at least once every two (2) years, in-service training programs for Circuit Judges, District Judges, and domestic relations and trial commissioners in: <section prefix="1">Child development, the dynamics of physical and sexual abuse, the impact of violence on child development, the treatment of offenders, and related issues; </section><section prefix="2">Dynamics of domestic violence, effects of domestic violence on adult and child victims, legal remedies for protection, lethality and risk issues, model protocols for addressing domestic violence, available community resources and victims services, and reporting requirements; and </section><section prefix="3">Dynamics of crimes against the elderly, including but not limited to elder abuse, neglect, and exploitation; the effects of these crimes on the elderly, institutions in which they may reside, and their families; legal remedies for protection; lethality and risk issues; financial implications; model protocols for addressing elder abuse, neglect, and exploitation and other crimes against the elderly; available community resources and victims services; and reporting requirements. </section>Each Circuit Judge, District Judge, and trial and domestic relations commissioner shall successfully complete the training prescribed by the Supreme Court by rule. </text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 15, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 54, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 351, sec. 8, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20543</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>