<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.984</section_number><catch_line>Surplus Agricultural Commodities Advisory Committee.   </catch_line><order_by>984</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Surplus Agricultural Commodities Advisory Committee is hereby created for the purpose of advising the department concerning the implementation and administration of the program established under KRS 247.980 to 247.986. The committee shall be composed of no fewer than ten (10) but no more than fifteen (15) members appointed by the Commissioner. Membership on the committee shall include: <section prefix="a">Food and nutrition advocates; </section><section prefix="b">Regional food bank representatives; </section><section prefix="c">Local government representatives; </section><section prefix="d">Representatives of the department and Governor's Office; </section><section prefix="e">Agricultural commodity producers; </section><section prefix="f">Representatives of farm advocacy groups; </section><section prefix="g">Representatives of Kentucky public or private colleges and universities; and </section><section prefix="h">At-large members designated by the Commissioner. </section></section><section prefix="2">The advisory committee shall elect a chairperson during the first organizational meeting. </section><section prefix="3">The committee shall: <section prefix="a">Advise the department concerning the implementation and administration of KRS 247.980 to 247.986; </section><section prefix="b">Make recommendations to the department regarding the content of administrative regulations promulgated by the department in accordance with KRS 247.980 to 247.986; </section><section prefix="c">Advise the department on administration of the fund created pursuant to KRS 247.985 by developing a written plan for the expenditure of funds. The initial plan shall be completed on or before October 1, 2013, and shall be reviewed and updated if needed on an annual basis on or before October 1 of each year thereafter. The plan shall, at a minimum, include the following: <section prefix="1">A summary of existing food banks in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="2">An evaluation of the needs of the hungry in Kentucky, including the population of areas served by food banks, the percent of the population that is at or below the federal poverty level, an estimate of the number of school children who receive free or reduced-price meals, and other criteria that can measure need; and </section><section prefix="3">A proposal for distributing funds to areas of recognized need; and </section></section><section prefix="d">Provide to the Governor and the Legislative Research Commission an annual report by October 1 of each year. The initial report shall include the plan developed under paragraph (c) of this subsection for the expenditure of funds. The initial and future reports shall include details of the amounts and recipients of funds distributed. </section></section><section prefix="4">Appointed committee members may be reimbursed for reasonable and necessary expenses incurred while engaged in carrying out the official duties of the committee. </section><section prefix="5">The committee shall be attached to the Department of Agriculture for administrative purposes. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 159, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 5, effective June 25, 2009. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2012). In 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 159, sec. 3, subsection (3)(c)2., "free or reduced meals" has been changed to read, "free or reduced-price meals" in codification. The Reviser of Statutes has corrected this manifest clerical or typographical error under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(h). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40976</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>