<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>362.2-201</section_number><catch_line>Formation of limited partnership -- Certificate of limited partnership.   </catch_line><order_by>2-201</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In order to form a limited partnership, a certificate of limited partnership shall be delivered to the Secretary of State for filing. The certificate shall state: <section prefix="a">The name of the limited partnership, which shall comply with KRS 14A.3-010; </section><section prefix="b">The street address of the initial designated office; </section><section prefix="c">The limited partnership's initial registered office and the name of its initial registered agent which shall comply with KRS 14A.4-010; </section><section prefix="d">The name and street address of each general partner; and </section><section prefix="e">Any additional information required by this subchapter. </section></section><section prefix="2">If the limited partnership elects to be a limited liability limited partnership, then the certificate shall contain a statement that the limited partnership elects to be a limited liability limited partnership. </section><section prefix="3">A certificate of limited partnership may also contain any other matters but shall not vary from the provisions specified in KRS 362.2-110(2) in a manner inconsistent with that section. </section><section prefix="4">Subject to subsection (2) of this section, if any provision of a partnership agreement is inconsistent with the filed certificate of limited partnership or with a filed statement of dissociation, cancellation, or change, or filed articles of conversion or merger, then: <section prefix="a">The partnership agreement prevails as to partners and transferees; and </section><section prefix="b">The filed certificate of limited partnership, statement of dissociation, cancellation, or change, or articles of conversion or merger prevail as to persons, other than partners and transferees, that reasonably rely on the filed record to their detriment. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 105, effective January 1, 2011. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 105, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36807</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>