<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="178" order_by="178">COUNTY ROADS -- GRADE CROSSING ELIMINATION </unit></structure><section_number>178.990</section_number><catch_line>Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>990</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any county road engineer who fails to comply with the provisions of KRS 178.050 shall be fined not less than ten ($10) nor more than one hundred dollars ($100) for each offense. </section><section prefix="2">Any county road engineer who makes a change in the location of a road without complying with the provisions of this chapter shall be fined not less than twenty-five dollars ($25). </section><section prefix="3">Any person who injures a sidewalk constructed under the provisions of KRS 178.290 and fails to repair or replace the sidewalk shall be fined not less than four ($4) nor more than fifty dollars ($50). </section><section prefix="4">Any owner or occupier of a dam who fails to comply with the provisions of KRS 178.300 shall be fined two dollars ($2) for every twenty-four (24) hours of noncompliance. Where a milldam is carried away or destroyed, the owner or occupier shall not be subject to the fine until one (1) month after the mill has been put in operation. </section><section prefix="5">If a fiscal court or county judge/executive willfully fails to perform any duty required of it by the provisions of this chapter, except KRS 178.170 and 178.210 to 178.240, every member of such court concurring in the failure shall be fined not less than ten ($10) nor more than one hundred dollars ($100) by the Circuit Court of the county. </section><section prefix="6">All fines imposed by this chapter shall be paid into the county road fund, except that in case of a privately owned road or bridge, the fines shall accrue to the owner. </section><section prefix="7">No fines imposed by this chapter shall bar action for damages for breach of contract. </section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 315, effective June 17, 1978. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 4299, 4304, 4318, 4320, 4322, 4346, 4349. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5471</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>