<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="227" order_by="227">FIRE PREVENTION AND PROTECTION -- ELECTRICIANS </unit></structure><section_number>227.710</section_number><catch_line>Sale or use of display fireworks prohibited -- Exceptions. </catch_line><order_by>710</order_by><text>No person, firm, copartnership, or corporation shall offer for sale, expose for sale, sell at retail, keep with intent to sell, possess, use, or explode any display fireworks, except as follows: <section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">In cities the chief of the fire department, or mayor, or similar official where there is no fire department, and in counties outside of cities the county judge/executive, may grant permits for supervised public displays of fireworks by municipalities, fair associations, amusement parks, and other organizations or groups of individuals. </section><section prefix="b">Every display shall be handled by a competent display operator to be approved by the public official by whom the permit is granted, and shall be of such character, and so located, discharged or fired as in the opinion of the official, after proper inspection, to not be hazardous to property or endanger any person. </section><section prefix="c">"Competent display operator" shall be defined as the person with overall responsibility for the operation and safety of a fireworks display. The competent display operator shall have a Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives (ATF) License and have participated as an assistant in firing at least five (5) public displays. A "competent display operator" is also an employee possessor. A permit under paragraph (a) of this subsection shall be issued only to a competent display operator holding an ATF license. </section><section prefix="d">At least one (1) competent display operator shall be on site during display set-up and firing. This competent display operator shall maintain a copy of the permit application, as signed by the local authority having jurisdiction as identified in this section, on site and at all times the display is in place, and shall be presented on demand of the state fire marshal or local fire chief. All public displays that require issuance of a permit shall be conducted in accordance with the provisions of National Fire Protection Association (NFPA) 1123 – Code for Fireworks Display (adopted edition). </section><section prefix="e">Permits shall be filed with the state fire marshal at least fifteen (15) days in advance of the date of the display. After the privilege is granted, sales, possession, use, and distribution of fireworks for the display shall be lawful for that purpose only. No permit granted under this subsection shall be transferable. For the purposes of this subsection, "public display of fireworks" shall include the use of pyrotechnic devices or pyrotechnic materials before a proximate audience, whether indoors or outdoors. </section><section prefix="f">Any person remaining within the display area shall be identified as licensed by the ATF, or an employee thereof, or be an assistant in training to become a competent display operator. All persons remaining within the display area shall be at least eighteen (18) years of age. </section><section prefix="g">The commissioner of the Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction with recommendation from the state fire marshal shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to administer the provisions of this subsection. The regulations shall address the process by which permits are issued and any other procedures that are reasonably necessary to effectuate this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="2">The sale, at wholesale, of any display fireworks for permitted displays by any resident manufacturer, wholesaler, dealer, or jobber, in accordance with regulations of the United States Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives if the sale is to the person holding a display permit as outlined in subsection (1) of this section. The permit holder shall present the permit along with other verifiable identification at the time of sale. </section><section prefix="3">The sale of display fireworks in accordance with a license issued by the United States Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives. </section><section prefix="4">The sale and use in emergency situations of pyrotechnic signaling devices and distress signals for marine, aviation, and highway use. </section><section prefix="5">The use of fuses and railway torpedoes by railroads. </section><section prefix="6">The sale and use of blank cartridges for use in a show or theater or for signal or ceremonial purpose in athletics or sports. </section><section prefix="7">The use of any pyrotechnic device by military organizations. </section><section prefix="8">The use of fireworks for agricultural purposes under the direct supervision of the United States Department of the Interior or any equivalent or local agency. </section><section prefix="9">Nothing in this section shall prohibit a person, firm, co-partnership, nonprofit, or corporation from offering for sale, exposing for sale, selling at retail, keeping with intent to sell, possessing or using consumer fireworks as defined in KRS 227.702 and as permitted pursuant to KRS 227.715. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 66, sec. 6, effective March 16,. 2011. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 425, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 70, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 335, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. - Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 436, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 49, sec. 16, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> March 16, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39506</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>