<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="605" order_by="605">ADMINISTRATIVE MATTERS </unit></structure><section_number>605.030</section_number><catch_line>Duties of court-designated workers.   </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A court-designated worker may: <section prefix="a">Receive complaints; </section><section prefix="b">Review complaints taken by peace officers; </section><section prefix="c">Investigate complaints except neglect, abuse, and dependency; </section><section prefix="d">Perform an initial screening for human trafficking as defined in KRS 529.010 for referral to the cabinet for investigation as a case of dependency, neglect, or abuse; </section><section prefix="e">Dispose of complaints limited to a total of three (3) status or nonfelony public offense complaints per child and, with written approval of the county attorney, one (1) felony complaint that does not involve the commission of a sexual offense or the use of a deadly weapon; </section><section prefix="f">Administer oaths; </section><section prefix="g">Issue summonses; </section><section prefix="h">Issue subpoenas; </section><section prefix="i">Make advisory dispositional recommendations and provide, within forty-eight (48) hours, exclusive of weekends and holidays, information concerning a child who has chosen to waive the investigation pursuant to KRS 610.100; </section><section prefix="j">Perform such duties as required by KRS Chapter 645; </section><section prefix="k">Administer evidence-based screenings and assessments to identify the risk and needs of a child and his or her family; </section><section prefix="l">Enter into diversion agreements, including referral to programs or service providers, providing case management and service coordination, assisting with barriers to completion, and monitoring progress; </section><section prefix="m">Impose graduated sanctions, from least restrictive to most restrictive, in response to violations of the terms of a diversion agreement; </section><section prefix="n">Gather information necessary to track and record outcomes of all diversion agreement recommendations and final diversion disposition; </section><section prefix="o">Collaborate and cooperate with the family accountability, intervention, and response team, director of pupil personnel as appropriate, and service providers to ensure all appropriate interventions are utilized; </section><section prefix="p">Report annually to his or her local public school districts and to the Administrative Office of the Courts an inventory of all programs and service providers within the judicial district they serve; </section><section prefix="q">Request from the schools a student's education records pursuant to KRS 17.125; and </section><section prefix="r">Perform such other functions related to activities of children as may be authorized or directed by the court. </section></section><section prefix="2">Upon the filing of a petition which initiates a formal court action in the interest of the child, the court-designated worker's involvement, with the exception of the activities defined in subsection (1)(i) of this section, shall cease. </section><section prefix="3">When a child is to be tried as an adult, the court-designated worker need not make dispositional recommendations. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 28, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 25, sec. 5, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 358, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1997. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 2, effective April 10, 1988. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 423, sec. 6, effective July 1, 1987. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/96).  Under 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 358, sec. 67(1), the amendment of this statute by Section 11 of that Act becomes effective July 15, 1997. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43501</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>