<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.970</section_number><catch_line>Police officers -- Use of vehicles.   </catch_line><order_by>970</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Vehicles used for emergency purposes by the police department of a public institution of postsecondary education shall be considered as emergency vehicles and shall be equipped with blue lights and sirens and shall be operated in conformance with the requirements of KRS Chapter 189. </section><section prefix="2">Police officers directly employed by the governing board of public institutions of postsecondary education pursuant to KRS 164.950 to 164.980 shall have the rights accorded to peace officers provided under KRS 527.020, provided the governing board of the public institution of postsecondary education so authorizes in writing. </section><section prefix="3">Police departments of public institutions of postsecondary education may install, maintain, and operate radio systems on police or other radio frequencies under licenses issued by the Federal Communications Commission, or its successor, KRS 432.570 to the contrary notwithstanding. </section><section prefix="4">Police departments of public institutions of postsecondary education shall comply with the requirements of the Kentucky Revised Statutes and the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet with regard to reporting of criminal and other statistics. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 230, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 6, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 173, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 367, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43815</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>