<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="117" order_by="117">REGULATION OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>117.235</section_number><catch_line>Persons permitted in voting room -- Prohibited activities -- Exit polls permitted -- Maintenance of order -- Mock elections for school children. </catch_line><order_by>235</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person, other than the election officers, challengers, person assisting voters in accordance with KRS 117.255(3), and a minor child in the company of a voter, shall be permitted within the voting room while the vote is being polled, except as follows: <section prefix="a">For the purpose of voting; </section><section prefix="b">By authority of the election officers to keep order and enforce the law; </section><section prefix="c">With the express approval of the county board of elections to repair or replace voting equipment that is malfunctioning and to provide additional voting equipment; or </section><section prefix="d">At the voter's discretion, a minor child in the company of a voter may accompany the voter into a voting booth or other private area provided for casting a vote. </section></section><section prefix="2">No officer of election shall do any electioneering on election day. </section><section prefix="3">No person shall electioneer at the polling place on the day of any election, as established in KRS 118.025, within a distance of three hundred (300) feet of any entrance to a building in which a voting machine is located if that entrance is unlocked and is used by voters on election day, unless the fiscal court or legislative body of an urban-county, charter county, or consolidated local government, on a countywide basis, specifically prohibits electioneering on the day of any election by ordinance for a distance greater than three hundred (300) feet from the polling place. No person shall electioneer within the interior of a building or affix any electioneering materials to the exterior or interior of a building where the county clerk's office is located, or any building designated by the county board of elections and approved by the State Board of Elections for absentee voting, during the hours absentee voting is being conducted in the building by the county clerk pursuant to KRS 117.085(1)(c). Electioneering shall include the displaying of signs, the distribution of campaign literature, cards, or handbills, the soliciting of signatures to any petition, or the solicitation of votes for or against any bona fide candidate or ballot question in a manner which expressly advocates the election or defeat of the candidate or expressly advocates the passage or defeat of the ballot question, but shall not include exit polling or other exceptions established by the State Board of Elections through the promulgation of administrative regulations. </section><section prefix="4">No voter shall be permitted to converse with others while in any room in which voting, including absentee voting, is conducted concerning their support or nonsupport of any candidate, party, or issue to be voted on, except as provided in KRS 117.255. </section><section prefix="5">Any precinct election officer, county clerk, deputy county clerk, or any law enforcement official may enforce the election laws and maintain law and order at the polls and within three hundred (300) feet of any entrance to the building in which the voting machine is located if that entrance is unlocked and is used by voters. Assistance may be requested of any law enforcement officer. </section><section prefix="6">Notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (1) of this section, the State Board of Elections may establish a program designed to instill in school children a respect for the democratic principles of voting by conducting in any county a mock election for school children in conjunction with any primary, or regular or special election. The State Board of Elections shall promulgate administrative regulations regarding the mock elections to insure that the regular voting process will not be impaired. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 107, sec. 3, effective March 30, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 176, sec. 1, effective March 31, 2005. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 49, sec. 1, effective March 12, 1996; and ch. 195, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 394, sec. 16, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 296, sec. 22, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 27, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 341, sec. 30, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 470, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 394, sec. 14, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 224, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978; and ch. 318, sec. 4, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 37, effective June 21, 1974. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27408</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>