<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="323" order_by="323">ARCHITECTS </unit></structure><section_number>323.404</section_number><catch_line>Construction of KRS 323.400 to 323.416 and 323.992. </catch_line><order_by>404</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The provisions of KRS 323.400 to 323.416 and 323.992 shall not apply to persons licensed under any other provisions of the Kentucky Revised Statutes, including but not limited to architects, landscape architects, professional engineers, and land surveyors, or students within accredited training programs of these professions. Nothing in KRS 323.400 to 323.416 or 323.992 shall be construed to limit, interfere, or restrict the practice, descriptions of services, or manner in which these persons practice. </section><section prefix="2">Nothing in KRS 323.400 to 323.416 or 323.992 shall be construed to prohibit or interfere with the ability of a licensed architect, landscape architect, professional engineer, or land surveyor to perform those activities that are associated with their practices, respectively, as provided under any provisions of the Kentucky Revised Statutes. </section><section prefix="3">Nothing in KRS 323.400 to 323.416 or 323.992 shall be construed to prohibit or interfere with the rendering of interior design services by students enrolled in a school approved by the board, if the students only perform services in accordance with a course of instruction or an assignment from an instructor. </section><section prefix="4">Nothing in KRS 323.400 to 323.416 or 323.992 shall be construed to prohibit any architect licensed under the provisions of KRS Chapter 323 from using the title "certified interior designer." </section><section prefix="5">Nothing in KRS 323.400 to 323.416 or 323.992 shall be construed to limit, interfere, or restrict the manner in which home builders, home designers, retailers of consumer products or their employees, certified kitchen designers, certified bath designers, or certified master kitchen and bath designers offer or provide their services. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 55, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31512</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>