<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="277" order_by="277">RAILROADS -- ORGANIZATION AND OPERATING REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>277.190</section_number><catch_line>Bell to be rung or whistle sounded at crossings -- Local government regulation of sounding train whistles at night. </catch_line><order_by>190</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every railroad company shall provide each locomotive engine running over any of its lines with a bell of ordinary size and a whistle. The bell shall be rung or the whistle sounded at a distance of at least fifty (50) rods from the place where the track crosses upon the same level any highway or crossing where a signboard is required to be maintained. The bell shall be rung or the whistle sounded continuously or alternately until the engine has reached the highway or crossing except as provided in subsection (2) of this section. </section><section prefix="2">A city, county, urban-county, or charter county government may regulate the sounding of train whistles at night if the city, county, urban-county, or charter county government enacts an ordinance adopting the provisions of Emergency Order Number 15, Notice Number 4, issued by the Federal Railroad Administration on August 31, 1993. If the Federal Railroad Administration updates the requirements of Emergency Order 15, a city, county, urban-county, or charter county government that has adopted the provisions of Emergency Order 15 shall by ordinance adopt the most recent federal requirements governing the sounding of train whistles. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 195, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 229, sec. 5, effective July 14, 1992. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 786. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14009</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>