<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.1925</section_number><catch_line>Who may make anatomical gift of decedent's body or part. </catch_line><order_by>1925</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Subject to subsections (2) and (3) of this section and unless barred by KRS 311.1921 or 311.1923, an anatomical gift of a decedent's body or part for purpose of transplantation, therapy, research, or education may be made by any member of the following classes of persons who is reasonably available, in the order of priority listed: <section prefix="a">An agent of the decedent at the time of death who could have made an anatomical gift under KRS 311.1915(2) immediately before the decedent's death; </section><section prefix="b">The spouse of the decedent; </section><section prefix="c">Adult children of the decedent; </section><section prefix="d">Parents of the decedent; </section><section prefix="e">Adult siblings of the decedent; </section><section prefix="f">Adult grandchildren of the decedent; </section><section prefix="g">Grandparents of the decedent; and </section><section prefix="h">The persons who were acting as the guardians of the person of the decedent at the time of death. </section></section><section prefix="2">If there is more than one (1) member of a class listed in subsection (1)(a), (c), (d), (e), (f), (g), or (h) of this section entitled to make an anatomical gift, an anatomical gift may be made by a member of the class unless that member or a person to which the gift may pass under KRS 311.1929 knows of an objection by another member of the class. If an objection is known, the gift may be made only by a majority of the members of the class who are reasonably available. </section><section prefix="3">A person may not make an anatomical gift if, at the time of the decedent's death, a person in a prior class under subsection (1) of this section is reasonably available to make or to object to the making of an anatomical gift. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 161, sec. 8, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30434</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>