<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="138" order_by="138">EXCISE TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>138.810</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 138.820 to 138.860. </catch_line><order_by>810</order_by><text>As used in KRS 138.820 to 138.860: <section prefix="1">"Contaminated waste materials" means those materials, in solid, liquid or gaseous form, which are transported or buried with radioactive wastes; </section><section prefix="2">"Department" means the Department of Revenue; </section><section prefix="3">"Person" includes every natural person, fiduciary, association, state or political subdivision, or corporation; </section><section prefix="4">"Processor" means any person receiving delivery or any person having an interest or right of occupancy or use in real property or improvements or any person owning, operating or maintaining a radioactive waste disposal site or facility of contaminated waste materials or radioactive waste materials for processing, packaging, storage, disposal, burial or other disposition; </section><section prefix="5">"Radioactive waste disposal site or facility" means any installation constructed, used or placed in operation primarily for disposing of contaminated waste materials or radioactive wastes; </section><section prefix="6">"Radioactive wastes" means any and all material which is radioactive or is contaminated by or with radioactive material including but not limited to any structures used in containing such radioactive wastes; and </section><section prefix="7">"Radioactive material" means any material, solid, liquid or gas, which emits radiation spontaneously. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 394, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 331, sec. 25, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 376, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:02</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28815</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>