<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IV" order_by="4">JUDICIAL BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="27" order_by="27">A JUDICIAL SUPPORT AGENCIES AND PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>27A.092</section_number><catch_line>Administrative Office of the Courts to provide Department of Kentucky State Police with information on applicants for and holders of concealed deadly weapon license. </catch_line><order_by>092</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Administrative Office of the Courts shall support the responsibilities of the Department of Kentucky State Police in the administration of KRS 237.110 by providing information: <section prefix="a">Possessed by the courts with regard to the suitability of an applicant for a license under KRS 237.110; and </section><section prefix="b">Possessed by the courts which may result in the revocation or suspension of a license issued pursuant to KRS 237.110. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Administrative Office of the Courts shall transmit information regarding a licensee which may result in the revocation or suspension of a license issued pursuant to KRS 237.110 as soon as practicable. </section><section prefix="3">The Administrative Office of the Courts shall not conduct a National Instant Criminal Background Check System (NICS) check for the Department of Kentucky State Police. </section><section prefix="4">For purposes of conducting the continual background check on licensees pursuant to KRS 237.110, the Department of Kentucky State Police may provide a list of licensees to the Administrative Office of the Courts. The list of persons holding a license pursuant to KRS 237.110 shall be held confidential by the Administrative Office of the Courts and shall be used only for purposes specified in this section and KRS 237.110. Information regarding licensees or applicants for a license shall be transmitted only to the Department of Kentucky State Police and shall not be distributed to any other person or organization within or without the Administrative Office of the Courts or the Court of Justice. The provisions of this section shall not be construed to prohibit or limit the distribution of information to or about any person which is authorized to be distributed by law, but the fact that the person is an applicant for or holds a license pursuant to KRS 237.110 shall not be distributed. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 112, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 240, sec. 12, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20941</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>