<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="353" order_by="353">MINERAL CONSERVATION AND DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>353.802</section_number><catch_line>Legislative findings and declarations relating to geologic storage of carbon dioxide. </catch_line><order_by>802</order_by><text>The General Assembly finds and declares that: <section prefix="1">The geologic storage of carbon dioxide will benefit the environment and the citizens of the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="2">It is vital that long-term geologic storage of carbon dioxide in the Commonwealth be accomplished without disturbance of surface, mineral, or water resources and that public safety is ensured; </section><section prefix="3">Carbon dioxide has current and potential value and its geologic storage may allow for its orderly withdrawal as necessary for commercial, industrial, or other uses, including for enhanced oil and gas recovery; </section><section prefix="4">Development and deployment of carbon capture and storage technology in the Commonwealth will allow industries to utilize diverse fuel sources, create jobs, contribute to state and local tax bases, and enable Kentucky industries to remain competitive in the global economy; and </section><section prefix="5">Attracting demonstration or pilot scale projects that incorporate carbon storage or projects that integrate carbon capture and storage is an economic development priority that will create jobs for Kentuckians and favorably position the Commonwealth for future leadership and growth in the field of carbon storage. </section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 2, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39643</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>