<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="98" order_by="98">HEALTH AND WELFARE IN CITIES OF THE FIRST CLASS AND IN COUNTIES CONTAINING SUCH CITIES </unit></structure><section_number>98.100</section_number><catch_line>Duties of commission -- Procedure in adopting plan. </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commission shall examine methods of constructing, equipping and furnishing buildings or improvements of the type contemplated so as to determine the plan that will best answer the needs of the city, taking into consideration its probable growth.  </section><section prefix="2">When the commission has decided upon a general plan for the construction and furnishing of the buildings or for making the improvements, it shall report the plan, with such alternative plans as it deems expedient, to the mayor, giving a description of the general plan and the probable cost of carrying out each plan. The mayor shall submit this report to the legislative body of the city and the plan recommended by the commission shall be adopted and carried out, unless the plan is rejected and disapproved by a two-thirds (2/3) vote of the legislative body within thirty (30) days from the time it is received by the legislative body. If the plan is rejected by the legislative body, then at any time within thirty (30) days thereafter one (1) of the alternative plans may be considered by the legislative body and of these plans the one (1) shall finally be adopted that is approved by a two-thirds (2/3) vote of the legislative body. If none of the plans receives the necessary two-thirds (2/3) vote within thirty (30) days after the one (1) recommended by the commission has been rejected, the commission, with the approval of the mayor, may choose a plan and carry it out. The legislative body shall have no power to vary any plan presented by the commission, but in adopting one (1) of those reported must adopt it in its entirety.  </section></text><history>Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 3037e-6. </history><metadata><effective>October 1, 1942</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:08</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26471</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>