<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="184" order_by="184">PUBLIC ROAD DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>184.060</section_number><catch_line>Appointment of board of directors -- Qualifications -- Term -- Vacancies -- Removal of member. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In the event that a road district is created pursuant to KRS 65.810 and 184.020, the county judge/executive shall appoint, with the approval of the fiscal court, three (3) persons as members of the road district board of directors, whose duty it shall be to control and manage the affairs of the district. Each director shall be at least twenty-five (25) years of age, shall be an owner of land abutting upon the road to be improved and shall have lived on such land for a period of at least six (6) months prior to his appointment. The members of the first board of directors shall hold their offices, respectively, for two (2), three (3) and four (4) years from the date of their appointment, and thereafter each director shall be appointed for a term of four (4) years. Vacancies resulting from any cause other than expiration of a term of office shall be filled by the county judge/executive and only for the unexpired term.  </section><section prefix="2">A member of the board of directors may be removed from office as provided by KRS 65.007. </section></text><history>Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 64, sec. 16, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 19, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 325, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) ch. 14, sec. 173, effective January 2,  1978. -- Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 6. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5886</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>