<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="83" order_by="83">A ORGANIZATION OF GOVERNMENT IN CITIES </unit></structure><section_number>83A.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Board" means the board of commissioners in any city organized and governed under the city manager plan. </section><section prefix="2">"Code of ordinances" means a reenactment of the body of positive municipal law, read and interpreted as a whole, with the text arranged by subject matter and properly indexed. </section><section prefix="3">"Commission" means the city commission in any city organized and governed under the commission plan. </section><section prefix="4">"Composite index" means a loose-leaf compilation of all ordinances listed by date of passage, arranged by subject matter of the contents and indexed alphabetically. </section><section prefix="5">"Council" means the city legislative body in any city organized and governed under the mayor-council plan. </section><section prefix="6">"Executive authority" means the mayor in any city organized and governed under the mayor-council plan or the mayor-alderman plan as provided in KRS Chapter 83, the commission in any city organized and governed under the commission plan, or the board of commissioners in any city organized under the city manager plan. </section><section prefix="7">"Executive order" means an order issued by the executive authority of a municipality which is binding upon the officers and employees of the municipality and any governmental agency over which the municipality has jurisdiction. </section><section prefix="8">"Legislative body member" means a city councilman in any city organized and governed under the mayor-council plan, a city commissioner in any city organized and governed under the commission plan, or city manager plan, or a city alderman in any city of the first class organized under the mayor-alderman plan provided by KRS Chapter 83. </section><section prefix="9">"Municipal order" means an official act of the legislative body of a municipality which is binding upon the officers and employees of the municipality and any governmental agency over which the municipality has jurisdiction. </section><section prefix="10">"Officer" means any person elected to a position by the voters or any person appointed to a position which (a) is created by the Constitution, the General Assembly, or a city; (b) possesses a delegation of a portion of the sovereign power of government; (c) has powers and duties to be discharged which are conferred directly or by implication by the city; (d) has duties performed independently and without control of a superior power other than law; (e) has some permanency; (f) requires an official oath; (g) is assigned by a commission or other written authority; and (h) provides for an official bond if required by proper authority. </section><section prefix="11">"Ordinance" means an official action of a city legislative body, which is a regulation of a general and permanent nature and enforceable as a local law or is an appropriation of money. </section><section prefix="12">"Summary" means a brief narrative prepared under the supervision of an attorney succinctly covering the main points of an official statement, ordinance, or rule in a way reasonably calculated to inform the public in a clear and understandable manner as to its meaning. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 435, sec. 5, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 235, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:11</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=25162</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>