<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="342" order_by="342">WORKERS' COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>342.382</section_number><catch_line>Report of workers' compensation experience. </catch_line><order_by>382</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any insurer authorized to write a policy of workers' compensation insurance shall transmit the following information on its workers' compensation experience only to the Department of Workers' Claims and the Workers' Compensation Advisory Council each year, and that information shall be certified and reported on a net basis with respect to reinsurance for nationwide experience and direct basis with respect to Kentucky experience: <section prefix="a">Direct premiums written; </section><section prefix="b">Direct premiums earned; </section><section prefix="c">Dividends paid or credited to policyholders; </section><section prefix="d">Losses paid; </section><section prefix="e">Allocated loss adjustment expenses; </section><section prefix="f">The ratio of allocated loss adjustment expenses to losses paid; </section><section prefix="g">Unallocated loss adjustment expenses; </section><section prefix="h">The ratio of unallocated loss adjustment expenses to losses paid; </section><section prefix="i">The total of losses paid and unallocated and allocated loss adjustment expenses; </section><section prefix="j">The ratio of losses paid and unallocated and allocated loss adjustment expenses to premiums earned; </section><section prefix="k">The number of claims outstanding as of December 31 of each year; </section><section prefix="l">The total amount of losses unpaid as of December 31 of each year; </section><section prefix="m">The total amount of allocated and unallocated loss adjustment expenses unpaid as of December 31 of each year; </section><section prefix="n">The total of losses paid and allocated loss adjustment expenses and unallocated loss adjustment expenses, plus the total of losses unpaid as of December 31 of each year and loss adjustment expenses unpaid as of December 31 of each year; and </section><section prefix="o">Net investment gain or loss. </section></section><section prefix="2">The first report of the information required in subsection (1) of this section shall include the information for the year ending December 31, 1987. Such report shall be filed no later than August 1, 1988. Beginning with the report for the period ending December 31, 1989, all future reports shall have all information required by subsection (1) of this section broken down by year for the current and two (2) preceding years. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1828, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 181, Part 15, sec. 86, effective April 4, 1994. -- Created 1987 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 61(9), (10), effective October 26, 1987. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32492</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>