<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.9115</section_number><catch_line>Certification as radon laboratory -- Renewal of certification -- Fees -- Requirements for radon laboratory. </catch_line><order_by>9115</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet shall issue a certification as a radon laboratory to any person or entity that: <section prefix="a">Submits a complete and accurate application for certification on a form prescribed by the cabinet through promulgation of an administrative regulation that includes the name of at least one (1) measurement contractor who is responsible for analytical activities; </section><section prefix="b">Pays the certification fee as established by the cabinet through promulgation of an administrative regulation within the following restrictions: <section prefix="1">An initial certification fee shall not exceed two hundred fifty dollars ($250); </section><section prefix="2">An annual renewal fee shall not exceed two hundred fifty dollars ($250); </section><section prefix="3">A duplicate certificate fee shall not exceed twenty dollars ($20); and </section><section prefix="4">A late renewal fee shall not exceed one hundred dollars ($100); </section></section><section prefix="c">Submits a quality control program plan that meets the minimum standard operating procedures requirements established by the cabinet through promulgation of an administrative regulation; </section><section prefix="d">Utilizes only cabinet-approved measurement devices and analytical services, and submits a description of each type of measurement device and analytical service utilized; and </section><section prefix="e">Provides documentation of enrollment and good standing within a cabinet-approved independent laboratory accreditation program for each type of measurement device and analytical service utilized. </section></section><section prefix="2">A radon laboratory shall: <section prefix="a">Employ as a staff member at least one (1) measurement contractor who shall direct the analytical activities of the laboratory; </section><section prefix="b">Ensure all laboratory analysis activities are conducted in accordance with the minimum standard operating procedures requirements established by the cabinet through promulgation of an administrative regulation for each type of measurement device and analytical service utilized; and </section><section prefix="c">Ensure all radon laboratory analyses are conducted in compliance with applicable state and federal regulations. </section></section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 74, sec. 8, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39803</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>