<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="280" order_by="280">PRIVATE TOLL BRIDGES AND FERRIES </unit></structure><section_number>280.990</section_number><catch_line>Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>990</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person who violates any of the provisions of subsection (3) of KRS 280.250 or any of the provisions of KRS 280.260 shall, for the first offense, forfeit twenty-five dollars ($25) to the person aggrieved, and shall, for every subsequent offense, forfeit one hundred dollars ($100) to the person aggrieved, but the person aggrieved shall not recover the forfeiture after a prosecution has been instituted under subsection (2) of this section. The forfeiture may be recovered by the person aggrieved by ordinary action in any court having jurisdiction to render judgment for the sum claimed to be forfeited, and the judgment may be enforced by execution against the property or against the person, at the election of the plaintiff. </section><section prefix="2">Any person who violates any of the provisions of subsection (3) of KRS 280.250 or any of the provisions of KRS 280.260 shall be liable to a fine of fifty dollars ($50) for the first offense and one hundred dollars ($100) for each subsequent offense, but no conviction shall be had under this subsection in any case where the person aggrieved has sued for and recovered the forfeiture prescribed in subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="3">Any person who violates any of the provisions of KRS 280.270 shall be fined twenty dollars ($20) for each day that the violation continues. </section><section prefix="4">Any person who violates any of the provisions of KRS 280.280 shall be fined not less than five dollars ($5) nor more than ten dollars ($10) for each day that the violation continues. </section></text><history>Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 7, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 266, effective January 2, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. IV, sec. 20(1). -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 850, 852, 1342a-3, 1809a, 1814, 1815, 1816, 1818, 1819, 1820, 1821a-2, 4356za-17, 4356za-23. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14271</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>