<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="I" order_by="1">SOVEREIGNTY AND JURISDICTION OF THE COMMONWEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="3" order_by="3">GRANTS TO UNITED STATES OF LANDS AND RIGHTS TO ACQUIRE </unit></structure><section_number>3.265</section_number><catch_line>Limitation of jurisdiction ceded. </catch_line><order_by>265</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The powers conferred by KRS 3.255 to 3.275 are solely to enable the Commonwealth and the United States to exercise concurrent legislative jurisdiction for purposes of criminal law enforcement over United States Department of the Interior National Park System lands in Kentucky. No other legislative jurisdiction is ceded by KRS 3.255 to 3.275, and there are specifically reserved over any lands as to which any legislative jurisdiction may be ceded pursuant to KRS 3.255 to 3.275: <section prefix="a">The entire legislative jurisdiction with respect to taxation of the Commonwealth, and of each state agency, county, urban-county government, city, special district and other political subdivision; </section><section prefix="b">The entire legislative jurisdiction of the Commonwealth with respect to marriage, divorce, annulment, adoption, the commitment or other civil disposition of the mentally incompetent, and the descent and distribution of property; and </section><section prefix="c">The power to execute any process, civil or criminal, issued under the authority of the Commonwealth. </section></section><section prefix="2">No person residing upon such lands shall be deprived of any civil or political rights by reason of the cession of such legislative jurisdiction to the United States. </section></text><history>Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 68, sec. 4, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978 </effective><note>  1980 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 43 would have amended this section effective July 1, 1982. However, 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 396 was repealed by 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 146, also effective July 1, 1982. </note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=97</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>