<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="138" order_by="138">EXCISE TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>138.502</section_number><catch_line>Prohibition on the sale, delivery, provision, or use of untaxed or dyed diesel fuel -- Exceptions -- Civil penalty. </catch_line><order_by>502</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person shall not sell or deliver untaxed diesel fuel or dyed diesel fuel when the person knows or has reason to know that the fuel will be used in a motor vehicle on any public highway. </section><section prefix="2">A person shall not introduce untaxed diesel fuel or dyed diesel fuel into the supply tank of any motor vehicle licensed for highway use. </section><section prefix="3">A person shall not use untaxed diesel fuel or dyed diesel fuel in any motor vehicle actually used on a public highway. </section><section prefix="4">The prohibitions contained in this section shall not apply to: <section prefix="a">Persons operating motor vehicles that have received fuel into the fuel tank outside this state in a jurisdiction that permits introduction of untaxed diesel fuel or dyed diesel fuel into the fuel supply tank of highway vehicles; and </section><section prefix="b">Uses of untaxed fuel or dyed diesel fuel on the highway which are lawful under the Internal Revenue Code and regulations, including state and local government vehicles, and buses, unless otherwise prohibited by this chapter. </section></section><section prefix="5">The department may assess a civil penalty as follows: <section prefix="a">For first offenses, one thousand dollars ($1,000) or ten dollars ($10) per gallon of untaxed fuel or dyed diesel fuel involved, whichever is greater, against any person who violates this section. The capacity of the fuel tank shall be assumed to be the amount of fuel involved, unless a lesser amount can be adequately verified by the violator; and </section><section prefix="b">For subsequent offenses, the penalty shall be the amount determined in paragraph (a) of this subsection, multiplied by the number of separate violations by the violator. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 390, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 267, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 397, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:02</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28761</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>