<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="194" order_by="194">A CABINET FOR HEALTH AND FAMILY SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>194A.050</section_number><catch_line>Execution of policies, plans, and programs -- Administrative regulations -- Fees. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The secretary shall formulate, promote, establish, and execute policies, plans, and programs and shall adopt, administer, and enforce throughout the Commonwealth all applicable state laws and all administrative regulations necessary under applicable state laws to protect, develop, and maintain the health, personal dignity, integrity, and sufficiency of the individual citizens of the Commonwealth and necessary to operate the programs and fulfill the responsibilities vested in the cabinet. The secretary shall promulgate, administer, and enforce those administrative regulations necessary to implement programs mandated by federal law, or to qualify for the receipt of federal funds and necessary to cooperate with other state and federal agencies for the proper administration of the cabinet and its programs. </section><section prefix="2">The secretary may utilize the Public Health Services Advisory Council to review and make recommendations on contemplated administrative regulations relating to initiatives of the Department for Public Health. No administrative regulations issued under the authority of the cabinet shall be filed with the Legislative Research Commission unless they are issued under the authority of the secretary, and the secretary shall not delegate that authority. </section><section prefix="3">The secretary may utilize the Council for Families and Children to review and make recommendations on contemplated administrative regulations relating to initiatives of the Department for Community Based Services. No administrative regulations issued under the authority of the cabinet shall be filed with the Legislative Research Commission unless issued under the authority of the secretary, and the secretary shall not delegate this authority. </section><section prefix="4">Except as otherwise provided by law, the secretary shall have authority to establish by administrative regulation a schedule of reasonable fees, none of which shall exceed one hundred dollars ($100), to cover the costs of annual inspections of efforts regarding compliance with program standards administered by the cabinet. All fees collected for inspections shall be deposited in the State Treasury and credited to a revolving fund account to be used for administration of those programs of the cabinet. The balance of the account shall lapse to the general fund at the end of each biennium. Fees shall not be charged for investigation of complaints. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 26, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 25, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6638</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>