<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIX" order_by="39">PROVISIONAL REMEDIES, ENFORCEMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="426" order_by="426">ENFORCEMENT OF JUDGMENTS </unit></structure><section_number>426.530</section_number><catch_line>Right of redemption -- Manner of redeeming -- Purchaser to receive writ of possession and deed. </catch_line><order_by>530</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If real property sold in pursuance of a judgment or order of a court, other than an execution, does not bring two-thirds (2/3) of its appraised value, the defendant and his or her representatives may redeem it within six (6) months from the day of sale, by paying the original purchase money and ten percent (10%) per annum interest thereon, and any reasonable costs incurred by the purchaser after the sale for maintenance or repair of the property, including but not limited to utility expenses, insurance, association fees, taxes, and the costs to conform the property to the minimum standards of: <section prefix="a">The local nuisance code as defined in KRS 82.700; and </section><section prefix="b">Local ordinances as defined in KRS 65.8805. </section></section><section prefix="2">The defendant shall pay the redemption money to the clerk of the court in which the judgment was rendered or the order of sale was made. Upon payment by the defendant, the master commissioner shall convey the real property to the defendant. </section><section prefix="3">When the right of redemption exists, the purchaser shall receive an immediate writ of possession and a deed containing a lien in favor of the defendant, reflecting the defendant's right to redeem during the statutory period. </section></text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 107, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 216, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2364. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 2014</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43433</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>