<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.625</section_number><catch_line>Regulations, authority, and duty of director of extension -- Extension council, membership, bylaws. </catch_line><order_by>625</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The director of extension is hereby authorized to promulgate regulations relating to the establishment of and continuation of extension councils. Said regulations may apply to a specific county. </section><section prefix="2">An extension council shall be established for each extension district. Each extension council shall be organized under regulations approved by the director of extension and shall be comprised of not less than fifteen (15) citizens nor more than forty (40) citizens of the county in which the extension district is located, subject to the provisions of subsection (2) of KRS 164.635. All members of the extension council shall be appointed by the county groups and organizations of the county whose major interest is in agriculture and home economics such as farm bureaus, homemaker councils, 4-H Club councils and various commodity groups but is not necessarily limited to those mentioned. In event of question the eligibility of a group to appoint to the extension council shall be determined by the director of extension. The number of members of each extension council shall be determined by the size of the county, the diversity of agricultural interests of the county, and other like factors and shall be according to regulations mentioned in subsection (1) of this section. Each extension council shall adopt a set of bylaws providing for its operation and terms of membership according to the same regulations. </section><section prefix="3">All regulations issued under the provisions of this section shall be filed in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A. Immediately after filing, the director of extension shall cause the text of every regulation to be published pursuant to KRS Chapter 424. The director of extension shall also mail two (2) copies of every regulation to the county clerk of the county in which the regulation is applicable, one (1) copy of which shall be posted on the courthouse door or bulletin board. Additional distribution may be made at the discretion of the director of extension. </section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 294, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 149. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 275, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4367</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>