<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="213" order_by="213">VITAL STATISTICS </unit></structure><section_number>213.161</section_number><catch_line>Sudden Infant Death Syndrome Program. </catch_line><order_by>161</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In order to obtain information which may be useful to research organizations studying the causes and incidence of the sudden infant death syndrome, a program is hereby established in the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. The purpose of this program shall be to obtain factual information concerning the characteristics, incidence, and distribution of the sudden infant death syndrome throughout the Commonwealth and to provide a means of public education concerning any research findings which may lead to the possible means of prevention, early identification, and treatment of children susceptible to the sudden infant death syndrome. </section><section prefix="2">In instances where an ostensibly healthy child dies suddenly and unexpectedly with no known or apparent cause as determined by a physician or a coroner, an autopsy with the written approval of the parents or legal guardian of the child shall be performed within forty-eight (48) hours and the results reported to the cabinet and to the parents or legal guardian of the child. </section><section prefix="3">In order to implement the provisions of this section, the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall: <section prefix="a">Promulgate administrative regulations as may be necessary in order to obtain in proper form all information relating to the occurrence of sudden infant deaths which is relevant and appropriate for the establishment of a reliable statistical index of the incidence, distribution, and characteristics of cases of the sudden infant death syndrome; </section><section prefix="b">Collect such factual information from physicians, coroners, medical examiners, hospitals, and public health officials who have examined any child known or believed to have the sudden infant death syndrome; </section><section prefix="c">Make such factual information available to physicians, coroners, medical examiners, hospitals, public health officials, and educational and institutional organizations conducting research as to the causes and incidence of the sudden infant death syndrome; </section><section prefix="d">Cause appropriate counseling services to be established and maintained for families affected by the occurrence of the sudden infant death syndrome; and </section><section prefix="e">Conduct educational programs to inform the general public of any research findings of educational and institutional organizations which may lead to the possible means of prevention, early identification, and treatment of the sudden infant death syndrome. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 444, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 392, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 369, sec. 32, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8756</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>