<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171">STATE LIBRARIES -- LIBRARIANS -- STATE ARCHIVES AND RECORDS </unit></structure><section_number>171.751</section_number><catch_line>Duties of Kentucky Capitol Centennial Commission. </catch_line><order_by>751</order_by><text>The Kentucky Capitol Centennial Commission shall: <section prefix="1">Study and recommend activities that may be conducted throughout the Commonwealth to celebrate the one hundredth anniversary of Kentucky's Capitol; </section><section prefix="2">Educate Kentucky's citizens and the nation about Kentucky's Capitol; </section><section prefix="3">Assist area development districts, local governments, school systems, businesses, organizations, and individuals with planning and preparation of events and projects to educate Kentuckians in all regions of the state about the significance of Kentucky's Capitol; </section><section prefix="4">Serve as the coordinating point for information about the various state, regional, and local activities occurring in Kentucky to celebrate the Capitol's centennial anniversary; </section><section prefix="5">Plan and implement the Capitol's centennial anniversary celebration; </section><section prefix="6">Recommend temporary or permanent improvements to the Capitol grounds to make them more amenable to activities associated with the centennial anniversary; </section><section prefix="7">Perform other duties necessary to highlight the role of Kentucky's Capitol in the Commonwealth's history and for decades to come; and </section><section prefix="8">Seek grants and philanthropic support for activities celebrating the centennial anniversary of Kentucky's Capitol. </section></text><history> Created 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 43, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2009. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4854</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>