<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="312" order_by="312">CHIROPRACTORS </unit></structure><section_number>312.115</section_number><catch_line>Examination of applicants -- Subjects tested. </catch_line><order_by>115</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Examination for a license to practice chiropractic shall be made by the board according to the method deemed by it to be the most practicable and expeditious to test the applicants' qualifications. Examination papers shall be designated by number, and not by name of applicant, so that the identity of the applicant will not be disclosed to members of the board until after the examination papers are graded. </section><section prefix="2">The examination shall consist of a written test including questions of essay or objective type designed to measure the applicants' knowledge of the subjects of anatomy, physiology, pathology, neurology, histology, hygiene, bacteriology, chemistry, chiropractic orthopedics, diagnosis, the use and effects of X-ray and chiropractic principles and practices as taught in chiropractic schools and colleges. The national board tests of the National Board of Chiropractic Examiners may be accepted as a part or all of the written examination. A portion of the licensing examination shall consist of a practical demonstration of clinical competency to be evaluated by the board by such methods as it may designate prior to the examination. </section></text><history>Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 359, sec. 12, effective June 19, 1976. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 179, sec. 11, effective June 14, 1962. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1988</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30783</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>