<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.9-080</section_number><catch_line>Licenses -- Renewal and reinstatement. </catch_line><order_by>9-080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each license may be renewed for the ensuing twelve (12) months period upon the timely submission of a completed renewal application and payment to the commissioner annually on or before June 20 of each year a license fee of five hundred dollars ($500) for the first location and five hundred dollars ($500) for each additional location. </section><section prefix="2">The commissioner may reinstate a license that has expired within thirty-one (31) days of the expiration of the license if the licensee pays a late fee in the amount of one hundred dollars ($100) and a reinstatement fee of five hundred dollars ($500). </section><section prefix="3">A license shall not be reinstated where the renewal application, fees, or any required information is received on or after August 1 of the year that the application was due. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 808, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 98, sec. 3, effective January 1, 2010. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 601, sec. 7, effective April 14, 1998. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 213, sec. 8, effective July 14, 1992; and ch. 341, sec. 8, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 368.080. </former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  In accordance with 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, secs. 38 and 39, this statute has been renumbered as a section of the Kentucky Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:13</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14911</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>