<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="141" order_by="141">INCOME TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>141.396</section_number><catch_line>Nonrefundable angel investor tax credit against individual income tax -- Carry forward -- Transfer of credit -- Recapture of credit. </catch_line><order_by>396</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Authority" has the same meaning as in KRS 154.20-230; </section><section prefix="b">"Qualified investor" has the same meaning as in KRS 154.20-230;  </section><section prefix="c">"Qualified small business" has the same meaning as in KRS 154.20-230; and </section><section prefix="d">"Taxpayer" means an individual subject to the tax imposed by KRS 141.020, who has either: <section prefix="1">Received a credit from the authority pursuant to KRS 154.20-236; or </section><section prefix="2">Received a credit through a valid transfer allowed under this section from a qualified investor that was originally awarded the credit. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">For taxable years beginning on or after January 1, 2015, there is hereby created the angel investor tax credit. The credit shall be nonrefundable, and shall apply against the tax imposed by KRS 141.020. The ordering of the credit shall be as provided in KRS 141.0205. </section><section prefix="3">A qualified investor may seek a credit by applying to the authority pursuant to KRS 154.20-236. </section><section prefix="4">The maximum amount of credit that may be claimed by a taxpayer in any taxable year shall not exceed fifty percent (50%) of the total amount of credit awarded or transferred to the taxpayer. </section><section prefix="5">Any amount of credit that a taxpayer is unable to utilize during a taxable year may be carried forward for use in a succeeding taxable year for a period not to exceed fifteen (15) years. Any amount of credit not used within fifteen (15) years shall be lost. No amount of credit may be carried back by any taxpayer. </section><section prefix="6">The credit shall not apply to any liability a taxpayer may have for interest, penalties, past due taxes, or any other additions to the taxpayer's tax liability. The holder of the credit shall assume any and all liabilities and responsibilities of the credit. </section><section prefix="7">A credit may be transferred by a qualified investor to any individual taxpayer. A qualified investor making a transfer shall give written notice to the department and shall provide any other information required by the department, in the manner prescribed by the department. Any transferred credit shall be subject to the original timeframes and requirements established by this section and KRS 154.20-230 to 154.20-240 as if held by the qualified investor. </section><section prefix="8">To receive the credit, a taxpayer shall claim the credit on his or her return in the manner prescribed by the department. </section><section prefix="9">The department shall recapture any portion, or the full amount, of a credit upon notification from the authority that a recapture is required pursuant to KRS 154.20-240. </section></text><history> Created 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 28, effective July 15, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:01</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43421</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>