<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="17" order_by="17">PUBLIC SAFETY </unit></structure><section_number>17.185</section_number><catch_line>Request to Department of Kentucky State Police to conduct background check on oneself through name-based or fingerprint-supported search -- Definitions for section -- Prerequisites and limitations on search and release of information -- Fees -- Administration regulations. </catch_line><order_by>185</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Fingerprint card" means the standard Federal Bureau of Investigation FD-258 fingerprint card; </section><section prefix="b">"Fingerprint-supported background check" means a statewide search of the centralized criminal history record information system created and maintained by the Commonwealth utilizing the fingerprints of the subject of the background check. This shall not include a national check by the Federal Bureau of Investigation; and </section><section prefix="c">"Name-based background check" means a statewide search of the centralized criminal history record information system created and maintained by the Commonwealth utilizing the name, date of birth, and Social Security number of the subject of the background check. This shall not include a national check by the Federal Bureau of Investigation. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any other provision of law to the contrary notwithstanding, a person may request the Department of Kentucky State Police to conduct a name-based or fingerprint-supported background check of himself or herself and release the results to any person designated by the requester. </section><section prefix="3">A person requesting a fingerprint-supported background check on himself or herself shall be fingerprinted by a law enforcement agency or other agency approved by the Department of Kentucky State Police to submit fingerprints. The fingerprinting agency shall forward the fingerprint card to the Department of Kentucky State Police. The fingerprinting agency may charge a fee, not to exceed the actual cost of processing the request. </section><section prefix="4">A request for a name-based or fingerprint-supported background check shall be submitted on forms approved by the Department of Kentucky State Police. </section><section prefix="5">The Department of Kentucky State Police may charge a fee for conducting a background check, not to exceed the actual cost of processing the request, to be paid by the requester. </section><section prefix="6">The Department of Kentucky State Police shall promulgate administrative regulations to implement the provisions of this section. </section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 60, sec. 2, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39753</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>