<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">A SPECIAL PURPOSE GOVERNMENTAL ENTITIES </unit></structure><section_number>65A.010Definitions</section_number><catch_line>for chapter.   </catch_line><order_by>010Definitions</order_by><text>As used in this chapter: <section prefix="1">"County" means any county, consolidated local government, urban-county government, unified local government, or charter county; </section><section prefix="2">"DLG" means the Department for Local Government established by KRS 147A.002; </section><section prefix="3">"Establishing entity" means the city or county, or any combination of cities and counties, that established a special purpose governmental entity and that has not subsequently withdrawn its affiliation with the special purpose governmental entity by ordinance or other official action; </section><section prefix="4">"Federally regulated municipal utility" means a municipal utility governed by the provisions of KRS 96.550 to 96.901, that maintains a wholesale power contract with a federal agency that also serves as its regulatory authority; </section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">"Fee" means any user charge, levy, assessment, fee, schedule of rates, or tax, other than an ad valorem tax, imposed by a special purpose governmental entity. </section><section prefix="b">"Fee" shall not include the following charges imposed by special purpose governmental entities that provide utility services: <section prefix="1">Any fuel cost adjustment that is: <section prefix="a">Made pursuant to an agreement with a power supplier; </section><section prefix="b">Amended by the power supplier based on the variable cost of fuel; and </section><section prefix="c">Passed through to the consumer by the utility pursuant to the agreement between the utility and the power supplier; </section></section><section prefix="2">Any power or energy cost adjustment implemented pursuant to a duly adopted base rate that provides for the periodic adjustment of a component of the rate, including any fuel costs or transmission costs, in accordance with the formula or conditions set forth in the base rate; or </section><section prefix="3">Any environmental control cost adjustments or surcharges implemented pursuant to a duly adopted base rate that provides for the periodic adjustment of a component of the rate in accordance with a formula or conditions set forth in the base rate; </section></section></section><section prefix="6"><section prefix="a">"Private entity" means any entity whose sole source of public funds is from payments pursuant to a contract with a city, county, or special purpose governmental entity, including funds received as a grant or as a result of a competitively bid procurement process. </section><section prefix="b">"Private entity" does not include any entity: <section prefix="1">Created, wholly or in part, by a city, county, or combination of cities and counties to perform one (1) or more of the types of public services listed in subsection (9)(c) of this section; or </section><section prefix="2">Governed by a board, council, commission, committee, authority, or corporation with any member or members who are appointed by the chief executive or governing body of a city, county, or combination of cities and counties, or whose voting membership includes governmental officials who serve in an ex officio capacity; </section></section></section><section prefix="7">"Public funds" means any funds derived from the levy of a tax, fee, assessment, or charge, or the issuance of bonds by the state or a city, county, or special purpose governmental entity; </section><section prefix="8">"Registry" means the online central registry and reporting portal established pursuant to KRS 65A.020; and </section><section prefix="9"><section prefix="a">"Special purpose governmental entity" or "entity" means any agency, authority, or entity created or authorized by statute which: <section prefix="1">Exercises less than statewide jurisdiction; </section><section prefix="2">Exists for the purpose of providing one (1) or a limited number of services or functions; </section><section prefix="3">Is governed by a board, council, commission, committee, authority, or corporation with policy-making authority that is separate from the state and the governing body of the city, county, or cities and counties in which it operates; and </section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">Has the independent authority to generate public funds; or </section><section prefix="b">May receive and expend public funds, grants, awards, or appropriations from the state, from any agency, or authority of the state, from a city or county, or from any other special purpose governmental entity. </section></section></section><section prefix="b">"Special purpose governmental entity" shall include entities meeting the requirements established by paragraph (a) of this subsection, whether the entity is formed as a nonprofit corporation under KRS Chapter 273, pursuant to an interlocal cooperation agreement under KRS 65.210 to 65.300, or pursuant to any other provision of the Kentucky Revised Statutes. </section><section prefix="c">Examples of the types of public services that may be provided by special purpose governmental entities include but are not limited to the following: <section prefix="1">Ambulance, emergency, and fire protection services; </section><section prefix="2">Flood control, drainage, levee, water, water conservation, watershed, and soil conservation services; </section><section prefix="3">Area planning, management, community improvement, and community development services; </section><section prefix="4">Library services; </section><section prefix="5">Public health, public mental health, and public hospital services; </section><section prefix="6">Riverport and airport services; </section><section prefix="7">Sanitation, sewer, waste management, and solid waste services; </section><section prefix="8">Industrial and economic development; </section><section prefix="9">Parks and recreation services; </section><section prefix="10">Construction, maintenance, or operation of roads and bridges; </section><section prefix="11">Mass transit services; </section><section prefix="12">Pollution control; </section><section prefix="13">Construction or provision of public housing, except as set out in paragraph (d)8. of this subsection; </section><section prefix="14">Tourism and convention services; and </section><section prefix="15">Agricultural extension services. </section></section><section prefix="d">"Special purpose governmental entity" shall not include: <section prefix="1">Cities; </section><section prefix="2">Counties; </section><section prefix="3">School districts; </section><section prefix="4">Private entities; </section><section prefix="5">Chambers of commerce; </section><section prefix="6">Any incorporated entity that: <section prefix="a">Provides utility services; </section><section prefix="b">Is member-owned; and </section><section prefix="c">Has a governing body whose voting members are all elected by the membership of the entity; </section></section><section prefix="7">Any entity whose budget, finances, and financial information are fully integrated with and included as a part of the budget, finances, and financial reporting of the city, county, or cities and counties in which it operates; or </section><section prefix="8">Federally regulated public housing authorities established pursuant to KRS Chapter 80 that receive no more than twenty percent (20%) of their total funding for any fiscal year from nonfederal fees, not including rental income. </section></section></section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 17, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 1, effective March 19, 2014. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts. ch. 124, sec. 8, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 1, effective March 21, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (3/19/2014). 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 11 provides that the amendments to this statute made in 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 1, shall apply retroactively beginning January 1, 2014. (3/21/2013). In subsection (5)(b)1. of this statute, a reference to "subsection (7)(c)" has been changed to read "subsection (8)(c)." In the Senate Committee Substitute to the bill that created this statute (2013 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 1), the former subsection (7) was renumbered as subsection (8), but an internal reference to subsection (7)(c) was not corrected. In codifying this section, the Reviser of Statutes has made this correction pursuant to KRS 7.136(1).  (3/21/2013). This statute was created in 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 1 (HB 1), and then amended in 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 8, after HB 1 had been enacted. That amendment has been incorporated into the text of this statute as created.</lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44073</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>