<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="137" order_by="137">LICENSE TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>137.170</section_number><catch_line>Tentative state license tax on race meetings. </catch_line><order_by>170</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every person engaged in the business of conducting a race meeting at which live horse races are run for stakes, purses, or prizes, under the jurisdiction of the Kentucky Horse Racing Commission, shall pay a tentative license tax to the state, as provided in subsection (2) of this section. </section><section prefix="2">Any race track for any year commencing December 1 and ending the following November 30 for the days upon which races are actually conducted for any stake, purse, or prize, shall pay a license tax based on the average daily mutuel handle for the preceding year as follows: </section>  Average Daily Mutuel Handle                           License Tax   $0 - $25,000 $       0   $25,000 - $250,000 $   175   $250,001 - $450,000 $   500   $450,001 - $700,000 $1,000   $700,001 - $800,000 $1,500   $800,001 - $900,000 $2,000   $900,001 and above $2,500 <section prefix="3">As used in subsection (2) of this section the term "daily mutuel handle" shall mean the total gross amount of money bet or wagered by a race track's patrons by means of pari-mutuel, combination, or French pools on live races conducted by the track. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 104, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 46, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 272, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 4, effective March 30, 1992. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 240, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 33, secs. 1 and 2, effective June 19, 1958. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 90, secs. 1 and 2. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 4223b-6, 4223b-7. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:02</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28635</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>