<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="500" order_by="500">GENERAL PROVISIONS </unit></structure><section_number>500.060</section_number><catch_line>Territorial applicability. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as otherwise provided in this section, a person may be convicted under the law of this state of an offense committed by his own conduct or the conduct of another for which he is legally accountable when: <section prefix="a">Either the conduct or the result which is an element of the offense occurs within this state; or </section><section prefix="b">Conduct occurring outside the state is sufficient to constitute an attempt to commit an offense within the state; or </section><section prefix="c">Conduct occurring outside the state is sufficient to constitute a conspiracy to commit an offense within the state and an overt act in furtherance of the conspiracy occurs within the state; or </section><section prefix="d">Conduct occurring within this state establishes complicity in the commission of, or an attempt, solicitation or conspiracy to commit, an offense in another jurisdiction which is also an offense under the law of this state; or </section><section prefix="e">The offense consists of the omission to perform a legal duty imposed by the law of this state regardless of where that person is when the omission occurs; or </section><section prefix="f">The offense is a violation of a statute of this state that expressly prohibits conduct outside the state. </section></section><section prefix="2">Subsection (1)(a) does not apply if causing a particular result is an element of an offense and the result is caused by conduct occurring outside the state that would not constitute an offense if the result had occurred there, unless the actor intentionally or knowingly caused the result within the state. </section><section prefix="3">When the offense is homicide, either the death of the victim or the bodily impact causing death constitutes a "result" within the meaning of subsection (1)(a). If the body of a homicide victim is found within this state, it shall be prima facie evidence that the result occurred within the state. </section></text><history>Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 6, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 1975</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:23</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19640</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>