<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="18" order_by="18">A STATE PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>18A.070</section_number><catch_line>Personnel board -- Organization -- Meeting notices required -- Records to be public. </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall annually elect one (1) of its members chairman and one (1) of its members vice chairman. </section><section prefix="2">The board shall meet at such time and place as shall be specified by call of the chairman. At least one (1) meeting shall be held each month. </section><section prefix="3">All meetings shall be open to the public as provided in KRS 61.805 to 61.850. Any head of the department or agency employing an elected member of the board or any other person shall not prohibit him from attending meetings of the board, conducting the business of the board, influence or attempt to influence any decision made by that person, discipline the individual for attending the meeting, or take any other action inimical to the interests of the employee or his family. Any person violating the provisions of this subsection shall be subject to the provisions of KRS 18A.990. </section><section prefix="4">At least seven (7) days in advance of each regular meeting, notice shall be given in writing to each member of the board by the executive director and the executive director shall post a notice in each building owned or leased by the state which houses at least five hundred (500) employees. Four (4) voting members shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business. The board shall keep records and minutes of its business and official actions. </section><section prefix="5">All records of the board shall be public records and open to public inspection as provided in KRS 61.870 to 61.884. </section></text><history>Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 278, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 448, sec. 14, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1988 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, C, 2, (2) at 628.  See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, D, 10, (1) at 636. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1354</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>