<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="150" order_by="150">FISH AND WILDLIFE RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>150.600</section_number><catch_line>Waterfowl, taking of -- Permits -- Fees -- Exemption. </catch_line><order_by>600</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commissioner, with the approval of the commission, shall have the authority to regulate the taking of waterfowl within the state and shall further have the power to establish waterfowl refuges and waterfowl shooting grounds, regulate distance of pits and shooting from refuges, either on public or private lands, where hunting or shooting is permitted; to build shooting pits or blinds and make charges for their use; and do anything else necessary to control or improve the conservation or hunting of waterfowl not contrary to federal regulations. </section><section prefix="2">It shall be unlawful for any person for commercial purposes to hold or control land and water, or land and water used or intended to be used in whole or part, or in part for the taking of migratory waterfowl, or have the privilege of taking migratory waterfowl thereon, without first having made application to the department and paying an annual permit fee that will entitle the licensee to possess blinds or pits on said lands or water in conformance with the laws and regulations as set out by the department. </section><section prefix="3">Any person holding or controlling land and water for commercial purposes used or intended to be used, in the whole or in part for the taking of migratory waterfowl, or for having the privilege of taking migratory waterfowl thereon shall make an application and pay an annual permit fee which entitles the holder thereof to build and construct blinds or pits on said land or water in conformance with the laws and regulations of this department. </section><section prefix="4">All such permits shall expire each year on the next day after the last day of the season during which it shall be lawful to take migratory waterfowl. </section><section prefix="5">The holder of such permits shall keep a daily register and kill survey as set out in the regulation. </section><section prefix="6">No person actually residing on and owning any piece of land and water, or land, or water, shall be required to secure any such permit for the privilege of hunting migratory waterfowl thereon for himself, or his immediate family, or his resident tenants and their immediate families living on the premises, but this privilege cannot be extended to anyone else and all hunting shall conform with the laws and regulations. </section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 38, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 43, sec. 1. -- Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 115, sec. 22, effective May 18, 1956. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2045</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>