<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="227" order_by="227">A ELECTRICIANS AND ELECTRICAL CONTRACTORS </unit></structure><section_number>227A.020</section_number><catch_line>Prohibitions -- Local licensing programs. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person who is not licensed as an electrical contractor shall not represent himself or herself to the public as an electrical contractor or use any terms, titles, or abbreviations which express or imply that the person is a licensed electrical contractor. </section><section prefix="2">A person who is not licensed as a master electrician shall not represent himself or herself to the public as a master electrician or use any terms, titles, or abbreviations which express or imply that the person is a licensed master electrician. </section><section prefix="3">A person who is not licensed as an electrician shall not represent himself or herself to the public as an electrician or use any terms, titles, or abbreviations which express or imply that the person is a licensed electrician. </section><section prefix="4">A person who is not licensed as an electrical contractor, electrician, or master electrician shall not engage in any activities or perform any of the duties usually performed by an electrical contractor, electrician, or master electrician unless the unlicensed person is under the direct supervision of a licensed electrician or master electrician who is present on the site where the work is being performed. </section><section prefix="5">An authorized local licensing program in existence on June 24, 2003, may contract with the department to become an agent of the department for purposes of the issuance and renewal of licenses issued pursuant to KRS 227A.010 to 227A.140. The department may also contract with local governments that want to become authorized licensing programs. </section><section prefix="6">KRS 227A.010 to 227A.140 shall supersede all ordinances or regulations regulating electricians, master electricians, and electrical contractors of any city, county, urban-county, charter county, or consolidated local government. This provision shall not affect city, county, urban-county, charter county, or consolidated local government regulations relating to zoning requirements or occupational payroll taxes pertaining to electricians, master electricians, and electrical contractors. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 430, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10719</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>