<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.210</section_number><catch_line>False statements in applications prohibited -- Possession of plates and receipts. </catch_line><order_by>210</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall make any false statement in an application for registration, application for duplicate receipt or plate, bill of sale, registration receipt, motor number or vehicle identification number. No person shall use, display or keep registration plates or registration receipts that do not belong or have not been issued to him. This subsection shall not apply to a false statement in an initial or renewal application for a military license plate issued under KRS 186.041. </section><section prefix="2">No person shall make any false statement in an initial or renewal application for a military license plate issued under KRS 186.041 or use, display, or keep military license plates that do not belong or have not been issued to him. </section><section prefix="3">The penalties established in KRS 186.990 for violations of this section shall be printed prominently on every form or blank used for these purposes and furnished by the cabinet. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 15, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 15, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 133, sec. 12, effective June 19, 1976. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 8, effective January 1, 1960. -- Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 153, sec. 6. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739g-22. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6024</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>