<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="139" order_by="139">SALES AND USE TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>139.531</section_number><catch_line>Application of taxes to horse industry. </catch_line><order_by>531</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding any other provisions of this chapter to the contrary, the taxes imposed by this chapter shall apply to: <section prefix="a">Fees paid for breeding a stallion to a mare in this state; </section><section prefix="b">Sales of horses unless exempted under the provisions of subsections (2)(a) or </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="d">of this section; and </section><section prefix="e">The boarding and training of horses within this state; and </section><section prefix="f">The temporary use of horses within this state for purposes of racing, </section></section>(c) The sales price of any horse claimed at any race meeting within this state. (2) In addition to any other exemptions provided for the horse industry in this chapter, the taxes imposed under the provisions of this chapter shall not apply to the following activities: (a) The sale or use of horses, or interests or shares in horses, provided the purchase or use is made for breeding purposes only; (b) The use of a stallion for breeding purposes by an owner or shareholder of the stallion; (c) The trading of stallion services by an owner or shareholder of the stallion; (d) The sale of horses less than two (2) years of age at the time of sale, provided the sale is made to a nonresident of Kentucky. For the purposes of this section, a nonresident means a person as defined in KRS 141.010(15) who is not a resident in this state as defined by KRS 141.010(17) or who is not commercially domiciled in this state as defined in KRS 141.120(1)(b); exhibiting, or performing. </text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 132, effective June 1, 2005. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 29. </history><metadata><effective> June 1, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28914</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>