<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="177" order_by="177">STATE AND FEDERAL HIGHWAYS -- LIMITED ACCESS FACILITIES -- TURNPIKES -- ROAD BONDS -- BILLBOARDS -- RECYCLERS </unit></structure><section_number>177.860</section_number><catch_line>Standards for billboard advertising. </catch_line><order_by>860</order_by><text>The commissioner of the Department of Highways shall prescribe by regulations reasonable standards for the advertising devices hereinafter enumerated, designed to protect the safety of and to guide the users of the highways and otherwise to achieve the objectives set forth in KRS 177.850, and the erection and maintenance of any of the following advertising devices, if they comply with the regulations, shall not be deemed a violation of KRS 177.830 to 177.890: <section prefix="1">An advertising device which is to be erected or maintained on property for the purpose of setting forth or indicating: <section prefix="a">The name and address of the owner, lessee, or occupant of the property; or </section><section prefix="b">The name or type of business or profession conducted on the property; or </section><section prefix="c">Information required or authorized by law to be posted or displayed on the advertising device; </section></section><section prefix="2">An advertising device which is not visible from any traveled portion of the highway; </section><section prefix="3">An advertising device indicating the sale or leasing of the property upon which it is placed; </section><section prefix="4">Advertising devices which otherwise comply with the applicable zoning ordinances and regulations of any county or city, and which are to be located in a commercially or industrially developed area, in which the commissioner of highways determines, in exercise of his sound discretion, that the location of the advertising devices is compatible with the safety and convenience of the traveling public. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 402, sec. 3, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 424, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 175, sec. 4, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5379</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>