<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="12" order_by="12">ADMINISTRATIVE ORGANIZATION </unit></structure><section_number>12.023</section_number><catch_line>Organizational units and administrative bodies attached to the Governor's office.   </catch_line><order_by>023</order_by><text>The following organizational units and administrative bodies shall be attached to the Office of the Governor: <section prefix="1">Council on Postsecondary Education; <section prefix="a">Foundation for Adult Education; </section></section><section prefix="2">Department of Military Affairs; </section><section prefix="3">Department for Local Government; </section><section prefix="4">Early Childhood Advisory Council; </section><section prefix="5">Kentucky Commission on Human Rights; </section><section prefix="6">Kentucky Commission on Women; </section><section prefix="7">Kentucky Commission on Military Affairs; </section><section prefix="8">Agricultural Development Board; </section><section prefix="9">Kentucky Agricultural Finance Corporation; </section><section prefix="10">Office of Minority Empowerment; <section prefix="a">The Martin Luther King Commission; and </section></section><section prefix="11">Office of Homeland Security. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 15, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2013; and ch. 57, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 8, effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 117, sec. 15, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 4, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2007 (2d Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 36, effective August 30, 2007. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 7, effective June 26, 2007; and ch. 85, sec. 8, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2006; ch. 193, sec. 12, effective July 12, 2006; and ch. 211, sec. 4, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 9, sec. 2, effective June 20, 2005; ch. 35, sec. 3, effective June 20, 2005; ch. 85, sec. 2, effective June 20, 2005; ch. 95, sec. 8, effective June 20, 2005; and ch. 99, sec. 8, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 41, sec. 7, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 3, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000; ch. 387, sec. 4, effective July 14, 2000; ch. 461, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000; ch. 506, sec. 11, effective July 14, 2000; ch. 530, sec. 15, effective April 26, 2000; and ch. 536, sec. 11, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998; ch. 239, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998; ch. 353, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 466, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 29, effective May 30, 1997. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 331, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 334, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 393, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1982; and ch. 447, sec. 6, effective April 12, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 295, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, secs. 3 and 104, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 299, sec. 2. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. I sec. 7. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><lrc-note>(6/25/2013). This statute was amended by 2013 Ky. Acts chs. 15 and 57, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together.  (7/12/2012). 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 158, sec. 84, instructs the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers affected by the Act, as it confirms the reorganization of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services within the executive branch, including the transfer of the Governor’s Council on Wellness and Physical Activity from the Office of the Governor to the Department for Public Health. Such a correction has been made in this statute. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:13</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41812</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>