<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="17" order_by="17">PUBLIC SAFETY </unit></structure><section_number>17.520</section_number><catch_line>Period of registration. </catch_line><order_by>520</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A registrant, upon his or her release by the court, the Parole Board, the cabinet, or any detention facility, shall be required to register for a period of time required under this section. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Lifetime registration is required for: <section prefix="1">Any person who has been convicted of kidnapping, as set forth in KRS 509.040, when the victim is under the age of eighteen (18) at the time of the commission of the offense, except when the offense is committed by a parent; </section><section prefix="2">Any person who has been convicted of unlawful confinement, as set forth in KRS 509.020, when the victim is under the age of eighteen (18) at the time of the commission of the offense, except when the offense is committed by a parent; </section><section prefix="3">Any person convicted of a sex crime: <section prefix="a">Who has one (1) or more prior convictions of a felony criminal offense against a victim who is a minor; or </section><section prefix="b">Who has one (1) or more prior sex crime convictions; </section></section><section prefix="4">Any person who has been convicted of two (2) or more felony criminal offenses against a victim who is a minor; </section><section prefix="5">Any person who has been convicted of: <section prefix="a">Rape in the first degree under KRS 510.040; or </section><section prefix="b">Sodomy in the first degree under KRS 510.070; and </section></section><section prefix="6">Any sexually violent predator. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">All other registrants are required to register for twenty (20) years following discharge from confinement or twenty (20) years following the maximum discharge date on probation, shock probation, conditional discharge, parole, or other form of early release, whichever period is greater. </section><section prefix="4">If a person required to register under this section is reincarcerated for another offense or as the result of having violated the terms of probation, parole, postincarceration supervision, or conditional discharge, the registration requirements and the remaining period of time for which the registrant shall register are tolled during the reincarceration. </section><section prefix="5">A person who has pled guilty, entered an Alford plea, or been convicted in a court of another state or territory, in a court of the United States, or in a court-martial of the United States Armed Forces who is required to register in Kentucky shall be subject to registration in Kentucky based on the conviction in the foreign jurisdiction. The Justice and Public Safety Cabinet shall promulgate administrative regulations to carry out the provisions of this subsection. </section><section prefix="6">The court shall designate the registration period as mandated by this section in its judgment and shall cause a copy of its judgment to be mailed to the Information Services Center, Department of Kentucky State Police, Frankfort, Kentucky 40601. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch.2, sec.93, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 101, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 7, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 401, sec. 17, effective April 11, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 606, sec. 139, effective January 15, 1999. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 392, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><lrc-note> (6/26/2007).  2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, relating to the creation and organization of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, instructs the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in that Act. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39603</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>