<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="78" order_by="78">COUNTY EMPLOYEES' CIVIL SERVICE AND RETIREMENT </unit></structure><section_number>78.852</section_number><catch_line>Benefits not to be reduced or impaired for members who began participating before January 1, 2014 -- Exceptions -- Amendmentof benefits and rights.   </catch_line><order_by>852</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For members who begin participating in the County Employees Retirement System prior to January 1, 2014, it is hereby declared that in consideration of the contributions by the members and in further consideration of benefits received by the county from the member's employment, KRS 78.510 to 78.852 shall, except as provided in KRS 6.696 effective September 16, 1993, constitute an inviolable contract of the Commonwealth, and the benefits provided therein shall, except as provided in KRS 6.696, not be subject to reduction or impairment by alteration, amendment, or repeal. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">For members who begin participating in the County Employees Retirement System on or after January 1, 2014, the General Assembly reserves the right to amend, suspend, or reduce the benefits and rights provided under KRS 78.510 to 78.852 if, in its judgment, the welfare of the Commonwealth so demands, except that the amount of benefits the member has accrued at the time of amendment, suspension, or reduction shall not be affected. </section><section prefix="b">For purposes of this subsection, the amount of benefits the member has accrued at the time of amendment, suspension, or reduction shall be limited to the accumulated account balance the member has accrued at the time of amendment, suspension, or reduction. </section><section prefix="c">The provisions of this subsection shall not be construed to limit the General Assembly's authority to change any other benefit or right specified by KRS 78.510 to 78.852, except the benefits specified by paragraph (b) of this subsection, for members who begin participating in the County Employees Retirement System on or after January 1, 2014. </section></section><section prefix="3">The provisions of this section shall not be construed to limit the General Assembly's authority to amend, reduce, or suspend the benefits and rights of members of the County Employees Retirement System as provided by KRS 78.510 to 78.852 that the General Assembly had the authority to amend, reduce, or suspend, prior to July 1, 2013. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 80, effective July 1, 2013. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 167, sec. 27, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1993 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 80, effective September 16, 1993. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 321, sec. 40. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 75. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:13</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42708</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>