<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="161" order_by="161">SCHOOL EMPLOYEES -- TEACHERS' RETIREMENT AND TENURE </unit></structure><section_number>161.148</section_number><catch_line>Use of volunteer personnel -- Criminal records check -- Orientation -- Exception. </catch_line><order_by>148</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, "volunteers" means adults who assist teachers, administrators, or other staff in public school classrooms, schools, or school district programs, and who do not receive compensation for their work. </section><section prefix="2">Local school districts may utilize adult volunteers in supplementary instructional and noninstructional activities with pupils under the direction and supervision of the professional administrative and teaching staff. </section><section prefix="3">Each board of education shall develop policies and procedures that encourage volunteers to assist in school or district programs. </section><section prefix="4">Each local board of education shall develop and adopt a policy requiring a state criminal records check on all volunteers who have contact with students on a regularly scheduled or continuing basis, or who have supervisory responsibility for children at a school site or on school-sponsored trips. The request for records may be from the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet or the Administrative Office of the Courts, or both, and shall include records of all available convictions as described in KRS 17.160(1). Any request for a criminal records check of a volunteer under this subsection shall be on a form or through a process approved by the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet or the Administrative Office of the Courts. If the cabinet or the Administrative Office of the Courts charges fees, the local board of education shall arrange to pay the cost which may be from local funds or donations from any source including volunteers. </section><section prefix="5">The local board of education shall provide orientation material to all volunteers who have contact with students on a regularly scheduled or continuing basis, including school policies, safety and emergency procedures, and other information deemed appropriate by the local board of education. </section><section prefix="6">The provisions of this section shall not apply to students enrolled in an educational institution and who participate in observations and educational activities under direct supervision of a local school teacher or administrator in a public school. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 170, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 60, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 336, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3868</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>