<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.720</section_number><catch_line>Assignment -- Subrogation -- Distribution of child support payments -- Effect of termination of Title IV-D services. </catch_line><order_by>720</order_by><text><section prefix="1">By applying for Title IV-D services or accepting public assistance for or on behalf of a needy dependent child, the recipient shall be deemed to have made an assignment to the cabinet of the right to any child support or maintenance owed up to the amount of public assistance paid by the cabinet to the recipient, including amounts which have accrued at the time the assignment is made between October 1, 1997, and September 30, 2000. The cabinet shall be subrogated to the right of the child or the person having custody to collect and receive all child support payments and to initiate any support action existing under the laws of this state. </section><section prefix="2">The cabinet shall distribute all child support payments and assigned arrearages as required by 42 U.S.C. secs. 651 et seq. </section><section prefix="3">When Title IV-D services on behalf of a dependent child are terminated, current and past due court-ordered or administratively determined child support owed the child shall be payable to the physical custodian of the dependent child for the period of time the dependent child was in the physical custody of that custodian. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 330, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 277, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 343, sec. 4. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7806</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>