<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="12" order_by="12">ADMINISTRATIVE ORGANIZATION </unit></structure><section_number>12.028</section_number><catch_line>Governor and elected state executive officers to submit proposals for change to General Assembly -- Review of temporary changes by interim joint legislative committee -- Restrictions on changes -- Reorganization plans -- Committee action -- Termination of temporary reorganization -- Legislative monitoring -- Lapsed funds. </catch_line><order_by>028</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Recognizing the necessity for grouping related functions of organizational units and administrative bodies in order to promote greater economy, efficiency and improved administration, the Governor, the Kentucky Economic Development Partnership as created in KRS 154.10-010, and other elected state executive officers may propose to the General Assembly, for its approval, changes in the state government organizational structure which may include the creation, alteration or abolition of any organizational unit or administrative body and the transfer of functions, personnel, funds, equipment, facilities, and records from one (1) organizational unit or administrative body to another. </section><section prefix="2">Recognizing that changes in the state government organizational structure may need to be made as rapidly as possible to achieve greater economy, efficiency, and improved administration as the needs of government dictate, the Governor, the Kentucky Economic Development Partnership as created in KRS 154.10-010, and other elected state executive officers may, between sessions of the General Assembly, temporarily effect a change in the state government organizational structure as described in subsection (1) of this section if such temporary reorganization plan is first reviewed by the interim joint legislative committee with appropriate jurisdiction. The Governor may not effect a temporary reorganization plan under this subsection that would change the organizational structure of an organizational unit or administrative body headed by the Kentucky Economic Development Partnership as created in KRS 154.10-010, or another elected state executive officer unless requested in writing by that officer. An elected state executive officer other than the Governor may only change the organizational structure of an organizational unit or administrative body that he heads. </section><section prefix="3">Any reorganization proposed under subsection (1) or (2) of this section shall be set forth in a reorganization plan which shall be filed with the Legislative Research Commission. The plan shall include: <section prefix="a">An explanation of each proposed change, including the need for the change; </section><section prefix="b">An estimate of any reduction or increase in expenditures, itemized as far as practicable, which the promulgating officer expects will result from the reorganization; </section><section prefix="c">A description of any improvements in the management, delivery of state services, and efficiency of state government operations which the promulgating officer expects will be realized as a result of the reorganization; and </section><section prefix="d">Specification of the effects of the reorganization on the budget and personnel of each affected organizational unit or administrative body, including but not limited to the amount of funds and the number of employees that will be transferred from one (1) organizational unit or administrative body to another, any reductions in the state workforce resulting from the reorganization, and the methods to be utilized to achieve such reductions. </section></section><section prefix="4">When a proposed reorganization plan is submitted for review under subsection (2) of this section the presiding co-chairman of the Legislative Research Commission shall determine which interim joint legislative committee has appropriate jurisdiction and shall refer the plan to such committee within ten (10) days after the director of the Legislative Research Commission receives the proposal. The interim joint legislative committee to which it is referred shall review the plan to determine whether the plan can reasonably be expected to achieve greater economy, efficiency or improved administration in state government. The committee shall report its findings to the Legislative Research Commission. The committee shall review and report on the plan within sixty (60) days after it is filed with the Legislative Research Commission. If the committee does not report on a proposed plan within the time specified in this subsection, the plan shall be considered reviewed by the interim joint legislative committee with appropriate jurisdiction. </section><section prefix="5">A temporary reorganization effected under subsections (2) to (4) of this section shall be terminated ninety (90) days after sine die adjournment of the next regular session of the General Assembly unless otherwise specified by the General Assembly. The Governor, the Kentucky Economic Development Partnership as created in KRS 154.10-010, or other officer who promulgated a temporary reorganization plan under this section shall recommend legislation to the General Assembly to confirm the temporary reorganization plan. The subject matter of each executive order relating to reorganization shall be presented to the General Assembly in a separate bill. If the General Assembly fails to enact the temporary reorganization plan or an alternative to such plan, the organizational structure that existed immediately prior to the implementation of the temporary plan shall be reinstated upon the termination of the temporary plan. If the General Assembly fails to enact a temporary reorganization plan, the Governor, the Kentucky Economic Development Partnership as created in KRS 154.10-010, and other elected state executive officers shall not effect the plan prior to the next succeeding session of the General Assembly. </section><section prefix="6">The Legislative Research Commission or the legislative program review and investigations committee may monitor the implementation of any reorganization plan to determine the extent to which the anticipated improvements in economy, efficiency, or administration have been realized as a result of the reorganization and shall report its findings to the General Assembly. </section><section prefix="7">Funds transferred due to reorganization shall be maintained in separately designated accounts. Any excess funds resulting from a reorganization shall lapse to the general fund surplus account. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 61, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 306, sec. 2, effective April 9, 1984. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 447, sec. 2, effective January 1, 1984. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:13</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=625</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>