<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IV" order_by="4">JUDICIAL BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="21" order_by="21">JUDICIAL RETIREMENT </unit></structure><section_number>21.460</section_number><catch_line>Refund of contributions or account balance -- Interest on deferred refunds -- Repayment.   </catch_line><order_by>460</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">For members who began participating in the Judicial Retirement Plan prior to January 1, 2014: If any member of the plan ceases, other than by death or by disability retirement under KRS 21.410, to hold an office qualifying him for membership in the plan established by KRS 21.350 to 21.480, without having met the requirements for vesting, he shall be refunded on demand the amount of his accumulated contributions and any service credit he had in the plan shall be nullified. </section><section prefix="b">A member who begins participating in the Judicial Retirement Plan on or after January 1, 2014, may, if the member ceases to hold an office qualifying him or her for membership in the plan established by KRS 21.345 to 21.580, elect to take a refund of his or her accumulated account balance subject to the limitations provided by KRS 21.402. </section></section><section prefix="2">The member may elect to leave his contributions in the plan, in which event the service credit he had in the plan shall be considered to be service credit for vesting purposes as provided in KRS 21.375 and for service retirement eligibility as provided in KRS 61.680(7), and, in the event he again becomes a member of the Judicial Retirement Plan, shall be counted toward his total service credit in that plan. </section><section prefix="3">If a person who has been refunded his accumulated contributions or accumulated account balance in accordance with subsection (1) of this section subsequently becomes a member of the Legislators' Retirement Plan, the Kentucky Employees Retirement System, County Employees Retirement System, State Police Retirement System, or Teachers' Retirement System, he may while holding such membership repurchase the service credit he previously had in the Judicial Retirement Plan by repaying to that plan the amount that was refunded to him with interest at six percent (6%) per annum, in which event such service credit shall have operative effect to the same limited extent as provided in subsection (2) of this section. Service purchased under this subsection on or after January 1, 2014, shall not be used to determine the member's participation date in the Judicial Retirement Plan. </section><section prefix="4">If a person who has been refunded his accumulated contribution or accumulated account balance in accordance with subsection (1) of this section thereafter becomes again the holder of an office qualifying him for membership in the Judicial Retirement Plan, he shall not be entitled to credit for his prior period of service unless he has previously repaid his refunded contributions in accordance with subsection (3) of this section or unless within thirty (30) days after again assuming office he repays to the plan the amount that was refunded to him with interest at six percent (6%) per annum. Service purchased under this subsection on or after January 1, 2014, shall not be used to determine the member's participation date in the Judicial Retirement Plan. </section><section prefix="5">If the taking of a refund of contributions by a member of the Kentucky Judicial Retirement Plan, when first entitled thereto, would subject the member to a federal excise tax, by reason of the refund's being made before the member has reached an age designated by the federal taxing act, and the member has elected, pursuant to subsection (2) of this section, to defer taking a refund, so much of the contributions as would have been subject to the excise tax shall accrue interest at the rate of six percent (6%) per annum, from the date the member first could have taken a refund until the date the refund is taken or the date as of which the federal excise tax no longer would apply to a refund, whichever is sooner, the interest to be paid by the plan at the time of the refund. The provisions of this subsection shall not apply to members who begin participating in the Judicial Retirement Plan on or after January 1, 2014. </section></text><history>Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 30, effective July 1, 2013. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 299, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 28, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 458, sec. 2, effective April 15, 1982. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 6. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 9, sec. 8. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 84, Art. III, sec. 12. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2013</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42658</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>