<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.10-100</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of cabinet. </catch_line><order_by>10-100</order_by><text>In addition to any other powers and duties vested in it by law, the cabinet shall have the authority, power, and duty to: <section prefix="1">Exercise general supervision of the administration and enforcement of this chapter, and all rules, regulations, and orders promulgated thereunder; </section><section prefix="2">Prepare and develop a comprehensive plan or plans related to the environment of the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="3">Encourage industrial, commercial, residential, and community development which provides the best usage of land areas, maximizes environmental benefits, and minimizes the effects of less desirable environmental conditions; </section><section prefix="4">Develop and conduct a comprehensive program for the management of water, land, and air resources to assure their protection and balance utilization consistent with the environmental policy of the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="5">Provide for the prevention, abatement, and control of all water, land, and air pollution, including but not limited to that related to particulates, pesticides, gases, dust, vapors, noise, radiation, odor, nutrients, heated liquid, or other contaminants; </section><section prefix="6">Provide for the control and regulation of surface coal mining and reclamation in a manner to accomplish the purposes of KRS Chapter 350; </section><section prefix="7">Secure necessary scientific, technical, administrative, and operational services, including laboratory facilities, by contract or otherwise; </section><section prefix="8">Collect and disseminate information and conduct educational and training programs relating to the protection of the environment; </section><section prefix="9">Appear and participate in proceedings before any federal regulatory agency involving or affecting the purposes of the cabinet; </section><section prefix="10">Enter and inspect any property or premises for the purpose of investigating either actual or suspected sources of pollution or contamination or for the purpose of ascertaining compliance or noncompliance with this chapter, or any regulation which may be promulgated thereunder; </section><section prefix="11">Conduct investigations and hold hearings and compel the attendance of witnesses and the production of accounts, books, and records by the issuance of subpoenas; </section><section prefix="12">Accept, receive, and administer grants or other funds or gifts from public and private agencies including the federal government for the purpose of carrying out any of the functions of the cabinet. The funds received by the cabinet shall be deposited in the State Treasury to the account of the cabinet; </section><section prefix="13">Request and receive the assistance of any state or municipal educational institution, experiment station, laboratory, or other agency when it is deemed necessary or beneficial by the cabinet in the performance of its duties; </section><section prefix="14">Advise, consult, and cooperate with other agencies of the Commonwealth, other states, the federal government, and interstate and interlocal agencies, and affected persons, groups, and industries; </section><section prefix="15">Formulate guides for measuring presently unidentified environmental values and relationships so they can be given appropriate consideration along with social, economic, and technical considerations in decision making; </section><section prefix="16">Monitor the environment to afford more effective and efficient control practices, to identify changes and conditions in ecological systems, and to warn of emergency conditions; </section><section prefix="17">Adopt, modify, or repeal with the recommendation of the commission any standard, regulation, or plan specified in KRS 224.1-110(5) and (6); </section><section prefix="18">Issue, after hearing, orders abating activities in violation of this chapter, or the provisions of this chapter, or the regulations promulgated pursuant thereto and requiring the adoption of the remedial measures the cabinet deems necessary; </section><section prefix="19">Issue, continue in effect, revoke, modify, suspend, or deny under such conditions as the cabinet may prescribe and require that applications be accompanied by plans, specifications, and other information the cabinet deems necessary for the following permits: <section prefix="a">Permits to discharge into any waters of the Commonwealth, and for the installation, alteration, expansion, or operation of any sewage system; however, the cabinet may refuse to issue the permits to any person, or any partnership, corporation, etc., of which the person owns more than ten percent (10%) interest, who has improperly constructed, operated, or maintained a sewage system willfully, through negligence, or because of lack of proper knowledge or qualifications until the time that person demonstrates proper qualifications to the cabinet and provides the cabinet with a performance bond; </section><section prefix="b">Permits for the installation, alteration, or use of any machine, equipment, device, or other article that may cause or contribute to air pollution or is intended primarily to prevent or control the emission of air pollution; or </section><section prefix="c">Permits for the establishment or construction and the operation or maintenance of waste disposal sites and facilities; </section></section><section prefix="20">May establish, by regulation, a fee or schedule of fees for the cost of processing applications for permits authorized by this chapter, and for the cost of processing applications for exemptions or partial exemptions which may include but not be limited to the administrative costs of a hearing held as a result of the exemption application, except that applicants for existing or proposed publicly owned facilities shall be exempt from any charge, other than emissions fees assessed pursuant to KRS 224.20-050, and that certain nonprofit organizations shall be charged lower fees to process water discharge permits under KRS 224.16-050(5); </section><section prefix="21">May require for persons discharging into the waters or onto the land of the Commonwealth, by regulation, order, or permit, technological levels of treatment and effluent limitations; </section><section prefix="22">Require, by regulation, that any person engaged in any operation regulated pursuant to this chapter install, maintain, and use at such locations and intervals as the cabinet may prescribe any equipment, device, or test and the methodologies and procedures for the use of the equipment, device, or test to monitor the nature and amount of any substance emitted or discharged into the ambient air or waters or land of the Commonwealth and to provide any information concerning the monitoring to the cabinet in accordance with the provisions of subsection (23) of this section; </section><section prefix="23">Require by regulation that any person engaged in any operation regulated pursuant to this chapter file with the cabinet reports containing information as to location, size, height, rate of emission or discharge, and composition of any substance discharged or emitted into the ambient air or into the waters or onto the land of the Commonwealth, and such other information the cabinet may require; </section><section prefix="24">Promulgate regulations, guidelines, and standards for waste planning and management activities, approve waste management facilities, develop and publish a comprehensive statewide plan for nonhazardous waste management which shall contain but not be limited to the provisions set forth in KRS 224.43-345, and develop and publish a comprehensive statewide plan for hazardous waste management which shall contain but not be limited to the following: <section prefix="a">A description of current hazardous waste management practices and costs, including treatment and disposal, within the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="b">An inventory and description of all existing facilities where hazardous waste is being generated, treated, recycled, stored, or disposed of, including an inventory of the deficiencies of present facilities in meeting current hazardous waste management needs and a statement of the ability of present hazardous waste management facilities to comply with state and federal laws relating to hazardous waste; </section><section prefix="c">A description of the sources of hazardous waste affecting the Commonwealth including the types and quantities of hazardous waste currently being generated and a projection of such activities as can be expected to continue for not less than twenty (20) years into the future; and </section><section prefix="d">An identification and continuing evaluation of those locations within the Commonwealth which are naturally or may be engineered to be suitable for the establishment of hazardous waste management facilities, and an identification of those general characteristics, values, and attributes which would render a particular location unsuitable, consistent with the policy of minimizing land disposal and encouraging the treatment and recycling of the wastes. </section></section> The statewide waste management plans shall be developed consistent with state and federal laws relating to waste; <section prefix="25">Perform other acts necessary to carry out the duties and responsibilities described in this section; </section><section prefix="26">Preserve existing clean air resources while ensuring economic growth by issuing regulations, which shall be no more stringent than federal requirements, setting maximum allowable increases from stationary sources over baseline concentrations of air contaminants to prevent significant deterioration in areas meeting the state and national ambient air quality standards; </section><section prefix="27">Promulgate regulations concerning the bonding provisions of subsection (19)(a) of this section, setting forth bonding requirements, including but not limited to requirements for the amount, duration, release, and forfeiture of the bonds. All funds from the forfeiture of bonds required pursuant to this section shall be placed in the State Treasury and credited to a special trust and agency account which shall not lapse. The account shall be known as the "sewage treatment system rehabilitation fund" and all moneys placed in the fund shall be used for the elimination of nuisances and hazards created by sewage systems which were improperly built, operated, or maintained, and insofar as practicable be used to correct the problems at the same site for which the bond or other sureties were originally provided; </section><section prefix="28">Promulgate administrative regulations not inconsistent with the provisions of law administered by the cabinet; and </section><section prefix="29">Through the secretary or designee of the secretary, enter into, execute, and enforce reciprocal agreements with responsible officers of other states relating to compliance with the requirements of KRS Chapters 350, 351, and 352 and the administrative regulations promulgated under those chapters. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 35, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2007 (2d Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 42, effective August 30, 2007. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 325, sec. 15, effective July 13, 1990; and ch. 412, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 455, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 109, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 264, sec. 2; and ch. 377, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 3, effective June 17, 1978; and ch. 266, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 355, sec. 2, effective June 21, 1974. -- Created 1972 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 3, effective January 1, 1973. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><former-codification> KRS 224.033</former-codification><lrc-note>(6/20/2005). 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 5, codified at KRS 224.10-103, provides that the Division of Energy and all "personnel, functions, powers, and duties of the Division of Energy shall be transferred to the Tourism Development Cabinet." The abolition of the Tourism Development Cabinet and creation of the Commerce Cabinet under Executive Order 2004-729 were confirmed by 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 95, in which the Office of Energy Policy is established and statutory references to the "Division of Energy" are changed to the "Office of Energy Policy."  (9/28/93). The Division of Energy within the Department for Natural Resources of the Natural Resources and Environmental Protection Cabinet was made "responsible for subsections (28) and (29)" of this statute by 1990 Ky. Acts, ch. 325, sec. 14. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:34</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43228</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>