<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.410</section_number><catch_line>Operators' licenses -- Requirements and issuance -- Personal identification cards, validity -- Driver training programs. </catch_line><order_by>410</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every person except those exempted by KRS 186.420 and 186.430 shall, before operating a motor vehicle, motorcycle, or moped upon a highway, secure an operator's license as provided in this chapter. </section><section prefix="2">Except as provided in KRS 186.412, all original, renewal, and duplicate licenses for the operation of motor vehicles, motorcycles, or mopeds shall be issued by the circuit clerk in the county of the applicant's residence. Applications for renewal licenses shall be made every four (4) years within the birth month of the applicant. A license shall not be issued until the application has been certified by the cabinet and the applicant has, if required under KRS 186.6401, successfully completed the examinations required under KRS 186.480. </section><section prefix="3">All color photo personal identification cards shall be issued under the provisions of KRS 186.412. </section><section prefix="4">A person may, at any time between the age of sixteen (16) and before the person's eighteenth birthday, enroll in one (1) of the following driver training programs: <section prefix="a">A driver's education course administered by a school district; </section><section prefix="b">A driver training school licensed pursuant to KRS Chapter 332 which offers a course meeting or exceeding the minimum standards established by the Transportation Cabinet; or </section><section prefix="c">State traffic school. The person may seek to enroll in state traffic school before the person's eighteenth birthday. Persons enrolling in state traffic school pursuant to this paragraph shall not be required to pay a fee. </section></section><section prefix="5">If, for any reason, a person fails to successfully complete the required driver training pursuant to subsection (4) of this section within one (1) year of being issued an operator's license, the Transportation Cabinet shall enroll the person in state traffic school and cancel or suspend the operator's driving privileges until the person completes state traffic school. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 173, sec. 29, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 264, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 535, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 198, sec. 3, effective October 1, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 267, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 389, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 349, sec. 3, effective June 17, 1978; and ch. 434, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. IV, sec. 20(7). -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 60, sec. 1. -- Amended 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 208, secs. 1, 2, and 3. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 127, sec. 1. -- Amended 1944 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739m-34. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6045</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>