<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="160" order_by="160">SCHOOL DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>160.280</section_number><catch_line>Per diem and expenses for board members -- Eligibility for insurance plans. </catch_line><order_by>280</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Members of boards of education shall receive no salaries, but members of boards of education may receive a per diem of seventy-five dollars ($75) in any calendar year, and their actual expenses for each regular or special meeting attended. Members shall receive this same per diem for training required by KRS 160.180. In no case shall the expenses incurred within the district or per diem of any member exceed three thousand dollars ($3,000) in any calendar year. </section><section prefix="2">Members of boards of education may be reimbursed for actual and necessary expenditures incurred outside the district in the performance of their duties authorized by the board. </section><section prefix="3">All claims shall be made out according to law and filed with the secretary of the board and shall be approved and paid as other claims against the board. </section><section prefix="4">Board members shall be eligible to participate in any group medical or dental insurance plan provided to employees of the district pursuant to KRS 161.158. Participating board members shall pay the full cost of any premium required for their participation in the plan. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 88, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 454, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 170, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Repealed and reenacted 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 431, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1982; and ch. 227, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 31, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 256, sec. 1; and ch. 278, sec. 1. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 1. -- Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 220, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4399-32. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3699</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>