<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="342" order_by="342">WORKERS' COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>342.232</section_number><catch_line>Quarterly reports on insurance guaranty funds, Kentucky coal workers' pneumoconiosis fund, and the status of KRS Chapter 342. </catch_line><order_by>232</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The boards of directors of the following funds shall make quarterly reports according to generally accepted accounting principles of all money received and disbursed by the listed funds during each quarter to the Legislative Research Commission. The funds which shall be reported are: <section prefix="a">Kentucky individual self-insurance guaranty fund; </section><section prefix="b">Kentucky group self-insurance fund; and </section><section prefix="c">Kentucky coal employers self-insurance fund. </section></section><section prefix="2">The director of the Division of Workers' Compensation Funds shall make quarterly reports according to generally accepted accounting principles of all money received and disbursed by the coal workers' pneumoconiosis fund to the Legislative Research Commission. </section><section prefix="3">The Department of Workers' Claims shall make quarterly reports to the Legislative Research Commission on the status of the provisions of this chapter. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1803, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 246, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1996 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 78, effective December 12, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32449</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>