<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.060</section_number><catch_line>Lights on vehicles in tow and projections -- Motor vehicle used as towing unit. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each vehicle towed by a towline shall display the lights required on vehicles of the class to which it belongs. </section><section prefix="2">Each vehicle being hauled by another and connected to it in a manner that will keep them uniformly spaced shall carry at least one (1) light on the left side in such a manner as to show an amber light to the front and a red light to the rear visible at least one thousand (1,000) feet away. </section><section prefix="3">When any part of a load projects more than four (4) feet beyond a vehicle, two (2) red flags by day and two (2) red lights during the period provided in KRS 189.030 must be placed upon the extremity of the projection marking the width of the overhang. </section><section prefix="4">Any motor vehicle used as a towing unit where two (2) lamps displaying red lights are not obscured by the towed unit or its load may be equipped with two (2) lamps displaying red lights on the towed unit, the towing unit, or both. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 72, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006; and ch. 173, sec. 5, effective July 12, 2006. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2739g-29 to 2739g-31. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2006).This section was amended by 2006 Ky. Acts chs. 72 and 173, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6303</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>