<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="214" order_by="214">DISEASES </unit></structure><section_number>214.610</section_number><catch_line>Cabinet for Health and Family Services to approve educational courses on all aspects of HIV and acquired immunodeficiency syndrome -- Publication of current informational resources to inform and update all health care professionals.   </catch_line><order_by>610</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall approve appropriate educational courses on the transmission, control, treatment, and prevention of the human immunodeficiency virus and acquired immunodeficiency syndrome, that may address appropriate behavior and attitude change. </section><section prefix="2">The Department for Public Health shall publish on its Web site the current informational resources for the development of the educational courses or programs. To the extent possible, the educational courses or programs under this subsection shall: <section prefix="a">Include changes in Kentucky law affecting HIV testing and reporting; confidentiality and privacy of HIV-related data, information, and reports; and advances in treatment protocols, intervention protocols, coordination of services, and other information deemed important by the Department for Public Health and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC); </section><section prefix="b">Inform all professions involved with or affected by the birthing process about the importance of HIV testing of pregnant women and the probability of preventing perinatal transmission of HIV with appropriate treatment; and </section><section prefix="c">Update all health care professionals requesting information about the potential involvement of their occupation in the treatment or prevention of blood-borne pathogens with the latest CDC guidelines on occupational exposure to HIV and other blood-borne pathogens. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 465, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 47, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 61, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 343, sec. 26, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 412, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 369, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 443, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44606</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>