<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.742</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Higher Education Assistance Authority created -- Adoption of assumed name. </catch_line><order_by>742</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby established a body corporate and politic constituting a public corporation and governmental agency and instrumentality of the Commonwealth by the name of the "Kentucky Higher Education Assistance Authority." The General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky hereby finds and determines that in carrying out its functions, powers, and duties as prescribed in this chapter, the authority will be performing vital public purposes that improve the public welfare and prosperity of the people of the Commonwealth of Kentucky by promoting the availability of and enhancing accessibility to higher educational opportunities. </section><section prefix="2">For purposes of transacting any business with respect to the insured student loan program in any state other than the Commonwealth, the authority may adopt an assumed name in its corporate capacity, to the extent permitted by the laws of that state. Any assumed name adopted by the authority shall not be identical to or deceptively similar to the registered name of any corporation, partnership, trust, or other business entity doing business in that state. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 339, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 93, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4414</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>