<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">A EMERGENCY MEDICAL SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>311A.125</section_number><catch_line>Continuing competence -- Education courses. </catch_line><order_by>125</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For each licensure renewal of a paramedic following the issuance of an initial license or certification by the board, as a prerequisite for license or certification renewal, all individuals licensed under the provisions of this chapter shall be required to document continuing competence during the immediate past licensure or certification period as prescribed in administrative regulations promulgated by the board. </section><section prefix="2">The compliance with continuing competency requirement shall be documented by the emergency medical services medical director and reported as set forth by the board in administrative regulations promulgated in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A. </section><section prefix="3">The board shall approve providers of emergency medical services education and continuing education. The approval may include recognition of providers approved by national organizations and state boards of emergency medical services with comparable standards. Standards for these approvals shall be set forth by the board in administrative regulations promulgated in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A. The board need not approve continuing education training provided by a licensed ambulance service for anyone certified or licensed by the board. </section><section prefix="4">The board shall work cooperatively with professional emergency medical services organizations, approved schools, and other potential sources of continuing education programs to ensure that adequate continuing education offerings are available statewide. The board may enter into contractual agreements to implement the provisions of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 243, sec. 7, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 22, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30741</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>