<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="160" order_by="160">SCHOOL DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>160.157</section_number><catch_line>Funding of community schools. </catch_line><order_by>157</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A public school district may receive funding for a community school program if it meets all of the following criteria: <section prefix="a">Submits an application for approval by the Kentucky Board of Education in the manner and form prescribed by the Department of Education; </section><section prefix="b">Submits a plan, approved by the local board, which outlines the proposed community education program, including procedures for obtaining the involvement and cooperation of other agencies and groups in identifying and recommending programs for meeting locally determined needs; </section><section prefix="c">Establishes a council with the power to make district-wide decisions of policy to assist in conducting community needs assessments and recommending program priorities; </section><section prefix="d">Employs one (1) full-time community education director. </section></section><section prefix="2">Two (2) or more school districts may combine for purposes of qualifying for state funds if the local districts identify a district of record for purposes of receiving state community education funds, maintaining records, and filing reports. Two (2) or more districts in the same county that wish to apply for state funds shall submit a joint proposal. </section><section prefix="3">Each grantee receiving state funds for a community education program shall submit an annual report to the Kentucky Department of Education. The report shall include an evaluation of the program and a financial statement. Failure to submit the report shall result in the loss of state funding. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 42, sec. 3, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 428, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Repealed and reenacted 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 425, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 107, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3685</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>