<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="220" order_by="220">SANITATION DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>220.030</section_number><catch_line>Purposes for which sanitation district may be established. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text>Sanitation districts may be established for any of the following purposes: <section prefix="1">To prevent and correct the pollution of streams. </section><section prefix="2">To regulate the flow of streams for sanitary purposes. </section><section prefix="3">To clean and improve stream channels for sanitary purposes. </section><section prefix="4">To provide for the collection and disposal of sewage and other liquid wastes produced within the district; and incident to those purposes and to enable their accomplishment, to construct, with all appurtenances, laterals, trunk sewers, intercepting sewers, siphons, pumping stations, treatment and disposal works, to maintain, operate, and repair these, and do all other things necessary for the fulfillment of the purposes of KRS 220.010 to 220.520. </section><section prefix="5">To provide for the management of onsite sewage disposal systems. </section><section prefix="6">To develop and implement plans for the collection and disposal of storm drainage. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 234, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 490, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1980. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2062g-3. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:37</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9769</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>