<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="13" order_by="13">A ADMINISTRATIVE REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>13A.030</section_number><catch_line>Duties of subcommittee. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Administrative Regulation Review Subcommittee shall: <section prefix="a">Conduct a continuous study as to whether additional legislation or changes in legislation are needed based on various factors, including, but not limited to, review of new, emergency, and existing administrative regulations, the lack of administrative regulations, and the needs of administrative bodies; </section><section prefix="b">Except as provided by KRS 158.6471 and 158.6472, review and comment upon administrative regulations submitted to it by the Commission; </section><section prefix="c">Make recommendations for changes in statutes, new statutes, repeal of statutes affecting administrative regulations or the ability of administrative bodies to promulgate them; and </section><section prefix="d">Conduct such other studies relating to administrative regulations as may be assigned by the Commission. </section></section><section prefix="2">The subcommittee may make a nonbinding determination: <section prefix="a">That an administrative regulation is deficient because it: <section prefix="1">Is wrongfully promulgated; </section><section prefix="2">Appears to be in conflict with an existing statute; </section><section prefix="3">Appears to have no statutory authority for its promulgation; </section><section prefix="4">Appears to impose stricter or more burdensome state requirements than required by the federal mandate, without reasonable justification; </section><section prefix="5">Fails to use tiering when tiering is applicable; </section><section prefix="6">Is in excess of the administrative body's authority; </section><section prefix="7">Appears to impose an unreasonable burden on government or small business, or both; or </section><section prefix="8">Appears to be deficient in any other manner; </section></section><section prefix="b">That an administrative regulation is needed to implement an existing statute; or </section><section prefix="c">That an administrative regulation should be amended or repealed. </section></section><section prefix="3">The subcommittee may require any administrative body to submit data and information as required by the subcommittee in the performance of its duties under this chapter, and no administrative body shall fail to provide the information or data required. </section></text><history> Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 3, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 4, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 598, sec. 7, effective April 14, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 410, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 417, sec. 3, effective April 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=727</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>