<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.1-310</section_number><catch_line>Tax exemption certificate application, issuance, revocation, modification -- Appeal. </catch_line><order_by>1-310</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Application for a pollution control tax exemption certificate shall be filed with the Department of Revenue in such manner and in such form as may be prescribed by regulations issued by the Department of Revenue and shall contain plans and specifications of the structure or structures including all materials incorporated and to be incorporated therein and a descriptive list of all equipment acquired or to be acquired by the applicant for the purpose of air, noise, waste or water pollution control and any additional information deemed necessary by the Department of Revenue for the proper administration of Acts 1974, Chapter 137. The cabinet shall provide technical assistance and factual information as requested in writing by the Department of Revenue. If the Department of Revenue finds that the facility qualifies as a pollution control facility as defined in KRS 224.1-300(1), it shall enter a finding and issue a certificate to that effect. The effective date of said certificate shall be the date of the making of the application for such certificate. </section><section prefix="2">Before issuing a pollution control tax exemption certificate, the Department of Revenue shall give notice in writing by mail to the secretary of the cabinet, and shall afford to the applicant and to the secretary of the cabinet an opportunity for a hearing. On like notice and opportunity for a hearing, the Department of Revenue shall on its own initiative revoke such certificate whenever any of the following appears: <section prefix="a">The certificate was obtained by fraud or misrepresentation; </section><section prefix="b">The holder of the certificate has failed substantially to proceed with the construction, reconstruction, installation, or acquisition of the pollution control facilities; </section><section prefix="c">The structure or equipment or both to which the certificate relates has ceased to be used for the primary purpose of pollution control and is being used for a different purpose. </section></section><section prefix="3">Provided, however, that where the circumstances so require, the Department of Revenue in lieu of revoking such certificate may modify the same. </section><section prefix="4">On the mailing of notice of the action of the Department of Revenue revoking or modifying a certificate as provided in subsection (5) of this section, such certificate shall cease to be in force or shall remain in force only as modified as the case may require. </section><section prefix="5">A pollution control tax exemption certificate, when issued, shall be sent by certified mail to the applicant and notice of such issuance in the form of certified copies thereof shall be sent to the secretary of the cabinet. Notice of an order of the Department of Revenue denying, revoking, or modifying a certificate in the form of certified copies thereof shall be sent by certified mail to the applicant or the holder thereof and shall be sent to the secretary of the cabinet. The applicant or holder and the secretary of the cabinet are deemed parties for the purpose of the review afforded by subsection (6) of this section. </section><section prefix="6">Any party aggrieved by the issuance, refusal to issue, revocation, or modification of a pollution control tax exemption certificate may appeal from the final ruling of the Department of Revenue to the Kentucky Board of Tax Appeals as provided in KRS 131.340. </section><section prefix="7">In the event of the sale, lease, or other transfer of a pollution control facility, not involving a different location or use, the holder of a pollution control tax exemption certificate for such facility may transfer the certificate by written instrument to the person who, except for the transfer of the certificate, would be obligated to pay taxes on such facility. The transferee shall become the holder of the certificate and shall have all rights pertaining thereto, effective as of the date of transfer of the facility or the date of transfer of the certificate, whichever is earlier. The transferee shall give written notice of the effective date of the transfer, together with a copy of the instrument of transfer to the cabinet and to the Department of Revenue. </section><section prefix="8">In the event a pollution control facility for which an exemption certificate is held ceases to be used for the primary purpose of pollution control or is used for a different purpose than that for which the exemption certificate was granted, the holder of the certificate shall give written notice by certified mail of such change to the cabinet and to the Department of Revenue. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 628, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 9, effective June 17, 1978; and ch. 155, sec. 123, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 1(9) to (16), effective June 21, 1974. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><former-codification> KRS 224.852. KRS 224.01-310. </former-codification><former-codification-former-code>224.01-310</former-codification-former-code><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41564</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>