<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.20-150</section_number><catch_line>Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>20-150</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in KRS 304.20-160 to 304.20-190, "authorized agencies" shall mean: <section prefix="a">State commissioner of insurance; </section><section prefix="b">The state fire marshal when authorized or charged with the investigation of fires at the place where the fire actually took place; </section><section prefix="c">The state Attorney General when authorized or charged with the investigation of fires at the place where the fire actually took place; </section><section prefix="d">The commissioner of the Department of Kentucky State Police; </section><section prefix="e">The full-time Commonwealth's or county attorney responsible for prosecutions in the county where the fire occurred; </section><section prefix="f">The Federal Bureau of Investigation or any other federal agency having the authority to investigate federal offenses arising from arson; and </section><section prefix="g">Any United States' attorney's office authorized or charged with investigation or prosecution of the fire in question or the violation of any statute arising from said fire. </section></section><section prefix="2">As used in KRS 304.20-160 to 304.20-190, "relevant" means information having any tendency to make the existence of any fact that is of consequence to the investigation or determination of the issue more probable or less probable than it would be without the evidence. </section><section prefix="3">For the purposes of KRS 304.20-160 to 304.20-190, information will be "deemed important" if such information is requested by an authorized agency. </section><section prefix="4">"Insurer," as used in KRS 304.20-160 to 304.20-190, shall be defined in the same manner as it is defined in KRS 304.1-040, and shall include the Kentucky FAIR plan and reinsurance association, and all authorized persons acting on behalf of an insurer. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1312, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 292, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 313, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:04</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29489</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>