<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">F LOCAL RESCUE PROGRAMS - STATE AND LOCAL SEARCH AND RESCUE PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>39F.130</section_number><catch_line>Rescue and project funding -- Application and review process. </catch_line><order_by>130</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A rescue grant fund project application shall be initiated by the chief rescue officer and forwarded to the local emergency management director. The local director shall review all applications for completeness and accuracy, prioritize and consolidate the applications, and make recommendations thereon. In the absence of a local director, the county judge/executive shall fill this role. </section><section prefix="2">The local director shall forward all applications to the area manager of the division, who shall review them, make recommendations thereon, and forward documentation to the director. </section><section prefix="3">The director shall forward all applications to the advisory committee. The advisory committee shall meet during the months of April, August, and December on dates announced by the director, to assess applications and compliance and to make recommendations to the director with regard to allocations of funds, assessment of compliance, reallocations of funds, release of equipment, reallocation of equipment, and any other matters assigned by the director. The advisory committee shall: <section prefix="a">Hold only public meetings; and </section><section prefix="b">Maintain written minutes reflecting the actions of the advisory committee. All applications on file and all other matters pending shall be reviewed during each session and recommendations made thereon to the director. </section></section><section prefix="4">Requests for funding shall be evaluated by the following criteria: <section prefix="a">Meeting the minimum eligibility criteria of KRS 39F.020 or 39F.120 and KRS 39F.030, unless some aspect thereof has been waived as provided in KRS 39C.090. In determining membership eligibility, no person may be counted as a member of more than one (1) rescue squad even though that person may be available to or a member of more than one (1) rescue squad. If possible, a squad of primary membership shall be determined and the person counted as a member of that squad. If this cannot be determined, the person shall not be counted as a member of any rescue squad; </section><section prefix="b">Unit and individual training; </section><section prefix="c">Number of rescue responses annually; </section><section prefix="d">Population served; </section><section prefix="e">Geographic area served; </section><section prefix="f">Number, type, and location of other rescue squads in the geographic area served; </section><section prefix="g">Equipment possessed by the squad; and </section><section prefix="h">The extent to which the rescue squad integrates its activities with the local emergency management program of the area served. </section></section><section prefix="5">The advisory committee shall forward the applications together with its recommendations thereon to the director for final decision and allocations of funds. The division's administrative officer shall ensure timely payment of the funds. </section><section prefix="6">The director shall maintain written reasons with regard to all funding decisions for a period of one (1) year from the time they are announced. </section><section prefix="7">The director shall provide applicants with written decisions with regard to their applications. </section><section prefix="8">Decisions and the reasons for any decisions regarding funding shall be made available to any person upon written request. </section><section prefix="9">The local emergency management director shall maintain file copies of all applications and decisions thereon for at least five (5) years. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 95, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21806</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>