<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="148" order_by="148">PARKS AND TOURISM </unit></structure><section_number>148.0212</section_number><catch_line>Permanently and totally disabled resident veteran exempt from overnight accommodation rate at Kentucky state parks -- Maximum number of stays -- Peak periods -- Administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>0212</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A Kentucky resident shall be exempt from the relevant overnight accommodations rate at any Kentucky state park if he or she is: <section prefix="a">A permanently and totally disabled veteran with a one hundred percent (100%) service-connected disability, regardless of wartime service; or </section><section prefix="b">A permanently and totally disabled member of the Kentucky National Guard or Reserve Component injured while on state active duty, active duty training, or inactive duty training. </section></section><section prefix="2">To be entitled to the exemption under this section, a veteran must be a Kentucky resident and must be rated one hundred percent (100%) permanently and totally disabled, as the result of an injury suffered while on active duty, by the United States Veterans Administration or the Department of Defense. Members of the Kentucky National Guard or Reserve Component must be rated one hundred percent (100%) permanently and totally disabled as provided in KRS Chapter 342. </section><section prefix="3">The exemption shall be made available to qualified Kentucky residents as described in this section for a maximum of three (3) overnight stays per calendar year at any Kentucky state park. Each stay shall be limited to a maximum of three (3) days, subject to availability. During peak periods, as defined elsewhere in this section, stays are to be taken during the Sunday through Thursday five (5) day period only. Outside of peak periods, stays are available at any time. </section><section prefix="4">The Department of Parks shall promulgate any administrative regulations necessary to carry out this section, including but not limited to: <section prefix="a">Defining peak periods, which shall be no longer than the days between Memorial Day and Labor Day and the month of October; </section><section prefix="b">Establishing the ten (10) day window during which reservations by residents under this section may be made; </section><section prefix="c">Establishing those accommodations which qualify for the exemption; and </section><section prefix="d">Delineating the types of proof acceptable for establishing eligibility for persons entitled to the exemption provided for in this section, while working in conjunction with the Kentucky Department of Veterans' Affairs. </section></section><section prefix="5">The exemption described in this section shall not limit the benefits of a qualified Kentucky resident if he or she is also eligible for benefits under KRS 148.0211. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1686</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>