<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="70" order_by="70">SHERIFFS, CONSTABLES, AND COUNTY POLICE FORCE </unit></structure><section_number>70.294</section_number><catch_line>Employment contract for law enforcement telecommunicator. </catch_line><order_by>294</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, "law enforcement agency" means a city, county, consolidated local government, urban-county government, charter county government, unified local government, or state law enforcement agency, and includes a sheriff's office. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Law enforcement agencies may, as a condition of employment, require a newly appointed law enforcement telecommunicator to enter into an employment contract for a period of no longer than three (3) years from the date of graduation from the Department of Criminal Justice Training, or other training approved by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council. </section><section prefix="b">If a law enforcement telecommunicator who has entered into a contract authorized under this section begins employment as a law enforcement telecommunicator with another law enforcement agency during the contractual period, that law enforcement agency or the law enforcement telecommunicator shall reimburse the law enforcement agency that initially hired the law enforcement telecommunicator for the actual costs incurred and expended which are associated with the initial hiring of that telecommunicator, including but not limited to the application process, training costs, equipment costs, and salary. The law enforcement agency that initially hired the law enforcement telecommunicator shall be reimbursed for the costs from the time of the law enforcement telecommunicator's initial application until graduation from the Department of Criminal Justice Training, or other training approved by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council. </section><section prefix="c">The amount of reimbursement authorized by paragraph (b) of this subsection shall be prorated based upon the percentage of time that the law enforcement telecommunicator completed his or her employment contract. </section></section></text><history> Created 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43388</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>