<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.20-750</section_number><catch_line>Fleet inspection station. </catch_line><order_by>20-750</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any registered owner or lessee of a fleet of vehicles may apply to the cabinet for a permit to establish at his own expense a fleet inspection station. The cabinet shall not issue any fleet inspection station permit until it has found that the applicant: <section prefix="a">Maintains an established place of business or facility for the repair and maintenance of the applicant's fleet of vehicles; </section><section prefix="b">Has obtained machinery, tools, and equipment approved by the cabinet and adequate to conduct the required emissions inspections; </section><section prefix="c">Employs properly trained personnel with whom to perform the necessary labor; and </section><section prefix="d">Will keep complete records of all inspections performed and repairs made and will provide the information or data to the cabinet. </section></section><section prefix="2">An operator of a fleet inspection station holding a valid permit shall, upon filing an application in the manner and form prescribed by the cabinet, receive a sufficient number of certificate forms for each vehicle in the applicant's fleet. No inspection certificate shall be issued to any fleet vehicle until it has been inspected and found to comply with all the standards that the vehicle would be required to meet at any inspection station. </section><section prefix="3">No holder of a fleet inspection station permit shall inspect or certify any vehicle for which the permittee is not the registered owner or lessee. </section><section prefix="4">Vehicles owned by a licensed vehicle dealer and which are held for resale as a part of the dealer's business inventory shall be deemed a part of the dealer's vehicle fleet for purposes of this section. </section><section prefix="5">The cabinet shall investigate the operation of each fleet inspection station as the conditions and circumstances of the operation may indicate. The cabinet may require the holder of any fleet permit to submit documentation concerning the operation of the inspection station. The cabinet may revoke and require the surrender and forfeiture of any fleet inspection station permit and inspection certificate forms held by a permittee if it finds that the station is not operated in accordance with KRS 224.20-710 to 224.20-765 or that the holder of the permit has failed or refused to submit records or documentation required by KRS 224.20-710 to 224.20-765. </section><section prefix="6">The holder of a fleet inspection station permit shall pay to the cabinet a fee in an amount to be established by regulation. </section></text><history>Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 467, sec. 8, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><former-codification> KRS 224.476. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:34</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10372</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>