<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="260" order_by="260">MARKETING OF AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS </unit></structure><section_number>260.663</section_number><catch_line>Membership of commission -- Terms -- Meetings. </catch_line><order_by>663</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">The consumer members of the Kentucky Milk Commission established in KRS 260.662 shall not, at the time of appointment or while serving as members of the commission, have a business or professional relationship or connection with or a financial interest in any milk producer, milk processor, or other person whose activities are subject to the jurisdiction of the commission. </section><section prefix="b"><section prefix="1">One (1) of the milk producer members shall be an independent milk producer who is not affiliated with a cooperative and is not associated with the milk processor representative. </section><section prefix="2">The other milk producer member may be an independent or cooperative milk producer who is not affiliated with the milk processor representative or the cooperative representative. </section></section><section prefix="c">Members of the commission shall adhere to the Executive Branch Code of Ethics pursuant to KRS Chapter 11A.</section></section><section prefix="2">Appointed members of the commission shall serve for a term of four (4) years or until their successors are duly appointed and qualified, except that the initial terms shall be for one (1), two (2), three (3), and four (4) years so that terms of the members are staggered. The Governor shall determine the initial staggered terms of the members and shall appoint them by August 1, 2009. </section><section prefix="3">A vacancy on the commission shall be filled for the remainder of the unexpired term in the same manner as the original appointment. </section><section prefix="4">Appointed members of the commission shall be reimbursed for reasonable and necessary expenses incurred while engaged in carrying out the official duties of the commission. </section><section prefix="5">The commission shall be attached to the Department of Agriculture for administrative oversight. The department may facilitate basic administrative functions; however, general administrative costs shall be borne by the dairy industry fund created in KRS 260.665. </section><section prefix="6">The commission shall meet quarterly, or at the call of the chair or a majority of the voting members. The first meeting may be called by the chair and may convene by September 1, 2009. </section></text><history> Created 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 67, sec. 4, effective June 25, 2009. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12610</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>