<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6">THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY </unit></structure><section_number>6.900</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 6.905 to 6.935. </catch_line><order_by>900</order_by><text>As used in KRS 6.905 to 6.935: <section prefix="1">"Committee" means the Legislative Program Review and  Investigations Committee; </section><section prefix="2">"Investigation" means an inquiry into possible acts of impropriety in the use of public funds or performance of public duty by an elected or appointed state official or a state employee or contractor; </section><section prefix="3">"Review" means a noninvestigative study of the operation, accomplishments, management, or activities of an agency or program and includes procedures such as fiscal audit, program/performance evaluation, program audit, management audit, policy analysis, or other related terms; </section><section prefix="4">"Study" means any investigation or review initiated or undertaken by the committee; and </section><section prefix="5">"State agency" means: <section prefix="a">Any entity, including multijurisdictional organization or interagency entities, created by the Constitution of Kentucky, by an act of the General Assembly, or by any of the branches of state government or any of its subdivisions, instrumentalities, or affiliated organizations, or by any employee or official acting in his official capacity; </section><section prefix="b">Any entity which receives any part of its funding or resources from state tax dollars, from funds or resources entrusted to the Commonwealth from other sources, or from fines, fees, licensing, or penalties authorized by state statute or administrative regulation; </section><section prefix="c">Any entity which is federally funded and for which the Commonwealth of Kentucky is responsible for the oversight or expenditures of the federal resources; </section><section prefix="d">That portion of a public or private entity which receives or has received resources, such as funds, equipment, property, supplies, or services, directly or indirectly from the Commonwealth of Kentucky; and </section><section prefix="e">That portion of a public or private entity related to the delivery of services to or for the Commonwealth of Kentucky or an entity of the Commonwealth as defined in paragraph (a), (b), (c), or (d) of this subsection. </section></section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=411</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>