<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.50-880</section_number><catch_line>Waste tire trust fund. </catch_line><order_by>50-880</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A waste tire trust fund is established in the state treasury. The fund shall be used by the cabinet for the following purposes: <section prefix="a">Properly managing waste tires; </section><section prefix="b">Paying the costs associated with any waste tire amnesty program established by the cabinet that permits waste tires to be turned in without incurring fees, charges, or penalties; </section><section prefix="c">Paying the Department of Revenue's costs of assessing and collecting the fee established by KRS 224.50-868; </section><section prefix="d">Entering into the agreements described in KRS 224.50-876; and </section><section prefix="e">Awarding the grants described in KRS 224.50-878. </section></section> The cabinet shall utilize no more than twenty-five percent (25%) of the funds for the administrative costs related to implementing the waste tire program. All remaining funds shall be utilized, in accordance with KRS 224.50-850 to 224.50-880, for waste tire amnesty programs, crumb rubber grants, tire-derived fuel programs, and other projects that will manage waste tires as appropriate to protect human health, safety, and the environment, or to develop markets for waste tires. <section prefix="2">All interest earned on money in the fund shall be credited to the fund. </section><section prefix="3">Money unexpended at the end of a fiscal year shall not lapse to the general fund. </section><section prefix="4">Any money remaining in the waste tire trust fund established by KRS 224.50-820 shall be transferred to the fund established by this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 34, sec. 5, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 631, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 46, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 529, sec. 16, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39682</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>