<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">COUNTY GOVERNMENT (FISCAL COURTS AND COUNTY COMMISSIONERS) </unit></structure><section_number>67.060</section_number><catch_line>County commissioners -- Election, term, qualifications.   </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If a majority of the votes cast at an election held under KRS 67.050 are in favor of the fiscal court being composed of the county judge/executive and three (3) commissioners, the county judge/executive shall, no later than the first Monday in January in the year of the regular election for county officers, divide the county into three (3) districts as nearly equal in population as practicable, and shall establish the boundary lines of each of the three (3) commissioner districts so that each district is an unbroken area and not split or divided by another commissioner district. At the next regular election for county officers, and every four (4) years thereafter, there shall be elected by the voters of the entire county three (3) commissioners, one (1) from each district who, with the county judge/executive, shall constitute the fiscal court. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">In any county containing a city of the first class, which county has heretofore voted in favor of a fiscal court composed of the county judge/executive and three (3) county commissioners, the county judge/executive shall divide the county into three (3) districts as provided in subsection (1) of this section, the districts to be designated for identification purposes by the letters A, B and C, respectively. </section><section prefix="b">The three (3) commissioners shall be elected by the qualified voters of the county at large at regular elections held every four (4) years. One commissioner shall represent District A and shall be elected at the regular election in the year 1973, and two (2) commissioners who shall represent Districts B and C, respectively, shall be elected at the regular election in the year 1975. </section></section><section prefix="3">Persons seeking the nomination of a political party as candidate for the office of county commissioner shall, where a primary election is required for such political party, be voted upon exclusively by the eligible voters of the district in which the person resides and seeks to represent. Persons seeking the nomination of a minor political party persons who file as independent candidates or persons seeking the nomination in counties containing a city with a population equal to or greater than eight thousand (8,000) as determined by the most recent federal decennial census but not a city of the first class shall not be subject to the provisions of this paragraph. They shall be nominated by the voters of the entire county. </section><section prefix="4">To be eligible for election as a commissioner representing one of the three (3) districts, a person shall have been a bona fide resident of the district he proposes to represent for at least one (1) year immediately preceding the election, and, upon election, shall continue to reside within the district he was elected to represent for the duration of his term of office, under penalty of forfeiture of the office. </section><section prefix="5">Commissioners elected under this section shall take the oath of office and enter upon the discharge of their duties on the first Monday in January after their election, and shall serve for terms of four (4) years and until their successors are elected and qualify, or until the effective date of a return to a fiscal court composed of justices of the peace and the county judge/executive. </section><section prefix="6">No person is eligible to be a county commissioner unless he is at least twenty-four (24) years of age and has been for two (2) years next preceding his election a resident of the county and a citizen of Kentucky. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 32, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 107, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984; and ch. 189, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 6, effective January 2, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 355, sec. 1. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 1; and ch. 47, sec. 1. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 300, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 1847, 1848, 1849, 1851b-1, 1851b-5, 1851b-8. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43617</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>