<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="7" order_by="7">B LONG-TERM POLICY RESEARCH </unit></structure><section_number>7B.030</section_number><catch_line>Board -- Membership -- Terms -- Removal -- Vacancies -- Vote required to act. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board of the Kentucky Long-Term Policy Research Center shall consist of twenty-one (21) members, including ten (10) members selected from state government and eleven (11) at-large members selected from the private and civic sectors, universities, and local governments. <section prefix="a">State government members shall be appointed as follows: <section prefix="1">Two (2) members of the House of Representatives shall be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives and one (1) member of the minority party in the House of Representatives shall be appointed by the Minority Floor Leader in the House of Representatives. Two (2) members of the Senate shall be appointed by the President of the Senate and one (1) member of the minority party in the Senate shall be appointed by the Minority Floor Leader in the Senate; and </section><section prefix="2">Four (4) members from the executive branch shall be appointed by the Governor. </section></section><section prefix="b">At-large members shall be appointed as follows: <section prefix="1">Five (5) members shall be appointed by the Legislative Research Commission; and </section><section prefix="2">Six (6) members shall be appointed by the Governor and confirmed by the House of Representatives and the Senate; </section><section prefix="3">Persons appointed may serve prior to confirmation, but shall continue to serve only if confirmed at the next regular session, or special session if the matter is included in the call therefor of the General Assembly; </section><section prefix="4">The provisions of KRS 11.160 shall apply to Senate and House of Representatives confirmation of at-large members appointed by the Governor. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">Board members shall serve four (4) year terms, except initial appointments shall be for terms as follows: <section prefix="a">The Legislative Research Commission shall initially appoint two (2) legislators for terms of two (2) years, two (2) legislators for terms of three (3) years and two (2) legislators for terms of four (4) years; and shall initially appoint one (1) at-large member for a two (2) year term, two (2) at-large members for three (3) year terms, and two (2) at-large members for four (4) year terms. </section><section prefix="b">The Governor shall initially appoint two (2) members from the executive branch for terms of two (2) years, one (1) for a three (3) year term, and one (1) for a four (4) year term, and shall initially appoint two (2) at-large members for terms of two (2) years, two (2) for three (3) year terms, and two (2) for four (4) year terms. </section></section><section prefix="3">Members of the board shall meet the same age and state residency requirements as provided in Section 32 of the Kentucky Constitution for members of the House of Representatives, shall represent the cultural diversity of Kentucky, and shall have demonstrated an interest in the well-being and development of the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="4">The chair shall be elected annually by the board and shall alternate between the members selected from state government and the at-large members. If the chair is a member selected from state government, the vice chair shall be an at-large member, and if the chair is an at-large member, the vice chair shall be a member selected from state government. </section><section prefix="5">Board members who miss three (3) consecutive meetings may be removed from the board by a majority vote of the board at any regularly scheduled meeting in which a quorum is present. The position shall then be declared vacant and shall be filled in the same manner as it was originally appointed. </section><section prefix="6">If vacancies are not filled by the original appointing authority within thirty (30) days of the occurrence of the vacancy, the board may fill the vacancy. </section><section prefix="7">A majority of the entire membership of the board shall constitute a quorum, and all actions of the board shall be by vote of a majority of its entire membership. </section></text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 185, sec. 9, effective March 31, 2003. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 39, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 103, sec. 3, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> March 31, 2003 </effective><budget-ref> See Legislative Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 123, Pt. I, 1, (3) at 782. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=507</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>