<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="16" order_by="16">STATE POLICE </unit></structure><section_number>16.070</section_number><catch_line>Uniforms, equipment, and facilities.   </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commissioner is the head and chief executive officer of the department. He or she shall provide for himself or herself, each officer of the department, and each individual employed as a Trooper R Class or CVE R Class, under the provisions of KRS 45A.045 to 45A.650, such uniforms, equipment, and facilities, including motor vehicles, necessary to the performance of their respective duties, but all uniforms, equipment, and facilities, including motor vehicles, shall remain the property of the Commonwealth. The commissioner may sell through the Finance and Administration Cabinet, under the provisions of KRS 45A.045 to 45A.650, such uniforms, equipment, and facilities, including motor vehicles, as become unfit for use, and all moneys received therefrom shall be paid into the State Treasury and credited to a revolving fund to be used by the department. </section><section prefix="2">The commissioner shall keep an inventory and shall charge against each officer and each individual employed as a Trooper R Class or CVE R Class the value of all property of the department issued to him or her, and if it is determined by the commissioner that any loss or destruction of property was due to the carelessness or neglect of an officer or an individual employed as a Trooper R Class, then the value of the property shall be deducted from the pay of the officer or the individual employed as a Trooper R Class or CVE R Class. </section><section prefix="3">By agreement with the commissioner of highways of the Commonwealth, the commissioner of the Department of Kentucky State Police may provide for the leasing of motor vehicles and accessories thereto, radio facilities and equipment, office equipment, and other property or facilities, upon such terms and conditions and for such compensation as said agreement may provide. The commissioner of highways and the commissioner of the Department of Kentucky State Police may further provide, by agreement, for the service and repair at any state garage of motor vehicles or accessories thereto which are owned, operated, or rented by the department, upon such terms and conditions and for such compensation as said agreement may provide. Subject to KRS Chapter 42, the department is authorized, by lease or purchase, to acquire, maintain, and operate motor vehicles, and the officers of said department, including the commissioner and individuals employed as a Trooper R Class or CVE R Class, are authorized and empowered to operate such motor vehicles in the course of their duties, and in carrying out the purposes, responsibilities, and functions provided for in KRS 16.010 to 16.170. </section><section prefix="4">The commissioner shall establish local headquarters so as to best distribute the officers, individuals employed as a Trooper R Class or CVE R Class, and employees of the department throughout the various sections of the Commonwealth where they will be most efficient in carrying out the provisions of KRS 16.010 to 16.199. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 64, sec. 11, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 5, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 60, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 496, sec. 24, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. II, sec. 9(1), Art. IV, sec. 20(1); and Art. V, sec. 24(3) to 24(6). -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 13. -- Amended 1956 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 7, Art. X, sec. 6. -- Created 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 7. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><lrc-note> (6/25/2009).  A reference in subsection (4) of this statute to "KRS 16.010 to 16.185 and Sections 12 to 15 of this Act" in 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 5, has been changed in codification to "KRS 16.010 to 16.199," to account for newly created statutes in 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 75, secs. 1 to 10, and 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 59, secs. 12 to 15, all of which have been assigned numbers in KRS Chapter 16 within that range of statutes. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42243</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>