<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.49-080</section_number><catch_line>Examination of captive insurers. </catch_line><order_by>49-080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any insurer holding a certificate of authority issued under this subtitle shall be subject to provisions of KRS 304.2-210 to 304.2-300 and provisions of Subtitle 2 of this chapter for determining market conduct and business practices. However, the commissioner upon application, in his or her discretion, may extend the period between examinations, provided the captive insurer is subject to a comprehensive annual audit during that period, of a scope satisfactory to the commissioner, by independent auditors approved by the commissioner. </section><section prefix="2">The examination for a branch captive insurer shall be of branch business and branch operations only, as long as the branch captive insurer provides annually to the commissioner a certificate of compliance, or its equivalent, issued by or filed with the licensing authority of the jurisdiction in which the branch captive insurer is formed, and demonstrates to the commissioner's satisfaction that it is operating in sound financial condition in accordance with all applicable laws and regulations of that jurisdiction. </section><section prefix="3">As a condition for issuance of a certificate of authority to a branch captive insurer, the foreign captive insurer shall grant authority to the commissioner for examination of the affairs of the foreign captive insurer in the jurisdiction in which the foreign captive insurer is formed. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1612, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 434, sec. 8, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30225</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>