<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.33-020</section_number><catch_line>Persons covered. </catch_line><order_by>33-020</order_by><text>The proceedings authorized by this subtitle may be applied to: <section prefix="1">All domestic insurers, whether or not they purport to do business in this state; </section><section prefix="2">All insurers who are doing, or have done, an insurance business in this state, and against whom claims arising from that business may exist now or in the future; </section><section prefix="3">All insurers who purport to do an insurance business in this state; </section><section prefix="4">All insurers who have insureds resident in this state; </section><section prefix="5">All other persons organized or in the process of organizing with the intent to do an insurance business in this state; </section><section prefix="6">All fraternal benefit societies as defined in Subtitle 29; </section><section prefix="7">All nonprofit hospital, medical-surgical, dental, and health service corporations, as defined in Subtitle 32; </section><section prefix="8">All health maintenance organizations as defined in Subtitle 38; </section><section prefix="9">All limited health service organizations as defined in KRS 304.38A-010; </section><section prefix="10">Workers' compensation self-insured groups authorized in KRS 342.350; </section><section prefix="11">Workers' compensation self-insured groups authorized in KRS 304.50-010 and defined in KRS 304.50-015; and </section><section prefix="12">Liability self-insurance groups defined in KRS 304.48-020 and authorized in KRS 304.48-030. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 33, effective March 1, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 30, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 422, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 357, sec. 21, effective June 21, 1974. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 33, sec. 2, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (3/1/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 51, states that "[t]he amendments made to KRS 304.33-020 in [2005 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 33] shall apply to proceedings initiated on or after August 1, 2004." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:00</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29816</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>