<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="317" order_by="317">BARBERS </unit></structure><section_number>317.410</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter.   </catch_line><order_by>410</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">A "barber" is any person who engages in the practice of "barbering" for the public generally or for consideration; </section><section prefix="2">"Barbering" is the practice upon the human neck and head, principally of shaving or trimming the beard or cutting the hair, but includes also: <section prefix="a">Giving facial and scalp massage or treatments with oils, creams, lotions, or other preparations, either by hand or any contrivance; </section><section prefix="b">Singeing, shampooing, pressing, arranging, dressing, or dyeing the hair or applying hair tonics; and </section><section prefix="c">Applying to the neck or head cosmetics, lotions, powders, oils, clays, or other preparations; </section></section><section prefix="3">"Barber pole" means a cylinder or pole with alternating stripes of any combination, including but not limited to red and white, or red, white, and blue, which run diagonally along the length of the pole; </section><section prefix="4">"Barber school" or "school of barbering" means an operation, place, or establishment of whatsoever kind or form in or through which persons are trained or taught the practice of barbering; </section><section prefix="5">"Barber shop" is any establishment of whatsoever kind in which the practice of barbering is conducted for the general public or for consideration; </section><section prefix="6">"Board" means the Kentucky Board of Barbering; </section><section prefix="7">"Independent contract owner" means any barber licensed under this chapter who leases or rents space in a barber shop; and </section><section prefix="8">"Lapse fees" means the annual renewal license fee which would have been paid for the period during which a license has lapsed. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 1. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 354, sec. 16. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 233, sec. 1, effective June 30, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:54</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42128</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>