<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="260" order_by="260">MARKETING OF AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS </unit></structure><section_number>260.166</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of Kentucky Grape and Wine Council. </catch_line><order_by>166</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Grape and Wine Council, created in KRS 260.165 to promote and facilitate the development of a grape, grape products, and wine industry, may: <section prefix="a">Conduct and contract with others to conduct research on grapes, grape products, and wine in Kentucky and elsewhere for use in Kentucky, including but not limited to: <section prefix="1">Methods of marketing, market development, and distribution; </section><section prefix="2">Methods of storage, refrigeration, processing, and transportation; </section><section prefix="3">Methods of production and product development; </section><section prefix="4">Methods of agronomic, enological, and viticultural practices to improve these practices in Kentucky; and </section><section prefix="5">Economic benefits and impact from the industry; </section></section><section prefix="b">Publish and provide and contract with others to publish and provide wholesalers and retailers in the Kentucky grape, grape products, and wine industry with information on proper methods of handling and selling grapes, grape products, and wine; </section><section prefix="c">Publish and provide and contract with others to publish and provide producers of Kentucky grapes, grape products, and wine, as well as the general public, with information relating to Kentucky grapes, grape products, and wine; and </section><section prefix="d">Design and implement or contract with others to design and implement activities relating to Kentucky grapes, grape products, and wine, including but not limited to: <section prefix="1">Market surveys and analyses; </section><section prefix="2">Industry promotion programs; </section><section prefix="3">Market maintenance and expansion plans; </section><section prefix="4">Education programs; </section><section prefix="5">Public relations programs; </section><section prefix="6">Economic impact analyses; and </section><section prefix="7">Other analysis or research relating to the promotion and sale of Kentucky grapes, grape products, and wine. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Grape and Wine Council, to the extent that funds are available, shall: <section prefix="a">Promote the sale of grapes, grape products, and wine for the purpose of maintaining and expanding present markets and creating new markets for Kentucky grapes, grape products, and wine for the maximum economic impact on the agricultural economy of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="b">Inform the public, producers, and vendors about Kentucky grapes, grape products, and wine, including uses and benefits of these products; </section><section prefix="c">Advise the Commissioner to: <section prefix="1">Expend moneys from the Kentucky Grape and Wine Council fund created in KRS 260.168 to carry out the duties and recommendations of the council; and </section><section prefix="2">Hire staff to carry out the duties and recommendations of the council; and </section><section prefix="3">Promulgate administrative regulations to carry out the duties and recommendations of the council; </section></section><section prefix="d">Coordinate with the Kentucky Department of Agriculture and other state agencies in carrying out these duties; </section><section prefix="e">Report annually to the Governor and the General Assembly on the activities of the Kentucky Grape and Wine Council; and </section><section prefix="f">Report by November 1 of each year to the Interim Joint Committee on Licensing and Occupations of the Kentucky General Assembly and the Agricultural Development Board on the coordination between Kentucky wineries and Kentucky wholesalers to promote the availability of Kentucky wine to retailers. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 179, sec. 3, effective January 1, 2007. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 315, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12556</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>