<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="281" order_by="281">MOTOR CARRIERS </unit></structure><section_number>281.730</section_number><catch_line>Federal regulation -- Maximum driving and on-time-duty -- Exemption for agricultural purposes.   </catch_line><order_by>730</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The secretary of the Transportation Cabinet may adopt by reference or set forth in its entirety the provisions of 49 C.F.R. secs. 350.341 and 395 in effect as of July 15, 1986, or as amended with respect to any motor vehicle registered in Kentucky. </section><section prefix="2">The provisions of subsection (1) of this section pertaining to the maximum driving and on-duty time shall not apply to transporters of agricultural commodities or farm supplies for agricultural purposes if the transportation is limited to an area within a one hundred (100) air mile radius from the source of the commodities or distribution point for the farm supplies and is during Kentucky's planting and harvesting seasons. For the purposes of this subsection, Kentucky's planting and harvesting seasons shall mean January 1 to December 31 of each year. </section><section prefix="3">The provisions of subsection (2) of this section shall be void if the Secretary of the United States Department of Transportation determines through a rulemaking proceeding that Section 345(a.)(1.) of the National Highway System Designation Act of 1995 presents a hazard to the traveling public. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 19, sec. 20, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 88, sec. 3, effective March 16, 2011. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 256, sec. 1, effective April 4, 1996. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 63, sec. 33, effective June 15, 1950. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44169</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>