<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="314" order_by="314">REGISTERED NURSES -- PRACTICAL NURSES </unit></structure><section_number>314.091</section_number><catch_line>Reprimand, denial, limitation, probation, revocation, or suspension of licenses, privileges, or credentials -- Hearings -- Appeals. </catch_line><order_by>091</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall have power to reprimand, deny, limit, revoke, probate, or suspend any license or credential to practice nursing issued by the board or applied for in accordance with this chapter or the privilege to practice as a nurse recognized by the board in accordance with this chapter, or to otherwise discipline a licensee, credential holder, privilege holder, or applicant, or to deny admission to the licensure examination, or to require evidence of evaluation and therapy upon proof that the person: <section prefix="a">Is guilty of fraud or deceit in procuring or attempting to procure a license, credential, or privilege to practice nursing; </section><section prefix="b">Has been convicted of any felony, or a misdemeanor involving drugs, alcohol, fraud, deceit, falsification of records, a breach of trust, physical harm or endangerment to others, or dishonesty, under the laws of any state or of the United States. The record of conviction or a copy thereof, certified by the clerk of the court or by the judge who presided over the conviction, shall be conclusive evidence; </section><section prefix="c">Has been convicted of a misdemeanor offense under KRS Chapter 510 involving a patient, or a felony offense under KRS Chapter 510, 530.064(1)(a), or 531.310, or has been found by the board to have had sexual contact as defined in KRS 510.010(7) with a patient while the patient was under the care of the nurse; </section><section prefix="d">Has negligently or willfully acted in a manner inconsistent with the practice of nursing; </section><section prefix="e">Is unfit or incompetent to practice nursing by reason of negligence or other causes, including but not limited to, being unable to practice nursing with reasonable skill or safety; </section><section prefix="f">Abuses use of controlled substances, prescription medications, illegal substances, or alcohol; </section><section prefix="g">Has misused or misappropriated any drugs placed in the custody of the nurse for administration, or for use of others; </section><section prefix="h">Has falsified or in a negligent manner made incorrect entries or failed to make essential entries on essential records; </section><section prefix="i">Has a license, privilege, or credential to practice as a nurse denied, limited, suspended, probated, revoked, or otherwise disciplined in another jurisdiction on grounds sufficient to cause a license or privilege to be denied, limited, suspended, probated, revoked, or otherwise disciplined in this Commonwealth, including action by another jurisdiction for failure to repay a student loan; </section><section prefix="j">Has violated any of the provisions of this chapter; </section><section prefix="k">Has violated any lawful order or directive previously entered by the board; </section><section prefix="l">Has violated any administrative regulation promulgated by the board; </section><section prefix="m">Has been listed on the nurse aide abuse registry with a substantiated finding of abuse, neglect, or misappropriation of property; or </section><section prefix="n">Has violated the confidentiality of information or knowledge concerning any patient, except as authorized or required by law. </section></section><section prefix="2">All hearings shall be conducted in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. A suspended or revoked license, privilege, or credential may be reinstated at the discretion of the board, and in accordance with regulations promulgated by the board. </section><section prefix="3">The executive director may issue subpoenas to compel the attendance of witnesses and the production of documents in the conduct of an investigation. The subpoenas may be enforced by the Circuit Court as for contempt. Any order or subpoena of the court requiring the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of documentary evidence may be enforced and shall be valid anywhere in this state. </section><section prefix="4">At all hearings on request of the board the Attorney General of this state or one (1) of the assistant attorneys general designated by the Attorney General shall appear and represent the board. </section><section prefix="5">A final order of the board shall be by majority vote thereof. </section><section prefix="6">Any person adversely affected by any final order of the board may obtain a review thereof by filing a written petition for review with the Circuit Court of the county in which the board's offices are located in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section><section prefix="7">If the board substantiates that sexual contact occurred between a nurse and a patient while the patient was under the care of or in a professional relationship with the nurse, the nurse's license, privilege, or credential may be revoked or suspended with mandatory treatment of the nurse as prescribed by the board. The board may require the nurse to pay a specified amount for mental health services for the patient which are needed as a result of the sexual contact. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 58, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 9, effective June 1, 2007; and ch. 182, sec. 60, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 55, sec. 7, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 391, sec. 15, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 26, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1996; and ch. 318, sec. 264, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 265, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1994; ch. 367, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 470, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 128, sec. 10, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 408, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 7, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 10. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/94).  This statute was amended by 1994 Ky. Acts chs. 265 and 470, which were companion bills and are substantively identical. These Acts have been codified together. For the few minor variations between the Acts, Acts ch. 470 prevails under KRS 446.250, as the Act which passed the General Assembly last. 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 367, sec. 9 is not in conflict with these two Acts and has been codified together with them. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30910</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>