<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="161" order_by="161">SCHOOL EMPLOYEES -- TEACHERS' RETIREMENT AND TENURE </unit></structure><section_number>161.048</section_number><catch_line>Alternative certification program -- Purpose -- Options -- Testing and eligibility requirements -- Salary schedule. </catch_line><order_by>048</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The General Assembly hereby finds that: <section prefix="a"><section prefix="1">There are persons who have distinguished themselves through a variety of work and educational experiences that could enrich teaching in Kentucky schools; </section><section prefix="2">There are distinguished scholars who wish to become teachers in Kentucky's public schools, but who did not pursue a teacher preparation program; </section><section prefix="3">There are persons who should be recruited to teach in Kentucky's public schools as they have academic majors, strong verbal skills as shown by a verbal ability test, and deep knowledge of content, characteristics that empirical research identifies as important attributes of quality teachers; </section><section prefix="4">There are persons who need to be recruited to teach in Kentucky schools to meet the diverse cultural and educational needs of students; and </section><section prefix="5">There should be alternative procedures to the traditional teacher preparation programs that qualify persons as teachers. </section></section><section prefix="b">There are hereby established alternative certification program options as described in subsections (2) to (9) of this section. </section><section prefix="c">It is the intent of the General Assembly that the Educational Professional Standards Board inform scholars, persons with exceptional work experience, and persons with diverse backgrounds who have potential as teachers of these options and assist local boards of education in implementing these options and recruitment of individuals who can enhance the education system in Kentucky. </section><section prefix="d">The Education Professional Standards Board shall promulgate administrative regulations establishing standards and procedures for the alternative certification options described in this section. </section></section><section prefix="2">Option 1: Certification of a person with exceptional work experience. An individual who has exceptional work experience and has been offered employment in a local school district shall receive a one (1) year provisional teaching certificate with approval by the Education Professional Standards Board of a joint application by the individual and the employing school district under the following conditions: <section prefix="a">The application contains documentation of all education and work experience; </section><section prefix="b">The candidate has documented ten (10) years of exceptional work experience in the area in which certification is being sought; </section><section prefix="c">The candidate possesses: <section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">A minimum of a bachelor's degree, with a cumulative grade point average of two and five-tenths (2.5) on a four (4) point scale or a grade point average of three (3.0) on a four (4) point scale on the last sixty (60) hours of credit completed, including undergraduate and graduate coursework from a nationally or regionally accredited postsecondary institution; or </section><section prefix="b">A graduate degree with a cumulative grade point average of two and five-tenths (2.5) on a four (4) point scale or a grade point average of three (3.0) on a four (4) point scale on the last sixty (60) hours of credit completed, including undergraduate and graduate coursework from a nationally or regionally accredited postsecondary institution; and </section></section><section prefix="2">An academic major or a passing score on the academic content assessment designated by the Education Professional Standards Board; and </section></section><section prefix="d">The candidate shall participate in the teacher internship program under subsections (5), (6), (7), and (8) of KRS 161.030. After successful completion of the internship, the candidate shall receive a regular professional certificate and shall be subject to certificate renewal requirements the same as any other teacher with a regular professional certificate. </section></section><section prefix="3">Option 2: Certification through a local district training program. A local district or group of districts may seek approval for a training program. The state-approved local district training program is an alternative to the college teacher preparation program as a means of acquiring teacher certification for a teacher at any grade level. The training program may be offered for all teaching certificates approved by Education Professional Standards Board, including interdisciplinary early childhood education, except for specific certificates for teachers of exceptional children. To participate in a state-approved local district alternative training program, the candidate shall: <section prefix="a">Possess a bachelor's degree with a grade point average of two and five tenths (2.5) on a four (4) point scale or, upon approval by the Education Professional Standards Board, at least a grade point average of two (2) on a four (4) point scale if the candidate has exceptional life experience related to teaching and has completed the bachelor's degree at least five (5) years prior to submitting an application to the program. </section><section prefix="b">Pass written tests designated by the Education Professional Standards Board for content knowledge in the specific teaching field of the applicant with minimum scores in each test as set by the Education Professional Standards Board. To be eligible to take a subject field test, the applicant shall have completed a thirty (30) hour major in the academic content area or five (5) years of experience in the academic content area as approved by the Education Professional Standards Board. </section><section prefix="c">Have been offered employment in a school district which has a training program approved by the Education Professional Standards Board. </section><section prefix="d">Upon meeting the participation requirements as established in this subsection, the candidate shall be issued a one (1) year provisional certificate by the Education Professional Standards Board. The regular provisional certificate shall be issued upon satisfactory completion of the program and the teacher testing internship program pursuant to KRS 161.030. </section><section prefix="e">The Education Professional Standards Board may reject the application of any candidate who is judged as not meeting academic requirements comparable to those for students enrolled in Kentucky teacher preparation programs. </section></section><section prefix="4">Option 3: Certification of a professional from a postsecondary institution: A candidate who possesses the following qualifications may receive alternative certification for teaching at any level: <section prefix="a">A master's degree or doctoral degree in the academic content area for which certification is sought; </section><section prefix="b">A minimum of five (5) years of full-time teaching experience, or its equivalent, in the academic content area for which certification is sought in a regionally or nationally accredited institution of higher education; and </section><section prefix="c">Successful completion of the teacher internship requirement imposed under KRS 161.030. </section></section><section prefix="5">Option 4: Certification of an adjunct instructor. A person who has expertise in areas such as art, music, foreign language, drama, science, and other specialty areas may be employed as an adjunct instructor in a part-time position by a local board of education under KRS 161.046. An individual certified as an adjunct instructor shall not be deemed "highly qualified" under the provisions of the federal No Child Left Behind Act of 2001, 20 U.S.C. secs. 6301 et seq. </section><section prefix="6">Option 5: Certification of a veteran of the Armed Forces. The Education Professional Standards Board shall issue a statement of eligibility, valid for five (5) years, to a veteran for teaching at the elementary, secondary, and secondary vocational education levels with the following qualifications: <section prefix="a"><section prefix="1">Discharged or released from active duty under honorable conditions after six (6) or more years of continuous active duty immediately before the discharge or release; or </section><section prefix="2">Completed a total of at least ten (10) years of active duty service, ten (10) years of service officially credited toward armed services retirement, or ten (10) years' combination of such service; </section></section><section prefix="b">At least a bachelor's degree in the content area or closely related area for which certification is sought, issued by a regionally or nationally accredited institution of higher education; </section><section prefix="c">A grade point average of two and five-tenths (2.5) on a four (4) point scale for a bachelor's degree or an advanced degree; and </section><section prefix="d">A passing score on the written exit assessment examination designated by the Education Professional Standards Board for content knowledge. </section></section> Upon an offer of employment by a school district, the eligible veteran shall receive a one (1) year provisional teaching certificate with approval by the Education Professional Standards Board of a joint application by the veteran and the employing school district. During this year, the veteran shall participate in the teacher internship program under subsections (5), (6), (7), and (8) of KRS 161.030. Upon successful completion of the internship program, the veteran shall receive a regular professional certificate. <section prefix="7">Option 6: University alternative program. With approval of the Education Professional Standards Board, a university may provide an alternative program that enrolls students in a postbaccalaureate teacher preparation program concurrently with employment as a teacher in a local school district. A student in the alternative program shall be granted a temporary provisional certificate and shall be a candidate in the Kentucky teacher internship program, notwithstanding provisions of KRS 161.030. A student may not participate in the internship program until the student has successfully completed the assessments required by the board. The temporary provisional certificate shall be valid for a maximum of one (1) year, and may be renewed two (2) additional years, and shall be contingent upon the candidate's continued enrollment in the preparation program and compliance with all requirements established by the board. A professional certificate shall be issued upon the teacher candidate's successful completion of the program, the internship requirements, and all assessments required by the board. </section><section prefix="8">Option 7: Certification of a person in a field other than education to teach in elementary, middle, or secondary programs. This option shall not be limited to teaching in shortage areas. <section prefix="a">An individual certified under provisions of this subsection shall be issued a one (1) year temporary provisional teaching certificate, renewable for a maximum of two (2) additional years with approval of the Education Professional Standards Board provided that the candidate: <section prefix="1">Possesses a bachelor's degree with a declared academic major in the area in which certification is sought and a cumulative grade point average of 3.0 on a 4.0 scale, or a professional or graduate degree in a field related to the area in which certification is sought; </section><section prefix="2">Has a minimum score of five hundred (500) on the verbal section and a minimum score of four (4) on the analytical writing section of the Graduate Record Examination (GRE). In addition, teachers of mathematics and physical and biological sciences shall have a minimum score of four hundred fifty (450) on the quantitative section of the GRE. A candidate who has a professional degree shall be exempt from the requirements of this subparagraph; and </section><section prefix="3">Passes written tests designated by the Education Professional Standards Board for content knowledge in the specific teaching field of the applicant with minimum scores in each test as set by the board. </section></section><section prefix="b">Prior to receiving the temporary provisional certificate or during the first year of the certificate, the teacher shall complete the following: <section prefix="1">For elementary teaching, the individual shall successfully complete the equivalent of a two hundred forty (240) hour institute, based on six (6) hour days for eight (8) weeks. The providers and the content of the institute shall be approved by the Education Professional Standards Board. The content shall include research-based teaching strategies in reading and math, research on child and adolescent growth, knowledge of individual differences, including teaching exceptional children, and methods of classroom management. </section><section prefix="2">For middle and secondary teaching, the individual shall successfully complete the equivalent of a one hundred eighty (180) hour institute, based on six (6) hour days for six (6) weeks. The providers and the content of the institute shall be approved by the Education Professional Standards Board and shall include research-based teaching strategies, research on child and adolescent growth, knowledge of individual differences, including teaching exceptional children, and methods of classroom management. </section></section><section prefix="c">The candidate shall participate in the teacher internship program under subsections (5), (6), (7), and (8) of KRS 161.030. After successful completion of the internship program, the candidate shall receive a regular professional certificate. </section></section><section prefix="9">Option 8: Certification of a Teach for America participant to teach in elementary, middle, or high schools. Nothing in this subsection shall conflict with the participation criteria of the Teach for America program. <section prefix="a">An individual certified under this subsection shall be issued a one (1) year temporary provisional teaching certificate if the candidate: <section prefix="1">Has an offer of employment from a local school district; </section><section prefix="2">Possesses a bachelor's degree; </section><section prefix="3">Successfully completes the summer training institute and ongoing professional development required by Teach for America, including instruction in goal-oriented, standards-based instruction, diagnosing and assessing students, lesson planning and instructional delivery, classroom management, maximizing learning for diverse students, and teaching methodologies; and </section><section prefix="4">Successfully passes written tests designated by the Education Professional Standards Board for content knowledge in the specific teaching field of the candidate with minimum scores in each test as set by the board. </section></section><section prefix="b">The temporary provisional certificate granted under paragraph (a) of this subsection may be renewed two (2) times with a recommendation of the superintendent and approval of the Education Professional Standards Board. </section><section prefix="c">A Teach for America participant who is approved for a second renewal of his or her temporary provisional certificate under paragraph (b) of this subsection may participate in the internship program under KRS 161.030. </section><section prefix="d">A Teach for America participant shall be issued a professional certificate upon the participant's successful completion of the internship program and assessments relating to teaching of subject matter required by the Education Professional Standards Board under KRS 161.030. </section><section prefix="e">Notwithstanding any statute or administrative regulation to the contrary, a teacher certified under this subsection shall have ten (10) years from the date that the teacher successfully completed the internship program to complete a master's degree or fifth year program, or the equivalent as specified by the Education Professional Standards Board in administrative regulation. </section><section prefix="f">Alternative certification under this subsection shall be considered a pilot program and shall be an option from July 15, 2010, until the federal Race to the Top funding program under Sections 14005 and 14006 of the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009, Pub. L. No. 111-5, is completed, except that the Education Professional Standards Board may promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to make this a permanent option. </section></section><section prefix="10">A public school teacher certified under subsections (2) to (9) of this section shall be placed on the local district salary schedule for the rank corresponding to the degree held by the teacher. </section><section prefix="11">Veterans who were discharged or released from active duty under honorable conditions after six (6) or more years of continuous active duty immediately before the discharge or release, and who have at least four (4) years of occupational experience in the area in which they seek certification as a vocational industrial education teacher, shall apply for certification under and meet the requirements of the administrative regulations promulgated by the Education Professional Standards Board. </section><section prefix="12">Subsections (1) to (3) of this section notwithstanding, a candidate who possesses the following qualifications may receive certification for teaching programs for exceptional students: <section prefix="a">An out-of-state license to teach exceptional students; </section><section prefix="b">A bachelor's or master's degree in the certification area or closely related area for which certification is sought; and </section><section prefix="c">Successful completion of the teacher internship requirement required under KRS 161.030. </section></section><section prefix="13">A teacher who is fully certified in Kentucky and who is seeking an additional certification is not required to repeat the Kentucky teacher internship program. </section><section prefix="14">Under KRS 161.030(5), a candidate for alternative certification may serve his or her internship in a nonpublic school. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 177, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 2, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 3, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 161, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 514, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 589, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996; and ch. 343, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. II, sec. 58, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3837</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>