<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="177" order_by="177">STATE AND FEDERAL HIGHWAYS -- LIMITED ACCESS FACILITIES -- TURNPIKES -- ROAD BONDS -- BILLBOARDS -- RECYCLERS </unit></structure><section_number>177.037</section_number><catch_line>Community boundary signs -- Commemorative boundary signs for city or unincorporated urban place.   </catch_line><order_by>037</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department of Highways may install and maintain signs recognizing the boundary of a city, town, or community whether incorporated or unincorporated. These signs shall be installed regardless of whether the community has a post office, if the Department of Highways had previously erected signs recognizing the city, town, or community. The signs shall be placed at the official community boundaries. If the community does not have official boundaries, the signs shall be installed at the community boundaries as determined by the built-up area. </section><section prefix="2">The department shall install and maintain signs at the boundaries of any city or an unincorporated urban place as defined in KRS 177.366, regardless of whether the city or unincorporated urban place has a post office or zip code, if the city or unincorporated urban place: <section prefix="a">Submits a written request for not more than two (2) signs: <section prefix="1">To honor the birthplace of a person important to the city or unincorporated urban place; or </section><section prefix="2">To honor an event or accomplishment important to the city or unincorporated urban place; and </section></section><section prefix="b">Agrees to pay for the actual cost to make and install the signs. </section></section><section prefix="3">The department shall work with the city or unincorporated urban place to determine the appropriate place to install the signs required under subsection (2) of this section. If an agreement cannot be reached on the appropriate place to install the signs, the site selected by the city or unincorporated urban place shall take precedence and the department shall not prohibit and shall not delay the installation of the signs. </section><section prefix="4">Each city or unincorporated urban place requesting a sign under subsection (2) of this section shall be limited to two (2) signs. Requests for additional signs authorized under subsection (2) of this section in excess of two (2) by the same city or unincorporated urban place shall be consolidated into a single sign. </section><section prefix="5">All statutes to the contrary notwithstanding, the Transportation Cabinet shall amend its policies and administrative regulations in effect on July 15, 2002, to comply with the provisions of this section, and shall not subsequently adopt new policies or promulgate new administrative regulations to the contrary. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 248, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 298, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43833</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>