<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="75" order_by="75">FIRE PROTECTION DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>75.180</section_number><catch_line>Duties and powers of chief and members -- Reimbursement of private owners for water used. </catch_line><order_by>180</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The chief, assistant chief, or highest officer present at the fires answered by his department shall investigate their causes. He may examine witnesses, compel the testimony of witnesses, administer oaths, compel production of evidence and make arrests as provided in KRS 75.160. He may enter any building at all reasonable times for the purpose of examining the building if, in his opinion the building is in danger of fire. He shall report his findings, when requested, to the board, Kentucky Inspection Bureau, and state fire marshal. </section><section prefix="2">The chief of the fire department shall direct and control the operation of the fire department and the control of the members in the discharge of their duties. He, and members of the fire department, shall have access to and the use of all cisterns, fireplugs, the waters of the waterworks of private persons and cisterns of private persons for the purpose of extinguishing fires and shall have the power to examine these water supplies at all reasonable times to see that they are in condition for use in case of fire. The chief shall have control of all hose, buildings, engines and other equipment provided for the fire department under direction of the board, or those authorized by the board to exercise this direction, and shall perform such other duties prescribed by the board not inconsistent with law. Upon application within ten (10) days to the board, any owner of property where water is used for firefighting shall be reimbursed in a reasonable amount by the board for water used. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 69, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 184, sec. 10. -- Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 207, sec. 9. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24453</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>