<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="324" order_by="324">REAL ESTATE BROKERS AND SALESMEN </unit></structure><section_number>324.141</section_number><catch_line>Reciprocal licensing between states -- Consent to service of process by nonresident applicant. </catch_line><order_by>141</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">An individual who holds an active real estate license issued by another jurisdiction within the United States may apply for a Kentucky license by first: <section prefix="1">Completing the application forms; </section><section prefix="2">Passing the state law portion of the licensing examination; and </section><section prefix="3">Fulfilling all other pre-license qualifications as outlined in this chapter. </section></section><section prefix="b">The commission shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to establish the procedures for implementing paragraph (a) of this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="2">All individuals who have held a real estate license in another jurisdiction, whether the license is currently active or canceled, shall be required to furnish, as part of his or her application for a Kentucky license, a certification of good standing, issued by the jurisdiction. The document shall include the individual's license history and any disciplinary information available from that jurisdiction. </section><section prefix="3">Every nonresident applicant shall file an irrevocable consent stating that legal actions may be commenced against the applicant in the proper court of any county of this state in which a cause of action may arise in which the plaintiff may reside, by the service of any process or pleading authorized by the laws of this state on the commission, the consent stipulating and agreeing that service of process or pleadings on the commission shall be taken and held in all courts to be as valid and binding as if service had been made upon the applicant in the State of Kentucky. Any process or pleadings served upon the commission shall be by duplicate copies, one (1) of which shall be filed in the office of the commission and the other immediately forwarded by certified mail, return receipt requested, to the main office of the applicant against which the process or pleadings are directed. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 58, sec. 4, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 448, sec. 14, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 304, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 141, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 196, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31574</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>