<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171">STATE LIBRARIES -- LIBRARIANS -- STATE ARCHIVES AND RECORDS </unit></structure><section_number>171.3961</section_number><catch_line>Credit against individual, corporate, and limited liability tax for certified rehabilitation to a qualifying certified historic structure within jurisdiction of consolidated local government or urban-county government. </catch_line><order_by>3961</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For taxable years beginning on or after January 1, 2014, a taxpayer completing a certified rehabilitation to a certified historic structure shall be allowed a credit against the taxes imposed by KRS 141.020 or 141.040 and 141.0401, with the ordering of credits as provided in KRS 141.0205, or KRS 136.505 if: <section prefix="a">The certified historic structure is located within the jurisdiction of a consolidated local government or urban-county government; </section><section prefix="b">The amount of qualified rehabilitation expenses exceeds fifteen million dollars ($15,000,000); </section><section prefix="c">The certified historic structure is located within one-half (1/2) mile of a tax increment financing development area which has received at least preliminary approval under KRS 65.490 or 154.30-050; and </section><section prefix="d">Substantial rehabilitation of the certified historic structure begins prior to July 1, 2015. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">The credit shall: <section prefix="1">Equal the percentage of qualified rehabilitation expenses as provided in KRS 171.397(1)(a); </section><section prefix="2">Only apply to the first thirty million dollars ($30,000,000) of qualified rehabilitation expenses; and </section><section prefix="3">Be refundable and transferable. </section></section><section prefix="b">Any projects approved for a credit under this section shall not be subject to any caps established by KRS 171.397 and shall not be considered in determining whether the certified rehabilitation credit cap has been met in any year. </section></section><section prefix="3">The taxpayer seeking the credit shall file the applications for preliminary determination and final determination as provided by KRS 171.397(2). </section><section prefix="4">The total approved credit shall be available over a four (4) year period and the maximum credit which may be claimed in a taxable year shall not exceed twenty-five percent (25%) of the total approved credit. </section><section prefix="5">The provisions of KRS 171.397(9) to (14) shall also apply to this section. </section></text><history> Created 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 20, effective July 15, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43413</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>