<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="104" order_by="104">FLOOD CONTROL AND WATER USAGE </unit></structure><section_number>104.520</section_number><catch_line>Boundaries of district -- Determination of -- When cities with population of 8,000 or more may be included.   </catch_line><order_by>520</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When the petition is filed with the secretary, he shall investigate at once the boundary of the district proposed to be organized, and may, at the cost of the petitioners, cause to be made surveys necessary to establish with reasonable accuracy a boundary that will, in his judgment, accomplish the purpose sought by the creation of the district in a practicable and workable manner, and that will be sufficiently comprehensive to avoid confusion or interference with any other similar district then existing or that may be created. The boundary established by the secretary need not follow the boundary proposed by the petitioners, but if the boundary established by the secretary results in a material change from that proposed in the original petition the petitioners shall secure, in case of a larger or smaller area, the signatures of seventy percent (70%) of the freeholders or owners in the area as established by the secretary. </section><section prefix="2">Should it be found desirable to include in a flood control district all or a portion of a city with a population equal to or greater than eight thousand (8,000) based upon the most recent federal decennial census, the governing body of such city shall determine by ordinance whether the city or portion thereof shall be included in the district, or whether the city shall bind itself to pay the taxes levied for the benefits of the district in such area. </section></text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 201, effective January 1, 2015. -- Created 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 42, sec. 8. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:11</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43786</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>