<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>271B.8-030</section_number><catch_line>Number and election of directors.   </catch_line><order_by>8-030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A board of directors shall consist of one (1) or more individuals, with the number specified in or fixed in accordance with the articles of incorporation or bylaws. </section><section prefix="2">If a board of directors has power to fix or change the number of directors, the board may increase or decrease by thirty percent (30%) or less the number of directors last approved by the shareholders, but only the shareholders may increase or decrease by more than thirty percent (30%) the number of directors last approved by the shareholders. </section><section prefix="3">The articles of incorporation or bylaws may establish a variable range for the size of the board of directors by fixing a minimum and maximum number of directors. If a variable range is established, the number of directors may be fixed or changed from time to time, within the minimum and maximum, by the shareholders or the board of directors. After shares are issued, only the shareholders may change the range for the size of the board or change from a fixed to a variable-range size board or vice versa. </section><section prefix="4">Directors shall be elected at the first annual shareholders' meeting and at each annual meeting thereafter unless their terms are staggered under KRS 271B.8-060. </section><section prefix="5">Every director of a corporation, by acceptance of election or appointment as a director, including by service, shall be deemed to have consented to the jurisdiction of the courts of the Commonwealth of Kentucky for any action by, in the name of, or on behalf of the corporation. </section></text><history>Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 89, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 70, effective January 1, 1989. </history><metadata><effective>July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:23</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40428</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>