<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="216" order_by="216">HEALTH FACILITIES AND SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>216.925</section_number><catch_line>Midlevel health care practitioner.   </catch_line><order_by>925</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A midlevel health care practitioner may be qualified by: <section prefix="a">Being a health professional licensed or certified by a body granted such authority by the Kentucky Revised Statutes and passing the qualifying examination; or </section><section prefix="b">Working under the supervision of a family physician in a network for a minimum of five (5) years and passing the qualifying examination. </section></section><section prefix="2">To maintain a certification in good standing, a midlevel health care practitioner shall: <section prefix="a">Complete annually a minimum of ten (10) medical education hours recognized by the board; and </section><section prefix="b">Retake and pass the qualifying examination at least once every five (5) years. </section></section><section prefix="3">Midlevel health care practitioners may assist physicians in networks as follows: <section prefix="a">Provide management of a limited number of chronic conditions for which protocols have been approved by the board and treatment plans prescribed by a network physician. Each patient for whom services are provided by a midlevel health care practitioner shall be examined at least twice a year by a network physician. During such examinations, the health care needs of the patient and the management regimen maintained by the midlevel health care practitioner shall be evaluated and documented in the patient's medical chart. No midlevel health care practitioner shall see a patient for initial consideration of a patient's medical problem nor shall a midlevel health care practitioner attempt to manage or treat a patient for an acute condition. Every encounter between a midlevel health care practitioner and a patient shall be reviewed by a medical chart auditor on the day of the encounter and any deviation from the treatment plan or protocol shall be immediately reported to the supervising network physician; </section><section prefix="b">Cause maintenance medications used in the treatment of chronic conditions to be dispensed to network patients solely within the confines of the network in accord with the protocols and formulary approved by the board and the treatment plan prescribed by a network physician at a charge not to exceed the cost of the medication plus a one dollar ($1) dispensing fee; </section><section prefix="c">Make referrals in accordance with the linkage agreements and follow-up on referrals to assure they did occur; </section><section prefix="d">Provide patient education in accordance with the treatment plan; and </section><section prefix="e">Provide treatment as defined herein in either the primary facility of the network or in network extension clinics, if physician consultation is immediately available in person or by telephone. Midlevel health care practitioners shall not provide treatment in hospitals, skilled-nursing homes, nursing homes, intermediate-care facilities, personal care homes, family care homes, outpatient clinics, ambulatory care facilities, ambulatory surgical centers, emergency care centers, ambulances, hospices, community facilities for mental health or individuals with an intellectual disability, home health agencies, and kidney disease treatment centers. A midlevel health care practitioner shall not replace existing licensed, registered, or certified health care personnel. </section></section><section prefix="4">Midlevel health care practitioners shall be utilized to expand the availability of health services. They shall not be used to expand the economic base of any network. </section></text><history>Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 105, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 482, sec. 6, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40833</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>