<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="212" order_by="212">LOCAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>212.170</section_number><catch_line>Appointment of health officers -- Assistant -- Employees -- Appeals. </catch_line><order_by>170</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The county board of health of each county having a county department of health shall, subject to the approval of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, appoint a health officer who shall, subject to merit system provisions, hold office at the pleasure of both the county board and the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. </section><section prefix="2">A health officer may: <section prefix="a">With the approval of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services and the local boards of health concerned, serve in such capacity for more than one county; and </section><section prefix="b">At the discretion of the local board, act as chief administrative officer of the board. </section></section><section prefix="3">A health officer may appoint an administrative assistant for each county served by him subject to the approval of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. An administrative assistant shall exercise such duties as may be delegated to him by the health officer. </section><section prefix="4">A health officer may employ and fix the compensation of, by contract or otherwise, subject to the approval of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, all medical, technical, clerical, professional, and other employees necessary for the maintenance and operation of the local health department in accordance with standards and merit system provisions prescribed by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. </section><section prefix="5">In the absence of a local health officer, the secretary for health and family services or his duly appointed representative shall serve as health officer for the county concerned. </section><section prefix="6">Appeals under the local health department merit system shall be conducted in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 399, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 350, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 114, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 228, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(1) and (11). -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 96, sec. 2. -- Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 209, sec. 1. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 153, sec. 5. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2054a-1, 2054a-10, 2054a-15, 2054a-18, 2054a-21, 2055. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><lrc-note>.  By virtue of KRS 212.350 to 212.620, enacted in 1942, this section no longer applies to counties containing a city of the first class. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8585</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>