<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="13" order_by="13">A ADMINISTRATIVE REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>13A.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter.   </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Administrative body" means each state board, bureau, cabinet, commission, department, authority, officer, or other entity, except the General Assembly and the Court of Justice, authorized by law to promulgate administrative regulations; </section><section prefix="2">"Administrative regulation" means each statement of general applicability promulgated by an administrative body that implements, interprets, or prescribes law or policy, or describes the organization, procedure, or practice requirements of any administrative body. The term includes an existing administrative regulation, a new administrative regulation, an emergency administrative regulation, an administrative regulation in contemplation of a statute, the amendment or repeal of an existing administrative regulation, but does not include: <section prefix="a">Statements concerning only the internal management of an administrative body and not affecting private rights or procedures available to the public; </section><section prefix="b">Declaratory rulings; </section><section prefix="c">Intradepartmental memoranda not in conflict with KRS 13A.130; </section><section prefix="d">Statements relating to acquisition of property for highway purposes and statements relating to the construction or maintenance of highways; or </section><section prefix="e">Rules, regulations, and policies of the governing boards of institutions that make up the postsecondary education system defined in KRS 164.001 pertaining to students attending or applicants to the institutions, to faculty and staff of the respective institutions, or to the control and maintenance of land and buildings occupied by the respective institutions; </section></section><section prefix="3">"Adopted" means that an administrative regulation has become effective in accordance with the provisions of this chapter; </section><section prefix="4">"Authorizing signature" means the signature of the head of the administrative body authorized by statute to promulgate administrative regulations; </section><section prefix="5">"Commission" means the Legislative Research Commission; </section><section prefix="6">"Effective" means that an administrative regulation has completed the legislative subcommittee review established by KRS 13A.290, 13A.330, and 13A.331; </section><section prefix="7">"Federal mandate" means any federal constitutional, legislative or executive law or order which requires or permits any administrative body to engage in regulatory activities which impose compliance standards, reporting requirements, recordkeeping, or similar responsibilities upon entities in the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="8">"Federal mandate comparison" means a written statement containing the information required by KRS 13A.245; </section><section prefix="9">"Filed" or "promulgated" means that an administrative regulation, or other document required to be filed by this chapter, has been submitted to the Commission in accordance with this chapter; </section><section prefix="10">"Government" means and includes a city, county, urban-county, charter county, consolidated local government, special district, or a quasi-governmental body authorized by the Kentucky Revised Statutes or a local ordinance; </section><section prefix="11">"Proposed administrative regulation" means an administrative regulation that: <section prefix="a">Has been filed by an administrative body; and </section><section prefix="b">Has not become effective or been withdrawn; </section></section><section prefix="12">"Regulatory impact analysis" means a written statement containing the provisions required by KRS 13A.240; </section><section prefix="13">"Small business" means a business entity, including its affiliates, that: <section prefix="a">Is independently owned and operated; and </section><section prefix="b"><section prefix="1">Employs fewer than one hundred fifty (150) full-time employees or their equivalent; or </section><section prefix="2">Has gross annual sales of less than six million dollars ($6,000,000). </section></section></section><section prefix="14">"Statement of consideration" means the document required by KRS 13A.280 in which the administrative body summarizes the comments received, its responses to those comments, and the action taken, if any, as a result of those comments and responses; </section><section prefix="15">"Subcommittee" means the Administrative Regulation Review Subcommittee, any other subcommittee of the Legislative Research Commission, an interim joint committee, or a House and Senate standing committee; and </section><section prefix="16">"Tiering" means the tailoring of regulatory requirements to fit the particular circumstances surrounding regulated entities. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 138, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 2, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 288, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 406, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 38, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 30, effective May 30, 1997. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 180, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 410, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 516, sec. 13, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 417, sec. 1, effective April 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40707</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>