<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.994</section_number><catch_line>Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>994</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any purchaser of soybeans, or corn, or small grains who violates, or fails or refuses to comply with the provisions of KRS 247.510 to 247.595 or KRS 247.5061 to 247.5095, or KRS 247.6001 to 247.6035, shall upon conviction be fined not less than twenty-five dollars ($25) nor more than fifty dollars ($50) for each offense. Each day of the violation, or failing or refusing to comply with the provisions of KRS 247.510 to 247.595 or KRS 247.5061 to 247.5095, or KRS 247.6001 to 247.6035 shall constitute a separate offense. </section><section prefix="2">Any operator of a livestock market, meat packing establishment, or slaughter establishment who violates or fails or refuses to comply with the provisions of KRS 247.610 to 247.685 shall upon conviction be fined not less than twenty-five dollars ($25) nor more than fifty dollars ($50) for each offense.  Each day of the violation, or failing, or refusing to comply with the provisions of KRS 247.610 to 247.685 shall constitute a separate offense. </section><section prefix="3">Any operator of a tobacco warehouse, tobacco manufacturing establishment, or tobacco dealer who violates or fails or refuses to comply with the provisions of KRS 247.710 to 247.785 shall upon conviction be fined not less than twenty-five dollars ($25) nor more than fifty dollars ($50) for each offense.  Each failure to withhold or refusal to comply with the provisions of KRS 247.710 to 247.785 shall constitute a separate offense. </section><section prefix="4">Any egg handler who violates, or fails, or refuses to comply with the provisions of KRS 247.850 to 247.865 shall, upon conviction, be fined not less than twenty-five dollars ($25) nor more than fifty dollars ($50) for each offense.  Each day of violating, or failing, or refusing to comply with the provisions of KRS 247.850 to 247.865 shall constitute a separate offense. </section></text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 223, sec. 19, effective July 13, 1990; and ch. 397, sec. 19, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 180, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 18, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 9, sec. 17; and ch. 265, sec. 17. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 83, sec. 19. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><lrc-note>(7/13/90).  This section was amended by two 1990 Acts which do not appear to be in conflict and have been compiled together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11893</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>