<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="344" order_by="344">CIVIL RIGHTS </unit></structure><section_number>344.080</section_number><catch_line>Regulation of advertisement for employment. </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text>It is an unlawful practice for an employer, labor organization, licensing agency, or employment agency to print or publish or cause to be printed or published a notice or advertisement relating to employment by such an employer or membership in or any classification or referral for employment by the employment or licensing agency, indicating any preference, limitation, specification, or discrimination, based on race, color, religion, national origin, sex, or age forty (40) and over, or because the person is a qualified individual with a disability, except that such a notice or advertisement may indicate a preference, limitation, or specification based on religion, national origin, sex, or age forty (40) and over, or because the person is a qualified individual with a disability, when religion, national origin, sex, or age forty (40) and over, or because the person is a qualified individual with a disability, is a bona fide occupational qualification for employment. </text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 378, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 282, sec. 9, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 245, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 7. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 2, Art. 3, sec. 306. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32610</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>