<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="248" order_by="248">TOBACCO </unit></structure><section_number>248.430</section_number><catch_line>Notice of sales and producers to be posted -- False notice prohibited. </catch_line><order_by>430</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person who receives or undertakes to receive or take care of leaf tobacco for sale at public auction, whether with or without compensation, shall post or cause to be posted, a notice in a conspicuous place upon his premises, stating the number of pounds in the aggregate, actually sold, and the average price per pound received on account of each day's sale. He shall post the notice not later than 9:00 a.m. on the day following the sale. He shall also, not less than thirty (30) minutes prior to such a sale, post at a point in the office of his warehouse, convenient and accessible for public inspection, a typewritten or printed list showing the true name and post office address of the owner and producer and the number of pounds of tobacco of each person whose tobacco will that day be offered for sale in the warehouse. No tobacco shall be delivered to or received by any warehouse for sale at public auction, unless the true names and post office addresses of the producer and owner of the tobacco are furnished the warehouse by the person delivering the tobacco. He shall also post on the outside of the scale house and in the farmer's waiting room, if such places are in the warehouse, a schedule setting forth the rates of all commissions, fees, discounts and deductions.  </section><section prefix="2">No person shall, in the notice required by subsection (1), falsify the actual number of pounds sold or the average price of the tobacco sold, or falsely list the name, post office address or number of pounds of tobacco of any producer or owner whose tobacco will that day be offered for sale, or furnish a false name or address of the owner or producer to any warehouse.  </section></text><history>Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 30, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs 4814b-1, 4814b-2, 4814b-4. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11943</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>