<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.025</section_number><catch_line>Prohibitions relating to employment of entities providing architectural services and construction management services on capital construction projects -- Effect of violation -- Best value procurement criteria -- Exception. </catch_line><order_by>025</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Employ" means to hire, retain, or otherwise contract with an individual or entity for goods or services; </section><section prefix="b">"Local government" means a city, county, charter county government, urban-county government, consolidated local government, or a special district; </section><section prefix="c">"Construction manager" means a person who coordinates and communicates the entire project process, clarifying cost and time consequences of design decisions as well as clarifying construction feasibility, and who manages the bidding, awarding, and construction phases of the project; </section><section prefix="d">"Design-build" means a system of contracting under which one (1) entity performs both architecture/engineering and construction under one (1) single contract; and </section><section prefix="e">"Best value" means a procurement in which the decision is based on the primary objective of meeting the specific business requirements and best interests of the local government. These decisions shall be based on objective and quantifiable criteria that shall include price and that have been communicated to the offerors as set forth in the invitation for bids or request for proposals. Every invitation for bids or request for proposals shall provide that an item equal to that named or described in the specifications may be furnished. The specification may identify a sole brand in cases where, in the written opinion of the chief procurement officer, documented unique and valid conditions require compatibility, continuity, or conformity with established standards. An item shall be considered equal to the item named or described if, in the opinion of the owner and the design professional responsible for the specifications: <section prefix="1">It is at least equal in quality, durability, appearance, strength, design, and other criteria deemed appropriate; </section><section prefix="2">It will perform at least equally the function imposed by the general design for the public work being contracted for or the material being purchased; and </section><section prefix="3">It conforms substantially to the detailed requirements for the item in the specifications. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">A local government shall not employ the same entity to provide both architectural services and construction management services on the same capital construction project. No local government shall knowingly employ an officer, employee, or agent of, or an immediate family member of an officer, employee, or agent of: <section prefix="a">The architectural firm that provided the architectural services to also provide construction management services for the same capital construction project for which the architectural firm provided architectural services; or </section><section prefix="b">The construction management firm that provided the construction management services to also provide architectural services for the same capital construction project for which the construction management firm provided construction management services. </section></section><section prefix="3">A violation of subsection (2) of this section shall suspend the local government from receiving any financial assistance from the state, or any state agency, with respect to the project for which the architectural or construction management firm was employed until the matter is resolved. </section><section prefix="4">Local governments initiating a capital construction project shall incorporate, or shall require architects or construction managers in the employment of the local government to incorporate, best value procurement criteria in all invitations for bids or requests for proposals as provided for in subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="5">Nothing in this section shall prohibit a local government from using design-build as a method of providing for capital construction services as long as best value contracting principles are followed as specified in subsection (1) of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23321</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>