<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="341" order_by="341">UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>341.060</section_number><catch_line>Employing unit. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this chapter, unless the context clearly requires otherwise, "employing unit" means any individual or type of organization, including any partnership, association, society, trust, estate, joint-stock company, corporation, insurance company, whether any of these are domestic or foreign, or the receiver, trustee in bankruptcy, trustee or the legal representative of a deceased person, or this state or any department, division, administrative unit, political subdivision or municipality thereof, which has or subsequent to January 1, 1936, had one (1) or more workers performing services for it within this state, or one (1) or more workers performing services for it in covered employment in any state, or any successor to any employing unit defined in this subsection. </section><section prefix="2">All workers performing service within this state for any employing unit which maintains two (2) or more separate establishments within this state shall be deemed to be employed by a single employing unit for all purposes of this chapter. </section><section prefix="3">For purposes of this chapter agricultural workers who are members of a crew furnished by a crew leader to perform agricultural labor for another person shall be deemed to be employed by such crew leader as the employing unit provided that: <section prefix="a">Such crew leader holds a valid certificate of registration under the Farm Labor Contractor Registration Act of 1963; or </section><section prefix="b">Substantially all the members of such crew operate or maintain tractors, mechanized harvesting or cropdusting equipment, or any other mechanized equipment, which is provided by such crew leader; and </section><section prefix="c">Such individual is not an employee of such other person within the meaning of paragraph (a). </section></section><section prefix="4">For purposes of this chapter, if an individual is furnished by a crew leader to perform agricultural labor for another person and who is not treated as an employee of such crew leader under subsection (3) such other person, and not the crew leader, shall be treated as the employing unit of such individual; and <section prefix="a">Such other person shall be treated as having paid cash remuneration to such individual in an amount equal to the amount of cash remuneration paid to such individual by the crew leader (either on his behalf or on behalf of such other person) for the agricultural labor performed for such other person. </section></section><section prefix="5">For purposes of this section, the term "crew leader" means an individual who: <section prefix="a">Furnishes individuals to perform agricultural labor for any other person, </section><section prefix="b">Pays (either on his behalf or on behalf of such other person) the individuals so furnished by him for the agricultural labor performed by them, and </section><section prefix="c">Has not entered into a written agreement with such other person under which such individual is designated as an employee of such other person. </section></section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 389, sec. 6, effective July 1, 1978. -- Amended 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4748g-3. </history><metadata><effective>July 1, 1978</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32237</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>