<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.38-199</section_number><catch_line>Coverage for newly-born child. </catch_line><order_by>38-199</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All health maintenance organization contracts issued by health maintenance organizations, regardless of whether the contracts are for nonfamily or family coverage, shall provide that health insurance benefits shall be payable with respect to a newly-born child of the subscribed from the moment of birth. </section><section prefix="2">The coverage for newly-born children shall consist of coverage of injury or sickness including the necessary care and treatment of medically-diagnosed congenital defects and birth abnormalities. </section><section prefix="3">If payment of a specific premium or fee is required to provide coverage for a child, the policy or contract may require that the notification of birth of a newly-born child and payment of the required premium or fees must be furnished to the health maintenance organization within thirty-one (31) days after the date of birth in order to have the coverage continued beyond such thirty-one (31) days. </section><section prefix="4">The requirements of this section shall apply to all contracts delivered or issued for delivery in this state on and after July 15, 1994. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 93, sec. 14, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 18, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:01</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30003</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>