<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="201" order_by="201">JEFFERSON COUNTY CHILDREN'S HOME </unit></structure><section_number>201.160</section_number><catch_line>Appropriations for purchase of property -- Right to alienate property. </catch_line><order_by>160</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In order to provide money for the purchase of property and the construction and equipment of buildings for the home, the fiscal court of the county may make an annual appropriation from the general fund of the county, and the legislative body of the city of the first class may make an annual appropriation from the general fund of the city. The appropriations, when in the judgment of the fiscal court and the legislative body of the city reasonably necessary for such purposes, shall be made by the county and the city in such amounts, in such proportion and upon such terms as the fiscal court and the legislative body may agree and provide. Moneys so appropriated may be paid over to the board in regular monthly installments. </section><section prefix="2">Whenever the board is able to raise sufficient funds for carrying out the purposes of this chapter by the use, lease, sale, exchange, mortgage or pledge of property which has been conveyed to the board, the appropriations mentioned in subsection (1) of this section shall not be made. The action of the board in making such sale, exchange, mortgage or pledge, must be approved by the county judge/executive and the mayor of such city. </section><section prefix="3">The appropriations made under this section shall not be expended by the board for any purpose other than that provided in subsection (1) of this section. </section></text><history>Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 169, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1954. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 938b-4, 938b-6. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1954</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7356</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>