<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171">STATE LIBRARIES -- LIBRARIANS -- STATE ARCHIVES AND RECORDS </unit></structure><section_number>171.800</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky African-American Heritage Commission -- Members -- Officers -- Meetings -- Funding -- Program established. </catch_line><order_by>800</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky African-American Heritage Commission is hereby established to perform the functions specified in KRS 171.805. </section><section prefix="2">The membership of the commission shall consist of three (3) ex officio members and seventeen (17) members who derive from geographically diverse areas of the state and who represent various heritage interests as follows: <section prefix="a">The secretary of the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet, or the secretary's designee to serve ex officio; </section><section prefix="b">The president of Kentucky State University, or the president's designee to serve ex officio; </section><section prefix="c">The director of the Kentucky Heritage Council, or the director's designee to serve ex officio; </section><section prefix="d">Four (4) members from institutions of higher education; </section><section prefix="e">One (1) member from the preservation community; </section><section prefix="f">One (1) member from the arts community; and </section><section prefix="g">Eleven (11) members from the public-at-large. </section></section><section prefix="3">Appointed members shall be appointed by the Governor and shall serve for terms of four (4) years. Any vacancies shall be filled by appointment of the Governor for the remainder of the unexpired term. </section><section prefix="4">Commission members shall receive no compensation for their services but may be reimbursed for actual and necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their duties. </section><section prefix="5">From the commission membership, the Governor shall appoint a chairman and a vice chairman of the commission. The commission may elect by majority vote other officers deemed necessary. </section><section prefix="6">The commission shall meet at the call of the chairman, but not less often than three times during each calendar year. A majority of the members appointed to the commission shall constitute a quorum. </section><section prefix="7">The commission shall be attached to the Kentucky Heritage Council for administrative purposes. </section><section prefix="8">The commission may accept grants or raise funds from any available source, public or private, to accomplish its duties and responsibilities. Committees may be formed at the discretion of the chairman. </section><section prefix="9">The African-American Heritage Program is established as a branch within the Kentucky Heritage Division, whose responsibilities shall include providing staff services needed to perform its duties under KRS 171.805. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 47, effective June 25, 2009. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 241, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><lrc-note> (6/20/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 95, 97, 98, 99, 123, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4863</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>