<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.1-524</section_number><catch_line>Notification to local governments and public of proposed corrective action plan -- Comment period -- Public hearing. </catch_line><order_by>1-524</order_by><text><section prefix="1">On or before the date that an applicant submits a corrective action plan to the cabinet, the applicant shall: <section prefix="a">Notify local government units affected by the remediation of the provisions of the corrective action plan; </section><section prefix="b">Provide a copy of the corrective action plan to at least one (1) public library in any county affected by the remediation; </section><section prefix="c">Submit for publication in a newspaper of general circulation in the county or counties where the property is located, a notice requesting public comment on the corrective action plan, and submit to the cabinet a copy of the notice as published, within ten (10) days of its publication; and </section><section prefix="d">Post a sign on the property stating that the site is undergoing remediation and providing information on where and when the corrective action plan is available for public review and comment. </section></section><section prefix="2">A comment period of at least thirty (30) days shall follow publication of the notice. During the comment period, any person may submit written comments to the cabinet concerning the corrective action plan and may request a public hearing. The cabinet may hold a public hearing if the request is made. </section><section prefix="3">The cabinet may hold a public hearing in any geographical area affected by the remediation on the question of whether to approve or deny the corrective action plan. </section><section prefix="4">The cabinet shall consider all written comments and public testimony prior to taking any action. </section></text><history> Created 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 128, sec. 8, effective June 21, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> June 21, 2001 </effective><former-codification>KRS 224.01-524. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41614</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>