<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="317" order_by="317">B ESTHETICIANS </unit></structure><section_number>317B.045</section_number><catch_line>Denial, suspension, probation, or revocation of license -- Grounds -- Administrative fine -- Hearing -- Mediation.   </catch_line><order_by>045</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board may refuse to issue or renew a license, or may suspend, revoke, impose probationary conditions upon, impose an administrative fine, issue a written reprimand or admonishment, or any combination thereof regarding proof of any applicant's or licensee's: <section prefix="a">Conviction of a felony; </section><section prefix="b">Gross malpractice or incompetence; </section><section prefix="c">Mental or physical health that would endanger public health or safety; </section><section prefix="d">False or deceptive practice or misrepresentation including advertising; </section><section prefix="e">Practicing in an unlicensed salon or in a salon knowing that the practice is not in compliance with this chapter or the administrative regulations of the board promulgated pursuant to this chapter; </section><section prefix="f">Immoral conduct, unprofessional conduct, or a violation of the code of ethics; </section><section prefix="g">Teaching in an unlicensed school or in a school knowing that the school is not in compliance with this chapter or the administrative regulations of the board promulgated pursuant to KRS 317B.010 to 317B.060; or </section><section prefix="h">Failure to comply with this chapter or the administrative regulations promulgated by the board. </section></section><section prefix="2">Payments in lieu of suspension collected by the board shall be deposited in the State Treasury and credited to the trust and agency account of the board. </section><section prefix="3">The board may require retesting of any licensee upon proper showing of gross malpractice or incompetence on the part of the licensee. </section><section prefix="4">Three (3) years from the date of a revocation, any person whose license has been revoked may petition the board for reinstatement. The board shall investigate the petition and may reinstate the license upon a finding that the individual has complied with any terms prescribed by the board, including retesting, and is again able to competently engage in the practice of esthetics. </section><section prefix="5">At any time during the investigative or hearing processes, the board may enter into an agreed order or accept an assurance of voluntary compliance with the licensee which effectively deals with the complaint. </section><section prefix="6">The board may utilize mediation as a technique in reasonably handling disciplinary matters. The board may appoint any member or members of the board, any staff member, or any other person or combination thereof to serve in the mediation process. </section><section prefix="7">The board may reconsider, modify, or reverse its probation, suspension, or other disciplinary action. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 23, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 8, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:54</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40900</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>