<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="153" order_by="153">THE ARTS -- STATE ZOO </unit></structure><section_number>153.380Kentucky</section_number><catch_line>Oral History Commission -- Membership -- Officers -- Duties.   </catch_line><order_by>380Kentucky</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is established the Kentucky Oral History Commission, hereinafter referred to as "the commission," which shall be attached to the Kentucky Historical Society as a branch of the Oral History and Educational Outreach Division. </section><section prefix="2">The commission, through funds made available from the State Treasury and from public or private foundations or other sources, shall coordinate, promote, and assist in the development of oral history programs across the state and shall otherwise implement programs which result in the accumulation of taped interviews and other supporting data which preserve the multifaceted history of the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="3">The commission shall consist of twelve (12) voting members, ten (10) appointed by the Governor. The commissioner of the Department for Libraries and Archives and the executive director of the Kentucky Historical Society shall serve as ex officio members. Commission members shall serve without compensation but shall be reimbursed for actual and necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their duties. </section><section prefix="4">After initial appointments, commission members shall be appointed for a four (4) year term, except that of the members appointed after July 15, 1998, three (3) members appointed to fill the terms expiring July 15, 1999, shall serve until February 15, 2000; two (2) members appointed to fill the terms expiring July 15, 2000, shall serve until February 15, 2001; three (3) members appointed to fill the terms expiring July 15, 2001, shall serve until February 15, 2002; and two (2) members appointed to fill the terms expiring July 2, 2002, and July 15, 2002, shall serve until February 15, 2003; and subsequent appointments shall be for four (4) year staggered terms ending on February 15. Upon the expiration of terms or in case of vacancies, terms shall be filled by the Governor. </section><section prefix="5">The commission shall, upon the appointment of its members, organize and elect officers from its membership. The commission shall choose, by a majority vote, a chairperson and a vice chairperson annually. The commission shall meet upon call of the chairman or by a majority of the members of the commission, but no less than twice each year. A majority of the voting members of the commission shall constitute a quorum for the purpose of conducting the business of the commission. </section><section prefix="6">The commission shall serve in an advisory capacity to oral history activities at the Kentucky Historical Society and shall be the final grant approval authority for all funds collected by or appropriated to the commission. </section><section prefix="7">The Kentucky Historical Society shall hire staff, expend funds, and operate the normal business activities required by the commission, which shall include the duty to provide: <section prefix="a">Office space; </section><section prefix="b">Administrative support; </section><section prefix="c">Telephone and other utilities; </section><section prefix="d">Storage or processing of oral history tapes; and </section><section prefix="e">Other activities of a support nature. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 4, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 209, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 264, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 364, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 360, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44490</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>