<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="244" order_by="244">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- PROHIBITIONS, RESTRICTIONS, AND REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>244.230</section_number><catch_line>Federal regulations adopted relating to labeling and standards of fill -- Labeling when manufactured outside country. </catch_line><order_by>230</order_by><text><section prefix="1">KRS 244.260 and 244.340 notwithstanding, the regulations of the Bureau of Internal Revenue in the United States Department of the Treasury, as they are now or may be hereafter, with respect to the labeling and standards of fill of distilled spirits and wine in their original sealed packages, are adopted and any distilled spirits and wine shall be deemed to be properly labeled under all the laws of this state, if the labels and standards of fill conform to those regulations. </section><section prefix="2">Distilled spirits not produced or bottled in the United States shall be labeled in the same manner that distilled spirits produced or bottled in this state are required to be labeled. </section><section prefix="3">Subsections (1) and (2) shall not prevent the department from promulgating regulations on this subject that are in addition to but not contrary to the regulations of the Bureau of Internal Revenue in the United States Department of the Treasury. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 594, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 2, effective July 13, 2004. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2554b-170. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11459</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>