<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="431" order_by="431">GENERAL PROVISIONS CONCERNING CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS </unit></structure><section_number>431.531</section_number><catch_line>Statement of collections to be filed -- Funds to be sent to State Treasury -- Certification of amounts and publication of annual audit by administrative office of the courts. </catch_line><order_by>531</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each Circuit Court clerk shall, on the first day of each month, send to the Finance and Administration Cabinet, a statement, subscribed and sworn to by him, showing the amount of money received or collected by or for him the preceding month pursuant to KRS 431.530(3) and shall, with such statements, send to the State Treasury the amount so collected for deposit to the credit of the general fund. </section><section prefix="2">The Circuit Court clerk shall send to the State Treasury for credit to the general fund all balances from fees collected pursuant to KRS 431.530. </section><section prefix="3">The Administrative Office of the Courts shall certify to the Finance and Administration Cabinet on an annual basis that all funds collected have been duly reported by the circuit clerk in accordance with KRS 30A.120. </section><section prefix="4">The Administrative Office of the Courts shall cause to be published an annual audit of the funds collected pursuant to KRS 30A.120 no later than December 1 for the preceding fiscal year receipts. </section></text><history>Created 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 21, sec. 26, effective January 2, 1978. </history><metadata><effective>January 2, 1978 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-16</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=18636</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>