<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="199" order_by="199">PROTECTIVE SERVICES FOR CHILDREN - ADOPTION </unit></structure><section_number>199.461</section_number><catch_line>Monthly statewide caseload average for social service workers -- Requirement of report if average in excess of specified quantity. </catch_line><order_by>461</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, "social service worker" means a social worker employed by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, Department for Community Based Services, to provide direct casework services in foster care, child protection, juvenile services, or adult protection. </section><section prefix="2">As used in this section, "active case" includes the total number of cases for which the family service worker has responsibility. </section><section prefix="3">The monthly statewide caseload average for social service workers in the area of foster care, child protection, juvenile services, or adult protection shall not exceed twenty-five (25) active cases. </section><section prefix="4">Nothing in this section shall prevent the department or a social service worker from handling emergencies to carry out statutory mandates. If the monthly statewide caseload average for social service workers exceeds twenty-five (25) active cases for ninety (90) consecutive days, the department shall report the fact to the Governor and to the Legislative Research Commission together with a description of the factors contributing thereto and shall make recommendations related thereto. The report shall include, by county and district, social service worker caseload averages; the number of established social service worker positions; and the number of vacant social service worker positions. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 175, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 18, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 137, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 285, sec. 1, effective July 1, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7164</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>