<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="161" order_by="161">SCHOOL EMPLOYEES -- TEACHERS' RETIREMENT AND TENURE </unit></structure><section_number>161.1211</section_number><catch_line>Classification of teachers. </catch_line><order_by>1211</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Education Professional Standards Board shall rank teachers as follows: Rank I. Those holding regular certificates and who have a master's degree in a subject field approved by the Education Professional Standards Board or equivalent continuing education and who have earned thirty (30) semester hours of approved graduate work or equivalent continuing education; or those teachers who have met the requirements for Rank II and earned initial certification of the National Board for Professional Teaching Standards. The board shall not allow a teacher who qualified for Rank I status on the basis of his or her national board certification to maintain that classification if the national board certificate is revoked for misconduct or voided for other reasons. Rank II. Those holding regular certificates and who have a master's degree in a subject field approved by the Education Professional Standards Board or equivalent continuing education. Rank III. Those holding regular certificates and who have an approved four (4) year college degree or the equivalent. Rank IV. Those holding emergency certificates and who have ninety-six (96) to one hundred twenty-eight (128) semester hours of approved college training or the equivalent. Rank V. Those holding emergency certificates and who have sixty-four (64) to ninety-five (95) semester hours of approved college training or the equivalent. </section><section prefix="2">In determining ranks, the Education Professional Standards Board shall classify teachers who hold valid certificates in the respective ranks according to approved college semester hours of credit or equivalent continuing education. The board, in defining preparation for certain types of vocational teachers as equivalent to college training, shall give consideration to apprenticeship training and industrial experience. </section><section prefix="3">For purposes of the state salary schedule only as referenced in KRS 158.070, rank shall be determined on September 15 of each year. </section><section prefix="4">Nothing in this section shall allow the Education Professional Standards Board by regulation to reclassify downward any teachers in Ranks II or I. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 87, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 527, sec. 7, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3854</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>