<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17A-136</section_number><catch_line>Coverage for cancer clinical trials. </catch_line><order_by>17A-136</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="a">"Cancer clinical trial" means a clinical trial that: <section prefix="1">Is approved by: <section prefix="a">The National Institutes of Health, or any institutional review board recognized by the National Institutes of Health; </section><section prefix="b">The United States Food and Drug Administration; </section><section prefix="c">The United States Department of Defense; or </section><section prefix="d">The United States Veterans Administration; and </section></section><section prefix="2">Does one (1) of the following: <section prefix="a">Tests how to administer a health care service, item, or drug for the treatment of cancer; </section><section prefix="b">Tests responses to a health care service, item, or drug for the treatment of cancer; </section><section prefix="c">Compares the effectiveness of health care services, items, or drugs for the treatment of cancer with that of other health care services, items, or drugs for the treatment of cancer; or </section><section prefix="d">Studies new uses of health care services, items, or drugs for the treatment of cancer; and </section></section></section><section prefix="b">"Routine patient healthcare costs" means all healthcare services, items, and drugs for the treatment of cancer, except for the following: <section prefix="1">The health care service, item, or investigational drug that is the subject of the cancer clinical trial; </section><section prefix="2">Any treatment modality outside the usual and customary standard of care required to administer or support the healthcare service, item, or investigational drug that is the subject of the cancer clinical trial; </section><section prefix="3">Any healthcare service, item, or drug provided solely to satisfy data collection and analysis needs that are not used in the direct clinical management of the patient; </section><section prefix="4">An investigational drug or device that has not been approved for market by the United States Food and Drug Administration; </section><section prefix="5">Transportation, lodging, food, or other expenses for the patient or a family member or companion of the patient that are associated with travel to or from a facility providing the cancer clinical trial; </section><section prefix="6">Any services, items, or drugs provided by the cancer clinical trial sponsors free of charge for any new patient; or </section><section prefix="7">Any services, items, or drugs that are eligible for reimbursement by a person other than the insurer, including the sponsor of the clinical trial. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">A health benefit plan shall not exclude coverage for routine patient healthcare costs that are incurred in the course of a cancer clinical trial if the health benefit plan would provide coverage for the routine patient healthcare costs had they not been incurred in a cancer clinical trial. </section><section prefix="3">The coverage that may not be excluded under this section shall be subject to all terms, conditions, restrictions, exclusions, and limitations that apply to any other coverage under the policy, plan, or contract, including the treatment under the policy, plan, or contract of services performed by participating and nonparticipating providers. </section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">Nothing in this section requires a policy, plan, or contract to offer cancer clinical trial services by a participating provider. </section><section prefix="b">Nothing in this section prohibits a policy, plan, or contract from offering cancer clinical trial services by a participating provider. </section><section prefix="c">Nothing in this section requires services that are performed in a cancer clinical trial by a nonparticipating provider of a policy, plan, or contract to be reimbursed at the same rate as those performed by a participating provider of the policy, plan, or contract. </section></section><section prefix="5">Nothing in this section shall be construed as imposing a new health benefit mandate. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17371</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>