<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="277" order_by="277">RAILROADS -- ORGANIZATION AND OPERATING REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>277.402</section_number><catch_line>Preservation of railroad corridors -- Public policy -- Preliminary declaration of state railbanking. </catch_line><order_by>402</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It is the public policy of this state to preserve railroad corridors for future railroad use. Toward this end, the Commonwealth recognizes that the salvage of tracks, ties, signaling equipment, ballast, and other items may indicate an intent to maximize return on present investment and not an intent to abandon any underlying easement for railroad or other use and that the obtaining of federal authority to discontinue service over or abandon a corridor does not necessarily indicate an intent to relinquish any property interests under state law. In any civil action to determine the status of a railroad use easement, ambiguity as to intent shall be resolved in favor of continued preservation of the corridor. </section><section prefix="2">Any holder of a railroad corridor held by easement or otherwise may preserve that corridor by filing with the Secretary of State a "Preliminary Declaration of State Railbanking," concurrently serving a copy of the declaration on the Transportation Cabinet. The declaration shall state the name of the entity holding the corridor, a textual description and map of the land area encompassed by the corridor, and a statement that the entity does not intend to abandon the corridor described in the declaration. The entity filing the declaration may at any later time cause that declaration to be withdrawn from the Secretary of State's files. While a preliminary declaration of state railbanking is on file with the Secretary of State, the corridor set out in the declaration shall not, regardless of the status or conclusion of any federal regulatory proceeding or the salvage of track and other material from the corridor, be deemed abandoned and shall continue to exist under Kentucky law and the property encompassed by the corridor shall not revert to any other form of ownership. </section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 338, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14031</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>