<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="216" order_by="216">HEALTH FACILITIES AND SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>216.335</section_number><catch_line>Powers of board. </catch_line><order_by>335</order_by><text>The government of the hospital district shall be vested in the board which shall have general control of the property and affairs of the district and shall have all the powers necessary to carry out the purposes of KRS 216.310 to 216.360 including, but not confined to, the following: <section prefix="1">To construct, acquire, add to, maintain, operate, develop and regulate, sell and convey all lands, property rights, equipment, hospital facilities and systems for the maintenance of hospitals, buildings, structures and any other facilities; </section><section prefix="2">To exercise the right of eminent domain for the purposes of the district except that no hospital district shall have the right of eminent domain against any hospital, clinic or sanatorium operated by a nonprofit charitable, religious or public organization, or against any private hospital, clinic or sanatorium; </section><section prefix="3">To receive, acquire, hold, manage, expend, sell and convey donations and bequests of real and personal property for hospital purposes within the district; </section><section prefix="4">To establish and maintain a public hospital or hospitals in the district and where necessary make provision for education of needed personnel to operate such hospitals; </section><section prefix="5">To lease existing hospital or hospitals and equipment and other property used in connection with the operation of a hospital, and to pay such rental therefor as the board shall deem proper; </section><section prefix="6">To enter into contracts and agreements with any person or corporation, public or private, affecting the affairs of the district, including contracts with cities, counties, other municipalities, the Commonwealth or the United States of America and any of its agents or instrumentalities; </section><section prefix="7">To enter into contracts with a nonprofit corporation acting as a governmental agency for the construction and equipping of a hospital or hospitals, and the leasing of the same to the district; </section><section prefix="8">To sue and be sued; </section><section prefix="9">To make contracts, employ an administrator, attorneys and other technical or professional assistance and all other employees as the needs of the district may require, and to prescribe their duties and compensation; </section><section prefix="10">To have perpetual existence; </section><section prefix="11">To borrow money on the credit of the board in anticipation of the revenue to be derived from anticipated revenue from user fees or from taxes levied by the district for the fiscal year in which the money is borrowed, and to pledge the taxes levied for the district for the payment of the principal and interest of the loan; </section><section prefix="12">To establish bylaws it deems necessary or expedient to define the duties of officers, assistants or employees, to fix the conditions of admission to the hospitals of the district, and the support and discharge of patients, and to conduct in a proper manner the professional and business affairs of the district; </section><section prefix="13">To establish and enforce a suitable system of rules and regulations for the internal government, discipline and management of the hospitals of the district; </section><section prefix="14">To determine annually the amount of tax, not to exceed ten cents ($0.10) per one hundred dollars ($100) of property assessed for taxation, to be levied upon the taxable property of the district, for the purposes of the district, and to certify to the fiscal court of each county in the district and to each county clerk for inclusion on the tax bills of property owners in the district. </section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 353, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 176, sec. 11, effective June 13, 1968. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9020</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>