<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.9-052</section_number><catch_line>Administrator -- License requirements -- Service of process. </catch_line><order_by>9-052</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No individual or business entity shall in this state be, act as, or hold himself or herself out to be an administrator unless then licensed as an administrator by the commissioner. </section><section prefix="2">For the protection of the people of this state, the commissioner shall not issue, continue, or permit to exist any administrator license for any person unless such person demonstrates to the satisfaction of the commissioner that the following standards are met: <section prefix="a">If an individual, the applicant has attained the age of twenty-one (21) years; </section><section prefix="b">The applicant is competent, trustworthy, reliable, and of good reputation; </section><section prefix="c">If an individual, the applicant has attained an educational level acceptable to the commissioner; </section><section prefix="d">The applicant is financially responsible; </section><section prefix="e">The applicant has not had any license issued by the commissioner, or application therefor, terminated for cause; </section><section prefix="f">The applicant is a resident of Kentucky or is currently licensed and in good standing in his or her home state; </section><section prefix="g">The applicant has paid the fee prescribed in KRS 304.4-010; </section><section prefix="h">If a business entity, each individual authorized to act for the business entity under its administrator license shall be designated with the commissioner in accordance with KRS 304.9-133; and </section><section prefix="i">Administrator licenses shall be renewed in accordance with KRS 304.9-260. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1043, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 143, sec. 4, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 273, sec. 9, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:07</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=16891</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>