<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="281" order_by="281">A COMMERCIAL DRIVER'S LICENSES </unit></structure><section_number>281A.070</section_number><catch_line>Information required from persons holding commercial driver's license or applying to be a commercial driver. </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any driver who holds a commercial driver's license or who is required to hold a commercial driver's license shall within thirty (30) days in the manner specified by the cabinet: <section prefix="a">Notify the cabinet of any conviction of a state law or local ordinance, relating to motor vehicle traffic control, other than a parking violation, committed in another state or jurisdiction; and </section><section prefix="b">Notify his employer in writing of any conviction of a state law or local ordinance, relating to motor vehicle traffic control other than a parking violation, committed in any state or jurisdiction. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any driver whose commercial driver's license is suspended, revoked, or canceled by any state, or who loses the privilege to drive a motor vehicle in any state for any period, including being disqualified from driving a commercial motor vehicle, or a driver who is subject to an out of service order, shall notify his employer of that fact before the end of the business day following the day the driver received notice of that fact. </section><section prefix="3">Any person who applies to be a commercial motor vehicle driver shall provide the employer, at the time of the application, with the following information for the ten (10) years preceding the date of application whenever the information is available: <section prefix="a">A list of the names and addresses of the applicant's previous employers for which the applicant was a driver of a commercial motor vehicle; </section><section prefix="b">The dates during which the applicant drove for each employer; </section><section prefix="c">The reason for leaving that employer; and </section><section prefix="d">A certification that all information furnished is true and complete. </section></section><section prefix="4">An employer may require an applicant to provide information additional to that required by subsection (3) of this section. </section></text><history>Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 455, sec. 7, effective July 1, 1991. </history><metadata><effective>July 1, 1991 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14465</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>