<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="260" order_by="260">MARKETING OF AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS </unit></structure><section_number>260.031</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Farmers Market Nutrition Program -- Fund. </catch_line><order_by>031</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Farmers Market Nutrition Program is created within the Kentucky Department of Agriculture, in collaboration with the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, for the purpose of enhancing nutrition. The program's services may include the provision of fresh, locally grown produce to low-income citizens, including but not limited to seniors and recipients of the Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children provided by the federal Food and Nutrition Service. </section><section prefix="2">The department may collaborate with the United States Department of Agriculture, the University of Kentucky College of Agriculture Cooperative Extension Service, local Area Agencies on Aging, community agencies, foundations, philanthropic organizations, farmers, and local fiscal courts to: <section prefix="a">Identify funding sources; </section><section prefix="b">Establish services and a program delivery strategy; </section><section prefix="c">Market the program to citizens and farmers; and </section><section prefix="d">Develop strategies to introduce fresh, locally grown fruits and vegetables into school food programs. </section></section><section prefix="3">The department may promulgate administrative regulations to establish eligibility criteria and implement the program established in subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="4">The department may accept gifts, grants, federal or state funds, or any other public or private funds to develop or implement the program. </section><section prefix="5">The Kentucky Farmers Market Nutrition Program fund is created in the State Treasury as a trust and agency account. Moneys deposited in the fund shall be disbursed by the State Treasurer upon the warrant of the Commissioner of the Kentucky Department of Agriculture. This fund shall be used solely for the purpose of providing nutritious food to low-income citizens. The fund shall not lapse, and funds not expended during any fiscal year shall carry forward to the next fiscal year. </section></text><history> Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><lrc-note>(6/26/2007).  A manifest clerical or typographical error in this section has been corrected by the Reviser of Statutes under the authority of KRS 7.136. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12536</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>