<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.739</section_number><catch_line>Granting of research contracts -- Reports -- Published research documents -- Acknowledgment of funding source. </catch_line><order_by>739</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A research contract shall be granted for a one (1) year period, with renewal for two </section><section prefix="2">additional years subject to the conditions established by this section. Renewal in </section>years two (2) and three (3) shall depend upon fulfillment of contract terms. (2) A grantee shall submit to the board an annual progress report, including a narrative and financial report of any progress. <section prefix="3">The annual progress report shall be due sixty (60) days prior to the effective date of the contract of the following year. </section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">A grantee shall submit a final narrative progress report thirty (30) days after completion or termination of the contract and a financial report no later than ninety (90) days after completion or termination of the contract. </section><section prefix="b">The financial report shall be completed by the contracting institution. </section></section><section prefix="5">The PI shall transmit to the board a copy of any document published as a result of the funded research, during and after the period of the contract. </section><section prefix="6">A grantee shall acknowledge the source of funding from the trust in all publications and presentations. </section></text><history> Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 171, sec. 5, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8477</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>