<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="229" order_by="229">BOXING AND WRESTLING </unit></structure><section_number>229.200</section_number><catch_line>Suspension, reprimand, revocation, probation, or refusal of licenses -- Grounds. </catch_line><order_by>200</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The authority may suspend, reprimand, revoke, probate, or refuse to renew or issue a license for the following reasons: that the licensee or applicant has, in the judgment of the authority, been guilty of an act detrimental to the interests of boxing, kickboxing, mixed martial arts, or wrestling generally or to the public interest, convenience, or necessity, including, but not by way of limitation, the violation of any of the provisions of this chapter or any rule or administrative regulation of the authority. </section><section prefix="2">The authority may suspend, reprimand, revoke, probate, or refuse to renew or issue a license if it finds that the applicant, or any person who is a partner, agent, employee, stockholder, or associate of the applicant, has been convicted of a crime in any jurisdiction, or is associating or consorting with any person who has or persons who have been convicted of a crime or crimes in any jurisdiction or jurisdictions, or is consorting or associating with or has consorted or associated with bookmakers, gamblers, or persons of similar pursuits, or has himself engaged in similar pursuits, or is financially irresponsible, or has been guilty of or attempted any fraud or misrepresentation in connection with boxing, kickboxing, mixed martial arts, or wrestling, or has violated or attempted to violate any law with respect to boxing, kickboxing, mixed martial arts, or wrestling in any jurisdiction or any rule, regulation, or order of the authority, or shall have violated any rule of boxing, kickboxing, mixed martial arts, or wrestling which shall have been approved or adopted by the authority, or has been guilty of or engaged in similar, related, or like practices. </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">The authority may suspend, reprimand, revoke, probate, or refuse to renew or issue a license to protect the health of the licensee, upon notification of the suspension or revocation of the license of a licensee in another state or jurisdiction. </section><section prefix="b">Upon proceedings for the revocation of any license under KRS 229.081, the authority may, in its discretion, order a suspension of the license. However, the licensee may have the alternative, subject to the approval of the authority, to pay in lieu of part or all of the days of any suspension period a sum not in excess of five hundred dollars ($500). </section></section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 91, sec. 19, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 13, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 286, sec. 10, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 170, sec. 11. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10802</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>