<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="230" order_by="230">HORSE RACING AND SHOWING </unit></structure><section_number>230.215</section_number><catch_line>Legislative purpose for chapter -- Racing Commission's power to exclude undesirables. </catch_line><order_by>215</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It is the policy of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, in furtherance of its responsibility to foster and to encourage legitimate occupations and industries in the Commonwealth and to promote and to conserve the public health, safety, and welfare, and it is hereby declared the intent of the Commonwealth to foster and to encourage the horse breeding industry within the Commonwealth and to encourage the improvement of the breeds of horses. Further, it is the policy and intent of the Commonwealth to foster and to encourage the business of legitimate horse racing with pari-mutuel wagering thereon in the Commonwealth on the highest possible plane. Further, it hereby is declared the policy and intent of the Commonwealth that all racing not licensed under this chapter is a public nuisance and may be enjoined as such. Further, it is hereby declared the policy and intent of the Commonwealth that the conduct of horse racing, or the participation in any way in horse racing, or the entrance to or presence where horse racing is conducted, is a privilege and not a personal right; and that this privilege may be granted or denied by the racing commission or its duly approved representatives acting in its behalf. </section><section prefix="2">It is hereby declared the purpose and intent of this chapter in the interest of the public health, safety, and welfare, to vest in the racing commission forceful control of horse racing in the Commonwealth with plenary power to promulgate administrative regulations prescribing conditions under which all legitimate horse racing and wagering thereon is conducted in the Commonwealth so as to encourage the improvement of the breeds of horses in the Commonwealth, to regulate and maintain horse racing at horse race meetings in the Commonwealth of the highest quality and free of any corrupt, incompetent, dishonest, or unprincipled horse racing practices, and to regulate and maintain horse racing at race meetings in the Commonwealth so as to dissipate any cloud of association with the undesirable and maintain the appearance as well as the fact of complete honesty and integrity of horse racing in the Commonwealth. In addition to the general powers and duties vested in the racing commission by this chapter, it is the intent hereby to vest in the racing commission the power to eject or exclude from association grounds or any part thereof any person, licensed or unlicensed, whose conduct or reputation is such that his presence on association grounds may, in the opinion of the racing commission, reflect on the honesty and integrity of horse racing or interfere with the orderly conduct of horse racing. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 444, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 44, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 12, effective March 30, 1992. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 296, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 1; and ch. 403, sec. 2. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 156, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10829</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>