<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="341" order_by="341">UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>341.430</section_number><catch_line>Review by commission. </catch_line><order_by>430</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commission may on its own motion affirm, modify, or set aside any decision of a referee on the basis of the evidence previously submitted in such case, or direct the taking of additional evidence, or may permit any of the parties to such decision to initiate further appeals before it. The commission may remove to itself or transfer to another referee the proceedings on any claims pending before a referee. </section><section prefix="2">An application for review by the commission of any administrative determination affecting an employing unit's liability, contribution rate, or amount of contributions may be filed by such employing unit within twenty (20) days after notice of such determination was mailed to such employing unit's last known address. </section><section prefix="3">Any proceedings before the commission shall be heard and determined by the entire commission composed of three (3) members, except that no member of the commission shall participate in any case in which he is an interested party, and the chairman shall act alone in the absence or disqualification of any other member. The commission shall promptly notify the parties to any proceedings of its findings and decisions. </section></text><history>Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4748g-11. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1988</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32305</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>