<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="317" order_by="317">BARBERS </unit></structure><section_number>317.420</section_number><catch_line>Barber license requirements – Exemptions -- Advertising.   </catch_line><order_by>420</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall engage in the practice of "barbering" for other than cosmetic purposes nor shall any person engage in barbering for the treatment of physical or mental ailments, except that the provisions of this chapter shall not apply to: <section prefix="a">Persons authorized by the law of this state to practice medicine, chiropody, optometry, dentistry, chiropractic, nursing, or embalming when incidental practices of barbering are performed by them in the normal course of the practice of their profession; </section><section prefix="b">Commissioned medical or surgical personnel of the United States Army, Navy, Air Force, or Marine Hospital Service performing incidental practices of barbering in the course of their duties; or </section><section prefix="c">Barbering services performed at an institution operated by or under contract to the Department of Corrections or the Department of Juvenile Justice. </section></section><section prefix="2">Except as provided in subsection (1) of this section, no person shall engage in the practice of barbering for the public generally or for consideration without the appropriate license required by this chapter. </section><section prefix="3">No person, unless duly and properly licensed pursuant to this chapter, shall: <section prefix="a">Teach barbering; </section><section prefix="b">Operate a barber shop; </section><section prefix="c">Conduct or operate a school for barbers; or </section><section prefix="d">Lease or rent booth space as an independent contract owner. </section></section><section prefix="4">No person shall aid or abet any person in violating the provisions of this section, nor shall any person engage or employ for consideration any person for the performance of any practice licensed by this chapter unless the person to perform such practice holds and displays the appropriate license therefor. </section><section prefix="5">Except as provided in this chapter, no person or business shall: <section prefix="a">Advertise barbering services, unless the person or business and the personnel it employs are licensed under this chapter; or </section><section prefix="b">Use or display a barber pole for the purpose of advertising barbering services to the public unless it: <section prefix="1">Has a barber shop license; and </section><section prefix="2">Employs a barber licensed under this chapter. </section></section></section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2013; and ch. 72, sec. 5, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 354, sec. 17. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 145, sec. 1. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 233, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><lrc-note> (6/25/2013). This statute was amended by 2013 Ky. Acts chs. 51 and 72, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:54</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42129</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>