<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="227" order_by="227">FIRE PREVENTION AND PROTECTION -- ELECTRICIANS </unit></structure><section_number>227.336</section_number><catch_line>Findings -- Correction of violations -- Fees. </catch_line><order_by>336</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Whenever the state fire marshal or any deputy state fire marshal appointed or employed by him or her makes any finding set forth in subsection (1) of KRS 227.330, or finds any property in violation of any provision of KRS 227.200 to 227.410 or any regulations adopted thereunder, in lieu of the order required in KRS 227.330(1), he or she shall notify the owner or his or her agent in writing of such specific finding and violation and instruct him or her to correct the violation within a period of time not to exceed sixty (60) days. Should the owner fail to make the required corrections within the specified time, the state fire marshal may proceed to take any other action authorized in this chapter. </section><section prefix="2">If the state fire marshal or a deputy state fire marshal is required to make additional inspections, beyond the initial inspection and one (1) follow-up inspection, to determine if the required corrections referred to in subsection (1) of this section have been made, the state fire marshal or the deputy state fire marshal shall assess a fee against the property owner to recover the cost of each additional inspection according to the following schedule: Third inspection fee.......................................................................................$100.00 Fourth inspection fee.....................................................................................$200.00 Fifth and subsequent inspection fee..............................................................$500.00 </section><section prefix="3">Any fee collected under the provisions of this section by the state fire marshal shall be payable to the State Treasury and credited to the Division of Fire Prevention for the operation of the general inspection program. Any fee collected under the provisions of this section by a deputy state fire marshal shall be payable to the fire department conducting the inspection. </section><section prefix="4">If during a follow-up inspection or any subsequent inspection for the same violation the state fire marshal or a deputy state fire marshal finds an additional violation not found during the initial inspection, such additional violation shall be treated as an initial violation which the property owner shall have the opportunity to correct under subsection (1) of this section prior to the assessment of a fee under subsection (2) of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 400, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 125, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 305, sec. 22, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10654</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>