<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.40-050</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of corporation. </catch_line><order_by>40-050</order_by><text>The Eastern Kentucky Exposition Center Corporation shall have the following powers and duties: <section prefix="1">The corporation shall supervise the design, construction, and operation of the Eastern Kentucky Exposition Center and shall provide all management functions for the facility and for any other property acquired or leased in accordance with its powers established in this section. </section><section prefix="2">The corporation shall promote the growth and development of the convention, trade, tourism, hotel, restaurant, and entertainment industry in eastern Kentucky, Pike County, and the Commonwealth through utilization of the center. </section><section prefix="3">The corporation shall have the exclusive control of all exhibitions, performances, and concessions in the Eastern Kentucky Exposition Center. The corporation shall have a prior lien upon the property of any private exhibitor, concessionaire, or other person holding an exhibition or performance or operating a concession in the center and may sell the property upon ten (10) days' notice to satisfy any indebtedness. </section><section prefix="4">The corporation shall participate with local hotels and the travel industry to develop tourist packages and additional services to attract conferences and conventions to the region. </section><section prefix="5">The corporation may take, acquire, and hold property, and all interests therein, by deed, purchase, gift, devise, bequest, or lease or by transfer from the State Properties and Buildings Commission and may dispose of any property so acquired in any manner provided by law. </section><section prefix="6">The corporation may levy a surcharge on tickets for functions held within the center to contribute to operating revenue. </section><section prefix="7">The corporation may sue and be sued and maintain and defend legal actions in its corporate name. </section></text><history> Created 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 27, sec. 5, effective June 21, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> June 21, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2917</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>