<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="167" order_by="167">EDUCATION OF THE PHYSICALLY HANDICAPPED </unit></structure><section_number>167.250</section_number><catch_line>Liability insurance for drivers of motor vehicles transporting specified students. </catch_line><order_by>250</order_by><text>The chief state school officer may provide liability insurance or an indemnity bond against the negligence of drivers of motor vehicles owned or operated by the Department of Education for the transportation of members of the student bodies of the Kentucky School for the Blind, the Kentucky School for the Deaf, and the Carl D. Perkins Vocational Training Center. If the transportation of members of the student bodies is let out under contract, the contract shall require the contractor to carry an indemnity bond or liability insurance against negligence in such amounts as the chief state school officer designates. In either case, the indemnity bond or insurance policy shall be issued by a surety or insurance company authorized to transact business in this state, and shall bind the company to pay any final judgment not to exceed the limits of the policy rendered against the insured for loss or damage to property of any student or other person, or death or injury of any student or other person. </text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 45, sec. 2, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. IV, sec. 278, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 438, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4723</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>