<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">A KENTUCKY MODEL PROCUREMENT CODE </unit></structure><section_number>45A.645</section_number><catch_line>Agencies to purchase Kentucky-grown products meeting quality standards and pricing requirements if available -- Reports -- Marketing assistance -- Annual report -- Vendors' duties. </catch_line><order_by>645</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">If purchasing agricultural products, state agencies, as defined by KRS 45A.505, shall purchase Kentucky-grown agricultural products if the products are available and if the vendor can meet the applicable quality standards and pricing requirements of the state agency. </section><section prefix="b">All state agencies that purchase agricultural products shall, on or before January 1 of each year, provide a report to the Legislative Research Commission and to the Department of Agriculture describing the types, quantities, and costs of each product purchased. The report shall be completed on a form provided by the department. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Prospective vendors of Kentucky-grown agricultural products may apply to the Kentucky Department of Agriculture for marketing assistance for the authorized use of logos or labeling statements to be used on Kentucky-grown agricultural products under KRS 260.017, the Kentucky Proud™ Program. </section><section prefix="b">Before a state agency may purchase Kentucky-grown agricultural products, the vendor shall be required to participate in the Kentucky Proud™ Program established by KRS 260.017, and shall provide to the purchasing officer written certification that the agricultural products under consideration for purchase meet the definition of Kentucky-grown agricultural product. </section><section prefix="c">All state agencies that purchase Kentucky-grown agricultural products shall, on or before January 1 of each year, provide a report to the Legislative Research Commission and to the Department of Agriculture describing the types, quantities, and costs of each product purchased. The report shall be completed on a form provided by the department. </section></section><section prefix="3">If a contract is awarded to a vendor that supplies agricultural products that are raised or produced outside the United States or its territories, the vendor shall be required to identify the country in which the agricultural product was raised or produced if the vendor is the producer or packager of the product or if the vendor is not the producer or packager, provided the information is available to the vendor from the producer or packager of the product. The producer or packager shall clearly label that information on any containers or packages holding the product. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 37, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 244, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 344, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22458</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>