<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="335" order_by="335">SOCIAL WORKERS AND PROFESSIONAL COUNSELORS </unit></structure><section_number>335.527</section_number><catch_line>Licensing reciprocity requirements -- Exemptions. </catch_line><order_by>527</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall grant the appropriate credential under KRS 335.525 to an applicant for endorsement who: <section prefix="a">Has received a master's, specialist, or doctoral degree in counseling or a related field from a regionally accredited institution with a minimum of sixty (60) hours of graduate coursework to include the following: <section prefix="1">The helping relationship, including counseling theory and practice; </section><section prefix="2">Human growth and development; </section><section prefix="3">Lifestyle and career development; </section><section prefix="4">Group dynamics, process, counseling, and consulting; </section><section prefix="5">Assessment, appraisal, and testing of individuals; </section><section prefix="6">Social and cultural foundations, including multicultural issues; </section><section prefix="7">Principles of etiology, diagnosis, treatment planning, and prevention of mental and emotional disorders and dysfunctional behavior; </section><section prefix="8">Research and evaluation; and </section><section prefix="9">Professional orientation and ethics; </section></section><section prefix="b">Holds an active valid license or certificate from another state to practice as a professional counselor; </section><section prefix="c">Is in good standing with the certifying or licensing board of that state; </section><section prefix="d">Is of good moral character; </section><section prefix="e">Has paid the application fee to the board; and </section><section prefix="f">Has provided the board with evidence of a minimum of five (5) years' experience as a certified or licensed professional counselor. </section></section><section prefix="2">The applicant shall be exempt from: <section prefix="a">The required hours of supervised experience in the practice of counseling set out in KRS 335.525(1)(e); and </section><section prefix="b">The examination requirement set out in KRS 335.525(1)(f). </section></section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 252, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31962</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>