<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.3-219</section_number><catch_line>Continuation of trust by corporate trustee -- Limitations -- Application. </catch_line><order_by>3-219</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A corporate trustee administering a trust may continue the term of a portion of the trust so long as the period of the continuation does not extend beyond the term allowable under KRS 381.224, 381.225, and 381.226 that is applicable to the trust. </section><section prefix="2">Subject to KRS 381.224, 381.225, and 381.226, the portion of the trust continued by the corporate trustee shall continue for the life of the remainder beneficiary of the trust, upon the same terms and conditions as provided in the trust, for the term preceding the life beneficiary's death. In addition, commencing with the death of the life beneficiary, the remainder beneficiary may withdraw that portion of the trust that has been continued by giving written notice to the corporate trustee. However, each year five percent (5%) of the remainder beneficiary's right of withdrawal shall lapse on December 31, and the lapses shall be cumulative. </section><section prefix="3">The corporate trustee's authority granted in subsection (1) of this section shall not apply to any portion of a trust which: <section prefix="a">Continues by its terms after the death of the life beneficiary; or </section><section prefix="b">Has been pledged to secure a debt. </section></section><section prefix="4">This section shall apply to any trust that was irrevocable on January 1, 1976. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 21, sec. 11, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 440, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 287.219. </former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  In accordance with 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, secs. 38 and 39, this statute has been renumbered as a section of the Kentucky Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14560</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>