<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="605" order_by="605">ADMINISTRATIVE MATTERS </unit></structure><section_number>605.130</section_number><catch_line>General duties of cabinet.   </catch_line><order_by>130</order_by><text>In addition to the other duties, functions, and responsibilities imposed by law, the cabinet, through its authorized representatives, shall have general supervision and management of all matters contained in KRS 620.150 and 620.170 and shall, wherever possible: <section prefix="1">Locate and plan for all children who are dependent, neglected, or abused; </section><section prefix="2">Cooperate with and assist the courts of the various counties; </section><section prefix="3">Assist Circuit Courts through services to children whenever requested by the court. The cabinet may charge a reasonable fee for such services to be taxed as costs by the court; </section><section prefix="4">Assess all referrals received from a court-designated worker, pursuant to direction from the family accountability, intervention, and response team, to determine whether a basis exists to file a dependency, neglect, or abuse petition; </section><section prefix="5">Track and report to the oversight council created in KRS 15A.063 the number of referrals received, the number of investigations made upon those referrals, and the number and type of petitions filed in response; </section><section prefix="6">Identify all youth who have status offense charges and are committed or probated to the cabinet and report the number of committed and probated youth to the oversight council created in KRS 15A.063; and </section><section prefix="7">Perform such other services as may be deemed necessary for the protection of children. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 32, effective July 1, 2015. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 257, sec. 11, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 11, effective April 10, 1988. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 423, sec. 16, effective July 1, 1987. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2015 </effective><lrc-note>(7/1/2015). In codification, the Reviser of Statutes has altered the numbering of subsections (4) to (7) of this statute from the way it appeared in 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 32, under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(c). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43963</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>