<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="7" order_by="7">A PLANNING AND OVERSIGHT OF GOVERNMENTAL FINANCE </unit></structure><section_number>7A.230</section_number><catch_line>Co-chairs of board -- Meetings -- Reimbursement of members -- Employees and operating costs.   </catch_line><order_by>230</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The co-chairs of the Public Pension Oversight Board shall have joint responsibilities for board meeting agendas and presiding at board meetings. </section><section prefix="2">On an alternating basis, each co-chair shall have the first option to set the monthly meeting date. A monthly meeting may be canceled by agreement of both co-chairs. The board shall meet at least twice during each calendar year. </section><section prefix="3">Members of the board shall be entitled to reimbursement for expenses incurred in the performance of their duties. </section><section prefix="4">A majority of the entire membership of the Public Pension Oversight Board shall constitute a quorum, and all actions of the board shall be by vote of a majority of its entire membership. </section><section prefix="5">The Legislative Research Commission shall have exclusive jurisdiction over the employment of personnel necessary to carry out the provisions of KRS 7A.200 to 7A.260. Staff and operating costs of the Public Pension Oversight Board shall be provided from the budget of the Legislative Research Commission. </section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 4, effective July 1, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42632</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>