<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="148" order_by="148">PARKS AND TOURISM </unit></structure><section_number>148.548</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Film Commission -- Functions and purpose -- Members -- Meetings -- Nonvoting ex officio members. </catch_line><order_by>548</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Film Commission is hereby established and administratively attached to the Office of the Secretary, Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet. </section><section prefix="2">The functions and purpose of the Kentucky Film Commission shall be: <section prefix="a">To serve in an advisory capacity to support the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet in: <section prefix="1">Promoting the growth of the film, television, and video production industry within the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="2">Marketing and promoting Kentucky as a location destination for motion picture productions throughout the Commonwealth for the express purpose of economic development; and </section><section prefix="3">Providing a broad base of industry-specific demographic, economic, and informational support to the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet; and </section></section><section prefix="b">To advise the Governor and members of the General Assembly on issues relating to the Commonwealth's development and implementation of programs to attract and encourage film, television, and video production in the Commonwealth. </section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">The commission shall consist of fifteen (15) members who shall be appointed by the Governor. </section><section prefix="b">Initially, the Governor shall appoint: <section prefix="1">Not more than four (4) members for a term of one (1) year; </section><section prefix="2">Not more than four (4) members for a term of two (2) years; </section><section prefix="3">Not more than four (4) members for a term of three (3) years; and </section><section prefix="4">Not more than three (3) members for a term of four (4) years. </section></section><section prefix="c">Thereafter, the Governor shall make all appointments for a term of four (4) years. </section><section prefix="d">The Governor shall appoint a chairman from among the members. </section></section><section prefix="4">The members of the commission shall serve without compensation but shall be reimbursed for necessary travel expenses. </section><section prefix="5">The commission shall meet at the call of the chairman at locations within the Commonwealth designated by the chairman. </section><section prefix="6">The commission, by majority vote, may appoint other nonvoting ex officio members within the Commonwealth to assist the commission in achieving its functions and purpose as described in subsection (2) of this section. </section></text><history> Created 2009 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 46, effective June 26, 2009. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1765</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>