<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="200" order_by="200">ASSISTANCE TO CHILDREN </unit></structure><section_number>200.508</section_number><catch_line>Rights of children with an emotional disability and their parents, custodians, or guardians. </catch_line><order_by>508</order_by><text>A child with an emotional disability and the parent, person exercising custodial control or supervision, or guardian of that child shall have the right to: <section prefix="1">Be adequately informed as to priorities, philosophy, and policies of the regional interagency council; </section><section prefix="2">Be informed in advance of scheduled regional or local interagency council and interagency service planning meetings relevant to services to the child; </section><section prefix="3">Participate in the development of the interagency service plan and revisions thereto; </section><section prefix="4">Be adequately informed as to the interagency service plan and any revisions thereto and receive a written copy of the plan; </section><section prefix="5">Refuse the interagency service plan; </section><section prefix="6">Access and utilize established grievance procedures without discontinuation or delay of needed services while the grievance is pending; </section><section prefix="7">Access all child-specific pertinent records and information accumulated by the regional interagency council, provided that the release of the information is not prohibited by existing state and federal laws or regulations governing confidentiality; </section><section prefix="8">Consult with existing advocacy groups for consultation and representation; and </section><section prefix="9">Receive an orderly transition to other available services if eligibility for regional interagency council services is ending. </section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 6, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7310</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>