<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="407" order_by="407">INTERSTATE SUPPORT ENFORCEMENT </unit></structure><section_number>407.5704Initiation</section_number><catch_line>by Cabinet for Health and Family Services of support proceeding under Convention.   </catch_line><order_by>5704Initiation</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In a support proceeding under this Article, the Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall: <section prefix="a">Transmit and receive applications; and </section><section prefix="b">Initiate or facilitate the institution of a proceeding regarding an application in a tribunal of this state. </section></section><section prefix="2">The following support proceedings are available to an obligee under the Convention: <section prefix="a">Recognition or recognition and enforcement of a foreign support order; </section><section prefix="b">Enforcement of a support order issued or recognized in this state; </section><section prefix="c">Establishment of a support order if there is no existing order, including, if necessary, determination of parentage of a child; </section><section prefix="d">Establishment of a support order if recognition of a foreign support order is refused under KRS 407.5708(2)(b), (d), or (i); </section><section prefix="e">Modification of a support order of a tribunal of this state; and </section><section prefix="f">Modification of a support order of a tribunal of another state or a foreign country. </section></section><section prefix="3">The following support proceedings are available under the Convention to an obligor against which there is an existing support order: <section prefix="a">Recognition of an order suspending or limiting enforcement of an existing support order of a tribunal of this state; </section><section prefix="b">Modification of a support order of a tribunal of this state; and </section><section prefix="c">Modification of a support order of a tribunal of another state or a foreign country. </section></section><section prefix="4">A tribunal of this state may not require security, bond, or deposit, however described, to guarantee the payment of costs and expenses in proceedings under the Convention. </section></text><history> Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 58, effective June 24, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44134</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>