<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.6677</section_number><catch_line>Power of inspector to refuse to approve work covered by permit -- Power of department or authorized local government to prohibit continued use of system --Aggrieved applicant's right to hearing. </catch_line><order_by>6677</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If an installation for which a permit is required does not meet the requirements of the Uniform State Building Code or the Uniform State Residential Code, whichever is applicable, or if the property owner refuses to allow an inspection, the inspector shall refuse to approve the work covered by the permit. The department or authorized local government may prohibit the continued use of a heating, ventilation, and air conditioning system that an authorized inspector determines was improperly installed or altered if continued use threatens human life or if the property owner refused to allow an inspection. </section><section prefix="2">An applicant aggrieved by an action of an inspector or the department may request a hearing in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 294, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 7, effective January 1, 2009. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (4/18/2008).  This statute was created by 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 7, to be effective January 1, 2009, pursuant to sec. 12 of that Act. However, 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 127 (2008 HB 406, the State/Executive Branch Budget) provided in Part I, F.,16., (2) HVAC Permitting and Inspecting, that notwithstanding the delayed effective date provided in 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 12, the effective date of this statute shall be January 1, 2011. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7065</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>