<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="235" order_by="235">BOATS AND BOATING </unit></structure><section_number>235.190</section_number><catch_line>Licensee's change of address -- Notice of theft or recovery required. </catch_line><order_by>190</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any holder of a certificate of registration shall notify the county clerk within fifteen (15) days if his address no longer conforms to the address appearing on the certificate and shall, as a part of the notification, furnish the county clerk with his new address. The department may provide in its administrative regulations for the surrender of the certificate bearing the former address and its replacement with a certificate bearing the new address or for the alteration of an outstanding certificate to show the new address of the holder. </section><section prefix="2">Any holder of a certificate shall give notice to the department within fifteen (15) days of the theft or recovery of a vessel to which he is the holder of the certificate of number. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 163, sec. 12, effective January 1, 1990. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 404, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 295, sec. 78, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 263, sec. 12, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 292, sec. 14. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 68, Art. VIII, sec. 20, effective March 17, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11064</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>