<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="367" order_by="367">CONSUMER PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>367.981</section_number><catch_line>Renegotiation of rental-purchase agreement. </catch_line><order_by>981</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A renegotiation shall occur when an existing rental-purchase agreement is satisfied and replaced by a new lease agreement undertaken by the same consumer. A renegotiation shall be a new agreement covered by KRS 367.976 to 367.985. However, events such as the following shall not be treated as a renegotiation: <section prefix="a">The addition or return of property in a multiple item agreement or the substitution of lease property, if in either case the average payment allocable to a payment period is not changed by more than twenty-five percent (25%); </section><section prefix="b">A deferral or extension of one (1) or more periodic payments, or portions of a periodic payment; </section><section prefix="c">A reduction in charges in the agreement; </section><section prefix="d">An agreement involving a court proceeding; or </section><section prefix="e">Any other event described in administrative regulations prescribed by the division. </section></section><section prefix="2">No disclosures shall be required for any extension of a rental-purchase agreement. </section></text><history>Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 196, sec. 6, effective July 13, 1990; and ch. 304, sec. 6, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><lrc-note> (7/13/90).  This section was created by two separate 1990 Acts which are identical and have therefore been compiled together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35153</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>