<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="319" order_by="319">A OCCUPATIONAL THERAPISTS </unit></structure><section_number>319A.080</section_number><catch_line>License required for practice of occupational therapy or use of title "occupational therapist" -- Training requirements for use of deep physical agent modalities. </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It shall be unlawful for any person to practice occupational therapy, assist in the practice of occupational therapy, or render services designated as occupational therapy in the Commonwealth of Kentucky, unless licensed under the provisions of this chapter. </section><section prefix="2">The licensure of occupational therapists and occupational therapy assistants shall extend only to individuals. A license shall not be issued to a partnership, unincorporated association, corporation, or similar business organization. </section><section prefix="3">It shall be unlawful for a person to act or represent himself or herself as an occupational therapist or occupational therapy assistant, use the title "occupational therapist" or "occupational therapy assistant," or use the letters OT or OTA or any abbreviation or acronym that would imply licensing under this chapter, unless the person is licensed and is in good standing in accordance with the requirements of this chapter. A person, health care institution, health care service, health plan, or other entity holding itself out to the public as providing occupational therapy services shall not use the title unless the occupational therapy services are provided by a person licensed under this chapter. </section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">It shall be unlawful for a person licensed under this chapter to utilize occupational therapy interventions involving deep physical agent modalities, unless the following requirements are met: <section prefix="1">The person is an occupational therapist licensed under this chapter who has successfully completed a minimum of thirty-six (36) hours of training or instruction that meets the requirements specified in administrative regulations promulgated by the board, as well as five (5) treatments under supervision; </section><section prefix="2">The person is an occupational therapist licensed under this chapter who has successfully completed the certified hand therapist examination approved by the Hand Therapy Certification Commission, and who has successfully completed a minimum of twelve (12) hours of training or instruction that meets the requirements specified in administrative regulations promulgated by the board, as well as five (5) treatments under supervision; or </section><section prefix="3">The person is an occupational therapy assistant licensed under this chapter who has successfully completed a minimum of seventy-two (72) hours of training or instruction that meets the requirements specified in administrative regulations promulgated by the board, as well as five (5) treatments under supervision. </section></section><section prefix="b">The board shall promulgate administrative regulations setting forth content guidelines for the training and instruction required in this subsection. Guidelines shall be based on policies and positions adopted by the American Occupational Therapy Association. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:54</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31261</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>