<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.6316</section_number><catch_line>Review of procedures for medical assistance reimbursement of pharmacists to reduce fraud and abuse -- Dispensing fee. </catch_line><order_by>6316</order_by><text>The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall review the procedures for medical assistance reimbursement of pharmacists to reduce fraud and abuse. The cabinet shall by promulgation of administrative regulation, pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A, establish the following: <section prefix="1">Point-of-sale computer technology, with integration of data at the physician's office and the pharmacy, that will permit prospective drug utilization review; </section><section prefix="2">Usage parameters by drug class to enable medical necessity and appropriateness reviews to be conducted prior to payment; </section><section prefix="3">A dialog among the Department for Medicaid Services, the Kentucky Medical Board of Licensure, and the Kentucky Board of Pharmacy, to develop recommendations for legislation for the 1996 Regular Session of the General Assembly that will strengthen the generic substitution laws for prescription medication; and </section><section prefix="4">A dispensing fee for each prescription. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 250, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 108, sec. 2, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 8, sec. 2, effective February 21, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 521, sec. 29, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 208, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 512, sec. 75, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7761</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>