<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>271B.7-250</section_number><catch_line>Quorum and voting requirements for voting groups. </catch_line><order_by>7-250</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Shares entitled to vote as a separate voting group may take action on a matter at a meeting only if a quorum of those shares exists with respect to that matter. Unless the articles of incorporation or this chapter provide otherwise, a majority of the votes entitled to be cast on the matter by the voting group shall constitute a quorum of that voting group for action on that matter. </section><section prefix="2">Once a share is represented for any purpose at a meeting, it shall be deemed present for quorum purposes for the remainder of the meeting and for any adjournment of that meeting, unless a new record date is or must be set for that adjourned meeting. </section><section prefix="3">If a quorum exists, action on a matter (other than the election of directors) by a voting group shall be approved if the votes cast within the voting group favoring the action exceed the votes cast opposing the action, unless the articles of incorporation or this chapter require a greater number of affirmative votes. </section><section prefix="4">An amendment of articles of incorporation adding, changing, or deleting a quorum or voting requirement for a voting group greater than specified in subsection (1) or (3) of this section shall be governed by KRS 271B.7-270. </section><section prefix="5">The election of directors shall be governed by KRS 271B.7-280. </section></text><history>Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 61, effective January 1, 1989. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 1989 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13365</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>