<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VII" order_by="7">PUBLIC PROPERTY AND PUBLIC PRINTING</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="56" order_by="56">STATE LANDS AND BUILDINGS </unit></structure><section_number>56.814</section_number><catch_line>Employees forbidden to disclose information prior to advertisement. </catch_line><order_by>814</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No officer or employee of any state agency shall engage in any act or make any representation or commitment to any person relative to the lease of any real property by the state without specific written authorization from and approval by the Finance and Administration Cabinet and neither the state nor the department shall be bound by the act, representation, or commitment unless so authorized and approved. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">No officer or employee of any state agency shall disclose to any person or firm who might reasonably be expected to submit a proposal, any approved plans by the department for the lease of real property for which public notice is required under KRS 43.050, 48.111, and 56.800 to 56.823 prior to the public notice. Discussions of approved leasing plans may be held after public notice with persons interested in submitting a proposal pertaining to the space requirements. </section><section prefix="b">If all of the proposals, submitted in response to the advertisement referred to in paragraph (a) of this subsection, are rejected, then the requirements of paragraph (a) shall govern disclosure before, and discussions after, new advertisements are placed. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 46, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 29, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 539, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 512, sec. 9, effective July 13, 1990. --- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 231, sec. 8, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22710</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>