<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="11" order_by="11">A EXECUTIVE BRANCH CODE OF ETHICS </unit></structure><section_number>11A.201</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 11A.201 to 11A.246 and KRS 11A.990.   </catch_line><order_by>201</order_by><text>As used in KRS 11A.201 to 11A.246 and KRS 11A.990: <section prefix="1">"Compensation" means any money, thing of value, or economic benefit conferred on, or received by, any person in return for services rendered, or to be rendered, by himself or another; </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">"Expenditure" means any of the following that is made to, or for the benefit of an elected executive official, the secretary of a cabinet listed in KRS 12.250, an executive agency official, or a member of the staff of any of the officials listed in this paragraph:<section prefix="1">A payment, distribution, loan, advance, deposit, reimbursement, or gift of money, real estate, or anything of value, including, but not limited to, food and beverages, entertainment, lodging, transportation, or honoraria; </section><section prefix="2">A contract, promise, or agreement to make an expenditure; or </section><section prefix="3">The purchase, sale, or gift of services or any other thing of value. </section></section><section prefix="b">"Expenditure" does not include a contribution, gift, or grant to a foundation or other charitable organization that is exempt from federal income taxation under Section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code. "Expenditure" does not include the purchase, sale, or gift of services or any other thing of value that is available to the general public on the same terms as it is available to the persons listed in this subsection. "Expenditure" does not include a payment, contribution, gift, purchase, or any other thing of value that is made to or on behalf of any elected executive official, the secretary of a cabinet listed in KRS 12.250, an executive agency official, or any member of the staff of any of the officials listed in this paragraph who works for a state agency for which the executive agency lobbyist is not registered to influence; </section></section><section prefix="3">"Employer" means any person who engages an executive agency lobbyist; </section><section prefix="4">"Engage" means to make any arrangement, and "engagement" means arrangement, whereby an individual is employed or retained for compensation to act for or on behalf of an employer to influence executive agency decisions or to conduct any executive agency lobbying activity; </section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">"Financial transaction" means a transaction or activity that is conducted or undertaken for profit and arises from the joint ownership, or the ownership, or part ownership in common of any real or personal property or any commercial or business enterprise of whatever form or nature between the following: <section prefix="1">An executive agency lobbyist, his employer, a real party in interest, or a member of the immediate family of the executive agency lobbyist, his employer, or a real party in interest; and </section><section prefix="2">Any elected executive official, the secretary of a cabinet listed in KRS 12.250, an executive agency official, or any member of the staff of any of the officials listed in this subparagraph. </section></section><section prefix="b">"Financial transaction" does not include any transaction or activity described in paragraph (a) of this subsection if it is available to the general public on the same terms; </section></section><section prefix="6">"Executive agency" means the office of an elected executive official, a cabinet listed in KRS 12.250, or any other state agency, department, board, or commission controlled or directed by an elected executive official or otherwise subject to his authority. "Executive agency" does not include any court or the General Assembly; </section><section prefix="7">"Executive agency decision" means a decision of an executive agency regarding the expenditure of funds of the state or of an executive agency with respect to the award of a contract, grant, lease, or other financial arrangement under which those funds are distributed or allocated; </section><section prefix="8"><section prefix="a">"Executive agency lobbyist" means any person engaged to influence executive agency decisions or to conduct executive agency lobbying activity as one (1) of his main purposes on a substantial basis. The term "executive agency lobbyist" shall also include placement agents and unregulated placement agents. </section><section prefix="b">"Executive agency lobbyist" does not include an elected or appointed officer or employee of a federal or state agency, state college, state university, or political subdivision who attempts to influence or affect executive agency decisions in his fiduciary capacity as a representative of his agency, college, university, or political subdivision; </section></section><section prefix="9"><section prefix="a">"Executive agency lobbying activity" means contacts made to promote, oppose, or otherwise influence the outcome of an executive agency decision by direct communication with an elected executive official, the secretary of any cabinet listed in KRS 12.250, any executive agency official, or a member of the staff of any one of the officials listed in this paragraph. </section><section prefix="b">"Executive agency lobbying activity" does not include any of the following: <section prefix="1">The action of any person having a direct interest in executive agency decisions, if the person acting under Section 1 of the Kentucky Constitution, assembles together with other persons for their common good, petitions any person listed in paragraph (a) of this subsection for the redress of grievances or other proper purposes; </section><section prefix="2">Contacts made for the sole purpose of gathering information contained in a public record; or </section><section prefix="3">Appearances before public meetings of executive agencies; </section></section></section><section prefix="10">"Executive agency official" means an officer or employee of an executive agency whose principal duties are to formulate policy or to participate directly or indirectly in the preparation, review, or award of contracts, grants, leases, or other financial arrangements with an executive agency; </section><section prefix="11">"Aggrieved party" means a party entitled to resort to a remedy; </section><section prefix="12">"Elected executive official" means the Governor, Lieutenant Governor, Secretary of State, Auditor of Public Accounts, State Treasurer, Attorney General, and Commissioner of Agriculture; </section><section prefix="13">"Person" means an individual, proprietorship, firm, partnership, limited partnership, joint venture, joint stock company, syndicate, business or statutory trust, donative trust, estate, company, corporation, limited liability company, association, club, committee, organization, or group of persons acting in concert; </section><section prefix="14">"Staff" means any employee of the office of the Governor, or a cabinet listed in KRS 12.250, whose official duties are to formulate policy and who exercises administrative or supervisory authority, or who authorizes the expenditure of state funds; </section><section prefix="15">"Real party in interest" means the person or entity on whose behalf an executive agency lobbyist is acting, if that person or entity is not the employer of the executive agency lobbyist; </section><section prefix="16">"Substantial basis" means contacts which are intended to influence a decision that involves one or more disbursements of state funds in an amount of at least five thousand dollars ($5,000) per year; </section><section prefix="17">"Placement agent" means an individual or firm who is compensated or hired by an employer or other real party in interest for the purpose of influencing an executive agency decision regarding the investment of the Kentucky Retirement Systems or the Kentucky Teachers' Retirement System assets; and </section><section prefix="18">"Unregulated placement agent" means a placement agent who is prohibited by federal securities laws and regulations promulgated thereunder from receiving compensation for soliciting a government agency. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 75, sec. 2, effective April 11, 2012. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 417, sec. 6, effective December 1, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1993 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 45, effective September 16, 1993. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><lrc-note> (12/1/2000). The contingency on the effectiveness of this statute set by 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 417, sec. 18, was met, the voters of the Commonwealth having ratified at the general election on November 7, 2000, a constitutional amendment (see 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 399) abolishing the Railroad Commission. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42376</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>