<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="309" order_by="309">MISCELLANEOUS OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS </unit></structure><section_number>309.353</section_number><catch_line>License required to practice massage therapy or use titles, advertisements, or signs indicating massage therapy is provided. </catch_line><order_by>353</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall practice massage therapy or hold himself or herself out to be a massage therapist unless the person meets the educational and licensing requirements of KRS 309.358 and 309.360 and holds a valid license that has not been suspended or revoked. </section><section prefix="2">A licensed massage therapist may represent himself or herself as a massage therapist or licensed massage therapist and may use the abbreviation "L.M.T." as part of or immediately following his or her name to identify the profession. </section><section prefix="3">It shall be unlawful for any person, or for any business entity, its employees, agents, or representatives, to practice massage or massage therapy or to use in connection with his, her, or its name or business activity the words "massage," "massage therapy," "massage therapist," "massage practitioner," "masseur," or "masseuse," or the letters "L.M.T.," or any other words, letters, abbreviations, or insignia indicating or implying directly or indirectly that massage therapy is provided or supplied unless massage therapy is provided by a massage therapist licensed and practicing in accordance with KRS 309.350 to 309.364. </section><section prefix="4">Any advertisement or sign to induce the public into believing that one is a massage therapist shall be prima facie evidence of a violation of this section if the person making the advertisement or displaying the sign is not licensed to practice massage therapy in accordance with KRS 309.350 to 309.364. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 45, sec. 4, effective June 24, 2003; and ch. 70, sec. 4, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><lrc-note> (6/24/2003).  2003 Ky. Acts ch. 45, sec. 4, and 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 70, sec. 4, are substantially identical and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30365</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>