<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="18" order_by="18">A STATE PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>18A.138</section_number><catch_line>Affirmative action plan for state government. </catch_line><order_by>138</order_by><text><section prefix="1">To ensure equal employment opportunity for all Kentuckians regardless of race, color, religion, national origin, disability, sex, or age, the affirmative action plan dated July 1, 1984, confirmed as part of Executive Order 84-549 continued in force by Executive Order 88-100, and incorporated herein by reference, shall be the official affirmative action plan for Kentucky state government. Copies of the plan, as well as the plans developed by individual agencies pursuant to the state plan, shall be maintained on file and made available for inspection in the Office of the Secretary of Personnel. </section><section prefix="2">Every program cabinet, department, and agency of state government shall comply with the provisions of the affirmative action plan. </section><section prefix="3">Equal employment opportunities shall be an integral part of each cabinet, department, and agency program, and any program evaluation shall include an assessment of equal opportunity performance. </section><section prefix="4">The secretary of personnel shall be responsible for the implementation of the plan. In fulfilling his duties, he shall: <section prefix="a">Require all cabinets, departments, and agencies of state government to develop programs consistent with the plan; </section><section prefix="b">Provide any technical assistance he may deem appropriate to accomplish the purposes of the plan; </section><section prefix="c">Provide, through the Personnel Cabinet, an annual analysis to ensure that persons protected by antidiscrimination laws are not adversely affected by examination and selection procedures; </section><section prefix="d">Provide for validation of examination procedures; </section><section prefix="e">Provide for procedures to monitor appointments and salary adjustments to ensure that standards are uniformly applied so as to prevent salary disparity; </section><section prefix="f">Report to the Governor semiannually on actions taken pursuant to the plan; and </section><section prefix="g">Review the plan on an annual basis and recommend necessary changes in consultation with the appropriate agencies. </section></section><section prefix="5">The secretary of personnel may also: <section prefix="a">Promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with this chapter and KRS Chapter 13A to implement the affirmative action plan; </section><section prefix="b">Implement programs to ensure that reasonable accommodations exist for persons with disabilities to allow them better access to all employment opportunities in state government; and </section><section prefix="c">Appoint an affirmative action advisory committee to assist him in implementation of the affirmative action plan. </section></section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 34, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 405, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 309, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 127, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, C, 2, (2) at 628.  See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, D, 10, (1) at 636. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1374</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>