<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="362" order_by="362">PARTNERSHIPS </unit></structure><section_number>362.605</section_number><catch_line>Suits by and against partnerships -- Effect of judgments.   </catch_line><order_by>605</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A general partnership may sue or be sued in its real name. A judgment by or against a partnership shall bind the partnership as if it were a legal entity. A judgment against a partnership shall not bind a partner in his individual capacity except to the extent permitted by KRS 362.220. </section><section prefix="2">A limited partnership may sue or be sued in its real name. A judgment by or against a limited partnership shall bind the limited partnership as a legal entity. Judgment against a limited partnership shall not bind a general partner in his, her or its individual capacity except to the extent permitted by KRS 362.447 and 362.220, and only if the general partner is named as a party in the action. </section><section prefix="3">The real name of a partnership or limited partnership shall be determined in accordance with KRS 365.015. </section></text><history>Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 34, sec. 55, effective June 24, 2015. -- Repeal the prior repeal contained in 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 239, which was to have been effective January 1, 2008, 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 180, effective June 26, 2007. -- Repealed 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 239, effective January 1, 2008. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 389, sec. 107, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective>June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44368</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>