<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="69" order_by="69">COMMONWEALTH'S AND COUNTY ATTORNEYS </unit></structure><section_number>69.350</section_number><catch_line>Employment of victim advocate. </catch_line><order_by>350</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each county attorney may employ individually or jointly with one (1) or more other county attorneys at least one (1) victim advocate to counsel and assist crime victims as defined in KRS 421.500. </section><section prefix="2">An individual employed as a victim advocate shall be a person who by a combination of education, professional qualification, training, and experience is qualified to perform the duties of this position. The victim advocate shall be an individual at least eighteen (18) years of age, of good moral character, with at least two (2) years of experience working in the human services field or court system in a position requiring professional contact with children or adults, who has: <section prefix="a">Received a baccalaureate degree in social work, sociology, psychology, guidance and counseling, education, religion, criminal justice, or other human service field; or </section><section prefix="b">Received a high school diploma or equivalency certificate, and, in addition to the experience required in this subsection, has at least four (4) years' experience working in the human services field or court system. </section></section><section prefix="3">Each county attorney who employs an individual to serve as a victim advocate shall develop a written job description which describes the duties of the position and shall ensure the victim advocate completes training relating to the appropriate intervention with crime victims, including victims of domestic violence and elder abuse, neglect, and exploitation and other crimes against the elderly. Each victim advocate shall perform those duties necessary to insure compliance with the crime victim's bill of rights contained in KRS 421.500 to 421.530. No victim advocate shall engage in political activities while in the course of performing duties as victim advocate or the practice of law as defined in KRS 524.130. The creation and funding of any new personnel position shall be reviewed and approved by the Prosecutors Advisory Council. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 16, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 189, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24161</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>