<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="212" order_by="212">LOCAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>212.639</section_number><catch_line>State aid -- Budget -- Annual report -- Compliance with KRS 65A.010 to 65A.090. </catch_line><order_by>639</order_by><text><section prefix="1">To provide sufficient funds for carrying out the provisions of KRS 212.626 to 212.639, the department shall be entitled to the same state aid as is provided for county and district health departments under KRS 212.120, upon notice of the establishment of the department being given to the Cabinet for Health and Family Services as provided in KRS 212.120, the legislative intent being hereby declared to be that funding from the Cabinet for Health and Family Services be continued at least at the same level and proportion after July 1, 1977, as before its implementation and that modification or alteration of the annual allotment not be made unless for causes enumerated under the provisions of KRS 212.120. </section><section prefix="2">If the sums derived from the appropriations, together with funds otherwise available from any other source to the board during any fiscal year, for its necessary expenditures in the maintenance and operation of the board, exceed its need for such expenditures during such fiscal year, any such unexpended funds at the end of the fiscal year shall be carried forward by the board to be used in paying for its operating costs and expenses for its ensuing year. </section><section prefix="3">The fiscal year of the board shall begin on July 1 of each year and shall end on June 30 of the following year. </section><section prefix="4">In a timely fashion governed by the requirements of the various funding sources such as the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, urban-county government, and any and all other sources, the commissioner shall prepare for board approval a budget setting forth the total amounts of funds available from all sources for expenditures during the board's fiscal year, and setting forth the estimated expenditures of the board for the fiscal year. </section><section prefix="5">The board shall install and maintain a system of accounting and shall file an annual report of its fiscal and other operations to the Cabinet for Health and Family Services and to the legislative body of the urban-county government after the close of the board's fiscal year. The annual report shall be accompanied by such information, tables, and data as may be necessary to present a reasonably detailed report of the board's condition and activities during the preceding year. </section><section prefix="6">The board shall comply with the provisions of KRS 65A.010 to 65A.090. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 66, effective March 21, 2013. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 417, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 368, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 347, sec. 13, effective July 1, 1977. </history><metadata><effective> March 21, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41746</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>