<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="514" order_by="514">THEFT AND RELATED OFFENSES </unit></structure><section_number>514.120</section_number><catch_line>Obscuring identity of machine or other property. </catch_line><order_by>120</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of obscuring the identity of a machine or other property when he or she: <section prefix="a">Removes, defaces, covers, alters, destroys, or otherwise obscures the manufacturer's serial number or any other distinguishing identification number or mark, including property marked with a Social Security number or motor vehicle operator's license number for identification purposes, upon any automobile or other propelled vehicle, machine, or electrical or mechanical device, or other property, including any part thereof, with intent to render it or other property unidentifiable; or </section><section prefix="b">Possesses any automobile or other propelled vehicle, machine, or electrical or mechanical device, or other property, including any part thereof, knowing that the serial number or other identification number or mark, including property marked with a Social Security number for identification purposes, has been removed, defaced, covered, altered, destroyed, or otherwise obscured. </section></section><section prefix="2">Possession of any automobile or other propelled vehicle, machine, or electrical or mechanical device, or other property, including any part thereof, on which the serial number or any other distinguishing identification number or mark, including property marked with a Social Security number or motor vehicle operator's license number for identification purposes, has been removed, defaced, covered, altered, destroyed, or otherwise obscured is prima facie evidence of knowledge of that fact. </section><section prefix="3">A person in possession of any property which is otherwise in violation of this section may apply in writing to the Department of Kentucky State Police, through any law enforcement agency in the county of his or her residence, for assignment of a number for the property providing he or she can show that he or she is the lawful owner of the property pursuant to the provisions of this section and KRS 16.200 and 500.090. If a number is issued in conformity with the provisions of this section and KRS 16.200 and 500.090, then the person to whom it was issued and any person to whom the property is lawfully disposed of shall not be in violation of these sections. A person lawfully holding a certification issued pursuant to KRS 500.090 shall also be deemed in compliance with this section. This section shall apply only when the application has been filed by the defendant prior to arrest or authorization of a warrant of arrest for the defendant by a court. </section><section prefix="4">Obscuring the identity of a machine or other property is a Class A misdemeanor unless the value of the property is: <section prefix="a">Five hundred dollars ($500) or more but less than ten thousand dollars ($10,000), in which case it is a Class D felony; or </section><section prefix="b">Ten thousand dollars ($10,000) or more, in which case it is a Class C felony. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 14, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 327, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 451, sec. 8, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 267, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 4, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 128, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19814</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>