<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="365" order_by="365">TRADE PRACTICES </unit></structure><section_number>365.577</section_number><catch_line>Certificate of registration. </catch_line><order_by>577</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon the applicant's compliance with the requirements of KRS 365.561 to 365.613, the Secretary shall cause a certificate of registration to be issued and delivered to the applicant. The certificate of registration shall be issued under the signature of the Secretary and the seal of the state, and it shall show the registrant's name and business address and, if the registrant is a corporation, the state of incorporation, or if a partnership, the state in which the partnership is organized, the names of the general partners, the person claiming ownership of the mark, the date claimed for the first use of the mark anywhere, the date claimed for the first use of the mark in this state, the class of goods or services, a description of the goods or services on or in connection with which the mark is used, a reproduction of the mark, the registration date, and the term of the registration. </section><section prefix="2">Any certificate of registration issued pursuant to this section or a copy of the certificate duly certified by the Secretary shall be admissible in evidence as competent and sufficient proof of the registration of the mark in any actions or judicial proceedings in any court of this state. </section></text><history> Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 468, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34808</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>