<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.6015</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Innovation Commission -- Members -- Duties -- Support staff. </catch_line><order_by>6015</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is established the Kentucky Innovation Commission, as an independent advisory commission, consisting of fifteen (15) members as follows: <section prefix="a">The Governor or designee; </section><section prefix="b">The secretary of the Governor's Executive Cabinet or designee; </section><section prefix="c">The secretary of the Cabinet for Economic Development or designee; </section><section prefix="d">The president of the Council on Postsecondary Education or designee; </section><section prefix="e">The state budget director or designee; </section><section prefix="f">The Speaker of the House or designee; </section><section prefix="g">The President of the Senate or designee; and </section><section prefix="h">Eight (8) at-large members appointed by the Governor as follows: <section prefix="1">Four (4) members of the private sector possessing extensive experience and expertise relating to managing a high-technology business or engaging in an innovation-driven, knowledge-based enterprise; </section><section prefix="2">One (1) member engaged in the business of venture capital; </section><section prefix="3">One (1) member of the private sector possessing extensive experience and expertise relating to providing or supporting communications infrastructure; and </section><section prefix="4">Two (2) members who are engineers or scientists recognized for their scientific or technological research efforts, or educators with an interest or background in teaching students to become highly skilled workers or entrepreneurs. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">The eight (8) at-large members shall serve terms of four (4) years, except that the original appointments shall be staggered so that two (2) appointments shall expire at two (2) years, three (3) appointments shall expire at three (3) years, and three (3) appointments shall expire at four (4) years from the dates of initial appointment. </section><section prefix="3">The commission shall meet quarterly and at other times upon call by the chair. </section><section prefix="4">Eight (8) members shall constitute a quorum for conducting business. </section><section prefix="5">Members shall receive no compensation except that the at-large members shall be reimbursed for actual and necessary travel expenses for attending meetings and performing other official functions, consistent with state reimbursement policy for state employees. </section><section prefix="6">A vacancy shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment. </section><section prefix="7">The chair and vice chair of the commission shall be appointed by the Governor. </section><section prefix="8">The commission shall provide ongoing advice, direction, and policy recommendations to the Governor and the General Assembly relating to the status of Kentucky knowledge-driven businesses, research and development initiatives, and related high-skill training and education in the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="9">The duties and responsibilities of the commission shall be to: <section prefix="a">Promote the cooperation of private and public entities that have the purpose and duty of advancing the knowledge-based economy in the Commonwealth through technological innovation and knowledge transfer; </section><section prefix="b">Report on the progress the Commonwealth has made annually toward achieving the goals in KRS 164.6013 through its agreed-upon benchmarks. In the setting of benchmarks the commission shall consider performance indicators recommended by public and private experts in and outside of the state in the fields of research and development and economic development, for the purpose of recommending benchmarks. Experts in this state shall include but not be limited to representatives from the universities undertaking research and development activities, representatives of the Kentucky Science and Technology Corporation, representatives of targeted technology sectors, representatives of the Cabinet for Economic Development, and representatives of other state agencies having economic development and information technology responsibilities. Outside state experts shall include nationally recognized independent reviewers to assess the competitiveness of technology sectors in this state and the impact of research and development activities on economic development in the Commonwealth. Quantitative and qualitative indicators may include but are not limited to the following: <section prefix="1">Kentucky companies modernizing to become more technologically innovative and globally competitive; </section><section prefix="2">Research and development initiatives undertaken at Kentucky universities with federal, state, or private funds; </section><section prefix="3">Educational attainment in areas that support the workforce needs of information technology and high-growth knowledge industries; </section><section prefix="4">High-technology sectors and companies moving to and operating in the state; </section><section prefix="5">Patents filed for technology or knowledge-based commercial products, processes, or services; </section><section prefix="6">Businesses using electronic commerce and the communications infrastructure access capacity for Kentucky businesses; </section><section prefix="7">Growth in corporate headquarters, research and development centers, high-income employees, and clustering of related technology industries and suppliers; and </section><section prefix="8">Monitoring reports indicating progress made by the Kentucky Innovation Act investments as reported by the Department of Commercialization and Innovation and the Council on Postsecondary Education; </section></section><section prefix="c">Operate as a common strategic umbrella to advocate for the use of federal, state, local government, and private sector funds to create research and development projects, modernize manufacturing facilities, and promote knowledge-based, technology sectors and companies in the Commonwealth; and </section><section prefix="d">Report to the Governor and to the General Assembly annually on performance indicators, recommending benchmarks for measuring progress toward the advancement of the knowledge-based economy, technological innovation, and knowledge transfer, and reporting on the programs and initiatives set forth in KRS 164.6019 to 164.6041, 154.12-274, 154.12-278, and KRS 154.12-300 to 154.12-310. </section></section><section prefix="10">The support staff for the commission shall be from the office of the state budget director. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 98, sec. 11, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 210, sec. 10, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 181, sec. 14, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 230, sec. 31, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 522, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4347</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>