<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.675</section_number><catch_line>Annual fees -- Permanent registration and fee. </catch_line><order_by>675</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The annual registration fee for trailers and semitrailers which are drawn by motor vehicles required to be licensed under KRS 186.050(1) shall be four dollars and fifty cents ($4.50). The annual registration fee for trailers and semitrailers which are drawn by motor vehicles required to be licensed under KRS 186.050(3) to (13) shall be nineteen dollars and fifty cents ($19.50). </section><section prefix="2">The provisions of KRS 186.650 to 186.700 shall not apply to privately owned and operated trailers used for the transportation of: <section prefix="a">Boats; </section><section prefix="b">Luggage; </section><section prefix="c">Personal effects; </section><section prefix="d">Farm products, farm supplies, or farm equipment; </section><section prefix="e">All-terrain vehicles as defined in KRS 189.010(24); </section><section prefix="f">Wildlife as defined in KRS 150.010(41) that the owner or operator of the trailer has obtained while hunting; and </section><section prefix="g">Firearms or other supplies used in conjunction with hunting wildlife. </section></section><section prefix="3">The registration fee for mobile homes and recreational vehicles shall be nine dollars and fifty cents ($9.50) except the registration fee for camping trailers, travel trailers, and truck campers shall be four dollars and fifty cents ($4.50). The clerk shall issue the registration plate furnished by the cabinet and shall be paid for this service the sum of one dollar ($1). </section><section prefix="4">Beginning April 1, 1993, at the request of the owner, trailers and semitrailers which are drawn by motor vehicles required to be licensed under KRS 186.050(3) to (13) may be permanently registered, except the registration shall expire when the trailer or semitrailer is sold or when it is otherwise permanently removed from service by the owner. The registration fee for the period shall be ninety-eight dollars ($98). The clerk shall issue the registration plate furnished by the cabinet and shall be paid for this service the sum of three dollars ($3). </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 460, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 428, sec. 32, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 1, effective April 1, 1993. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 25, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982; and ch. 395, sec. 15, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 84, sec. 6, effective June 17, 17, 1978. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 139, sec. 17, effective January 1, 1967. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 70, sec. 27. -- Created 1956 (2nd Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 7. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6110</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>