<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.39-010</section_number><catch_line>Policy and purpose. </catch_line><order_by>39-010</order_by><text>The toll of about 20,000,000 motor vehicle accidents nationally and comparable experience in Kentucky upon the interests of victims, the public, policyholders and others require that improvements in the reparations provided for herein be adopted to effect the following purposes:  <section prefix="1">To require owners, registrants and operators of motor vehicles in the Commonwealth to procure insurance covering basic reparation benefits and legal liability arising out of ownership, operation or use of such motor vehicles;  </section><section prefix="2">To provide prompt payment to victims of motor vehicle accidents without regard to whose negligence caused the accident in order to eliminate the inequities which fault-determination has created;  </section><section prefix="3">To encourage prompt medical treatment and rehabilitation of the motor vehicle accident victim by providing for prompt payment of needed medical care and rehabilitation;  </section><section prefix="4">To permit more liberal wage loss and medical benefits by allowing claims for intangible loss only when their determination is reasonable and appropriate;  </section><section prefix="5">To reduce the need to resort to bargaining and litigation through a system which can pay victims of motor vehicle accidents without the delay, expense, aggravation, inconvenience, inequities and uncertainties of the liability system;  </section><section prefix="6">To help guarantee the continued availability of motor vehicle insurance at reasonable prices by a more efficient, economical and equitable system of motor vehicle accident reparations;  </section><section prefix="7">To create an insurance system which can more adequately be regulated; and  </section><section prefix="8">To correct the inadequacies of the present reparation system, recognizing that it was devised and our present Constitution adopted prior to the development of the internal combustion motor vehicle.  </section></text><history>Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 385, sec. 1, effective July 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective>July 1, 1975 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30024</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>