<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">A URBAN-COUNTY GOVERNMENT </unit></structure><section_number>67A.878</section_number><catch_line>Public hearing. </catch_line><order_by>878</order_by><text>A public hearing shall be held at the time and place designated in the ordinance of initiation.  Any person qualifying under the provisions of KRS 67A.875(7) shall preside and conduct the hearing.  The presiding officer shall cause reasonable notes or minutes of the proceedings to be made, and they shall be submitted in writing to a subsequent regularly scheduled meeting of the urban-county council of the government.  Any owner of property proposed to be benefited by the proposed wastewater collection project may appear and be heard at the public hearing, either in person or by a duly authorized representative.  Any such owner of benefited property may submit to the presiding officer or to the designated clerk a written instrument in which such owner of benefited property is identified by name, address and designation of benefited property, and containing a statement of any reason for advocating or objecting to any of the aspects of the proposed project, and such written instruments shall be attached to and included in the written report of the hearing.  Whether or not any such written instruments are submitted, the presiding officer at the public hearing may require those in attendance to execute an attendance roster, to properly identify themselves as owners of benefited property or representatives of the owners, and may impose reasonable rules upon the conduct of the public hearing.  The estimated costs of the project shall be disclosed at the public hearing, or, if construction bids for construction of the project have been received, the results of the bidding shall be disclosed.  A report of local health agencies may be made a part of the public hearing, and the government may cause distribution of informative materials and summarizations of engineering and health reports to be carried out at the public hearing.  The public hearing may be adjourned to convene again, and from time to time either at a time and place announced at the public hearing or upon public notice of the time and place to be given in any manner the government may determine. </text><history>Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 371, sec. 8, effective March 30, 1976. </history><metadata><effective>March 30, 1976 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23961</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>