<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="64" order_by="64">FEES AND COMPENSATION OF PUBLIC OFFICERS AND EMPLOYEES </unit></structure><section_number>64.355</section_number><catch_line>Fees in counties of 70,000 or more are property of respective county -- Applicability of KRS 64.368 if population decreases below 70,000. </catch_line><order_by>355</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It is hereby declared to be the intent of the General Assembly that all fees of the office of county clerk and sheriff in counties having a population of seventy thousand (70,000) or more that are paid into the State Treasury pursuant to the provisions of Section 106 of the Constitution of Kentucky are the property of the respective county, and these fees along with those collected by the circuit clerk shall be computed as part of the county's total tax effort for the purpose of determining credit for any federally funded program. </section><section prefix="2">If a county's population that equaled or exceeded seventy thousand (70,000) is less than seventy thousand (70,000) after the most recent federal decennial census, then the provisions of KRS 64.368 shall apply. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 11, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 220, sec. 7, effective January 1, 1994. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 385, sec. 18, effective July 1, 1982. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 35, effective January 2, 1978. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23237</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>