<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.878</section_number><catch_line>Application for certification -- Eligibility. </catch_line><order_by>878</order_by><text><section prefix="1">After June 30, 2006, an applicant for a certificate shall file a written application with the board on a form prescribed by the board and shall pay the application fee set by the board. </section><section prefix="2">To be eligible for a certificate a person shall: <section prefix="a">Hold and maintain certification by one (1) of the following: <section prefix="1">The National Surgical Assistant Association; or </section><section prefix="2">The Liaison Council on Certification for the Surgical Technologist; </section></section><section prefix="b">Document one (1) of the following: <section prefix="1">Graduation from a program approved by the Commission on Accreditation of Allied Health Education Programs (CAAHEP); or </section><section prefix="2">Graduation from a United States Military program that emphasizes surgical assisting; and </section></section><section prefix="c">Demonstrate to the satisfaction of the board the completion of full-time work experience performed in this country under the direct supervision of a physician licensed in this country and consisting of at least eight hundred (800) hours of performance as an assistant in surgical procedures for the three </section></section><section prefix="3">years preceding the date of the application. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 7, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 8, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30667</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>