<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.570</section_number><catch_line>Pedestrians. </catch_line><order_by>570</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Pedestrians shall obey the instruction of any official traffic control devices specifically applicable to them, unless otherwise directed by a police officer or other officially designated persons. </section><section prefix="2">Pedestrians shall be subject to traffic and pedestrian control signals as provided in KRS 189.231 and 189.338. </section><section prefix="3">At all other places, pedestrians shall be accorded the privileges and shall be subject to the restrictions stated in this chapter. </section><section prefix="4">When traffic control signals are not in place or in operation the operator of a vehicle shall yield the right-of-way, slowing down or stopping if need be to so yield, to a pedestrian crossing the roadway upon which the vehicle is traveling, or when the pedestrian is approaching so closely from the opposite half of the roadway as to be in danger. </section><section prefix="5">Whenever any vehicle is stopped at a marked crosswalk or at any unmarked crosswalk at an intersection, to permit a pedestrian to cross the roadway, the operator of any other vehicle approaching from the rear shall not overtake and pass the stopped vehicle. </section><section prefix="6"><section prefix="a">Every pedestrian crossing a roadway at a point other than within a marked crosswalk or within an unmarked crosswalk at an intersection shall yield the right-of-way to all vehicles upon the roadway. </section><section prefix="b">Any pedestrian crossing a roadway at a point where a pedestrian tunnel or overhead pedestrian crossing has been provided shall yield the right-of-way to all vehicles upon the roadway. </section><section prefix="c">Between adjacent intersections within the city limits of every city at which traffic control signals are in operation, pedestrians shall not cross at any place except in a marked crosswalk. </section><section prefix="d">Notwithstanding other provisions of this subsection or the provisions of any local ordinance, every operator of a vehicle shall exercise due care to avoid colliding with any pedestrian and shall give warning by sounding the horn when necessary and shall exercise proper precaution upon observing a child or an obviously confused or incapacitated person upon a roadway. </section></section><section prefix="7">No vehicle shall at any time be driven through or within a safety zone. </section><section prefix="8">The operator of a vehicle shall yield the right-of-way to any pedestrian on a sidewalk. </section><section prefix="9">No pedestrian shall suddenly leave a curb or other place of safety and walk or run into the path of a vehicle which is so close as to constitute an immediate hazard. </section><section prefix="10">No pedestrian shall cross a roadway intersection diagonally unless authorized by official traffic control devices; and, when authorized to cross diagonally, pedestrians shall cross only in accordance with the official traffic control devices pertaining to such crossing movements. </section><section prefix="11">Pedestrians shall move, whenever practicable, upon the right half of crosswalks. </section><section prefix="12">Where a sidewalk is provided and its use is practicable, it shall be unlawful for any pedestrian to walk along and upon an adjacent roadway. </section><section prefix="13">Where a sidewalk is not available, any pedestrian walking along and upon a highway shall walk only on a shoulder, as far as practicable from the edge of the roadway. </section><section prefix="14">Where neither a sidewalk nor a shoulder is available, any pedestrian walking on or along a highway shall walk as near as practicable to an outside edge of the roadway, and, if on a two-way roadway shall walk only on the left side of the roadway. </section><section prefix="15">Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, any pedestrian upon a roadway shall yield the right-of-way to all vehicles upon the roadway. </section><section prefix="16">A pedestrian who is under the influence of alcohol or any kind of drug to a degree which renders himself a hazard shall not walk or be upon a highway except on a sidewalk. </section><section prefix="17">No pedestrian shall enter or remain upon any bridge or approach thereto beyond the bridge signal, gate, or barrier, after a bridge operation signal indication has been given. </section><section prefix="18">No pedestrian shall pass through, around, over, or under any crossing gate or barrier at a railroad grade crossing or bridge while such gate or barrier is closed or is being opened or closed. </section><section prefix="19">No person shall stand in a roadway for the purpose of soliciting a ride. </section><section prefix="20">No person shall stand on a roadway for the purpose of soliciting employment or business from the occupant of any vehicle. </section><section prefix="21">No person shall stand on a highway for the purpose of soliciting contributions unless such soliciting is designated by the presence of a traffic control device or warning signal or an emergency vehicle or public safety vehicle as defined in KRS 189.910 making use of the flashing, rotating or oscillating red, blue, or yellow lights on such devices or vehicles. </section><section prefix="22">No person shall stand on or in proximity to a street or highway for the purpose of soliciting the watching or guarding of any vehicle while parked or about to be parked on a street or highway. </section><section prefix="23">Upon the immediate approach of an emergency vehicle equipped with, and operating, one (1) or more flashing, rotating, or oscillating red or blue lights, visible under normal conditions from a distance of 500 feet to the front of such vehicle, and the operator of which is giving audible signal by siren, exhaust whistle, or bell, every pedestrian shall yield the right-of-way to the emergency vehicle. </section><section prefix="24">This section shall not relieve the operator of an emergency vehicle from the duty to drive with due regard for the safety of all persons using the highway nor from the duty to exercise due care to avoid colliding with any pedestrian. </section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 46, sec. 8, effective June 17, 1978. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2739g-69q to 2739g-69v. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6417</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>