<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">A KENTUCKY MODEL PROCUREMENT CODE </unit></structure><section_number>45A.740</section_number><catch_line>Procedures for proposed project requiring architectural or engineering services. </catch_line><order_by>740</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When a project requiring architectural or engineering services is proposed by a local public agency, except as provided by subsections (2) and (3) of this section, the agency shall: <section prefix="a">Transmit a notice requesting a statement of interest in the proposed project from all firms that have a current qualifications statement on file; </section><section prefix="b">Give adequate public notice of the proposed project, which may include posting on the Internet or newspaper advertisement, requesting firms to submit qualification statements and statements of interest in the proposed project; or </section><section prefix="c">Contact an appropriate professional organization for a list of firms capable of providing the necessary services. </section></section><section prefix="2">If the regulations of a federal department or agency require a procurement process that is different from the process in KRS 45A.730 to 45A.750 in order that financial aid can be granted, then the local government agency may exempt itself from the provisions of KRS 45A.730 to 45A.750. </section><section prefix="3">When a local public agency has formed a working relationship with one (1) or more firms based on work previously contracted between them, then the local public agency may enter directly into negotiations according to KRS 45A.750. If no contract is successfully negotiated, then the local public agency shall comply with this section, KRS 45A.745, and KRS 45A.750. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 18, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 249, sec. 3, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22477</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>