<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="148" order_by="148">PARKS AND TOURISM </unit></structure><section_number>148.850</section_number><catch_line>Tourism Development Finance Authority created -- Members -- Terms -- Conflicts of interest -- Powers. </catch_line><order_by>850</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Tourism Development Finance Authority is created within the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet. The authority shall consist of seven (7) members appointed by the Governor. The members of the authority shall serve without compensation but shall be entitled to reimbursement for their necessary expenses incurred in performing their duties. Of the members initially appointed to the authority, two (2) members shall be appointed for terms of one (1) year, three (3) members shall be appointed for terms of two (2) years, and two (2) members shall be appointed for terms of three (3) years. Thereafter, the members of the authority shall be appointed for terms of four (4) years. </section><section prefix="2">The Governor shall appoint one (1) member as chairperson of the Tourism Development Finance Authority. The members of the authority may elect other officers as they deem necessary. </section><section prefix="3">No member of the Tourism Development Finance Authority shall either directly or indirectly be a party to, or be in any manner interested in, any contract or agreement with the authority for any matter, cause, or thing that creates any liability or indebtedness against the authority. </section><section prefix="4">The Tourism Development Finance Authority shall have the powers necessary to carry out the purposes of this section, KRS 139.536, KRS 148.851 to 148.860, and the Tourism Development Loan Program created by 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 549, Part IX, Section 47, including but not limited to the power to: <section prefix="a">Make and condition all loans from the Tourism Development Loan Program; </section><section prefix="b">Employ fiscal consultants, attorneys, appraisers, and other agents on behalf of the authority whom the authority deems necessary or convenient for the preparation and administration of agreements and documents necessary or incidental to any project. The fees for the services provided by persons employed on behalf of the authority shall be paid by the beneficiary of a loan under this program directly to the person providing consultation, advisory, legal, or other services; and </section><section prefix="c">Impose and collect fees and charges in connection with any transaction and provide for reasonable penalties for delinquent payment of fees and charges. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 26, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 23, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1806</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>