<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="149" order_by="149">FORESTRY </unit></structure><section_number>149.342</section_number><catch_line>Timber harvesting operations -- Master logger training and educational requirements -- Temporary master logger designation. </catch_line><order_by>342</order_by><text><section prefix="1">After two (2) years from July 15, 1998, no person shall conduct timber harvesting operations within the Commonwealth unless there is on the site during the timber harvesting operations at least one (1) logger in charge of the harvest who has successfully completed the Master Logger Program or who has received a temporary master logger designation in accordance with the cabinet requirements as provided for in subsection (4) of this section. </section><section prefix="2">After successful completion of the Master Logger Program, continuing education shall be required of the loggers every three (3) years. </section><section prefix="3">The cabinet shall specify the education and training requirements for the Master Logger Program as developed by the University of Kentucky, the Kentucky Forest Industries Association, and the division, shall specify the requirements for continuing education, and, may establish a basic fee for the program that bears a reasonable relationship to the cost of training. </section><section prefix="4">The cabinet shall specify requirements for a temporary master logger designation, which shall be valid for four (4) months. </section><section prefix="5">A logger or operator who uses a temporary master logger shall notify the division prior to beginning the timber harvesting operation on which a temporary master logger is on site and in charge. </section><section prefix="6">The division shall maintain a current list of all loggers who have successfully completed the Master Logger Program and required continuing education, and shall make the list available to the public. All master loggers shall provide the cabinet with a published phone number. </section><section prefix="7">Loggers who have previously completed the Kentucky Master Logger Program are considered to be in compliance with subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="8">Any logger who primarily uses mules or horses in the logging operation shall be exempt from the Master Logger Program. </section><section prefix="9">After two (2) years from July 15, 1998, all state parks shall have on staff at least one (1) employee who has completed the Master Logger Program. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 39, sec. 1, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 555, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1884</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>