<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">A STATEWIDE EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>39A.230</section_number><catch_line>Procedures for one multirisk, multiagency, unified incident command or management system. </catch_line><order_by>230</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Emergency Operations Plan shall include procedures for one multirisk, multiagency, unified incident command or management system to be used by all state agencies responding to the scene of an emergency, declared emergency, disaster, or catastrophe, as contemplated by KRS 39A.010, 39A.020, or 39A.030. </section><section prefix="2">Local emergency operations plans shall include procedures for: <section prefix="a">An incident command or management system to be used by individual local agencies or departments when responding to the scene of day-to-day, routine emergency incidents; and </section><section prefix="b">One unified incident command or management system to be used by all local agencies or departments when responding to the scene of a multiagency or multijurisdictional emergency, declared emergency, disaster, or catastrophe, as contemplated by KRS 39A.010, 39A.020, or 39A.030. </section></section><section prefix="3">All incident command or management system procedures required pursuant to subsections (1) or (2) of this section shall be based upon or utilize the five (5) functions of: command, operations, planning, logistics, and finance. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 22, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21717</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>