<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.970</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 211.972 to 211.982. </catch_line><order_by>970</order_by><text>As used in KRS 211.972 to 211.982, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Approved" means that which has been considered acceptable to the cabinet; </section><section prefix="2">"Cabinet" means the Cabinet for Health and Family Services and includes its authorized agents; </section><section prefix="3">"Grease" means fats or oils of animal, vegetable, or mineral origin, separately or in colloidal or dissolved states in combination with soaps, detergents, or food particles; </section><section prefix="4">"Grease trap" means a component designed to separate grease and its constituents from the wastewater stream, provide for storage of separated grease, and discharge the remaining wastewater for treatment; </section><section prefix="5">"Holding tank" means a tank which provides limited pretreatment and storage for off-site disposal where site limitations preclude immediate installation of a subsurface soil absorption system, or connection to a municipal sewer. It also includes portable toilets and similar temporary-use units which contain holding tanks; </section><section prefix="6">"Person" means any individual, firm, association, organization, partnership, business trust, corporation, company, or governmental unit; </section><section prefix="7">"Secretary" means the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="8">"Sewage" means domestic blackwater and greywater wastes, but does not include waste from industrial or commercial processes; </section><section prefix="9">"Sewage pretreatment unit" means a watertight sewage treatment structure designed and constructed to receive raw sewage, separate solids from liquids, digest organic matter through a period of retention, and allow clarified effluent to discharge to a subsurface soil absorption system. Pretreatment units fall into three (3) basic categories: <section prefix="a">Septic tanks, which rely predominantly on anaerobic bacterial action for treatment; </section><section prefix="b">Aerobic units, which introduce atmospheric air into the sewage to promote treatment by aerobic bacteria; and </section><section prefix="c">Combination units, which provide treatment through both anaerobic and aerobic bacterial action and mechanical filtering, ozonation, or ultraviolet irradiation; </section></section><section prefix="10">"Sewage sludge" means the solid or semisolid residues which are retained within a sewage pretreatment unit or grease trap, as a result of mechanical, hydraulic, biologic, or chemical actions. It also includes raw sewage accepted and stored within a holding tank; </section><section prefix="11">"Site" means a facility or parcel of land under the ownership of any person which is intended for use as the ultimate disposal or treatment location for sewage sludge; and </section><section prefix="12">"Tank" means any container placed on a vehicle to carry in transport sewage sludge removed from a sewage pretreatment unit, grease trap, or holding tank. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 392, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 342, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 248, sec. 3, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1972 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 1, effective January 1, 1973. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><lrc-note>.  Due to the transfer of functions by KRS 224.022, subsections (1) to (3) have been included in this section by the Reviser of Statutes. Subsections (4) to (7) were formerly compiled in KRS 224.005. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8551</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>