<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="235" order_by="235">BOATS AND BOATING </unit></structure><section_number>235.287</section_number><catch_line>Prohibition areas on lake waters at drinking water intakes -- Exemption. </catch_line><order_by>287</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If a water supply system requests and receives authorization from the Division of Water to designate a prohibition area, no vessel on lake waters of this state shall moor or anchor within one hundred (100) feet of a drinking water intake unless an extension of the area of prohibition is requested and granted under subsection (3) of this section. </section><section prefix="2">The Division of Water shall identify areas on lake waters of this state where a drinking water intake is located. The division shall authorize a water supply system to designate a prohibition area if circumstances are demonstrated justifying the designation. The water supply system shall be responsible for posting signs visible to persons operating vessels indicating areas containing a drinking water intake. </section><section prefix="3">The division shall allow water supply systems with intakes on lake waters of this state to request that the prohibition on mooring or anchoring be extended beyond one hundred (100) feet but no farther than three hundred (300) feet. The division may grant a request if the water supply system demonstrates circumstances that justify extending the area of prohibition. The division shall inform the Department for Fish and Wildlife Resources when an area of prohibition is designated or a request to extend an area of prohibition is granted. </section><section prefix="4">Private or commercial docks shall be exempt from the provisions of subsection (1) of this section. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 413, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11077</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>