<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="322" order_by="322">PROFESSIONAL ENGINEERS AND LAND SURVEYORS </unit></structure><section_number>322.110</section_number><catch_line>Licensure -- Designations -- Rights associated with license. </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall issue a license authorizing the practice of engineering or land surveying to any applicant who has met the respective requirements set forth in this chapter. </section><section prefix="2">All licenses issued under this subsection shall be signed by the chairman and the secretary of the board, under the seal of the board. Each license shall bear the full name of the licensee, the license number, and one (1) of the following designations: <section prefix="a">"Professional Engineer"; </section><section prefix="b">"Professional Land Surveyor"; </section><section prefix="c">"Professional Engineer, Inactive"; </section><section prefix="d">"Professional Engineer, Retired"; </section><section prefix="e">"Professional Land Surveyor, Inactive"; or </section><section prefix="f">"Professional Land Surveyor, Retired." </section></section><section prefix="3">The designations in paragraphs (c), (d), (e), and (f) of subsection (2) of this section shall be defined in administrative regulations promulgated by the board. </section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">A valid professional engineer or professional land surveyor license shall be prima facie evidence that the licensee is entitled to all rights, privileges, and responsibilities of a professional engineer or a professional land surveyor. </section><section prefix="b">A valid license bearing the designation "inactive" or "retired" shall be prima facie evidence that the licensee is entitled to all rights, privileges, and responsibilities of a professional engineer or professional land surveyor, except the right to practice. </section></section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 214, sec. 12, effective January 1, 1999. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 291, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 148, sec. 8. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 1599e-15. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 1999 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31430</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>