<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="278" order_by="278">PUBLIC SERVICE COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>278.274</section_number><catch_line>Review of natural gas utility's purchasing practices in determining reasonableness of proposed rates -- Reduction of rates by commission. </catch_line><order_by>274</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In determining whether proposed natural gas utility rates are just and reasonable, the commission shall review the utility's gas purchasing practices. The commission may disallow any costs or rates which are deemed to result from imprudent purchasing practices on the part of the utility. </section><section prefix="2">When proposing new rates, the utility shall be required to prove that the proposal is just and reasonable in accordance with the requirements of this section. </section><section prefix="3">It shall be presumed that natural gas purchases from affiliated companies are not conducted at arm's length. <section prefix="a">For purposes of this subsection, affiliated companies shall be defined as those in which one (1) or more of the owners control or have the right to control the business affairs of all affected companies. </section><section prefix="b">In instances in which a utility purchases natural gas from an intrastate affiliate, the commission shall assume jurisdiction of the affiliated company as though it were a utility as defined in KRS 278.010. The commission's jurisdiction shall extend to that extent necessary to ensure that the rates charged the utility and ultimately to the consumer are just and reasonable. </section><section prefix="c">If the commission determines that the rates charged by the utility are not just and reasonable in that the cost of natural gas purchased from the affiliated company is unjust or unreasonable, the commission may reduce the purchased gas component of the utility's rates by the amount deemed to be unjust or unreasonable. </section><section prefix="d">The commission may also reduce the rate charged by the affiliated company by the same amount. </section></section></text><history>Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14098</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>