<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.684</section_number><catch_line>Revocation of license -- Written admonishment -- Other disciplinary proceedings. </catch_line><order_by>684</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board may: <section prefix="a">Revoke a license; </section><section prefix="b">Suspend a license for a period not to exceed five (5) years; </section><section prefix="c">Deny an application for a license; </section><section prefix="d">Decline to renew a license; </section><section prefix="e">Indefinitely restrict or limit a license; </section><section prefix="f">Issue a fine of up to two thousand dollars ($2,000) per violation and/or the costs of the proceedings; </section><section prefix="g">Place a license on probation for a period not to exceed five (5) years; </section><section prefix="h">Reprimand the acupuncturist; or </section><section prefix="i">Impose any combination of such sanctions, upon proof that the acupuncturist has: <section prefix="1">Knowingly made or presented or caused to be made or presented any false, fraudulent, or forged statement, writing, certificate, diploma, or other document relating to an application for licensure; </section><section prefix="2">Practiced, aided, or abetted in the practice of fraud, forgery, deception, collusion, or conspiracy relating to an examination for licensure; </section><section prefix="3">Entered a guilty or nolo contendere plea, or been convicted, by any court within or without the Commonwealth of Kentucky, of committing an act which is or would be a felony under the laws of the Commonwealth of Kentucky or of the United States; </section><section prefix="4">Entered a guilty or nolo contendere plea, or been convicted, by any court within or without the Commonwealth of Kentucky, of any misdemeanor offense which has dishonesty as a fundamental and necessary element, including but not limited to crimes involving theft, embezzlement, false swearing, perjury, fraud, or misrepresentation; </section><section prefix="5">Become addicted to, or is an abuser of, alcohol, drugs, or any illegal substance; </section><section prefix="6">Developed a physical or mental disability or other condition that presents a danger in continuing to practice acupuncture to patients, the public, or other health-care personnel; </section><section prefix="7">Knowingly made, caused to be made, or aided or abetted in the making of a false statement in any document executed in connection with the practice of acupuncture; </section><section prefix="8">Aided, assisted, or abetted the unlawful practice of medicine or acupuncture; </section><section prefix="9">Willfully violated a confidential communication; </section><section prefix="10">Performed the services of an acupuncturist in an unprofessional, incompetent, or grossly or chronically negligent manner; </section><section prefix="11">Been removed, suspended, expelled, or placed on probation by any health-care facility or professional society for unprofessional conduct, incompetence, negligence, or violation of any provision of this section; </section><section prefix="12">Violated any applicable provision of a statute or administrative regulation relating to acupuncture practice; </section><section prefix="13">Violated any term of a final order or agreed order issued by the board; or </section><section prefix="14">Failed to complete the required number of hours of approved continuing education. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">All disciplinary proceedings against an acupuncturist shall be conducted in accordance with KRS 311.591, 311.592, 311.593, 311.599, and KRS Chapter 13B and related administrative regulations promulgated under KRS Chapter 311. </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">The board may issue a written admonishment to the licensed acupuncturist when, in the judgment of the board: <section prefix="1">An alleged violation is not of a serious nature; and </section><section prefix="2">The evidence presented to the board after the investigation, including an appropriate opportunity for the licensed acupuncturist to respond, provides a clear indication that the alleged violation did in fact occur. </section></section><section prefix="b">A copy of the admonishment shall be placed in the permanent file of the licensed acupuncturist. </section><section prefix="c">The licensed acupuncturist shall have the right to file a response to the admonishment within thirty (30) days of its receipt and to have the response placed in the permanent licensure file. </section><section prefix="d">The licensed acupuncturist may alternatively, within thirty (30) days of the admonishment's receipt, file a request for a hearing with the board. </section><section prefix="e">Upon receipt of a request for a hearing, the board shall set aside the written admonishment and set the matter for a hearing under the provisions of KRS Chapter 13B. </section></section><section prefix="4">At any time during the investigative or hearing processes, the board may enter into an agreed order or accept an assurance of voluntary compliance with the licensed acupuncturist which effectively deals with the complaint. </section><section prefix="5">The board may, upon the agreement of the aggrieved party, use mediation to handle disciplinary matters. The board may appoint any member or members of the board, any staff member, or any other person or combination thereof to serve in the mediation process. </section><section prefix="6">The board may reconsider, modify, or reverse its disciplinary actions. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 12, effective July 15, 2014. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 249, sec. 14, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2006).  For the sake of clarity and under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(c), the Reviser of Statutes has divided 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 249, sec. 14(1) into paragraphs and subparagraphs. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43061</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>