<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="117" order_by="117">REGULATION OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>117.165</section_number><catch_line>Examination of machines by county board -- Approval -- Delivery of election supplies to precinct. </catch_line><order_by>165</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon completing the preparation of the machines in accordance with the provisions of KRS 117.155, and not later than the Thursday preceding the day of the election, the county clerk shall notify the members of the county board of elections that the machines are ready for use. The board shall thereupon convene at the office of the county clerk, not later than the Friday preceding the day of the election, and examine the machines to determine whether the requirements of KRS 117.155 have been met. The county board of elections shall publish notice, in accordance with KRS 424.130(1)(d), at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance of the time when the machines are to be examined by the board. If found in proper order, the members of the county board of elections shall endorse their approval in the book in which the county clerk has entered the numbers of the machines opposite the numbers of the precincts. The clerk shall then deliver all of the keys to the machines to the county board of elections who shall give a receipt for the keys which shall contain identification of the keys. Not later than one (1) hour before the time set for the opening of the polls, the board shall deliver all election supplies including the precinct list, tabulation sheets, and the key to the device covering the registering counters and other keys necessary for the operation of the machine in registering votes, to the election officers of the precinct in which the machine is being used, who shall give the board a receipt containing identification of the keys. The master key and all other keys shall remain in the possession of the county board of elections. </section><section prefix="2">Not later then four (4) business days preceding the date set by the county board of elections to conduct absentee voting in accordance with KRS 117.085(1)(c), the county clerk shall notify the members of the county board of elections that the voting machines designated for use during absentee voting are ready for use. The board shall thereupon convene at the office of the county clerk, not later than three </section><section prefix="3">business days preceding the date set by the county board of elections to conduct </section>absentee voting, and examine the machines to determine whether the requirements of KRS 117.155 have been met. The county board of elections shall publish notice, in accordance with KRS 424.130(1)(d), at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance of the time when the absentee voting machines are to be examined by the board. If found in proper order, the members of the county board of elections shall endorse their approval in the book in which the county clerk has entered the identification number of the machines designated for use during absentee voting. (3) Any candidate, one (1) representative of each political party having candidates to be voted for at the election, and representatives of the news media may be present when the examination of the machines is made by the county board of elections. </text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 296, sec. 4, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 394, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 30, effective June 21, 1974. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27392</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>