<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">A AUTOMATED MOTOR VEHICLE REGISTRATION SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>186A.990</section_number><catch_line>Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>990</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person who knowingly gives false, fraudulent, or erroneous information in connection with an application for the registration, and when required, titling of a vehicle, or any application for assignment of a vehicle identification number, or replacement documents, or gives information in connection with his review of applications, or falsely certifies the truthfulness and accuracy of information supplied in connection with the registration and when required, titling of a vehicle, shall be guilty of forgery in the second degree. </section><section prefix="2">Any person who violates KRS 186A.260 or KRS 186A.275 to 186A.285 shall be guilty of a Class D felony. </section><section prefix="3">Any person who violates KRS 186A.300 to 186A.315 shall be guilty of a Class D felony. </section><section prefix="4">Any person who operates a motor vehicle or trailer upon the highways of this state without a temporary tag when one is required, or with one that is expired, improperly executed, or displayed on a vehicle other than the one (1) to which it was legitimately and lawfully issued, shall be guilty of a Class B misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="5">Any person who violates the disclosure provisions of KRS 186A.530(8) shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="6">Any person who violates any provisions of this chapter, or regulations promulgated pursuant thereto, and for which a specific penalty is not prescribed by statute, shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="7">Criminal remedies or sanctions provided in this chapter are in addition to, and not exclusive of, any other criminal remedies or sanctions provided elsewhere in the statutes. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 2, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 243, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 66, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6217</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>