<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="407" order_by="407">INTERSTATE SUPPORT ENFORCEMENT </unit></structure><section_number>407.5604Choice</section_number><catch_line>of law.   </catch_line><order_by>5604Choice</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (4) of this section, the law of the issuing state or foreign country governs: <section prefix="a">The nature, extent, amount, and duration of current payments under a registered support order; </section><section prefix="b">The computation and payment of arrearages and accrual of interest on the arrearages under the support order; and </section><section prefix="c">The existence and satisfaction of other obligations under the support order. </section></section><section prefix="2">In a proceeding for arrears under a registered support order, the statute of limitation of this state, or of the issuing state or foreign country, whichever is longer, applies. </section><section prefix="3">A responding tribunal of this state shall apply the procedures and remedies of this state to enforce current support and collect arrears and interest due on a support order of another state or a foreign country registered in this state. </section><section prefix="4">After a tribunal of this state or another state determines which is the controlling order and issues an order consolidating arrears, if any, a tribunal of this state shall prospectively apply the law of the state or foreign country issuing the controlling order, including its law on interest on arrears, on current and future support, and on consolidated arrears. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 43, effective June 24, 2015. -- Contingent effective date repealed 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 20, effective March 23, 1998. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 365, sec. 49, effective upon contingency. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44119</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>