<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="161" order_by="161">SCHOOL EMPLOYEES -- TEACHERS' RETIREMENT AND TENURE </unit></structure><section_number>161.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 161.020 to 161.120. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in KRS 161.020 to 161.120: <section prefix="1">"Continuing education" means study or other activities to provide professional improvement and personal growth for certified teachers throughout their career. It may include, but shall not be limited to, university courses, an advanced degree, or a combination of university courses, field-based experience, individual research, and approved professional development activities, pursuant to KRS 156.095. </section><section prefix="2">"Standard college or university" means an institution accredited by the Southern Association of Colleges and Schools or by one of the other recognized regional accrediting agencies or by the Education Professional Standards Board. </section><section prefix="3">"College or university work of graduate grade" means academic preparation which extends beyond the usual four (4) year program of undergraduate studies leading to a bachelor's degree and which is completed at a college or university accredited for the graduate level. </section><section prefix="4">"Student teacher" means an adult who has completed the prerequisite teacher preparation as prescribed by the accredited teacher education institution in which he or she is enrolled, and who is jointly assigned by the institution and a local school district to engage in a period of practice teaching under the direction and supervision of the administrative and teaching staff of the school district and the institution. </section><section prefix="5">"Teacher's aide" means an adult school employee who works under the direction of the professional administrative and teaching staff in performing, within the limitations of his or her training and competency, certain instructional and noninstructional functions in the school program including, but not limited to, clerical duties, tutoring individual pupils, leading pupils in recreational activities, conducting pupils from place to place, assisting with classroom instruction as directed by the teacher, aiding the school librarian, and preparing and organizing instructional materials and equipment. </section></text><history> Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 5, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 298, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. II, sec. 53, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 38, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1985 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 38, effective October 18, 1985. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 55, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 178, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4502-2. </history><metadata><effective> June 21, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3823</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>