<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="134" order_by="134">PAYMENT, COLLECTION, AND REFUND OF TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>134.191</section_number><catch_line>Monthly reporting and payment of taxes collected by sheriff. </catch_line><order_by>191</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The sheriff shall provide monthly reports by the tenth day of each month to the chief executive of the county, the department, and any other district for which the sheriff collects taxes. The governing body of the county may require the sheriff to report and pay on a more frequent basis if necessary for bonding requirements; however, the sheriff shall not be required to report and pay more frequently than weekly. </section><section prefix="2">The report shall be broken down by governmental entity and shall include the following information for the preceding month or reporting period, if the reporting period is other than monthly: <section prefix="a">The total amount of taxes collected; </section><section prefix="b">The total amount of any fines, forfeitures, or other moneys collected; and </section><section prefix="c">The disposition of such revenue or money collected. </section></section><section prefix="3">At the time of making the report, the sheriff shall pay to the county treasurer or other officer designated by the governing body of a county, to the department, and to any other district for which the sheriff collects taxes, all funds belonging to the county, the state, or the district that were collected during the period covered by the report. </section><section prefix="4">Any sheriff failing to pay over taxes collected as required by law shall be subject to a penalty of one percent (1%) for each thirty (30) day period or fraction thereof that the payment is not made, plus interest at the tax interest rate provided in KRS 131.183 on such amounts. The governing body of a county, the department, or the other district for which the sheriff collects taxes, in its settlement with the sheriff, shall charge him or her with such penalties and interest. </section><section prefix="5">The chief executive of a county, or the commissioner of the department may grant an extension of time, not to exceed fifteen (15) days, for filing the report required by subsection (1) of this section with that entity when good cause exists. The extension shall be in writing and shall be recorded in the office of the county clerk. The extension when granted shall suspend the penalty and interest for the duration of the extension. The penalty and interest shall apply at the expiration of the extension. </section></text><history> Created 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 21, effective January 1, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:04</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28399</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>