<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.36-030</section_number><catch_line>Scope of subtitle. </catch_line><order_by>36-030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">This subtitle shall apply to all kinds of direct insurance, except: <section prefix="a">Life, annuity, health, or disability; </section><section prefix="b">Mortgage guaranty, financial guaranty, or other forms of insurance offering protection against investment risks; </section><section prefix="c">Credit insurance, vendors' single interest insurance, or collateral protection insurance or any similar insurance protecting the interests of a creditor arising out of a creditor-debtor transaction; </section><section prefix="d">Insurance of warranties or service contracts, including insurance that provides for the repair, replacement, or service of goods or property, indemnification for repair, replacement, or service for the operational or structural failure of the goods or property due to a defect in materials, workmanship, or normal wear and tear, or that provides reimbursement for the liability incurred by the issuer of agreements or service contracts that provide these benefits; </section><section prefix="e">Title insurance; </section><section prefix="f">Ocean marine insurance; </section><section prefix="g">Any transaction or combination of transactions between a person, including affiliates of the person, and an insurer, including affiliates of the insurer, that involves the transfer of investment or credit risk and that is unaccompanied by transfer of insurance risk; or </section><section prefix="h">Any insurance provided, written, reinsured, or guaranteed by any government or governmental agencies. </section></section><section prefix="2">Notwithstanding subsection (1) of this section, this subtitle shall apply to health insurance where such insurance is written by a member of the Kentucky Insurance Guaranty Association. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 16, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 3, effective June 16, 1972. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:04</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29914</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>