<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="322" order_by="322">A PROFESSIONAL GEOLOGISTS </unit></structure><section_number>322A.020</section_number><catch_line>Board of Registration for Professional Geologists -- Membership -- Removal and filling of vacancies -- Officers -- Compensation of members.   </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is created and established the Board of Registration for Professional Geologists, which shall administer the provisions of this chapter. All board members shall be residents of Kentucky and be appointed by the Governor. The board shall consist of five (5) members, including four (4) registered geologists, one (1) of whom shall be the state geologist or his or her designee, and one (1) member representing the public at large. Except for the state geologist or his or her designee, the term of the members of the board shall always be for four (4) years and until their successors are appointed and qualified. </section><section prefix="2">Board members may succeed themselves. The Governor may remove any member from the board for misconduct, incompetence, neglect of duty, or for any good and sufficient cause, in the manner prescribed by law. Vacancies in the membership of the board shall be filled for the unexpired term by appointment by the Governor. </section><section prefix="3">Three (3) members of the board shall constitute a quorum. </section><section prefix="4">There shall be no liability on the part of and no cause of action of any nature shall arise against the board, or its agents, for any action taken in the performance of the board's powers and duties under this chapter. </section><section prefix="5">The board shall elect from its members a chair and secretary each year. </section><section prefix="6">At least thirty (30) days prior to the appointment date each year, the Governor shall receive a list of not more than three (3) nominations for board members from a joint committee of the Geological Society of Kentucky and the Kentucky Section of the American Institute of Professional Geologists. The appointed members on the board shall be selected from the list submitted to the Governor by the joint committee. </section><section prefix="7">While discharging duties associated with the board, including meetings of the board and its committees and necessary travel, each member shall receive compensation as established by administrative regulation of the board promulgated in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A. Members of the board shall be reimbursed for costs for actual travel and for incidental, clerical, and all other actual and necessary expenses incurred in the discharge of official duties associated with the board. </section></text><history>Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 140, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 64, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40729</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>