<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="153" order_by="153">THE ARTS -- STATE ZOO </unit></structure><section_number>153.390</section_number><catch_line>Duties of the commission. </catch_line><order_by>390</order_by><text>The Kentucky Bicentennial Commission shall: <section prefix="1">Prepare an overall program to include specific plans for celebrating in 1992 the two hundredth anniversary of Kentucky's admission as the fifteenth state of the United States of America; </section><section prefix="2">Select persons and events to be commemorated.  In preparing its plans and programs, the commission shall give consideration to any plans advanced by civic, patriotic, historical, or educational groups, and cooperate with them in all possible ways. The commission may designate special committees with representation from such groups to plan and conduct specific programs; </section><section prefix="3">Encourage the location and presentation of books, documents, manuscripts, letters, relics, and other materials pertaining to the settlement of Kentucky and its attainment of statehood; </section><section prefix="4">Prepare on or before November 1, 1987, and each year thereafter, a complete report of the commission's activities and plans for the celebration in 1992; and </section><section prefix="5">Establish the "Kentucky Bicentennial Celebration Trust Fund" which shall be used by the commission for the bicentennial celebration to cover personnel costs and operating expenses incurred and to provide grants for bicentennial projects approved by the commission. The trust fund shall consist of all funds appropriated to it by the General Assembly of this Commonwealth and all funds received from the federal government, or any agency thereof, or from any other source, for the purpose of implementing the provisions of KRS 153.386 to 153.396. After July 15, 1990, the commission shall have the authority to borrow an amount of money equal to, but not exceeding, the amount of money appropriated to the trust fund for bicentennial projects. The commission may borrow money from the general fund or from a source approved by the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet. Any interest accrued by moneys placed in the trust fund shall remain in the fund for use by the commission. After July 15, 1993, any moneys remaining in the fund shall be transferred to a trust and agency fund, established by the Finance and Administration Cabinet and administered by the Kentucky Heritage Council for the purpose of matching Kentucky Humanities Council grants and other similar grants which promote or explore Kentucky's heritage. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 2, erfective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 498, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 45, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2475</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>