<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="222" order_by="222">KENTUCKY ALCOHOL AND OTHER DRUG ABUSE PREVENTION, INTERVENTION, AND TREATMENT LAW </unit></structure><section_number>222.211</section_number><catch_line>Cabinet's functions as to tobacco addiction and alcohol and other drug abuse -- Authority for administrative regulations -- Required services. </catch_line><order_by>211</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet shall, in conjunction with the Office of Drug Control Policy and KY-ASAP and in furtherance of the strategic plan developed in KRS 15A.342, coordinate matters affecting tobacco addiction and alcohol and other drug abuse in the Commonwealth and shall assure that there is the provision of prevention, intervention, and treatment services for both juveniles and adults to address the problems of tobacco addiction and alcohol and other drug abuse within individuals, families, and communities; that the coordination of these matters shall be done in cooperation with public and private agencies, business, and industry; and that technical assistance, training, and consultation services shall be provided within budgetary limitations when required. The cabinet may promulgate administrative regulations under KRS Chapter 13A to carry out its powers and duties under this chapter. The cabinet shall utilize community mental health centers and existing facilities and services within the private sector when possible. The cabinet shall be responsible for assuring that the following services are available: <section prefix="a">Primary prevention services directed to the general population and identified target groups for the purposes of avoiding the onset of tobacco addiction and alcohol and other drug abuse related problems and enhancing the general level of health of the target groups. The purpose of the services shall be to provide individuals with the information and skills necessary to make healthy decisions regarding the use or nonuse of tobacco, alcohol, and other drugs as well as to influence environmental factors, such as social policies and norms which will support healthy lifestyle; </section><section prefix="b">Intervention services for the purpose of identifying, motivating, and referring individuals in need of tobacco addiction and alcohol and other drug abuse education or treatment services. Services may be provided in settings such as industry and business, schools, health, and social service agencies; </section><section prefix="c">Detoxification services on a twenty-four (24) hour basis in or near population centers which meet the immediate medical and physical needs of persons intoxicated from the use of alcohol or drugs, or both, including necessary diagnostic and referral services. The services shall be provided in either a hospital or a licensed alcohol and other drug abuse program; </section><section prefix="d">Rehabilitation services offered on an inpatient or outpatient basis for the purposes of treating an individual's alcohol and other drug abuse problem. The services shall be provided in a licensed alcohol and other drug abuse program; </section><section prefix="e">Therapeutic services to family members of alcohol and other drug abusers for the purpose of reducing or eliminating dysfunctional behavior that may occur within individuals who are emotionally, socially, and sometimes physically dependent on an alcohol or other drug abuser. The services shall be offered primarily on a outpatient basis; </section><section prefix="f">Inpatient psychiatric services for those alcohol and other drug abusers whose diagnosis reflects both serious mental health disturbances as well as alcohol and other drug abuse disorders; </section><section prefix="g">Training programs for personnel working in the field of prevention, intervention, and treatment of tobacco addiction and alcohol and other drug abuse problems; and </section><section prefix="h">Driving under the influence services to include assessment, education, and treatment for persons convicted of operating a motor vehicle, while under the influence of alcohol or other substance which may impair driving ability, pursuant to KRS Chapter 189A. </section></section><section prefix="2">The cabinet shall comply with all policy recommendations of the Office of Drug Control Policy and KY-ASAP, and shall honor requests for information from the Office of Drug Control Policy created under KRS 15A.020. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 256, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 536, sec. 30, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 334, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9919</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>