<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="309" order_by="309">MISCELLANEOUS OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS </unit></structure><section_number>309.134</section_number><catch_line>Licensure of professional art therapy associate -- Education -- Supervision -- Terms of licensure -- Advancement.   </catch_line><order_by>134</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board may issue a license as a professional art therapist associate for a period of up to five (5) years to an applicant who has; <section prefix="a">Completed the educational requirements for registration with the Art Therapy Credentials Board, Inc.; </section><section prefix="b">Obtained a board-approved supervisor of record; and </section><section prefix="c">Paid the required fees. </section></section><section prefix="2">A licensed professional art therapist associate shall maintain on-going supervision as approved by the board until he or she: <section prefix="a">Is registered by the Art Therapy Credentials Board, Inc.; and </section><section prefix="b">Has passed an examination approved by the board. </section></section><section prefix="3">At the end of the five (5) year period approved under subsection (1) of this section, a licensed professional art therapist associate who has not completed the requirements for licensure as a professional art therapist shall submit to the board an application for an extension of licensure as a professional art therapy associate. The application shall include: <section prefix="a">A plan for completing the requirements to obtain licensure as a professional art therapist; </section><section prefix="b">Documentation of compliance with the continuing education requirements; </section><section prefix="c">Reports of compliance with supervisory requirements; </section><section prefix="d">Letters of recommendation from two (2) supervisors of record; and </section><section prefix="e">Payment of an extension fee not to exceed one hundred dollars ($100). </section></section><section prefix="4">Upon review of the application and accompanying documentation, the board may approve an extension of the license as a professional art therapist for a period of time not to exceed two (2) years. </section><section prefix="5">If, at the end of the period of extension referenced in subsection (4) of this section, the applicant has not completed all requirements for licensure as a professional art therapist, the board shall rescind the license as a professional art therapist associate and the individual may no longer practice art therapy, or refer to himself or herself by any title which would indicate that he or she is credentialed by the board. </section><section prefix="6">A licensed professional art therapist associate may apply for the credential of licensed professional art therapist upon: <section prefix="a">Registration with the Art Therapy Credentials Board, Inc.; and </section><section prefix="b">Passage of an examination approved by the board. </section></section><section prefix="7">An individual who is a registered art therapist as defined by the Art Therapy Credentials Board, Inc., but who has not passed the required examination, shall: <section prefix="a">Maintain the professional art therapist associate license in order to practice under board-approved supervision; and </section><section prefix="b">Be scheduled to take the next examination following the approval of the professional art therapist license application. </section></section><section prefix="8">A professional art therapist associate shall not supervise licensed professional art therapists, licensed professional art therapist associates, or applicants for these licenses. </section></text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 4, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42310</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>