<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.4009</section_number><catch_line>License required to work as elevator contractor or mechanic -- Exemption for helper or apprentice -- Applicability to public universities -- Administrative regulations.  </catch_line><order_by>4009</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person shall not work as an elevator contractor or elevator mechanic unless licensed by the department. A person may work as an elevator helper or apprentice without a license while under the general supervision of a licensed elevator mechanic. </section><section prefix="2">A person who is a regular and bona fide full-time employee of a public university and who performs only routine maintenance on elevators for the public university shall be licensed as an elevator mechanic. The public university shall not be required to become licensed as an elevator contractor to employ a licensed elevator mechanic performing elevator maintenance for the public university under this subsection. An elevator mechanic who qualifies under this subsection shall only be authorized to conduct routine maintenance on any elevators for the public university, and shall be prohibited from performing any of the other activities authorized by KRS 198B.4003(1). </section><section prefix="3">The department may promulgate administrative regulations necessary to implement KRS 198B.400 to 198B.540. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 4, effective July 1, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2011 </effective><lrc-note> (7/1/2011).  References to the "office" of housing, buildings and construction in this section, as created by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 4, have been changed in codification to the "department" of housing, buildings and construction to reflect the reorganization of certain parts of the Executive Branch, as set forth in Executive Order 2009-535 and confirmed by the General Assembly in 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24. These changes were made by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1938. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-16</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36589</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>