<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17B-019</section_number><catch_line>Types of health benefit plans to be issued under Kentucky Access. </catch_line><order_by>17B-019</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Kentucky Access shall offer at least three (3) health benefit plans to enrollees, which shall be similar to the health benefit plans currently being marketed to individuals in the individual market. </section><section prefix="2">At least one (1) plan shall be offered in a traditional fee-for-service form. At least one (1) plan may be offered in a managed-care form at such time as the department can establish an appropriate provider network in available service areas. </section><section prefix="3">The department shall provide for utilization review and case management for all health benefit plans issued under Kentucky Access. </section><section prefix="4">The department shall review and compare health benefit plans provided under Kentucky Access to health benefit plans provided in the individual market. Based on the review, the department may amend or replace the health benefit plans issued under Kentucky Access. </section><section prefix="5">Individuals who apply and are determined eligible for health benefit plans issued under Kentucky Access shall have coverage effective the first day of the month after the application month. </section><section prefix="6">For eligible individuals, health benefit plans issued under Kentucky Access shall not impose any pre-existing condition exclusions. In all other cases, a pre-existing condition exclusion may be imposed in accordance with KRS 304.17A-230. </section><section prefix="7">Health benefit plans issued under Kentucky Access shall be guaranteed renewable except as otherwise specified in KRS 304.17B-015 and KRS 304.17A-240. </section><section prefix="8">All health benefit plans issued under Kentucky Access shall provide that, upon the death or divorce of the individual in whose name the contract was issued, every other person covered in the contract may elect within sixty-three (63) days to continue under the same or a different contract. </section><section prefix="9">Health benefit plans issued under Kentucky Access shall coordinate benefits with other health benefit plans and be the payor of last resort. </section><section prefix="10">Health benefit plans issued under Kentucky Access shall pay covered benefits up to a lifetime limit of two million dollars ($2,000,000) per covered individual. The maximum limit under this subsection may be increased by the department. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1282, effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 126, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 476, sec. 10, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  This section was amended by 2010 Ky. Acts chs. 24 and 126, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29394</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>