<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXII" order_by="32">OWNERSHIP AND CONVEYANCE OF PROPERTY</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="385" order_by="385">UNIFORM TRANSFERS TO MINORS ACT </unit></structure><section_number>385.192</section_number><catch_line>Accounting by and determination of liability of custodian. </catch_line><order_by>192</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A minor who has attained the age of fourteen (14) years, the minor's guardian of the person or legal representative, an adult member of the minor's family, a transferor, or a transferor's legal representative may petition the court: <section prefix="a">For an accounting by the custodian or the custodian's legal representative; or </section><section prefix="b">For a determination of responsibility, as between the custodial property and the custodian personally, for claims against the custodial property unless the responsibility has been adjudicated in an action under KRS 385.172 to which the minor or the minor's legal representative was a party. </section></section><section prefix="2">A successor custodian may petition the court for an accounting by the predecessor custodian. </section><section prefix="3">The court, in a proceeding under KRS 385.032 to 385.222 or in any other proceeding, may require or permit the custodian or the custodian's legal representative to account. </section><section prefix="4">If a custodian is removed under KRS 385.182(6), the court shall require an accounting and order delivery of the custodial property and records to the successor custodian and the execution of all instruments required for transfer of the custodial property. </section></text><history>Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 19, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35817</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>