<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="407" order_by="407">INTERSTATE SUPPORT ENFORCEMENT </unit></structure><section_number>407.5606Procedure</section_number><catch_line>to contest validity or enforcement of registered order.   </catch_line><order_by>5606Procedure</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A nonregistering party seeking to contest the validity or enforcement of a registered support order in this state shall request a hearing within the time required by KRS 407.5605. The nonregistering party may seek to vacate the registration, to assert any defense to an allegation of noncompliance with the registered order, or to contest the remedies being sought or the amount of any alleged arrearages pursuant to KRS 407.5607. </section><section prefix="2">If the nonregistering party fails to contest the validity or enforcement of the registered order in a timely manner, the order is confirmed by operation of law. </section><section prefix="3">If a nonregistering party requests a hearing to contest the validity or enforcement of the registered support order, the registering tribunal shall schedule the matter for hearing and give notice to the parties of the date, time, and place of the hearing. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 45, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 16, effective March 23, 1998.-- Contingent effective date repealed 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 20, effective March 23, 1998. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 365, sec. 51, effective upon contingency. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44121</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>