<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="44" order_by="44">CLAIMS UPON THE TREASURY </unit></structure><section_number>44.071</section_number><catch_line>Jurisdiction of Board of Claims as to municipal maintenance of state-owned traffic control devices. </catch_line><order_by>071</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Board of Claims, created by KRS 44.070, is hereby vested with full power, authority, and jurisdiction to investigate, hear proof, and compensate persons for damages sustained to either person or property as approximate result of negligence on the part of any municipality, or any of its officers, agents, or employees while acting within the scope of their employment by the municipality, or any agency thereof, relating to the maintenance by the municipality of state-owned traffic control devices pursuant to a contract with the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="2">Claims for personal injury or property damage against any municipality, or any of its officers, agents, or employees while acting within the scope of their employment of the municipality, arising out of negligence in the maintenance of state-owned traffic control devices pursuant to a contract with the Commonwealth, shall be limited and reduced in the same manner as described in KRS 44.070 with respect to claims against the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="3">It is the intention of subsections (1) and (2) of this section to provide every municipality and agency thereof, and their respective officers, agents, or employees with the same liability protection, restrictions, and reductions when such municipalities and agencies are performing maintenance on state-owned traffic control devices pursuant to a contract with the Commonwealth as the Commonwealth and its agencies, officers, and employees would enjoy if performing the work itself. </section></text><history>Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 225, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22135</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>