<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.1755</section_number><catch_line>Merit system for local health department personnel. </catch_line><order_by>1755</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet shall administer a personnel program for local health departments based on the principles of merit governing the recruitment, examination, appointment, discipline, removal, and other incidents of employment for county, city-county, and district agencies. </section><section prefix="2">The cabinet shall establish policies and procedures for the personnel program through the promulgation of administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A. </section><section prefix="3">The administrative regulations promulgated by the cabinet governing the personnel program shall include the following: <section prefix="a">Personnel policies for the governance of all agency employees, which shall include, but not be limited to, the following areas of personnel administration: <section prefix="1">Leave policies; </section><section prefix="2">Salary, wage, and price policy and administration; </section><section prefix="3">Conditions of employment; </section><section prefix="4">Conditions of termination; </section><section prefix="5">Fringe benefits; </section><section prefix="6">Employee grievance procedure; </section><section prefix="7">Employee performance evaluations; </section><section prefix="8">Staff development, and continuing education requirements; and </section><section prefix="9">Method of salary increments. </section></section><section prefix="b">A classification plan based upon the duties and responsibilities assigned to each classification, which shall include for each classification an appropriate title, description of duties and responsibilities, required education and experience, and other qualifications at the discretion of the cabinet. </section><section prefix="c">A compensation plan which provides salary ranges for the various classifications of the classification plan commensurate with the duties and responsibilities of the classification within budgetary limitations. </section><section prefix="d">The recruitment of applicants, the determination of eligibility of applicants, the appropriate examination for applicants, and the provision of a list of qualified individuals for employment with an agency. </section></section></text><history> Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 336, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8358</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>