<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.450</section_number><catch_line>Stopping, standing, parking, or repairing vehicle on roadway or shoulders of highway. </catch_line><order_by>450</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall stop a vehicle, leave it standing, or cause it to stop or to be left standing upon any portion of the roadway; provided, however, that this section shall not be construed to prevent parking in front of a private residence off the roadway or street in a city or suburban area where such parking is otherwise permitted, as long as the vehicle so parked does not impede the flow of traffic. This subsection shall not apply to: <section prefix="a">A vehicle that has been disabled on the right-of-way of such a highway in such a manner and to such extent that it is impossible to avoid the occupation of the shoulder of a state-maintained highway or impracticable to remove it from the shoulder of the highway until repairs have been made or sufficient help obtained for its removal. In no event shall a disabled vehicle remain on the shoulder of a state-maintained highway for twenty-four (24) hours or more; </section><section prefix="b">Motor vehicles when required to stop in obedience to the provisions of any section of the Kentucky Revised Statutes or any traffic ordinance, regulation, or sign or the command of any peace officer; </section><section prefix="c">Vehicles operating as common carriers of passengers for hire and school buses taking passengers on such vehicle or discharging passengers therefrom; provided, that no such vehicle shall stop for such purposes at a place on the highway which does not afford reasonable visibility to approaching motor vehicles from both directions; or </section><section prefix="d">Any vehicle required to stop by reason of an obstruction to its progress. </section></section><section prefix="2">When any police officer finds a vehicle standing upon such a highway in violation of this section, he may move or cause to be moved the vehicle or require the operator or other person in charge of the vehicle to move it. The police officer may cause the vehicle to be removed by ordering any person engaged in the business of storing or towing motor vehicles to remove the vehicle to a site chosen by such person. Ownership of the vehicle shall be determined by the police officer's enforcement agency through the vehicle's license plates, serial number, or other means of determining ownership. As soon as practicable, the police officer's enforcement agency shall notify the owner by mail that the vehicle was illegally upon public property; the name and address of the storage facility where the vehicle is located; that removal of the vehicle from the storage facility will involve payment of towing and storage charges; and that the vehicle may be sold pursuant to the provisions of KRS 376.275 if not claimed within sixty (60) days. No notification shall be required if ownership cannot be determined. In the event of a sale pursuant to KRS 376.275, the state shall receive any proceeds after the satisfaction of all liens placed on the vehicle. </section><section prefix="3">No vehicle shall be parked, stopped, or allowed to stand on the shoulders of any toll road, interstate highway, or other fully controlled access highway, including ramps thereto, nor shall any vehicle registered at a gross weight of over forty-four thousand (44,000) pounds be parked, stopped, or allowed to stand on the shoulders of any state-maintained highway, except that, in the case of emergency or in response to a peace officer's signal, vehicles shall be permitted to stop on the shoulders to the right of the traveled way with all wheels and projecting parts of the vehicles, including the load, completely clear of the traveled way. Parking of any vehicle which is disabled on the shoulders of a toll road, interstate highway, other fully controlled access highway, including ramps thereto, or any state-maintained highway not mentioned in this section for twenty-four (24) hours continuously is prohibited and vehicles violating this provision may be towed away at the cost of the owner. </section><section prefix="4">When any police officer finds a vehicle unattended upon any bridge or causeway or in a tunnel where the vehicle constitutes an obstruction to traffic, the officer may provide for the removal of the vehicle to the nearest garage or other place of safety as provided in subsection (2) of this section. </section><section prefix="5">No person shall stop or park a vehicle except when necessary to avoid conflict with other traffic or in compliance with the directions of a police officer or traffic control device, in the following places: <section prefix="a">On a sidewalk; </section><section prefix="b">In front of sidewalk ramps provided for persons with disabilities; </section><section prefix="c">In front of a public or private driveway; </section><section prefix="d">Within an intersection or on a crosswalk; </section><section prefix="e">At any place where official signs prohibit stopping or parking; </section><section prefix="f">Within thirty (30) feet upon the approach to any flashing beacon, stop sign, or traffic control signal located at the side of a roadway; </section><section prefix="g">On any controlled access highway; </section><section prefix="h">Within a highway tunnel; </section><section prefix="i">Within fifteen (15) feet of a fire hydrant; or </section><section prefix="j">In an area between the roadways of a divided highway. </section></section><section prefix="6">No person shall move a vehicle not lawfully under his control into any such prohibited area. </section><section prefix="7">The restrictions in subsection (5)(e) of this section shall not apply to sheriffs and their deputies or police officers when operating properly identified vehicles during performance of their official duties. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 173, sec. 19, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 405, sec. 39, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 322, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 163, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 405, sec. 1. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 93, sec. 11. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 25, sec. 1. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 288, sec. 2. -- Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 235, sec. 1. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 3. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739g-48. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6395</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>