<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.095</section_number><catch_line>Postsecondary education accountability process -- Annual accountability report. </catch_line><order_by>095</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="a">"Disability" means hard of hearing, including deafness; speech or language impairment; visual impairment, including blindness; orthopedic impairment; other health impairment that substantially limits a major life activity; or specific learning problem. </section><section prefix="b">"Institution" means public universities, their subdivisions, and the Kentucky Community and Technical College System. </section></section><section prefix="2">It is the intent of the General Assembly that an accountability process be implemented which provides for a systematic ongoing evaluation of quality and effectiveness in Kentucky postsecondary educational institutions and to provide a method for evaluating each institution's progress toward meeting specific goals, principles, strategies, objectives, and benchmarks as set forth in the strategic agenda established in KRS 164.0203. It is further the intent of the General Assembly that the accountability process monitor performance at the institutions in each of the major areas of instruction, research, and public service, while recognizing the individual missions of each of the institutions. The accountability process shall provide for the adoption of systemwide and individual performance goals with standards identified with the advice of the postsecondary educational institutions and the Council on Postsecondary Education. </section><section prefix="3">The Council on Postsecondary Education shall develop and implement a system of accountability for the postsecondary education institutions that measures: <section prefix="a">Educational quality and educational outcomes; </section><section prefix="b">Student progress in the postsecondary system; </section><section prefix="c">Research and service activities; </section><section prefix="d">Use of resources; </section><section prefix="e">Other performance or outcomes that support the achievement of the strategic agenda, including involvement in quality enhancement of elementary and secondary education; and </section><section prefix="f">Other indicators as deemed appropriate by the Council on Postsecondary Education. </section></section><section prefix="4">The Council on Postsecondary Education shall collect information, maintain a comprehensive database, and publish reports on the condition of the postsecondary education system that include but are not limited to student enrollments, utilization of facilities, and the finances of the institutions. </section><section prefix="5">The Council on Postsecondary Education shall submit to the Governor and the Legislative Research Commission an annual accountability report providing information on the implementation of performance standards and the achievement of the performance goals during the prior year and initiatives to be undertaken during the next year. </section></text><history> Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 84, effective May 30, 1997. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 236, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> May 30, 1997 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4201</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>