<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6">THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY </unit></structure><section_number>6.797</section_number><catch_line>Notice of filing deficiency -- Penalties for deficient or false filing. </catch_line><order_by>797</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commission shall notify by certified mail each person required to file a statement of financial interests who fails to file the statement in a timely manner, completely, or in the form required by the commission. The notice shall specify the type of failure or delinquency and shall advise the person of the penalties for violation of this section. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Any person who fails to file the statement or who fails to remedy a deficiency in his filing identified by the commission in the notice under subsection (1) of this section in a timely manner may be fined by the commission an amount not to exceed one hundred dollars ($100) per day, up to a maximum total fine of one thousand dollars ($1,000) without the necessity of a complaint being filed, notwithstanding KRS 6.686(1)(a), but only after notice has been given to the alleged violator of the intent of the commission to impose a fine, including the amount of the fine, and an opportunity has been afforded the alleged violator to appear before the commission or otherwise offer evidence as he may choose in mitigation of the imposition of the fine. </section><section prefix="b">Any person who intentionally files a statement of financial interests which he knows to contain false information or to omit required information shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 493, sec. 6, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1993 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 21, effective September 16, 1993. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=394</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>