<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.623</section_number><catch_line>Living will directive or medical order for scope of treatment -- Eligible persons -- Scope -- Effect -- Recognition of person's desire not to be resuscitated.   </catch_line><order_by>623</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An adult with decisional capacity may make a written living will directive that does any or all of the following: <section prefix="a">Directs the withholding or withdrawal of life-prolonging treatment; or </section><section prefix="b">Directs the withholding or withdrawal of artificially provided nutrition or hydration; or </section><section prefix="c">Designates one (1) or more adults as a surrogate or successor surrogate to make health care decisions on behalf of the grantor. During any period in which two (2) or more surrogates are serving, all decisions shall be by unanimous consent of all the acting surrogates unless the advance directive provides otherwise; or </section><section prefix="d">Directs the giving of all or any part of the adult's body upon death for any purpose specified in KRS 311.1929. </section></section><section prefix="2">Except as provided in KRS 311.633, a living will directive made pursuant to this section or a medical order for scope of treatment made pursuant to KRS 311.6225 shall be honored by a grantor's family, regular family physician or attending physician, and any health care facility of or in which the grantor is a patient. </section><section prefix="3">For purposes of KRS 311.621 to 311.643, notification to any emergency medical responder as defined by KRS Chapter 211 or any paramedic as defined by KRS Chapter 311, of a person's authentic wish not to be resuscitated shall be recognized only if on a standard form or identification approved by the Kentucky Board of Medical Licensure, in consultation with the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, or a standard medical order for scope of treatment form approved by the Kentucky Board of Medical Licensure pursuant to KRS 311.6225. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 3, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 161, sec. 30, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 586, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 392, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998; and. ch. 426, sec. 538, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 235, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44036</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>