<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="273" order_by="273">RELIGIOUS, CHARITABLE, AND EDUCATIONAL SOCIETIES -- NONSTOCK, NONPROFIT CORPORATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>273.287</section_number><catch_line>Articles of merger or consolidation. </catch_line><order_by>287</order_by><text>Upon such approval, articles of merger or articles of consolidation shall be delivered to the Secretary of State for filing and shall set forth: <section prefix="1">The plan of merger or the plan of consolidation; </section><section prefix="2">If the members of any merging or consolidating corporation are entitled to vote thereon, then as to each such corporation: <section prefix="a">A statement setting forth the date of the meeting of members at which the plan was adopted, that a quorum was present at such meeting, and that such plan received at least two-thirds (2/3) of the votes which members present at such meeting or represented by proxy were entitled to cast; or </section><section prefix="b">A statement that such amendment was adopted by a consent in writing signed by all members entitled to vote with respect thereto; and </section><section prefix="c">If any merging or consolidating corporation has no members, or no members entitled to vote thereon, then as to each such corporation a statement of such fact, the date of the meeting of the board of directors at which the plan was adopted and a statement of the fact that such plan received the vote of a majority of the directors in office. </section></section></text><history>Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 204, effective January 1, 1989. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 452, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 27, sec. 11. -- Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 40. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 1989 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13676</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>