<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">A URBAN-COUNTY GOVERNMENT </unit></structure><section_number>67A.400</section_number><catch_line>Service credit -- Computation. </catch_line><order_by>400</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each person becoming a member on the date of establishment shall be entitled to full credit for all service rendered prior to such date. Each person becoming a member after the date of establishment shall be entitled to credit after such date, provided contributions are made or, after August 1, 1982, picked up pursuant to KRS 67A.510(2) for all such subsequent service. Total service shall include prior service and membership service.  </section><section prefix="2">The following types of service shall be eligible for service credit:  <section prefix="a">Service as a full-time member of a department of the government;  </section><section prefix="b">Service in a civilian or other capacity in the service of the government, Commonwealth of Kentucky, or the federal government, while on approved leave of absence from a department, subject to maximum credit for such service of one (1) year;  </section><section prefix="c">Service in any branch of the armed forces of the United States during a period of national emergency while on leave of absence from a department, provided that such leave-of-absence-service shall not exceed five (5) years, and that such member shall reenter the service of a department of the government within a period of six (6) months following the date of separation other than by dishonorable discharge from such service; and  </section><section prefix="d">All service rendered in a civilian capacity as provided in subsection (3) of KRS 67A.390.  </section></section><section prefix="3">In the computation of service credit, nine (9) months or more of service during a year shall entitle a member for one (1) year of service; six (6) to nine (9) months of service shall constitute three-quarters (3/4) of a year; three (3) to six (6) months, one-half (1/2) year; less than three (3) months, one-quarter (1/4) of a year. </section></text><history>Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 166, sec. 39, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 5, effective July 1, 1974. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1982 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23875</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>