<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">A EMERGENCY MEDICAL SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>311A.180</section_number><catch_line>Medical control documents -- Review -- Approval -- Appeal -- Schedule for submission and review.   </catch_line><order_by>180</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each emergency medical services medical director for an ambulance service, or other emergency medical services provider, shall submit: <section prefix="a">His or her protocols, including the pre-hospital care protocols related to the assessment, treatment, and transport of stroke patients; </section><section prefix="b">His or her standing orders; and </section><section prefix="c">Similar medical control documents to the board for approval prior to placing the document in use. </section></section><section prefix="2">The medical advisor for the board shall review each document submitted to ascertain if it is in accordance with accepted standards of medical care and in accordance with the provisions of this chapter and administrative regulations promulgated thereunder. If the protocol, standing order, or other medical control document clearly violates the accepted standards of medical care, this chapter, or an administrative regulation, the medical advisor shall notify the emergency medical services medical director of the exact violation and recommend a correction thereof. </section><section prefix="3">Following review of protocol, standing order, and medical control documents and giving the emergency medical services medical director who submitted the documents an opportunity to review the medical advisor's comments, the medical advisor shall submit the documents together with his or her comments to the board for approval or disapproval. </section><section prefix="4">The board shall approve, disapprove, or approve with modifications protocol, standing order, and medical control documents submitted by the emergency medical services medical director at its next regular or special meeting following the submission of the documents. </section><section prefix="5">If a protocol, standing order, or other medical control document is disapproved by the board, the emergency medical services medical director who submitted it may appeal the decision to the Franklin Circuit Court. If the decision of the board is appealed to the Franklin Circuit Court, the board shall bear the burden of proving that the protocol, standing order, or other medical control document violates the accepted standards of medical care, or an administrative regulation. </section><section prefix="6">The board shall, by administrative regulation, specify a schedule for submission and prompt review and decision making with regard to protocols, standing orders, and medical control documents submitted to the board. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 9, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2015. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 33, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44044</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>