<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="117" order_by="117">REGULATION OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>117.995</section_number><catch_line>Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>995</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person appointed to serve as an election officer but who shall knowingly and willfully fail to serve and who is not excused by the county board of elections for the reasons specified in this chapter shall be guilty of a violation and shall be ineligible to serve as an election officer for a period of five (5) years. </section><section prefix="2">Any county clerk or member of the county board of elections who knowingly and willfully violates any of the provisions of this chapter, including furnishing applications for absentee ballots to persons other than those specified by the provisions of this chapter and failure to type the name of the voter on the application form as required by the provisions of this chapter, shall be guilty of a Class D felony. </section><section prefix="3">Any officer who willfully fails to prepare or furnish ballot labels or absentee ballots or fails to allow a qualified voter to cast his or her vote on the machine as required of the voter by this chapter shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="4">Any election officer who knowingly and willfully violates any of the provisions of this chapter, including failure to enforce the prohibition against electioneering established by KRS 117.235, shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor for the first offense and a Class D felony for each subsequent offense. </section><section prefix="5">Any person who signs a name other than his or her own on an application for an absentee ballot or on the verification form for the ballot or on an emergency absentee ballot affidavit, or any person who votes an absentee ballot other than the one issued in his or her name, or any person who applies for the ballot for the use of anyone other than himself or herself or the person designated by the provisions of this chapter, or any person who makes a false statement on an application for an absentee ballot or on an emergency absentee ballot affidavit shall be guilty of a Class D felony. </section><section prefix="6">Any person who violates any provision of KRS 117.235 or 117.236 related to prohibited activities during absentee voting or on election day, after he or she has been duly notified of the provisions by any precinct election officer, county clerk, deputy county clerk, or other law enforcement official, shall, for each offense, be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="7">Any person who knowingly and willfully prepares or assists in the preparation of an inaccurate or incomplete voter assistance form or fails to complete a voter assistance form when required shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor for the first offense and a Class D felony for each subsequent offense; however, if a voter has been permanently certified as requiring voting assistance, there shall be no offense for the failure of the voter to complete the form. </section><section prefix="8">The members of a county board of elections that fails to provide the training to precinct election officers required by KRS 117.187(2) shall be subject to removal by the State Board of Elections. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 394, sec. 19, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 4, effective March 19, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 34, effective July 13, 1990; and ch. 476, Part V, sec. 303, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 341, sec. 34, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 287, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 4, effective July 17, 1978; and ch. 224, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 62, effective June 21, 1974. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><lrc-note> (7/13/90).  The Act amending this section prevails over the repeal and reenactment in House Bill 940, Acts ch. 476, pursuant to Section 653(1) of Acts ch. 476. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:10</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27557</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>