<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="136" order_by="136">CORPORATION AND UTILITY TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>136.616</section_number><catch_line>Imposition of tax on gross revenues -- Multichannel video programming services and communications services -- Rates -- Collection of tax from purchaser prohibited -- Exclusion for municipal utility.   </catch_line><order_by>616</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A tax is hereby imposed on the gross revenues received by all providers. </section><section prefix="2">The tax rate shall be: <section prefix="a">Two and four-tenths percent (2.4%) of the gross revenues received for the provision of multichannel video programming service provided to a person whose place of primary use is in this state, billed on or after January 1, 2006; and </section><section prefix="b">One and three-tenths percent (1.3%) of the gross revenues received for the provision of communications services, as sourced under the provisions of KRS 136.605, billed on or after January 1, 2006. </section></section><section prefix="3">The provider shall not collect the tax directly from the purchaser or separately state the tax on the bill to the purchaser. </section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">The tax imposed by this section shall apply to all providers except a municipal utility. "Municipal utility" as used in this section means a utility owned, operated, and controlled directly or indirectly by a city. </section><section prefix="b">To the extent that the provisions of KRS Chapter 279 are inconsistent with KRS 136.600 to 136.660, KRS 136.600 to 136.660 shall control. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 219, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 14, effective July 1, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 4, effective March 6, 2006. -- Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 96, effective January 1, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (3/6/2006).  2006 Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 26, provides that this section applies retroactively to January 1, 2006. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:01</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43804</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>