<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="117" order_by="117">REGULATION OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>117.030</section_number><catch_line>Announcements and signs regarding importance of voting -- Notice of illegal acts, penalties, and right to report administrative errors at polling places. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The State Board of Elections shall publish and broadcast announcements throughout the state regarding the importance of voting in a free and conscientious manner, procedures for registering to vote and voting, general election laws, and penalties for vote buying and selling. </section><section prefix="2">The State Board of Elections shall provide for the conspicuous placement of signs at all precinct polling places, which shall state that vote buying and selling are illegal and shall state the penalties for such acts. </section><section prefix="3">The State Board of Elections shall provide for the conspicuous placement of signs at all precinct polling places, which display the telephone number and mailing address of the county board of elections, and which inform the voters of their right to report any administrative or clerical errors they witness to the county board of elections, either by phone or in writing within ten (10) days after the election. </section></text><history> Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 341, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> June 21, 2001 </effective><former-history>  Repealed 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 63, effective June 19,1952. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 1441. </former-history><former-history-former-name>KRS 117.030:</former-history-former-name><catchline-at-repeal>  Poll tax; when payment condition precedent to voting in city election. </catchline-at-repeal><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27347</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>