<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="275" order_by="275">LIMITED LIABILITY COMPANIES </unit></structure><section_number>275.500</section_number><catch_line>Share exchange between corporation and limited liability company. </catch_line><order_by>500</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A limited liability company may acquire all or part of the outstanding shares of one (1) or more classes or series of a domestic or foreign corporation if the corporation, limited liability company, and a majority of their owners approve the exchange and, if the corporation is a foreign corporation, the share exchange is permitted under the laws of the state or country under which the foreign corporation is incorporated. </section><section prefix="2">The plan of share exchange shall set forth: <section prefix="a">The name of the corporation whose shares will be acquired and the name of the acquiring limited liability company; </section><section prefix="b">The terms and conditions of the exchange; and </section><section prefix="c">The manner and basis of exchanging the shares to be acquired for limited liability company interests, obligations, or other securities of the acquiring limited liability company or for cash or other property, in whole or part. </section></section><section prefix="3">The plan of share exchange may set forth other provisions relating to the exchange. </section><section prefix="4">This section shall not limit the power of a limited liability company to acquire all or part of the shares of one (1) or more classes or series of a corporation through a voluntary exchange or otherwise. </section><section prefix="5">Unless otherwise provided in the articles of organization, a written operating agreement, or a written plan of share exchange, no member of a limited liability company shall have the right to dissent from a share exchange. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 5, effective June 26, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 183, provides, "The specific textual provisions of Sections 1 to 178 of this Act which reflect amendments made to those sections by 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137 shall be deemed effective as of June 26, 2007, and those provisions are hereby made expressly retroactive to that date, with the remainder of the text of those sections being unaffected by the provisions of this section." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13926</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>