<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="319" order_by="319">PSYCHOLOGISTS </unit></structure><section_number>319.015</section_number><catch_line>Activities not included in practice of psychology. </catch_line><order_by>015</order_by><text>Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to limit: <section prefix="1">The activities, services, and use of title on the part of a person in the employ of the federal government; </section><section prefix="2">Persons from engaging in the teaching of psychology, the conduct of psychological research, the provision of consultation services to organizations or institutions, or the provision of expert testimony, provided that such activities do not involve the delivery or supervision of direct psychological services to individuals or groups; </section><section prefix="3">Persons licensed, certified, or registered under any other provision of the Kentucky Revised Statutes from rendering services consistent with the laws regulating their professional practice and the ethics of their profession. The use of written or computerized interpretations of any psychological testing or the administration and use of symptomatic and behavioral assessments by a practitioner of the healing arts as defined in KRS 311.271(2), clinical social worker, marriage and family therapist, professional art therapist, advanced practice registered nurse, physician, physical therapist, or occupational therapist who uses these interpretations or administers and uses these assessments shall not be limited. They shall not represent themselves to be psychologists or use the term "psychological" in describing their services; </section><section prefix="4">The activities of a student, intern, or resident in psychology, pursuing a course of study approved by the department of psychology of an educational institution rated acceptable by the board for qualifying training and experience, provided such activities are recognized by transcript as a part of his or her supervised course of study; </section><section prefix="5">The recognized educational activities of teachers in accredited public and private schools, the authorized duties of guidance counselors who are certified by the Education Professional Standards Board, or the activities of persons using psychological techniques in business and industrial organizations for employment placement, promotion, or job adjustment of their own officers and employees; </section><section prefix="6">Persons who are credentialed as school psychologists by the Education Professional Standards Board from using the title "school psychologist" and practicing psychology as defined in KRS 319.010, if their practice is restricted to regular employment within a setting under the purview of the Education Professional Standards Board. These individuals shall be employees of the educational institution and not independent contractors providing psychological services to educational institutions; </section><section prefix="7">A duly ordained minister, priest, rabbi, Christian Science practitioner, or other clergyman from carrying out his or her responsibilities while functioning in a ministerial capacity within a recognized religious organization serving the spiritual needs of its constituency, if he or she does not hold himself or herself out as a psychologist; or </section><section prefix="8">Any nonresident temporarily employed in this state from rendering psychological services for not more than thirty (30) days every two (2) years, if he or she holds a valid current license or certificate as a psychologist in his or her home state or country and registers with the board prior to commencing practice in the Commonwealth or if he or she holds a valid current IPC. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 50, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 10, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 3, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 128, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 15. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 52, changed the designation of "advanced registered nurse practitioner" to "advanced practice registered nurse" in KRS 314A.011, the definitions section for KRS Chapter 314A relating to nursing. A change has been made in the text of this statute to conform. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:54</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31221</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>