<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6">THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY </unit></structure><section_number>6.940</section_number><catch_line>Medicaid Oversight and Advisory Committee -- Membership -- Meetings -- Vote required to act. </catch_line><order_by>940</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby established a Medicaid Oversight and Advisory Committee, consisting of ten (10) members appointed as follows: four (4) members of the Senate appointed by the President of the Senate; one (1) member of the minority party in the Senate appointed by the Minority Floor Leader in the Senate; four (4) members of the House of Representatives appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives; and one (1) member of the minority party in the House of Representatives appointed by the Minority Floor Leader in the House of Representatives. Members appointed from each chamber shall elect one (1) member from their chamber to serve as co-chair. The co-chairs shall have joint responsibilities for committee meeting agendas and presiding at committee meetings. The committee shall meet at least four (4) times annually and shall provide oversight on the implementation of Medicaid within the Commonwealth including access to services, utilization of services, quality of services, and cost containment. </section><section prefix="2">A majority of the entire membership of the Medicaid Oversight and Advisory Committee shall constitute a quorum, and all actions of the committee shall be by vote of a majority of its entire membership. </section></text><history> Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 4, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 185, sec. 2, effective March 31, 2003. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 545, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=420</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>