<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.672</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for 311.671 to 311.686. </catch_line><order_by>672</order_by><text>In KRS 311.671 to 311.686, the following words and phrases shall have the meanings given to them, unless the context clearly indicates otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Acupuncturist" means an individual licensed to practice acupuncture by the board; </section><section prefix="2">"Board" means the State Board of Medical Licensure; </section><section prefix="3">"Committee" means the Acupuncture Advisory Committee under the State Board of Medical Licensure; </section><section prefix="4">"Licensure" means licensure by the board to practice acupuncture; and </section><section prefix="5">"Practice of acupuncture" means the insertion of acupuncture needles, with or without accompanying electrical or thermal stimulation, at certain acupuncture points or meridians on the surface of the human body for purposes of changing the flow of energy in the body and may include acupressure, cupping, moxibustion, or dermal friction. The practice of acupuncture shall not include laser acupuncture, osteopathic manipulative treatment, chiropractic adjustments, physical therapy, or surgery. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2014. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 249, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2006).  2006 Ky. Acts ch. 249, sec. 2, subsec. (3), read: ""Council" means the Acupuncture Advisory Council under the State Board of Medical Licensure." However, 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 249, sec. 3, created the Acupuncture Advisory Committee, not the Acupuncture Advisory Council. The Reviser of Statutes has changed the references to "Council" to "Committee" in codifying this statute, under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(h). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43051</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>