<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="524" order_by="524">INTERFERENCE WITH JUDICIAL ADMINISTRATION </unit></structure><section_number>524.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>The following definitions apply in this chapter unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Judge" means, with reference to intimidating a participant in the legal process, any current justice or judge of the Court of Justice, a trial commissioner of the Court of Justice, and any person serving as a judge at a trial or judicial proceeding of or authorized by the Court of Justice. With reference to retaliating against a participant in the legal process, the term "judge" also includes a former justice or judge of the Court of Justice, a trial commissioner of the Court of Justice, and any person serving as a judge at a trial or judicial proceeding authorized by the Court of Justice. The term includes persons who have been elected or appointed, but have not yet taken office. </section><section prefix="2">"Juror" means a person who is or has been a member of any impaneled jury, including a grand jury, and includes any person who has been drawn or summoned to attend as a prospective juror. </section><section prefix="3">"Participant in the legal process" means any judge, prosecutor, attorney defending a criminal case, juror, or witness and includes members of the participant's immediate family. </section><section prefix="4">"Official proceeding" means a proceeding heard before any legislative, judicial, administrative or other governmental agency or official authorized to hear evidence under oath, including any referee, hearing examiner, commissioner, notary or other person taking testimony or depositions in any such proceedings. </section><section prefix="5">"Pecuniary benefit" means benefit in the form of money, property, commercial interests, or anything else the primary significance of which is economic gain. </section><section prefix="6">"Physical evidence" means any article, object, document, record, or other thing of physical substance. </section><section prefix="7">"Prosecutor" means, with reference to intimidating a participant in the legal process, a current Commonwealth's attorney, assistant Commonwealth's attorney, county attorney, assistant county attorney, Attorney General, deputy attorney general, assistant attorney general, or special prosecutor appointed pursuant to law. With reference to retaliating against a participant in the legal process, the term "prosecutor" also includes a former Commonwealth's attorney, assistant Commonwealth's attorney, county attorney, assistant county attorney, Attorney General, deputy attorney general, assistant attorney general, or special prosecutor appointed pursuant to law. </section><section prefix="8">"Threat" means any direct threat to kill or injure a person protected by this chapter or an immediate family member of such a person. Persons protected by this chapter include persons who have been elected or appointed but have not yet taken office. </section><section prefix="9">"Witness" means any person who may be called to testify in an official proceeding, has been called to testify in an official proceeding, is testifying in an official proceeding, or who has testified in an official proceeding. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 251, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 200, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19903</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>