<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="13" order_by="13">A ADMINISTRATIVE REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>13A.255</section_number><catch_line>Notice of ordinary administrative regulation proposing to establish or increase fees.   </catch_line><order_by>255</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Within five (5) working days of the filing of an ordinary administrative regulation that proposes to establish or increase fees, except those fees exempted by KRS 13A.100(3), an administrative body shall mail or e-mail a notice containing the information required by subsection (2) of this section, to each state association, organization, or other body representing a person or entity affected by the administrative regulation. </section><section prefix="2">The notice shall include the following information: <section prefix="a">The name of the administrative body that filed the proposed administrative regulation; </section><section prefix="b">A statement that the administrative body has promulgated an administrative regulation that establishes or increases fees; </section><section prefix="c">A summary of the administrative regulation that includes: <section prefix="1">The amount of each fee being established; </section><section prefix="2">The amount of any increases to any fees previously established; and </section><section prefix="3">The necessity for the establishment or increase in the fees; </section></section><section prefix="d">A statement that a person or entity may contact the administrative body for additional information; </section><section prefix="e">The time, date, and place of the scheduled public hearing; </section><section prefix="f">The deadline for submitting written comments as established in KRS 13A.270(1)(c); and </section><section prefix="g">The name, address, and telephone number of the contact person for the administrative body. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 138, sec. 10, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 14, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40716</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>