<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171">STATE LIBRARIES -- LIBRARIANS -- STATE ARCHIVES AND RECORDS </unit></structure><section_number>171.814Underground</section_number><catch_line>Railroad Advisory Council -- Members -- Duties -- Meetings.   </catch_line><order_by>814Underground</order_by><text>An Underground Railroad Advisory Council shall be established within the commission. <section prefix="1">The council shall consist of thirteen (13) members, as follows: <section prefix="a">Secretary of the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet, or designee; </section><section prefix="b">Secretary of the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet, or designee; </section><section prefix="c">Secretary of the Transportation Cabinet, or designee; </section><section prefix="d">Executive director of the Kentucky Historical Society, or designee; </section><section prefix="e">State historic preservation officer of the Kentucky Heritage Council, or designee; </section><section prefix="f">Chair of the commission or designee; </section><section prefix="g">Director of the Underground Railroad Institute at Georgetown College, or designee; </section><section prefix="h">Two (2) members of the General Assembly who hold an interest in the Underground Railroad, one (1) appointed by the President of the Senate and one (1) appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives; </section><section prefix="i">Two (2) at-large representatives who hold an interest in the protection, preservation, and promotion of the history of the Underground Railroad in Kentucky, appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="j">One (1) member of the board or staff of the National Underground Railroad Freedom Center who resides within a county of the Northern Kentucky Area Development District; and </section><section prefix="k">One (1) member of the board or staff of the National Underground Railroad Museum who resides within a county of the Buffalo Trace Area Development District. </section></section><section prefix="2">The duties of the council shall be to: <section prefix="a">Advise and assist the commission with respect to issues and opportunities related to the Underground Railroad; and </section><section prefix="b">Annually review and make recommendations to the commission on the annual report and plan for future action. </section></section><section prefix="3">Members of the council shall be appointed for four (4) year terms, except that initial appointments for the two (2) at-large members shall be made so that one (1) member is appointed for two (2) years, and one (1) member is appointed for three (3) years. Sitting members shall be eligible for reappointment. </section><section prefix="4">The chair of the commission shall serve as chair of the council. </section><section prefix="5">The council shall meet annually or more frequently at the request of the chair. </section><section prefix="6">Six (6) members shall constitute a quorum for conducting business. </section><section prefix="7">In the event of a vacancy, the appropriate appointing entity shall appoint a replacement member who shall hold office during the remainder of the term so vacated. </section><section prefix="8">Members of the council shall serve without compensation. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 12, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 57, effective June 25. 2009; and ch. 16, sec. 50, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 113, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 38, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 3, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44498</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>