<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VII" order_by="7">PUBLIC PROPERTY AND PUBLIC PRINTING</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="56" order_by="56">STATE LANDS AND BUILDINGS </unit></structure><section_number>56.8161</section_number><catch_line>Determination that agency is entitled to use built-to-suit to acquire space -- Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>8161</order_by><text>If the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet determines that an agency is entitled to additional space and that built-to-suit on private property or built-to-suit on state-owned land is the most economically advantageous method for acquiring that space, the secretary shall set forth his determination in a written finding which shall be approved by the Governor. The following definitions shall apply to built-to-suit projects: <section prefix="1">"Design-build-finance" means a built-to-suit project delivery method in which the chief purchasing officer enters into a single procurement and contract award for design, construction, and financing of a capital project over a contractually defined period; and in which the ownership and title of the capital project shall be conveyed at any time to the Commonwealth of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="2">"Design-build-finance-operate" means a built-to-suit project delivery method in which the chief purchasing officer enters into a single procurement and contract award for design, construction, financing, and operation of a capital project over a contractually defined period; and in which the ownership and title of the capital project shall be conveyed at any time to the Commonwealth of Kentucky. </section></text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 98, sec. 14, effective June 24, 2003. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 54, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22712</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>