<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="367" order_by="367">CONSUMER PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>367.980</section_number><catch_line>Required provisions. </catch_line><order_by>980</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each rental-purchase agreement shall: <section prefix="a">Provide that the consumer may terminate the agreement without penalty by voluntarily surrendering or returning the merchandise upon expiration of any lease term; and </section><section prefix="b">Contain a provision for reinstatement which, at a minimum permits a consumer who fails to make a timely rental payment to reinstate the agreement, without losing any rights or options which exist under the agreement, by the payment of all past due rental charges, the reasonable costs of pickup, redelivery, any refurbishing and any applicable  late fee within five (5) days of the renewal date if the consumer pays monthly, or within two (2) days of the renewal date if the consumer pays more frequently than monthly. </section></section><section prefix="2">If a lessee returns the property to the lessor during the times stated in subsection (1) of this section, the reinstatement period shall be extended for an additional thirty (30) days from the date of return. </section><section prefix="3">Nothing in this section shall prevent a lessor from attempting to repossess property during the reinstatement period, but that repossession shall not affect the consumer's right to reinstate. Upon reinstatement, the lessor shall provide the consumer with the same property or substitute property of comparable quality and condition. </section></text><history>Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 196, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1990; and ch. 304, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><lrc-note> (7/13/90).  This section was created by two separate 1990 Acts which are identical and have therefore been compiled together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35152</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>