<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">A URBAN-COUNTY GOVERNMENT </unit></structure><section_number>67A.6901</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 67A.6901 to 67A.6911. </catch_line><order_by>6901</order_by><text>As used in KRS 67A.6901 to 67A.6911: <section prefix="1">"Secretary" means the secretary of the cabinet; </section><section prefix="2">"Corrections personnel" means an employee of an urban-county government permanently assigned to a detention facility and working in any capacity in that detention facility; </section><section prefix="3">"Cabinet" means the Kentucky Labor Cabinet; </section><section prefix="4">"Exclusive representative" means the labor organization which has been designated by the cabinet as the representative of the majority of police officers, firefighter personnel, firefighters, or corrections personnel in appropriate units or has been so recognized by the urban-county government; </section><section prefix="5">"Firefighter" means an employee of an urban-county government engaged in serving the public by providing fire protection, including those covered by KRS Chapter 95; </section><section prefix="6">"Firefighter personnel" means dispatch communications officers; </section><section prefix="7">"Labor organization" means any chartered labor organization of any kind in which police officers, firefighter personnel, firefighters, or corrections personnel participate and which exists for the primary purpose of dealing with urban-county governments concerning grievances, labor disputes, wages, rate of pay, hours of employment, or conditions of employment; </section><section prefix="8">"Person" includes one (1) or more individuals, labor organizations, associations, corporations, legal representatives, trustees, trustees in bankruptcy, or receivers; and </section><section prefix="9">"Police officer" means an employee, sworn or certified, of an urban-county government who participates in the Law Enforcement Foundation Program Fund provided in KRS 15.410 to 15.510. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 59, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 177, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23911</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>