<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">A KENTUCKY MODEL PROCUREMENT CODE </unit></structure><section_number>45A.425</section_number><catch_line>Surplus or excess property. </catch_line><order_by>425</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A local public agency may sell or otherwise dispose of any personal property which is not needed or has become unsuitable for public use, or which would be suitable, consistent with the public interest, for some other use. </section><section prefix="2">A written determination as to need of suitability of any personal property of the local public agency shall be made; and such determination shall fully describe the personal property; its intended use at the time of acquisition; the reasons why it is in the public interest to dispose of the item; and the method of disposition to be used. </section><section prefix="3">Surplus or excess personal property as described in this section may be transferred, with or without compensation, to another governmental agency; or it may be sold at public auction or by sealed bids in accordance with KRS 45A.365. </section><section prefix="4">In the event that a local public agency receives no bids for surplus or excess personal property, either at public auction or by sealed bid, such property may be disposed of, consistent with the public interest, in any manner deemed appropriate by the local public agency. In such instances, a written description of the property, the method of disposal, and the amount of compensation, if any, shall be made. Any compensation resulting from the disposal of surplus or excess personal property shall be transferred to the general fund of the local public agency. </section><section prefix="5">A local board of education may dispose of its surplus technology in accordance with KRS 160.335. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 199, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 86, effective January 1, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22419</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>