<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.501</section_number><catch_line>Student health services -- Responsibilities of Department of Education and Department for Public Health -- Filling of position -- Funding. </catch_line><order_by>501</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department of Education shall provide leadership and assistance to local school districts relating to student health services. The department, working in cooperation with the Department for Public Health, shall provide, contract for services, or identify resources to improve student health services, including but not limited to the following: <section prefix="a">Standardized protocols and guidelines for health procedures to be performed by health professionals and school personnel. The protocols and guidelines shall include but not be limited to the following: <section prefix="1">The delegation of nursing functions consistent with administrative regulations promulgated by the Kentucky Board of Nursing; </section><section prefix="2">Training of designated nonmedical school personnel; and </section><section prefix="3">Appropriate documentation and recordkeeping including, but not limited to, notification to school administrators and parents or guardians of the provision of health services by a school employee, including certification of medical necessity for health services signed by a health care professional, and informed consent for the provision of health services by a parent or guardian. </section></section> A copy of the protocols and guidelines shall be made available to each school in the Commonwealth and shall be maintained by each school in the school's library; <section prefix="b">Consultation, technical assistance, and development of quality improvement measures for the state and local boards of education, individual public schools, and local health departments; </section><section prefix="c">Facilitation of statewide and local data collection and reporting of school health services; and </section><section prefix="d">Information and resources that relate to the provision of school health services. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Department of Education shall establish a position to assist in carrying out the responsibilities required under subsection (1) of this section. The position may be established with existing personnel resources, or by contract, with an individual who: <section prefix="a">Holds, at a minimum, a bachelor's degree in nursing with a master's degree in nursing or a related field from an accredited postsecondary institution; and </section><section prefix="b">Is a registered nurse licensed under the provisions of KRS Chapter 314. </section></section><section prefix="3">The Department of Education shall provide fifty percent (50%) of the costs for the position required by subsection (2) of this section and the Department for Public Health shall provide the remaining fifty percent (50%) for the position. The Department of Education may enter into a contractual arrangement, such as a Memorandum of Agreement, with the Department for Public Health to share the costs. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 294, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3214</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>