<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="83" order_by="83">A ORGANIZATION OF GOVERNMENT IN CITIES </unit></structure><section_number>83A.075</section_number><catch_line>Equating of compensation rate of mayors and members of city legislative bodies with purchasing power of dollar -- Limitation. </catch_line><order_by>075</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In order to equate the compensation of mayors and members of city legislative bodies with the purchasing power of the dollar, the Department for Local Government shall compute by the second Friday in February of every year the annual increase or decrease in the consumer price index of the preceding year by using 1949 as the base year in accordance with Section 246 of the Constitution of Kentucky which provides that the mayor in cities of the first class shall be paid at a rate no greater than twelve thousand dollars ($12,000) per annum and mayors in cities other than the first class and legislative body members shall be paid at a rate no greater than seven thousand two hundred dollars ($7,200) per annum. </section><section prefix="2">The legislative body of the city shall set the compensation of the officer in accordance with KRS 83A.070 at a rate no greater than that stipulated by the Department for Local Government. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 66, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 60, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 44, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 508, sec. 40, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 50, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:11</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=25173</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>