<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="318" order_by="318">PLUMBERS AND PLUMBING </unit></structure><section_number>318.130</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky State Plumbing Code -- Rules and regulations. </catch_line><order_by>130</order_by><text>In order to administer this chapter, the department shall promulgate and thereafter from time to time may amend a code to be known as the Kentucky State Plumbing Code, regulating the construction, installation, and alteration of plumbing and plumbing fixtures and appliances, house sewers and private water supplies, and methods and materials to be used therein within this state, using as a minimum standard the basic principles of the National Plumbing Code Coordinating Committee, as evidenced by that committee's final report of 1951 with variations thereof or additions thereto as the committee considers are warranted by local, climatic, or other conditions. The code may also designate the number of plumbing fixtures for public buildings. The department may adopt any other reasonable rule or regulation to administer this chapter if the rule or regulation has been subject to review and comment by the committee under the requirements of KRS 198B.030(8) and (9) and 198B.040(11). No rules or regulations so approved by the committee shall become effective except upon adoption by the department, in satisfaction of the requirements of KRS Chapter 13A. The department shall furnish to the committee proposed amendments to the code for the committee's review and comment prior to their adoption by the department. The department shall not promulgate any rules or regulations related to this chapter without granting the committee the opportunity to comment on the administrative regulation. </text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 21, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1685, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 256, sec. 10, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 392, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 193, sec. 5; and ch. 299, sec. 70. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 147. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 1. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 222, sec. 17. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 3909b-2. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><lrc-note> (10/5/90).  Pursuant to KRS 7.136(1), KRS Chapter 13A has been substituted for the prior reference to KRS Chapter 13 in this statute. The sections in KRS Chapter 13 were repealed by 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 417, รยง 36 and KRS Chapter 13A was created in that same chapter of the 1984 Ky. Acts. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39916</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>