<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="278" order_by="278">PUBLIC SERVICE COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>278.290</section_number><catch_line>Valuation of utility property in connection with rates, service or issuance of securities -- Unit rate base. </catch_line><order_by>290</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Subject to the provisions of subsection (2) of this section, the commission may ascertain and fix the value of the whole or any part of the property of any utility in so far as the value is material to the exercise of the jurisdiction of the commission, and may make revaluations from time to time and ascertain the value of all new construction, extensions and additions to the property of the utility. In fixing the value of any property under this subsection, the commission shall give due consideration to the history and development of the utility and its property, original cost, cost of reproduction as a going concern, capital structure, and other elements of value recognized by the law of the land for rate-making purposes.  </section><section prefix="2">The commission shall not value or revalue the property of any utility unless the valuation or revaluation is necessary or advisable in order to determine the legality or reasonableness of any rate or service or of the issuance of securities, and then only after an investigation affecting the rate, service or securities has been instituted by the commission upon complaint or application or upon its own motion, and a hearing has been held on reasonable notice.  </section><section prefix="3">In any rate investigation where the utility serves two (2) or more municipalities, the commission may, in computing the rate of return on the property used and useful, take as the base for the computation the valuation of the system as a whole, but may make a differential in the case of an individual municipality in proportion to the increased cost of service, if the utility can show that such a differential should be allowed.  </section></text><history>Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 33, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 379, sec. 36, effective April 1, 1979. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 46, sec. 3, effective March 5, 1952. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 3952-17, 3952-19. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1982</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14102</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>