<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.2-100</section_number><catch_line>General powers and duties of commissioner. </catch_line><order_by>2-100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commissioner shall personally supervise the operations of the department. </section><section prefix="2">The commissioner shall examine and inquire into violations of this code, shall enforce the provisions of this code with impartiality and shall execute the duties imposed upon him or her by this code. </section><section prefix="3">The commissioner shall have the powers and authority expressly conferred upon him or her by or reasonably implied from the provisions of this code. </section><section prefix="4">The commissioner may conduct such examinations and investigations of insurance matters, in addition to examinations and investigations expressly authorized, as the commissioner may deem proper upon reasonable and probable cause to determine whether any person has violated any provisions of this code or to secure information useful in the lawful administration of any such provision. The cost of such additional examinations and investigations shall be borne by the state. </section><section prefix="5">The commissioner may establish and maintain such branch offices in this state as may be reasonably required for the efficient administration of this code. </section><section prefix="6">The commissioner shall have such additional powers and duties as may be provided by other laws of this state. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 924, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 31, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 2, sec. 10, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=16656</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>