<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="160" order_by="160">SCHOOL DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>160.725</section_number><catch_line>Directory information on student -- Student's right to restrict release -- Official recruiters' access to public high school campuses and student directory information. </catch_line><order_by>725</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An educational institution may publish and release to the general public directory information relating to a student. An educational institution shall give public notice of the categories of directory information that it has designated as directory information with respect to each student in attendance and shall allow a reasonable time after the notice has been given for a parent or eligible student to inform the institution that any or all of the information designated should not be released without prior consent. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">If an educational institution provides access to its campus or its student directory information to persons or groups which make students aware of occupational or educational options, the board shall provide access on the same basis to official recruiting representatives of: <section prefix="1">The Armed Forces of the United States; </section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Air National Guard; </section><section prefix="3">The Kentucky Army National Guard; and </section><section prefix="4">The service academies of the Armed Forces of the United States. </section></section><section prefix="b">Local secondary schools shall provide the student directory information to official recruiting representatives by September 30 of each year. </section><section prefix="c">Student directory information given to official recruiting representatives may be used for the purpose of informing students of educational and career opportunities available in the Armed Forces of the United States, the Kentucky Air National Guard, the Kentucky Army National Guard and the service academies of the Armed Forces of the United States. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 39, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended and renumbered 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 98, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1994, pursuant to KRS 7.136(1). -- Repealed and reenacted 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 473, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 84, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><former-codification> KRS 160.297. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3819</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>