<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="210" order_by="210">STATE AND REGIONAL MENTAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>210.400</section_number><catch_line>Duties of board. </catch_line><order_by>400</order_by><text>Subject to the provisions of this section and the policies and regulations of the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, each community board for mental health or individuals with an intellectual disability shall: <section prefix="1">Review and evaluate services for mental health or individuals with an intellectual disability provided pursuant to KRS 210.370 to 210.460, and report thereon to the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, the administrator of the program, and, when indicated, the public, together with recommendations for additional services and facilities; </section><section prefix="2">Recruit and promote local financial support for the program from private sources such as community chests, business, industrial and private foundations, voluntary agencies, and other lawful sources, and promote public support for municipal and county appropriations; </section><section prefix="3">Promote, arrange, and implement working agreements with other social service agencies, both public and private, and with other educational and judicial agencies; </section><section prefix="4">Adopt and implement policies to stimulate effective community relations; </section><section prefix="5">Be responsible for the development and approval of an annual plan and budget; </section><section prefix="6">Act as the administrative authority of the community program for mental health or individuals with an intellectual disability; </section><section prefix="7">Oversee and be responsible for the management of the community program for mental health or individuals with an intellectual disability in accordance with the plan and budget adopted by the board and the policies and regulations issued under KRS 210.370 to 210.480 by the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; and </section><section prefix="8">Comply with the provisions of KRS 65A.010 to 65A.090. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 64, effective March 21, 2013. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 79, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 328, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 272, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 4, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(1) and (8). -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 90, sec. 64(3). -- Created 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 8. </history><metadata><effective> March 21, 2013 </effective><former-codification> KRS 203.440. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41744</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>