<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXII" order_by="32">OWNERSHIP AND CONVEYANCE OF PROPERTY</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="381" order_by="381">TITLE TO PROPERTY AND RESTRICTIONS ON USE, OWNERSHIP, AND ALIENATION </unit></structure><section_number>381.755</section_number><catch_line>Removal of grave or cemetery on application of landowner or county -- Procedure -- Expenses. </catch_line><order_by>755</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon application of the owner of property upon which is located an abandoned grave or cemetery or whenever the fiscal court of any county deems it to be in the best interest of the county to remove and relocate any such grave or cemetery the court may issue an order or resolution authorizing such removal or relocation. </section><section prefix="2">The order or resolution for the removal and relocation of the grave or cemetery pursuant to subsection (1) shall specify and declare that at any time after the expiration of sixty (60) days after the first publication of notice of such intended action pursuant to KRS Chapter 424, the court shall direct the removal and relocation of the grave or cemetery. </section><section prefix="3">Expenses for removal and relocation of any grave or cemetery under the provisions of this section shall be paid by the individual requesting such removal or if the removal is made in the best interest of the county the expenses shall be paid from county funds. </section><section prefix="4">Any grave or cemetery removed under the provisions of this section shall be relocated in a suitable place at the expense of the person or county requesting such removal and relocation. </section><section prefix="5">For the purposes of this section a grave or cemetery shall be considered abandoned when left untended for a period of ten (10) years preceding the date of the resolution for removal and relocation of the grave or cemetery. </section></text><history>Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 251, secs. 1 to 5. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35488</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>