<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="215" order_by="215">TUBERCULOSIS </unit></structure><section_number>215.520</section_number><catch_line>Duties relating to tuberculosis control. </catch_line><order_by>520</order_by><text>The secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall discharge all duties relating to all matters of tuberculosis control, including, but not limited to, the following: <section prefix="1">The facilitation of appropriate clinical services for either recalcitrant or drug resistant persons with active tuberculosis for which failure to provide services will lead to further spread of disease in the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="2">The promulgation of administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A for the purpose of carrying out the directives of this section, KRS 215.540, 215.550, 215.560, 215.570, 215.580, 215.590, and 215.600; </section><section prefix="3">The maintenance of a central register of all known cases of tuberculosis in the Commonwealth, and local registers as desirable, and the collection, collation, analysis, and publication of statistics and other information; </section><section prefix="4">The facilitation of tuberculosis programs in cooperation with the Department of Corrections, Department of Education, and other state agencies within their respective jurisdictions; </section><section prefix="5">The establishment within the Cabinet for Health and Family Services of appropriate social service and financial responsibility appraisal methods to insure that tuberculosis patients or suspects receive all possible support from third-party payors, or from the Medical Assistance Program. The Cabinet for Health and Family Services may contract for services for persons with tuberculosis, either directly or through local health departments, and may pay the rates it deems necessary as a charge against the tuberculosis control funds of the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="6">The dissemination of educational materials to the citizens of the Commonwealth regarding tuberculosis and its control; </section><section prefix="7">The initiation of special programs and demonstrations in cooperation with agencies of the federal government, universities, voluntary agencies, and other individuals or corporations; </section><section prefix="8">The provision of direct assistance to local health departments, to other agencies of state government, and to other organizations to assist them in carrying out education, prevention, and treatment programs of tuberculosis control; and </section><section prefix="9">Except as otherwise provided by law, to do all other things reasonably necessary to carry out the intent of this section and KRS 215.540 to 215.600. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 471, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 416, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 33, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 78, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 331, sec. 34, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 271, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 208, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 78. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 133, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8935</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>