<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IV" order_by="4">JUDICIAL BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="23" order_by="23">A CIRCUIT COURT </unit></structure><section_number>23A.208Additional</section_number><catch_line>fee for sex crime, stalking, or related inchoate offenses.   </catch_line><order_by>208Additional</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In addition to fees created by KRS 23A.205, 23A.206, and 23A.2065, an administrative fee of thirty dollars ($30) shall be added to the costs that the defendant is required to pay for the following crimes: <section prefix="a">A sex crime, meaning an offense described in: <section prefix="1">KRS Chapter 510; </section><section prefix="2">KRS 530.020; </section><section prefix="3">KRS 530.064(1)(a); </section><section prefix="4">KRS 531.310; and </section><section prefix="5">KRS 531.320; </section></section><section prefix="b">Stalking, meaning conduct prohibited under KRS 508.140 and 508.150; and </section><section prefix="c">A criminal attempt, conspiracy, facilitation, or solicitation to commit the crimes set forth in this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="2">The first one dollar and fifty cents ($1.50) of each fee collected under this section shall be placed into the general fund, and the remainder of the fee shall be allocated by the clerk of the court on a quarterly basis to the address protection program fund established in KRS 14.260 to be used solely to establish, operate, and maintain the confidential address protection program established in KRS 14.260. </section><section prefix="3">The court may waive all or any portion of the fee required by this section if the court finds that a person subject to the surcharge is indigent or financially unable to pay all or any portion of the surcharge. The court may waive only the portion of the surcharge that the court finds the person is financially unable to pay. </section></text><history> Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:24</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44573</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>