<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>271B.2-020</section_number><catch_line>Articles of incorporation.   </catch_line><order_by>2-020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The articles of incorporation shall set forth: <section prefix="a">A corporate name for the corporation that satisfies the requirements of KRS 14A.3-010; </section><section prefix="b">The number of shares the corporation is authorized to issue; </section><section prefix="c">The corporation's initial registered office and initial registered agent that satisfy the requirements of KRS 14A.4-010; </section><section prefix="d">The mailing address of the corporation's principal office; and </section><section prefix="e">The name and mailing address of each incorporator. </section></section><section prefix="2">The articles of incorporation may set forth: <section prefix="a">The names and mailing addresses of the individuals who are to serve as the initial directors; </section><section prefix="b">Provisions not inconsistent with law regarding: <section prefix="1">The purpose or purposes for which the corporation is organized; </section><section prefix="2">Managing the business and regulating the affairs of the corporation; </section><section prefix="3">Defining, limiting, and regulating the powers of the corporation, its board of directors, and shareholders; </section><section prefix="4">A par value for authorized shares or classes of shares; and </section><section prefix="5">The imposition of personal liability on shareholders for the debts of the corporation to a specified extent and upon specified conditions; </section></section><section prefix="c">Any provision that under this chapter is required or permitted to be set forth in the bylaws; and </section><section prefix="d">A provision eliminating or limiting the personal liability of a director to the corporation or its shareholders for monetary damages for breach of his duties as a director, provided that such provision shall not eliminate or limit the liability of a director: <section prefix="1">For any transaction in which the director's personal financial interest is in conflict with the financial interests of the corporation or its shareholders; </section><section prefix="2">For acts or omissions not in good faith or which involve intentional misconduct or are known to the director to be a violation of law; </section><section prefix="3">For any vote for or assent to an unlawful distribution to shareholders as prohibited under KRS 271B.8-330; or </section><section prefix="4">For any transaction from which the director derived an improper personal benefit. </section></section> No such provision shall eliminate or limit the liability of any director for any act or omission occurring prior to the date when such provision becomes effective. In no case shall this subsection or any such provision be construed to expand the liability of any director as determined pursuant to KRS 271B.8-300. </section><section prefix="3">The articles of incorporation need not set forth any of the corporate powers enumerated in this chapter. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 52, effective January 1, 2011. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 341, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 16, effective January 1, 1989; and ch. 224, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2011 </effective><former-codification> KRS 271A.271. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:24</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36640</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>