<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">A AUTOMATED MOTOR VEHICLE REGISTRATION SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>186A.210</section_number><catch_line>Clerk to release lien assignment. </catch_line><order_by>210</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When a security interest has been discharged under the provisions of KRS 186.045(3), the county clerk shall discharge the security interest and remove the lien information from AVIS. </section><section prefix="2">When a security interest has been discharged as provided by KRS 186.045(4), the county clerk of a county that is operating under automated procedures shall, upon receiving a termination statement, within five (5) days enter the record of termination into the automated system. The automated system shall be programmed to allow a county clerk in a county where the termination statement was not received to access the automated system to determine the county and date that the record of termination was entered into the automated system. The clerk of the county where the termination statement was received shall then release the lien recorded upon the title in the manner directed by the Department of Vehicle Regulation, and take such other action with respect to a termination as is directed by the Department of Vehicle Regulation. </section></text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 103, sec. 3, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 101, effective July 1, 1987. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 39, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><lrc-note>(6/24/2003).  2000 Ky. Acts ch. 408, sec. 178, renumbered the former subsection (2) of KRS 186.045 as subsection (1), but that Act failed to include a conforming amendment to change the reference to that subsection in former subsection (1) of this statute. Under KRS 7.136(1)(e), that change has now been made. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6178</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>