<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="227" order_by="227">FIRE PREVENTION AND PROTECTION -- ELECTRICIANS </unit></structure><section_number>227.650</section_number><catch_line>Inspection powers -- Training programs for local government personnel. </catch_line><order_by>650</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The department is empowered to inspect all mobile homes which are not covered by the federal act and previously owned recreational vehicles for which it has issued a seal of approval. </section><section prefix="2">The board may establish and require such training programs in the concept, techniques, and inspection of manufactured homes, mobile homes, and previously owned recreational vehicles for the personnel of local governments, as the board considers necessary. </section><section prefix="3">The staff of the department, upon showing proper credentials and in the discharge of their duties pursuant to KRS 227.550 to 227.660 or the federal act, is authorized with the consent of the manufacturer or by proper warrant to enter and inspect all factories, warehouses, or establishments in this state in which manufactured homes are manufactured or stored. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 423, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 217, sec. 8, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 74, sec. 12, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 340, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 200, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1979 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 19, sec. 3, effective May 12, 1979. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 10. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10691</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>