<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="273" order_by="273">RELIGIOUS, CHARITABLE, AND EDUCATIONAL SOCIETIES -- NONSTOCK, NONPROFIT CORPORATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>273.302</section_number><catch_line>Effect of dissolution.   </catch_line><order_by>302</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A dissolved corporation shall continue its corporate existence but shall not carry on any business except that appropriate to wind up and liquidate its business and affairs, including: <section prefix="a">Collecting its assets; </section><section prefix="b">Disposing of its properties in accordance with KRS 273.303; </section><section prefix="c">Discharging or making provision for discharging its liabilities including, as appropriate, entering into agreements with creditors for the satisfaction thereof; and </section><section prefix="d">Doing every other act necessary to wind up and liquidate its business and affairs. </section></section><section prefix="2">Dissolution of a corporation shall not: <section prefix="a">Transfer title to the corporation's property; </section><section prefix="b">Subject its directors or officers to standards of conduct different from those prescribed in KRS 273.161 to 273.390; </section><section prefix="c">Change quorum or voting requirements for its board of directors or members; change provisions for selection, resignation, or removal of its directors or officers or both; or change provisions for amending its bylaws; </section><section prefix="d">Prevent commencement of a proceeding by or against the corporation in its corporate name; </section><section prefix="e">Abate or suspend a proceeding pending by or against the corporation on the effective date of dissolution; </section><section prefix="f">Terminate the authority of the registered agent of the corporation; </section><section prefix="g">Alter the obligations and responsibilities of the corporation as prescribed by applicable federal or state law with regard to the filing or examination of all federal and state tax returns or the payment, assessment, or collection of any federal or state tax due with respect to those returns; or </section><section prefix="h">Abate or suspend KRS 273.187(2). </section></section></text><history> Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 34, sec. 73, effective June 24, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44386</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>