<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.453</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 247.450 to 247.505. </catch_line><order_by>453</order_by><text>As used in KRS 247.450 to 247.505, unless the context otherwise requires:  <section prefix="1">"Commissioner" means the commissioner of agriculture;  </section><section prefix="2">"Board" means the state board of agriculture;  </section><section prefix="3">"Producer" means every person who produces milk or cream from cows and thereafter causes the same to be marketed as milk, cream or other dairy products;  </section><section prefix="4">"New producer" means a producer who was not engaged in the business of producing milk at the time a referendum was conducted in accordance with the provisions of KRS 247.450 to 247.505;  </section><section prefix="5">"Person" means any individual, corporation, partnership, association, cooperative or other business entity;  </section><section prefix="6">"Milk" means milk from cows and all of its natural components, sweet cream, sour cream, skim milk, flavored milk, buttermilk, condensed or concentrated whole or skim milk for use in milk products of every kind and description;  </section><section prefix="7">"Handler" or "dealer" means any person, including any distributor, processor, bulk milk handler, or operator of a store, who purchases or receives on consignment or otherwise, milk and milk products of every kind and description, within the state, for sale, shipment, storage, processing, or manufacture;  </section><section prefix="8">"Processor" means any person engaged in the business of processing milk and other material into milk products of every kind and description.  </section></text><history>Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 171, sec. 2. </history><metadata><lrc-note>.A technical correction has been made in this section by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to KRS 7.136. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11672</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>