<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="150" order_by="150">FISH AND WILDLIFE RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>150.028</section_number><catch_line>Required administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>028</order_by><text>The department shall promulgate administrative regulations regarding: <section prefix="1">Specific permitted and prohibited uses of department-owned property and activities on department-owned property; </section><section prefix="2">For a violation of an administrative regulation promulgated under subsection (1), (4), or (5) of this section relating to prohibited uses of department-owned property and prohibited activities thereon, offenses and penalties which do not authorize imprisonment, and for which the offense and the penalty are not established by statute; </section><section prefix="3">The issuance of licenses or permits for the use of and conduct of activities on department-owned property, including but not limited to docks on department-owned lakes; </section><section prefix="4">The revocation or suspension, following a hearing pursuant to KRS Chapter 13B, of a license or permit issued pursuant to this section; and </section><section prefix="5">Specific permitted and prohibited uses of a department-owned or controlled buffer zone on land adjacent to a department-owned lake, including sanctions which do not authorize imprisonment for violation of the administrative regulations where a statute does not provide an offense and does not provide a penalty. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 158, sec. 13, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1938</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>