<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.004</section_number><catch_line>Strategic Committee on Postsecondary Education. </catch_line><order_by>004</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Strategic Committee on Postsecondary Education is hereby created and established. The committee shall be composed of members appointed by the Council on Postsecondary Education, the Governor, and the General Assembly. The council's representatives shall consist of the chair of the council, the president of the council, and five (5) members of the council designated by the chair. The Governor's representatives shall consist of the Governor and six (6) persons designated by the Governor. The General Assembly's representatives shall consist of the President of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the Majority and Minority Floor Leaders of both chambers of the General Assembly, the minority caucus chair of each chamber, a member appointed by the President of the Senate, a member appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, a member appointed by the Minority Floor Leader of the Senate, a member appointed by the Minority Floor Leader of the House of Representatives, and the chair of the Committee on Appropriations and Revenue of each chamber. </section><section prefix="2">The chair of the council shall serve as chair of the committee. The committee shall meet at least quarterly and at other times upon the written call of the chair or of majorities of any two (2) of the three (3) groups that compose the committee. </section><section prefix="3">Nonlegislative members of the committee shall serve without compensation but shall be reimbursed for their actual and necessary expenses, as set forth in KRS 12.070(5). Committee members who are Kentucky legislators shall be compensated for attendance at committee meetings from the legislative branch budget bill and as set forth in KRS 6.190. </section><section prefix="4">The committee shall serve as a forum for the council and the elected leadership of the Commonwealth to exchange ideas about the future of postsecondary education in Kentucky. </section><section prefix="5">The council shall periodically review its strategic implementation plan for the strategic agenda under KRS 164.0203 and advise the committee of the actions necessary to meet the goals established in KRS 164.003(2). The elected leaders shall review and comment on the strategic agenda and the timetable for implementation. </section><section prefix="6">The Governor shall advise the committee about the financial condition of the Commonwealth and the probable funds the executive branch intends to recommend to the General Assembly to be appropriated for postsecondary education. </section><section prefix="7">The legislative members shall react to the comments of the council and the Governor. </section><section prefix="8">The council shall advise the committee about its opinion of how the postsecondary education funds projected to be available should be allocated based on priorities and projected resources. Nothing in this section shall be construed to infringe upon the Governor's duty under KRS 48.100 to recommend appropriations to the General Assembly or upon the General Assembly's power to make final appropriations in the enacted budget. </section><section prefix="9">The committee shall have the advisory authority not explicitly prohibited by law that is necessary to carry out and effectuate its advisory functions, duties, and responsibilities, including the following: <section prefix="a">Receive reports from the council on the development and implementation of the long-term strategic agenda, including biennial budget requests for postsecondary education and any subsequent and related budget requests; </section><section prefix="b">Review the council's proposed objectives and benchmarks for the next fiscal biennium for furthering the Commonwealth's achievement of the goals set out in KRS 164.003(2); </section><section prefix="c">Consider and advise the council on the general budget parameters regarding development of the postsecondary budget for the next fiscal biennium; </section><section prefix="d">Review biennial budget requests from the council for the next fiscal biennium including base funding, increases in base funding, and funding for a strategic investment and incentive funding program, including criteria to be used in allocating these funds to institutions; </section><section prefix="e">Receive from the council, at least annually and on a more frequent basis if requested by the committee, accountability reports, budget information, and other information the committee deems proper; and </section><section prefix="f">Serve as the search committee for the review and consideration of candidates to be presented to the council for the initial appointment to the position of president of the Council on Postsecondary Education. Each group of the committee shall have one (1) vote on the search committee. The vote of each group shall be determined by a majority of the members of that group. </section></section></text><history> Created 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 4, effective May 30, 1997. </history><metadata><effective> May 30, 1997 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4159</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>