<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXII" order_by="32">OWNERSHIP AND CONVEYANCE OF PROPERTY</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="382" order_by="382">CONVEYANCES AND ENCUMBRANCES </unit></structure><section_number>382.110</section_number><catch_line>Recording of deeds and mortgages -- Place of recording -- Use of certified copies of original records -- Contents of deed -- Filing of deed in lieu of foreclosure.   </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All deeds, mortgages and other instruments required by law to be recorded to be effectual against purchasers without notice, or creditors, shall be recorded in the county clerk's office of the county in which the property conveyed, or the greater part thereof, is located. </section><section prefix="2">No county clerk or deputy county clerk shall admit to record any deed of conveyance of any interest in real property equal to or greater than a life estate, unless the deed plainly specifies and refers to the next immediate source from which the grantor derived title to the property or the interest conveyed therein. </section><section prefix="3">An authentic photocopy of any original record may be certified, as a true, complete, unaltered copy of the original record on file by the official public custodian of the record. A certified copy of a document certified by the official public custodian of that document may be submitted for filing in any other filing officer's jurisdiction as though it were the original record. However, no county clerk or deputy county clerk shall accept for filing any original document or certified copy of any document unless the original document and its certified copy conforms to all statutory requirements for filing the document under KRS Chapter 382. The provisions of this subsection shall apply only to a record generated and filed in Kentucky, and only if the certified copy thereof is to be utilized in Kentucky. If the record is a foreign record or a Kentucky record to be filed or utilized in a foreign jurisdiction, then this subsection shall not apply and applicable federal, Kentucky, or foreign law shall apply. </section><section prefix="4">If the source of title is a deed or other recorded writing, the deed offered for record shall refer to the former deed or writing, and give the office, book and page where recorded, and the date thereof. If the property or interest therein is obtained by inheritance or in any other way than by recorded instrument of writing, the deed offered for record shall state clearly and accurately how and from whom the title thereto was obtained by the grantor. </section><section prefix="5">If the title to the property or interest conveyed is obtained from two (2) or more sources, the deed offered for record shall plainly specify and refer to each of the sources in the manner provided in subsections (2) and (4), and shall show which part of the property, or interest therein, was obtained from each of the sources. </section><section prefix="6">No grantor shall lodge for record, and no county clerk or deputy shall receive and permit to be lodged for record, any deed that does not comply with the provisions of this section. </section><section prefix="7">No clerk or deputy clerk shall be liable to the fine imposed by subsection (1) of KRS 382.990 because of any erroneous or false references in any such deed, nor because of the omission of a reference required by law where it does not appear on the face of such deed that the title to the property or interest conveyed was obtained from more than one (1) source. </section><section prefix="8">This section does not apply to deeds made by any court commissioner, sheriff or by any officer of court in pursuance of his duty as such officer, nor to any deed or instrument made and acknowledged before March 20, 1928. No deed shall be invalid because it is lodged contrary to the provisions of this section. </section><section prefix="9">A mortgage holder shall file a deed in lieu of foreclosure in the county clerk's office of the county in which the property conveyed, or the greater part thereof, is located, no later than forty-five (45) days after the date the deed in lieu of foreclosure is executed. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 44, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 2, effective June 20, 2005. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 495. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40166</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>