<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.250</section_number><catch_line>Business authorized by quota retail drink license -- Compatible licenses.   </catch_line><order_by>250</order_by><text>A quota retail drink license shall authorize the licensee to purchase, receive, possess, and sell distilled spirits and wine at retail by the drink for consumption on the licensed premises. The licensee shall purchase distilled spirits and wine only from licensed wholesalers, and unless he or she also holds a quota retail package license, he or she shall not buy or possess distilled spirits or wine in containers smaller than two hundred (200) milliliters. A licensee may purchase wine in containers not smaller than one hundred (100) milliliters if the wine does not exceed fourteen percent (14%) alcohol by volume and the quota retail drink license is held by a restaurant or private club which receives a minimum of fifty percent (50%) of its food and beverage receipts from the sale of food and has a minimum seating capacity of fifty (50) people at tables. A licensee may buy mixed drinks in containers of a capacity not smaller than three hundred fifty-five (355) milliliters if the mixed drinks contain a substantial proportion of carbonated water. A quota retail drink license shall not authorize the licensee to sell distilled spirits or wine by the package. The holder of a quota retail drink license may also hold a NQ4 retail malt beverage drink license. </text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 16, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 69, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 125, sec. 6, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 522, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 16, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 136, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2554b-123. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43038</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>