<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="142" order_by="142">MISCELLANEOUS TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>142.321</section_number><catch_line>Application for certificate of registration -- Information from licensure boards. </catch_line><order_by>321</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every provider subject to the taxes imposed by KRS 142.303, 142.307, 142.309, 142.311, 142.314, 142.315, 142.316, 142.361, and 142.363 that is not registered with the department pursuant to the provisions of KRS 142.221 shall, on July 15, 1994, file an application for a certificate of registration with the department. A certificate of registration filed in accordance with the provisions of KRS 142.221 shall remain valid for purposes of KRS 142.301 to 142.363. Every provider seeking to provide health care items or services in Kentucky for the first time after July 15, 1994, shall, prior to providing these items or services, file an application for a certificate of registration with the department. The application shall be in the form prescribed by the department. The application shall be signed by the owner if a natural person; in the case of an association or partnership, by a member or partner; in the case of a corporation, by an executive officer or some person specifically authorized by the corporation to sign the application. </section><section prefix="2">Every state board responsible for licensing or governing any provider subject to the tax imposed by KRS 142.303, 142.307, 142.309, 142.311, 142.314, 142.315, 142.316, 142.361, and 142.363 shall, upon request by the department, provide any information available to the licensing board necessary for the administration of the taxes imposed by KRS 142.303, 142.307, 142.309, 142.311, 142.314, 142.315, 142.316, 142.361, and 142.363. The information shall be in the form required by the department and shall be used by the department for the sole purpose of administering the taxes imposed by KRS 142.303, 142.307, 142.309, 142.311, 142.314, 142.315, 142.316, 142.361, and 142.363. </section><section prefix="3">Every state board responsible for licensing or governing any provider subject to the tax imposed by KRS 142.303, 142.307, 142.309, 142.311, 142.314, 142.315, 142.316, 142.361, and 142.363 shall, upon request by the department, include the application for certificate of registration required by subsection (1) of this section with any new license issued. Application forms shall be provided by the department to the licensing board. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 524, effective June 20, 2005; and ch. 120, sec. 7, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 6, effective August 1, 1996. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 512, sec. 102, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><lrc-note>(6/20/2005).  This section was amended by 2005 Ky. Acts chs. 85 and 120, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29212</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>