<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">A LOW-COST HOUSING </unit></structure><section_number>198A.050</section_number><catch_line>Administration of programs by executive director -- Requirements. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In the administration of the programs authorized by or receiving benefits under KRS 198A.040, the executive director of the Kentucky Housing Corporation shall require:  <section prefix="a">That to the greatest extent feasible opportunities for training and employment arising in connection with the planning, construction, rehabilitation, and operation of housing assisted under such programs shall be given to persons of lower and moderate income residing in the area of such housing; and  </section><section prefix="b">That to the greatest extent feasible contracts for work to be performed pursuant to such programs shall be awarded to business concerns, including but not limited to individuals or firms doing business in the fields of design, architecture, building construction, rehabilitation, maintenance or repair, located in or owned in substantial part by persons residing in the area of such housing.  </section></section><section prefix="2">In the administration of rental residential housing assisted under this chapter, the executive director of the Kentucky Housing Corporation shall require maximum feasible tenant participation and responsibility in tenant programs and services.  </section><section prefix="3">The executive director of the Kentucky Housing Corporation shall establish standards of performance for materials, methods and design which meet the minimum requirements of appropriate federal or state agencies.  </section></text><history>Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 4, effective March 23, 1982. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 383, sec. 4. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 70, sec. 6. </history><metadata><effective>March 23, 1982 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6930</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>