<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.282</section_number><catch_line>Instruction of all blind students in the use of braille -- Assessment for blind students in program -- Exceptions. </catch_line><order_by>282</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The purpose of KRS 156.476, 158.281, 161.051, and this section shall be to assure, to the maximum extent possible, that all blind students shall be instructed in the use of braille. </section><section prefix="2">The written individualized education program for each exceptional student, as promulgated by administrative regulation, shall also include the following assessment for blind students: <section prefix="a">A braille skills inventory, including an assessment of the student's strengths and weaknesses; </section><section prefix="b">A statement as to whether the use of braille shall be that student's primary mode of communication; </section><section prefix="c">The date on which braille instruction shall begin; </section><section prefix="d">The length of the period of instruction, and the frequency and duration of each instructional session; and </section><section prefix="e">The level of competency in braille reading and writing to be achieved, and the assessment measures to be used in determining if that level has been achieved. </section></section><section prefix="3">Braille instruction and use shall not be required by this section if, during the course of developing the blind student's individualized educational program, the members of the Administrative Admission and Release Committee as established for this purpose, pursuant to administrative regulations, concur that the student shall not be required to learn to read and write braille. In reaching its decision, the committee shall consider the student's reading readiness, functional reading skills, reading comprehension rate and stamina, functional writing skills, communication skills, eye condition and prognosis, and functional vision and tactile discrimination skills. Upon reaching this determination the committee shall write into the individualized education program of a blind student, the factors and evidence considered by the committee in reaching its decision. </section><section prefix="4">Nothing in this section shall require the exclusive use of instruction in braille if other methods of reading and writing may also be learned by the student. </section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 382, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3486</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>