<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.1-720</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Peace Corps -- Purpose -- Director. </catch_line><order_by>1-720</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A Kentucky Peace Corps, headed by a director appointed by the board created by KRS 154.1-705, is hereby created. </section><section prefix="2">The purpose of the corps is to: <section prefix="a">Create a volunteer, domestic service corps to promote a mechanism for selfless service for those who wish to improve the lives of other Kentuckians, raise the standard of living, enhance self actualization, and create a more conducive environment for future generations of Kentuckians. </section><section prefix="b">Assist the Commonwealth of Kentucky through targeted activities which promote the public good and achieve measurable or visible improvement in the environment, public service, individual productivity, education, health, and humanitarian endeavors. </section><section prefix="c">Identify and utilize the skills, knowledge, and expertise of dedicated, well-trained volunteers who have met stringent selection criteria and have effectively demonstrated their commitment to the Kentucky Peace Corps. </section><section prefix="d">Promote a cross-fertilization of ideas, skills, and concepts. </section></section><section prefix="3">The director, authorized by subsection (1) of this section, shall be a graduate of an accredited college or university and have at least five (5) years' experience in administration or in related fields. Additional education may be substituted for the required experience on a year-to-year basis. Additional experience may be substituted for the required education on a year-to-year basis, provided the experience level is deemed appropriate by the board. </section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 5, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><former-codification>KRS 154.01-720. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41636</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>