<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="260" order_by="260">MARKETING OF AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS </unit></structure><section_number>260.815</section_number><catch_line>License fees. </catch_line><order_by>815</order_by><text>The license fees to be paid for respective licenses provided for in KRS 260.795, 260.800, and 260.805 shall be per year or any portion of a year with the license year commencing July 1 and ending June 30. No license may be transferred or assigned. The license fees shall be as follows: <section prefix="1">License to handle: For each location: <section prefix="a">One hundred twenty-five dollars ($125) per license for those handling less than ten million (10,000,000) pounds of milk during the past year; or </section><section prefix="b">Three hundred fifty dollars ($350) per license for those handling more than ten million (10,000,000) pounds of milk during the past year. </section></section><section prefix="2">License to test: fifteen dollars ($15) per person for a temporary license or an annual license. </section><section prefix="3">License to sample and weigh: fifteen dollars ($15) per person for a temporary license or an annual license. </section><section prefix="4">Transfer station license: twenty-five dollars ($25) annually. </section><section prefix="5">Laboratory license: twenty-five dollars ($25) annually. </section><section prefix="6">License fees for renewal of licenses that are due and have not been remitted to the director within thirty (30) days following the expiration date shall be assessed a penalty fee prescribed in KRS 260.992. Assessment of this penalty fee shall not prevent the director from taking other actions under KRS 260.775 to 260.845. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 229, sec. 18, effective January 1, 2001. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 276, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 217, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 9, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12649</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>