<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="273" order_by="273">RELIGIOUS, CHARITABLE, AND EDUCATIONAL SOCIETIES -- NONSTOCK, NONPROFIT CORPORATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>273.217</section_number><catch_line>Quorum of directors -- Prohibition on director voting by proxy.   </catch_line><order_by>217</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A majority of the number of directors fixed by the bylaws, or in the absence of a bylaw fixing the number of directors, then of the number stated in the articles of incorporation, shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business, unless otherwise provided in the articles of incorporation or the bylaws. </section><section prefix="2">Unless the articles of incorporation or bylaws provide otherwise, the board of directors may permit any or all directors to participate in a regular or special meeting by, or conduct the meeting through the use of, any means of communication by which all directors participating may simultaneously hear each other during this meeting. A director participating in a meeting by this means shall be deemed to be present in person at the meeting. </section><section prefix="3">The act of the majority of the directors present at a meeting at which a quorum is present shall be the act of the board of directors, unless the act of a greater number is required by KRS 273.161 to 273.390, the articles of incorporation or the bylaws. </section><section prefix="4">Irrespective of whether or not the corporation has members, a director may not vote by proxy. </section></text><history>Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 34, sec. 70, effective June 24, 2015. -- Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 19. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44383</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>