<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">COUNTY GOVERNMENT (FISCAL COURTS AND COUNTY COMMISSIONERS) </unit></structure><section_number>67.904</section_number><catch_line>Procedure for initiation of unification process -- Appointment of unification review commission. </catch_line><order_by>904</order_by><text>The unification process shall be initiated in the following manner: <section prefix="1">The legislative body of one (1) or more cities within the county and the county fiscal court may enact ordinances proposing that a commission be formed to study the question of unifying the county government with one (1) or more cities within the county to form a unified local government. The executive authority of each city enacting an ordinance shall cause a copy of the ordinance to be filed with the county clerk no later than ten (10) days after enactment. </section><section prefix="2">The county clerk shall be responsible for determining whether the required ordinances have been filed to initiate the unification process. The unification process shall be initiated when the county clerk determines that: <section prefix="a">An ordinance has been enacted by the county fiscal court under subsection (1) of this section; and </section><section prefix="b">An ordinance has been enacted and filed by one (1) or more cities within the county. </section></section><section prefix="3">If the county clerk makes the determination required by subsection (2) of this section, the clerk shall notify the county judge/executive, the mayor of each city within the county, and the chief executive officer of every special district within the county that the unification process has been initiated by the county and the city or cities named in the notification. </section><section prefix="4">Within sixty (60) days of notification by the county clerk that the unification process has been officially initiated, a unification review commission shall be appointed. </section></text><history> Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 246, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23817</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>