<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="645" order_by="645">MENTAL HEALTH ACT </unit></structure><section_number>645.070</section_number><catch_line>Hearing procedure. </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All hearings under this chapter shall be conducted in accordance with the Kentucky Rules of Criminal Procedure unless otherwise provided. </section><section prefix="2">Hearings under this chapter may be conducted in an informal manner, consistent with orderly procedures, and in a physical setting not likely to have a harmful effect on the child's physical or mental health. Hearings may be held in chambers, the hospital, or any other suitable place. </section><section prefix="3">The child shall have the right to be present at any hearing under this chapter unless: <section prefix="a">He and his counsel have waived this right; or </section><section prefix="b">On motion of any interested party, the court determines the child's presence at all or part of the hearing is likely to have a harmful effect on the child's physical or mental health. </section></section><section prefix="4">The child and his counsel shall have the right to cross-examine witnesses and to present testimony and evidence in opposition to certification, including the testimony of a qualified mental health professional. </section><section prefix="5">The child's parents shall have a right to participate in the hearing. </section><section prefix="6">The court may, on its own motion, subpoena and question relevant witnesses. </section></text><history>Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 114, effective April 10, 1988. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 423, sec. 152, effective July 1, 1987. </history><metadata><effective>April 10, 1988 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20329</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>