<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="336" order_by="336">LABOR CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>336.060</section_number><catch_line>Authority to issue and serve subpoenas and take depositions -- Enforcement of subpoenas. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In the conduct of an investigation or hearing, the secretary or any authorized deputy may issue subpoenas to compel the attendance of witnesses and parties and the production of books, papers, and records competent and relevant to the matter under investigation; administer oaths; examine witnesses under oath; take the verification or proof of written instruments; and take testimony, depositions, and affidavits to carry out any law over which the cabinet has jurisdiction. </section><section prefix="2">When a person fails to comply with a cabinet subpoena, the Circuit Court of the county in which the person is found, resides, or has his principal place of business may, upon application of the secretary, his or her authorized representatives, or the party requesting the subpoena, issue an order requiring compliance. In any proceeding brought under this section, the Circuit Court having issued said order of compliance may modify or set aside the subpoena. </section><section prefix="3">Subpoenas issued under this section may be served by an inspector or other authorized representative of the cabinet, at any place in the state. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1705, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 244, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 1599c-12, 1599c-13, 4767a-3. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31995</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>