<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="212" order_by="212">LOCAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>212.080</section_number><catch_line>Elections in one county. </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text>A number of legal voters equal to ten percent (10%) of the total number of votes cast at the last general election of any county may file their petition with the county judge/executive asking that the proposition of creating, establishing and maintaining a county health department be submitted to the voters of the county at the next general election held in the county that does not occur within less than eighty-four (84) days after filing the petition. Each voter signing the petition shall state his full name and address. At the time of filing the petition the petitioners shall deposit with the county judge/executive a sufficient sum of money to pay the cost of publication, as required by this section. Upon the filing of the petition with the county judge/executive, he shall enter an order directing the publication in full of the petition, pursuant to KRS Chapter 424, and shall further enter and file an order with the county clerk not later than the second Tuesday in August preceding a general election directing the county clerk to have placed before the voters at such election the question, "Are you in favor of establishing a county department of health?" The voter shall indicate a "Yes" or a "No" vote. If the majority of those voting on the proposition vote "Yes," a department of health for the county shall be created, established and maintained. The vote shall be canvassed and returned by the board of election commissioners for the general election. If the election is contested, the members of the fiscal court of the county shall be made defendants. </text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 195, sec. 67, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 360, sec. 56, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 344, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 239, sec. 163. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2054a-5, 2054a-6. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8576</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>