<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.378</section_number><catch_line>Funeral processions. </catch_line><order_by>378</order_by><text><section prefix="1">"Funeral procession," as used in this section, means two (2) or more vehicles accompanying the body of a deceased person when each vehicle has its headlights on or is displaying a pennant attached in such a manner as to be clearly visible to approaching traffic. </section><section prefix="2">A vehicle in a funeral procession has the right-of-way at an intersection and may proceed through the intersection if the procession is led by an escort vehicle displaying flashing yellow, red, or blue lights, except: <section prefix="a">When the right-of-way is required by an emergency vehicle as defined by KRS 189.910; </section><section prefix="b">When vehicles in the procession are directed otherwise by a police or safety officer; or </section><section prefix="c">When the vehicle is a train or locomotive. </section></section><section prefix="3">Before assuming the right-of-way, a person who drives a vehicle in a funeral procession shall exercise due caution with regard to crossing traffic. </section><section prefix="4">A person who drives a vehicle that is not part of a funeral procession shall not drive the vehicle between the vehicles of the funeral procession or otherwise interfere with the progress of the procession, except when: <section prefix="a">The person is authorized to do so by a police or safety officer; or </section><section prefix="b">The vehicle is an emergency vehicle as defined by KRS 189.910. </section></section><section prefix="5">A person who drives a vehicle that is not a part of a funeral procession shall not illuminate the vehicle headlights or engage in any other act for the purpose of securing the right-of-way granted to funeral processions. </section><section prefix="6">The escort vehicle, hearse, or other vehicles in a procession may be equipped with flashing amber lights for the purpose of notifying the general public of the procession and gaining the right-of-way at intersections, or signaling the end of a procession. </section><section prefix="7">Persons authorized to use flashing lights as defined in KRS 189.920 may use them while accompanying a funeral procession to warn traffic that a procession is approaching or that it is in progress. </section><section prefix="8">When a funeral procession is in progress, a person driving a vehicle not in the procession shall not pass or overtake any vehicle in the procession unless: <section prefix="a">The person is directed to do so by a police or safety officer; </section><section prefix="b">The procession is on a street, road, or highway outside the corporate limits of a city, town, or urban-county; or </section><section prefix="c">The procession is on an interstate highway or a state parkway. </section></section><section prefix="9">Any person who violates this section shall be guilty of a Class B misdemeanor. </section></text><history> Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 251, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6381</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>