<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="137" order_by="137">LICENSE TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>137.130</section_number><catch_line>Transporters of crude petroleum must report and register. </catch_line><order_by>130</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every person engaged in the transportation of crude petroleum in this state from receptacles located at the place of production in this state shall be considered a transporter of crude petroleum. Every transporter of crude petroleum shall make a verified report to the Department of Revenue by the twentieth day of the month succeeding each month in which crude petroleum is so received for transportation, showing the quantity of each kind or quality of crude petroleum so received from each county in this state and the market value of the crude petroleum on the first business day after the tenth day of the month in which the report is made. The report shall show any sales of crude petroleum so received, the quantity of crude petroleum in each sale, the date of each sale, and the market price of the crude petroleum on each date of sale for the preceding month. This report shall be made upon blanks furnished and prescribed by the department. The department may require additional reports from time to time, on blanks prepared by it, from all producers and transporters of crude petroleum. </section><section prefix="2">Every person required to report under subsection (1) of this section shall register as a transporter of crude petroleum in the office of the county clerk in each county in which such business is carried on by him, in a book which the department shall provide, showing the name, residence and place of business of the transporter. The county clerk shall immediately certify to the department a copy of each registration as made. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 340, effective June 20, 2005. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 4223c-4, 4223c-5, 4223c-8. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:02</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28630</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>