<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="18" order_by="18">A STATE PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>18A.203</section_number><catch_line>Annual-leave sharing program. </catch_line><order_by>203</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Commonwealth of Kentucky annual leave sharing program is created. An employee who has accrued an annual leave balance of more than seventy-five (75) hours may request that the appointing authority of the agency for which the employee works makes available for transfer a specified amount of his or her annual leave balance to another named employee authorized to receive leave under subsection (2) of this section. The employee may not request a transfer of an amount of leave that would result in reducing his or her annual leave balance to less than seventy-five (75) hours. </section><section prefix="2">An appointing authority, with the approval of the secretary of personnel, may permit an employee of the agency to receive leave under this section if: <section prefix="a">The employee suffers from a catastrophic loss to his or her personal property, due to either a natural disaster or fire, that either has caused or will likely cause the employee to go on leave for at least ten (10) consecutive working days; </section><section prefix="b">The employee has exhausted his or her accumulated annual leave and compensatory leave balances; and </section><section prefix="c">The employee has complied with administrative regulations governing the use of annual leave. </section></section><section prefix="3">The appointing authority, with the approval of the secretary of personnel, shall determine the amount of leave, if any, that an employee within his or her agency may receive under subsection (2) of this section. Transfers of leave shall not exceed the amount requested by the recipient. </section><section prefix="4">Leave may be transferred from an employee of one (1) agency to an employee within the same agency. With the approval of the secretary of personnel and of the appointing authorities of both agencies, leave may be transferred from an employee of one (1) agency to an employee of another state agency. The Personnel Cabinet shall maintain records of leave transferred between employees and the utilization of transferred leave. </section><section prefix="5">While an employee is on leave transferred under this section, he or she shall be deemed a state employee and shall receive the same treatment with respect to salary, wages, and employee benefits. </section><section prefix="6">All salary and wage payments made to an employee while on leave transferred under this section shall be made by the agency employing the person receiving the leave. </section><section prefix="7">Any leave transferred under this section that remains unused shall be returned to the employees who transferred the leave when the appointing authority finds that the leave is no longer needed and will not be needed at a future time in connection with the catastrophic loss for which the leave was transferred to an employee in his or her agency. </section><section prefix="8">No employee shall directly or indirectly intimidate, threaten, or coerce, or attempt to intimidate, threaten, or coerce any other employee for the purpose of interfering with the employee's right to voluntarily contribute leave when authorized under this section. For the purpose of this subsection, "intimidate, threaten, or coerce" shall include, without being limited to, the promise to confer or the conferring of any benefit or effecting or threatening to effect any reprisal. </section><section prefix="9">The secretary of the Personnel Cabinet shall promulgate procedural administrative regulations to implement the provisions of this section. </section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 97, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1393</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>