<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.280</section_number><catch_line>Business authorized by nonquota malt beverage package license -- Compatible licenses -- Certain premises not to be licensed.   </catch_line><order_by>280</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A nonquota retail malt beverage package license shall authorize the licensee to: <section prefix="a">Sell malt beverages at retail by the package from the licensed premises only for consumption off the licensed premises only; and </section><section prefix="b">Purchase malt beverages only from a distributor. </section></section><section prefix="2">The holder of a quota retail package license under KRS 243.240 may also obtain a license under this section. </section><section prefix="3">The holder of a nonquota retail malt beverage package license may also hold a NQ4 retail malt beverage drink license. </section><section prefix="4">A nonquota retail malt beverage package license shall not be issued to sell malt beverages at retail for any premises from which gasoline and lubricating oil are sold or from which the servicing and repair of motor vehicles is conducted, unless there is maintained in inventory on the premises for sale at retail not less than five thousand dollars ($5,000) of food, groceries, and related products valued at cost. </section><section prefix="5">The term "food and groceries" means: <section prefix="a">Any food or food product intended for human consumption except alcoholic beverages, tobacco, hot foods, and hot food products prepared for immediate consumption; </section><section prefix="b">Seeds and plants to grow food for personal consumption. </section></section><section prefix="6">The provisions of this section shall not apply to any licensed premises which sells no fuel other than marine fuel. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 71, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 16, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 72, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 313, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 27, effective June 17, 1978. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2554b-200. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42506</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>