<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">A KENTUCKY MODEL PROCUREMENT CODE </unit></structure><section_number>45A.745</section_number><catch_line>Criteria for evaluation of interested firms. </catch_line><order_by>745</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A local public agency shall evaluate those firms submitting statements of interest in a proposed project according to the following criteria: <section prefix="a">Qualifications; </section><section prefix="b">Ability of professional personnel; </section><section prefix="c">Past record and experience; </section><section prefix="d">Performance data on file; </section><section prefix="e">Willingness to meet time and budget requirements; </section><section prefix="f">Location; </section><section prefix="g">Workload; and </section><section prefix="h">Any other factors that the local public agency has set forth in writing, including the reciprocal preference for resident bidders required by KRS 45A.494. </section></section><section prefix="2">The local public agency may then conduct discussions and require interviews with firms deemed to be the most qualified according to the criteria in subsection (1) of this section. Bids for the cost of the proposed project shall not be a factor in the evaluation of firms until negotiations are begun in accordance with KRS 45A.750. </section><section prefix="3">The local public agency shall select, on the basis of the evaluations done in subsections (1) and (2) of this section, at least three (3) firms that are judged to be the most qualified and rank them accordingly. If fewer than three (3) firms are judged to be qualified, then those firms that remain shall be ranked in like manner. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 16, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 249, sec. 4, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22478</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>