<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="194" order_by="194">A CABINET FOR HEALTH AND FAMILY SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>194A.990</section_number><catch_line>Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>990</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person who violates the provisions of KRS 194A.505(1), (2), or (7) shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor, unless the sum total of benefits received in excess of that to which the person was entitled at the time of the offense was committed is valued at or over one hundred dollars ($100), in which case it is a Class D felony. </section><section prefix="2">Any person who violates KRS 194A.505(3) shall be guilty of a Class D felony. </section><section prefix="3">Any person who violates the provisions of KRS 194A.505(4) or (5) shall be guilty of a Class C felony. </section><section prefix="4">Any person who violates the provisions of KRS 194A.505(6) shall be guilty of a Class D felony, unless the purpose of the violation is to obtain ten thousand dollars ($10,000) or more, in which case it shall be a Class C felony. </section><section prefix="5">Any person who violates KRS 194A.505(1) to (6) shall, in addition to any other penalties provided by law, forfeit and pay a civil penalty of payment to the cabinet in the amount of all benefits and payments to which the person was not entitled. </section><section prefix="6">Any provider who violates KRS 194A.505(1) to (6) shall, in addition to any other penalties provided by law, including the penalty set forth in subsection (5) of this section, forfeit and pay civil penalties of: <section prefix="a">Payment to the State Treasury's general revenue fund in an amount equal to three (3) times the amount of the benefits and payments to which the person was not entitled; and </section><section prefix="b">Payment to the State Treasury's general revenue fund of all reasonable expenses that the court determines have been necessarily incurred by the state in the enforcement of this section. </section></section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 28, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6714</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>