<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="214" order_by="214">DISEASES </unit></structure><section_number>214.458</section_number><catch_line>Blood for transfusion -- Labeling -- Data retention -- Destruction. </catch_line><order_by>458</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each unit of blood collected by a blood establishment for transfusion shall be affixed with the United States Food and Drug Administration required label which includes a donor identification number through which the following information can be obtained: <section prefix="a">Date the blood was collected; </section><section prefix="b">Name of blood establishment; </section><section prefix="c">Nonidentifying code representing the name of the blood donor; </section><section prefix="d">A blood establishment serial number for the blood; </section><section prefix="e">The date of laboratory testing of the blood; </section><section prefix="f">The name of the person and laboratory testing the blood; </section><section prefix="g">The laboratory test results. </section></section><section prefix="2">Each unit of blood received by a blood establishment or health facility within the Commonwealth from an out-of-state blood establishment shall contain a label in accordance with the provisions of subsection (1) of this section and the blood establishment or health facility shall either test the blood in accordance with the requirements for blood establishments within the Commonwealth under the provisions of KRS 214.452(2) or may accept documented evidence of the test results as are required under subsection (1) of this section for blood collected within the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="3">Each laboratory testing blood for transfusion shall maintain for ten (10) years from the date of testing, and each blood establishment shall maintain for ten (10) years from the date of collection, a list containing the information set forth in subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="4">No blood may be transfused into any patient in any health facility or health service or by any health care provider unless the unit of blood has affixed to it the label as required under this section and the blood has tested negative for the human immunodeficiency virus or any causative agent of AIDS, or any blood-borne communicable disease as provided under KRS 214.452. When a unit of blood is transfused, a label containing the donor identification number required under this section shall be removed from the unit and affixed to the patient's medical chart or the blood donor identification number for the unit of blood shall be recorded in the patient's medical chart. </section><section prefix="5">Any unit of blood not containing the label required under this section shall be destroyed by the health facility, health service, or health care provider. </section><section prefix="6">Any unit of blood testing confirmatory positive for an agent of a blood-borne communicable disease and in the possession of a health facility, health service, or health care provider may be donated to educational or scientific research institutions for the purpose of scientific research only and not for transfusion. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 325, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8825</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>