<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.430</section_number><catch_line>Exemption of nonresidents. </catch_line><order_by>430</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided in subsection (2) of this section, a person over the age of sixteen (16) who is a United States citizen and who is not a resident of Kentucky may drive in Kentucky for a period of time not to exceed one (1) year from the date the person enters Kentucky if: <section prefix="a">The person possesses a valid license issued by the person's home state; </section><section prefix="b">The person has the license in his or her immediate possession at all times when operating a vehicle on the highways; and </section><section prefix="c">The person's home state accords similar privileges to licensed residents of Kentucky. </section></section><section prefix="2">A person who is a United States citizen but who is not a resident of Kentucky who is enrolled as a full-time or part-time student at a university, college, or technical college located in Kentucky may drive in Kentucky on a valid license issued by the person's state of domicile, and shall not be required to obtain a Kentucky operator's license under this chapter if the person has a student identification card from a university, college, or technical college located in Kentucky in his or her immediate possession at all times when driving in Kentucky. </section><section prefix="3">A person over the age of sixteen (16) who is not a United States citizen and who is legally visiting this country for less than one (1) year may drive in Kentucky on a valid domestic license issued by the person's country of domicile and shall not be required to obtain a Kentucky driver's license. </section><section prefix="4">A person over the age of sixteen (16) who is not a United States citizen, who has not been granted status as a permanent resident of the United States, but is a resident of Kentucky, shall be issued a Kentucky operator's license if the person complies with the requirements of KRS 186.412. Except as provided in this subsection, an operator's license issued to a person who is not a United States citizen, who has not been granted status as a permanent resident of the United States, and who is not a special status individual but is a Kentucky resident, shall be valid for a period equal to the length of time the person's documentation from the United States Department of Justice, Immigration and Naturalization Service is issued, or four (4) years, whichever time period is shorter. An initial or renewal operator's license shall be valid for a period of two (2) years if the person is not a special status individual and the person's documentation issued by the United States Department of Justice, Immigration and Naturalization Service, is issued for an indefinite period of time and does not have an expiration date. The fee shall be the same as for a regular operator's license. The cabinet may at any time refuse or discontinue the exemptions authorized in this section for any grounds and may deny, cancel, suspend, or revoke an instruction permit or operator's license issued under this chapter. </section><section prefix="5">A person whose operator's license or privilege to operate a motor vehicle, motorcycle, or moped in this state has been denied, withdrawn, canceled, suspended, or revoked as provided in KRS 186.400 to 186.640 shall not operate a motor vehicle, motorcycle, or moped in this state under a license, permit, or registration certificate issued by any other jurisdiction during the period of denial, withdrawal, cancellation, suspension, or revocation. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 264, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 198, sec. 6, effective October 1, 1996. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 127, sec. 2. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739m-36. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6054</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>