<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="335" order_by="335">SOCIAL WORKERS AND PROFESSIONAL COUNSELORS </unit></structure><section_number>335.332</section_number><catch_line>Application for marriage and family therapist associate permit -- Qualifying experience for licensure -- Fees. </catch_line><order_by>332</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person who fills all of the requirements of KRS 335.330 shall apply to the board for a marriage and family therapist associate permit in order to practice and earn the experience required for license application. </section><section prefix="2">A marriage and family therapy associate shall engage in the practice of marriage and family therapy while receiving qualifying experience by contracting, in writing, with an approved supervisor, as defined by the board in administrative regulations, who shall assume responsibility for and supervise the marriage and family therapy associate's practice as directed by the board by promulgation of administrative regulations. No marriage and family therapy associate shall enter into a practice of marriage and family therapy until this contract has been approved by the board, and the marriage and family therapy associate shall cease the practice of marriage and family therapy immediately upon termination of the contract. At the termination of the contract, the marriage and family therapy associate shall apply for licensure as a marriage and family therapist or request an extension of the contract from the board. </section><section prefix="3">The fees and all other requirements for a marriage and family therapist associate permit shall be established by the board by promulgation of administrative regulations. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 594, sec. 9, effective January 1, 1999. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 1999 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31946</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>