<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXII" order_by="22">LEVEES, DRAINAGE, AND RECLAMATION OF LANDS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="268" order_by="268">DRAINAGE AND RECLAMATION ACT OF 1918 </unit></structure><section_number>268.210</section_number><catch_line>Compensation of officers and employees -- Selection of treasurer. </catch_line><order_by>210</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Attorneys selected by the petitioners to prepare and file ex parte petitions for the establishment of any district shall faithfully perform the duties of attorney in such proceedings, aid in the preparation of all reports of the viewers, and do any other work necessary until judgment is rendered on the exceptions to the viewers' preliminary report, establishing or refusing to establish the district, at which time their duties shall cease. If the district is established the court organizing it shall allow the attorney representing the petitioners a reasonable fee for the service actually rendered, to be taxed as a part of the cost of the proceeding, and paid by the board out of the funds belonging to the district when funds come into their hands. </section><section prefix="2">The compensation of the engineer who is a member of the board of viewers shall be fixed by the fiscal court at or before the time of his appointment, by order entered of record. The other viewers and the members of the board of appraisers shall be paid five dollars ($5) per day for the time actually engaged in performing their duties. Rodmen, chain carriers and other laborers employed in the improvement shall receive three dollars ($3) per day for their services. </section><section prefix="3">The secretary of the board shall receive three dollars ($3) per day for attending the meetings of the board and ten cents ($0.10) per one hundred (100) words for matter required to be written or recorded by him. </section><section prefix="4">The treasurer shall receive not more than one percent (1%) for receiving and disbursing funds under the control of the board. If any bank or any qualified person will execute proper bond and serve as treasurer without remuneration or will pay the district a fee for being allowed to serve as treasurer with the privilege of selecting the depository of the funds, that bank or person may be appointed treasurer within the discretion of the board. The board shall receive bids or terms from all the banks of the city where its office is located that desire to act as treasurer, and select the bank or person that will best serve the interest of the district. </section><section prefix="5">The board, except where otherwise provided, shall by resolution at the time of employing or appointing any person to render services, provide for reasonable compensation for the work done and necessary expenses. </section></text><history>Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 234, effective January 2, 1978. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2380b-40. </history><metadata><effective>January 2, 1978</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12944</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>