<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="36" order_by="36">DEPARTMENT OF MILITARY AFFAIRS </unit></structure><section_number>36.088Morale,</section_number><catch_line>welfare, and recreation facilities -- Nonappropriated fund instrumentality -- Administrative regulations -- Use of facilities and proceeds derived therefrom. </catch_line><order_by>088Morale,</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="a">"Morale, welfare, and recreation facility" means any post exchange, canteen, barber shop, fitness center, snack bar, transient housing, billeting operation, daycare, laundry, or similar facility, the purpose of which is to enhance the morale and welfare of military personnel; </section><section prefix="b">"Nonappropriated fund employee" means an employee of a nonappropriated fund instrumentality who is not an employee of the federal government or the Commonwealth of Kentucky; and </section><section prefix="c">"Nonappropriated fund instrumentality" means an enterprise operated exclusively with funds derived from sales or user fees, which receives no legislative appropriations for its operations. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">The adjutant general is authorized to establish morale, welfare, and recreation facilities within the state as in his or her judgment may be necessary and proper for military purposes. </section><section prefix="b">Morale, welfare, and recreation facilities may be established at any property under the control of the Department of Military Affairs. </section><section prefix="c">As used in this subsection, "property under the control of the Department of Military Affairs" means any property on the facility installations stationing plan as maintained by the construction and facilities manager for the Kentucky National Guard, and includes all armories, training areas, ranges, and other facilities leased, licensed, or owned by the Department of Military Affairs. </section></section><section prefix="3">Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, the adjutant general is authorized to establish a nonappropriated fund instrumentality for the purpose of operating the morale, welfare, and recreation facilities. </section><section prefix="4">A nonappropriated fund instrumentality established under this section may: <section prefix="a">Contract for goods and services; </section><section prefix="b">Hire nonappropriated fund employees under terms and conditions as it may negotiate, subject only to applicable state and federal labor laws; </section><section prefix="c">Establish a system of bookkeeping, accounting, and auditing procedures for the proper handling of funds derived from its operations; and </section><section prefix="d">Perform any other action necessary to establish a board, corporation, or other entity for the purpose of operating the morale, welfare, and recreation facilities. </section></section><section prefix="5">A nonappropriated fund instrumentality established under this section is solely responsible for its operations. No debt of the nonappropriated fund instrumentality is a debt of the Commonwealth. An action of the nonappropriated fund instrumentality is not an action of the Commonwealth, and shall not obligate the Commonwealth in any manner. </section><section prefix="6">The adjutant general may promulgate administrative regulations for the operation of morale, welfare, and recreation facilities and any nonappropriated fund instrumentality established under this section. </section><section prefix="7">All proceeds derived from the operation of the morale, welfare, and recreation facilities within the state shall, after payment of operating expenses, notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, be used exclusively to benefit the morale, welfare, and recreation facilities. </section><section prefix="8">Use of the morale, welfare, and recreation facilities provided for in this section is limited to: <section prefix="a">Current and retired members of the Kentucky National Guard and their eligible dependents; and </section><section prefix="b">Civilian employees of the United States or the Commonwealth of Kentucky working under Department of Military Affairs management or in support of Department of Military Affairs activities. </section></section></text><history> Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 75, sec. 1, effective March 30, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> March 30, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44025</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>