<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="41" order_by="41">DEPARTMENT OF THE TREASURY </unit></structure><section_number>41.165</section_number><catch_line>Wage payment by electronic transfer of funds -- Request forms. </catch_line><order_by>165</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding the provisions of KRS 337.010 through 337.070 and 41.160, the Treasurer shall pay, by electronic fund transfer, the wages of any state employee who makes a prior written request to the employing state agency to be paid by electronic fund transfer. The Treasurer may refuse to comply with the request of an employee if the financial institution designated by the employee does not have the capability of receiving electronic transfers of funds. </section><section prefix="2">The Personnel Cabinet shall provide forms on which to request wage payments by electronic transfer of funds. The Personnel Cabinet may, by regulations promulgated pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A, require information on the request forms for wage payment by electronic transfer of funds that sufficiently identifies the employee and the designated financial institution of the employee. </section><section prefix="3">Any state agencies which employ persons who have exercised the option authorized by subsection (1) of this section shall retain the forms described in subsection (2) of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 154, sec. 60, effective July 15, 1998 -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 252, sec. 1, effective July 1, 1983. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/98).  This section was amended by 1998 Ky. Acts chs. 118 and 154 which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together.  (10/5/90).  Pursuant to KRS 7.136(1), KRS Chapter 13A has been substituted for the prior reference to KRS Chapter 13 in this statute. The sections in KRS Chapter 13 were repealed by 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 417, รยง 36 and KRS Chapter 13A was created in that same chapter of the 1984 Ky. Acts. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21900</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>