<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="403" order_by="403">DISSOLUTION OF MARRIAGE -- CHILD CUSTODY </unit></structure><section_number>403.300</section_number><catch_line>Investigation: court may order in custody proceedings -- Attorney to receive copy. </catch_line><order_by>300</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In contested custody proceedings, and in other custody proceedings if a parent or the child's custodian so requests, the court may order an investigation and report concerning custodial arrangements for the child. The investigation and report may be made by the friend of the court or such other agency as the court may select.  </section><section prefix="2">In preparing his report concerning a child, the investigator may consult any person who may have information about the child and his potential custodial arrangements. Upon order of the court, the investigator may refer the child to professional personnel for diagnosis. The investigator may consult with and obtain information from medical, psychiatric, or other expert persons who have served the child in the past without obtaining the consent of the parent or the child's custodian; but the child's consent must be obtained if he has reached the age of 16, unless the court finds that he lacks mental capacity to consent. If the requirements of subsection (3) are fulfilled, the investigator's report may be received in evidence at the hearing.  </section><section prefix="3">The clerk shall mail the investigator's report to counsel and to any party not represented by counsel at least 10 days prior to the hearing. The investigator shall make available to counsel and to any party not represented by counsel the investigator's file of underlying data, and reports, complete texts of diagnostic reports made to the investigator pursuant to the provisions of subsection (2), and the names and addresses of all persons whom the investigator has consulted. Any party to the proceeding may call the investigator and any person whom he has consulted for cross-examination. A party may not waive his right of cross-examination prior to the hearing.  </section></text><history>Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 20. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1467</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>