<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.345</section_number><catch_line>Prohibitions against driving on left side of roadway. </catch_line><order_by>345</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No vehicle shall be driven on the left side of the roadway under the following conditions: <section prefix="a">When approaching or upon the crest of a grade or a curve in the highway where the operator's view is obstructed within such distance as to create a hazard in the event another vehicle might approach from the opposite direction; </section><section prefix="b">When approaching within one hundred (100) feet of or traversing any intersection or railroad grade crossing; </section><section prefix="c">When the view is obstructed upon approaching within one hundred (100) feet of any bridge, viaduct or tunnel. </section></section><section prefix="2">The foregoing limitations shall not apply upon a one (1) way roadway, nor when an obstruction exists making it necessary to drive to the left of the center of the highway; provided, any person so doing shall yield the right-of-way to all vehicles traveling in the proper direction upon the unobstructed portion of the highway within such distance as to constitute an immediate hazard, nor to the operator of a vehicle turning left into or from an alley, private road or driveway. </section></text><history>Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 46, sec. 7, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6376</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>