<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="I" order_by="1">SOVEREIGNTY AND JURISDICTION OF THE COMMONWEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="1" order_by="1">BOUNDARIES </unit></structure><section_number>1.200</section_number><catch_line>Boundary with Ohio, Indiana, and Illinois. </catch_line><order_by>200</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The boundary with Indiana begins at the point on the Ohio River common to the boundary lines for the States of Ohio, Indiana, and the Commonwealth of Kentucky, thence southwesterly, along the boundary line common to the States of Indiana and Kentucky, the boundary line being a series of straight lines between sequentially numbered geodetic points, 1927 North American Datum, as fixed by the Supreme Court of the United States in Kentucky v. Indiana, No. 81, Original, decided November 4, 1985, thence to the point on the Ohio River common to the boundary lines for the States of Indiana, Illinois, and the Commonwealth of Kentucky as described in the case cited above. </section><section prefix="2">The boundary with Ohio begins at the point on the Ohio River common to the boundary lines for the States of Ohio, West Virginia, and the Commonwealth of Kentucky, thence generally northwesterly, northerly, and westerly along the boundary line common to the States of Ohio and Kentucky, the boundary line being a series of straight lines between sequentially numbered geodetic points, 1927 North American Datum, as fixed by the Supreme Court of the United States in Ohio v. Kentucky, No. 27, Original, decided April 15, 1985, thence to the point on the Ohio River common to the boundary lines for the States of Ohio, Indiana, and the Commonwealth of Kentucky as described in the case cited above. </section><section prefix="3">The boundary with Illinois is the low water mark on the northern side of the Ohio River, beginning with the point on the Ohio River common to the boundary lines for the States of Indiana, Illinois, and the Commonwealth of Kentucky, thence due west and downstream with the low water mark on the northern side of the Ohio River, and into the Mississippi River, intersecting a line drawn through the center of the Mississippi. </section></text><history>Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 272, secs. 1 and 3, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>