<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="367" order_by="367">CONSUMER PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>367.97514</section_number><catch_line>Processing procedures and restrictions. </catch_line><order_by>97514</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The simultaneous cremation of the remains of more than one (1) individual within the same cremation chamber is specifically declared unlawful. The fact that incidental and unavoidable residue remains in the cremation chamber or other equipment or any container used in a prior cremation is not a violation of this section. </section><section prefix="2">No human remains delivered to a crematory shall be removed from the cremation container, and the cremation container shall be cremated with the human remains. The identification from the outside of the cremation container shall be removed and placed near the cremation chamber control panel where it shall remain in place until the cremation process is complete. </section><section prefix="3">A body shall not be cremated with a pacemaker or other potentially hazardous implant, including any toxic or explosive-type sealed implants, in place. If the authorizing agent is the decedent, then the next class of authorizing agent in the order set forth in KRS 367.97501(1) shall be responsible for disclosing the existence of any pacemaker or other hazardous implants to the crematory authority. </section><section prefix="4">No crematory authority or any person employed by or acting on behalf of a crematory authority shall remove or possess dental gold or dental silver from any human remains. The fact that there is incidental and unavoidable dental gold or dental silver remains in the cremation chamber, in other equipment, or in any container used in a prior cremation is not a violation of this section. </section><section prefix="5">The crematory or crematorium shall be secure from access by unauthorized persons. </section><section prefix="6">The crematory retort operator shall have at least forty eight (48) hours of on the job training supervised by the crematory operator, with verification of this training having been filed with the Attorney General. </section></text><history> Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 140, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35140</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>