<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6">THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY </unit></structure><section_number>6.656</section_number><catch_line>Chair and vice chair -- Meetings -- Compensation of members. </catch_line><order_by>656</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The chair and the vice chair of the commission shall be elected by a majority vote of the members of the commission. The chair and the vice chair shall serve terms of one (1) year and may be reelected. The chair shall preside at meetings of the commission. The vice chair shall preside in the absence or disability of the chair. </section><section prefix="2">The commission shall meet within ninety (90) days of February 18, 1993. The time and place of the meeting shall be determined by the chair. Thereafter, the commission shall meet at such times deemed necessary at the call of the chair or a majority of its members. A quorum shall consist of five (5) or more members. An affirmative vote of five (5) or more members shall be necessary for commission action. </section><section prefix="3">A member of the commission shall receive one hundred dollars ($100) per day and reimbursement for actual and necessary expenses incurred in the performance of his official duties as a member of the commission for meeting days and for a maximum of two (2) nonmeeting days per month devoted to commission-related work. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 493, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1993 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 43, effective September 16, 1993. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=346</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>