<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="367" order_by="367">CONSUMER PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>367.982</section_number><catch_line>Advertisement for rental-purchase agreement. </catch_line><order_by>982</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If an advertisement for a rental-purchase agreement refers to or states the amount of any payment or the right to acquire ownership for any specific item, the advertisement also shall state clearly and conspicuously the following items, as applicable: <section prefix="a">That the transaction advertised is a rental-purchase agreement; </section><section prefix="b">The total of payments necessary to acquire ownership; and </section><section prefix="c">That the consumer acquires no ownership rights if the total amount necessary to acquire ownership is not paid. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any owner or personnel of any medium in which an advertisement appears or through which it is disseminated shall not be liable under this section. </section><section prefix="3">Subsection (1) of this section shall not apply to an advertisement: <section prefix="a">Which does not refer to a specific item of merchandise; </section><section prefix="b">Which does not refer to or state the amount of any payment; or </section><section prefix="c">Which is published in the yellow pages of a telephone directory or any similar directory of business. </section></section><section prefix="4">With respect to matters specifically governed by the Federal Consumer Credit Protection Act, compliance with that act shall satisfy the requirements of this section. </section></text><history>Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 196, sec. 7, effective July 13, 1990; and ch. 304, sec. 7, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><lrc-note> (7/13/90).  This section was created by two separate 1990 Acts which are identical and have therefore been compiled together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35154</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>