<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">A KENTUCKY MODEL PROCUREMENT CODE </unit></structure><section_number>45A.225</section_number><catch_line>Definitions and applicability. </catch_line><order_by>225</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For purposes of KRS 45A.225 to 45A.290, court means the court of this Commonwealth which would have original jurisdiction over the action if it were between private citizens of this Commonwealth; and in the event of an appeal from such a court, the court which would have jurisdiction over such an appeal if the action were between private citizens of this Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="2">KRS 45A.225 to 45A.290 apply only to each contract solicited or entered into after January 1, 1979. </section></text><history>Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 45, effective January 1, 1979. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 1979 </effective><lrc-note> (10/19/2004). 2004 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 2, provides, "Notwithstanding KRS 18A.225, 45A.022, 45A.080, 45A.085, 45A.090, 45A.225 to 45A.290, or any other provision of KRS Chapter 45A to the contrary, retroactive to August 12, 2004, the Finance and Administration Cabinet shall implement the provisions of this Act by amending the previously negotiated contracts for public employee health insurance. The secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet shall provide an actuarial certification that the self-insured contract amounts are actuarially sound. Any contracts entered into or modified pursuant to this section shall be forwarded to the Legislative Research Commission." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22375</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>