<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17B-011</section_number><catch_line>Third-party administrator to administer Kentucky Access -- Selection and duties -- Reimbursement for expenses. </catch_line><order_by>17B-011</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The department shall select a third-party administrator, through the state competitive bidding process, to administer Kentucky Access. The third-party administrator shall be an administrator licensed by the department. The department shall consider criteria in selecting a third-party administrator that shall include, but not be limited to, the following: <section prefix="a">A third-party administrator’s proven ability to demonstrate performance of the operations of an insurer to include the following: enrollee enrollment, eligibility determination, provider enrollment and credentialing, utilization management, quality improvement, drug utilization review, premium billing and collection, claims payment, and data reporting; </section><section prefix="b">The total cost to administer Kentucky Access; </section><section prefix="c">A third-party administrator’s proven ability to demonstrate that Kentucky Access shall be administered in a cost-efficient manner; </section><section prefix="d">A third-party administrator’s proven ability to demonstrate experience in two (2) or more states administering a risk pool for a minimum of a three (3) year period; and </section><section prefix="e">A third-party administrator’s financial condition and stability. </section></section><section prefix="2">The department may contract with the third-party administrator for a period of four (4) years with an option for a two (2) year extension as approved by the department on a year-by-year contract basis. At least one (1) year prior to the expiration of the third-party administrator’s contract, the department may solicit third-party administrators, including the current third-party administrator, to submit bids to serve as the third-party administrator for the succeeding four (4) year period. </section><section prefix="3">In addition to any duties and obligations set forth in the contract with the third-party administrator, the third-party administrator shall: <section prefix="a">Develop and establish policies and procedures for enrollee enrollment, eligibility determination, provider enrollment and credentialing, utilization management, case management, disease management, quality improvement, drug utilization review, premium billing and collection, data reporting, and other responsibilities determined by the department; </section><section prefix="b">Develop and establish policies and procedures for paying the agent referral fee under KRS 304.17B-001 to 304.17B-031; </section><section prefix="c">Develop and establish policies and procedures to ensure timely and efficient payment of claims to include, but not limited to, the following: <section prefix="1">Develop and provide a claims billing manual to health care providers enrolled in Kentucky Access that includes information relating to the proper billing of a claim and the types of claim forms to use; </section><section prefix="2">Payment of all claims in accordance with the provisions of this chapter and the administrative regulations promulgated thereunder; and </section><section prefix="3">Notification to an enrollee through an explanation of benefits if a claim is denied or if there is enrollee financial responsibility of a paid claim for deductible or coinsurance amounts; </section></section><section prefix="d">Issue denial letters under KRS 304.17A-540 for denial of preauthorization and precertification requests for medical necessity and medical appropriateness determinations; </section><section prefix="e">Submit information to the department under KRS 304.17A-330; </section><section prefix="f">Submit reports to the department regarding the operation and financial condition of Kentucky Access. The frequency, content, and form of the reports shall be determined by the department; </section><section prefix="g">Submit an annual report to the department three (3) months after the end of each calendar year. The annual report shall include: <section prefix="1">Earned premium; </section><section prefix="2">Administrative expenses; </section><section prefix="3">Incurred losses for the year; </section><section prefix="4">Paid losses for the year; </section><section prefix="5">Number of enrollees enrolled in Kentucky Access by category of eligibility; and </section><section prefix="6">Any other information requested by the department; and </section></section><section prefix="h">Be subject to examination by the department under Subtitles 2 and 3 of this chapter. </section></section><section prefix="4">The third-party administrator shall be paid for necessary and reasonable expenses, as provided in the contract between the department and the third-party administrator. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1278, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 476, sec. 6, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29390</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>