<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="150" order_by="150">FISH AND WILDLIFE RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>150.660</section_number><catch_line>Establishment of pay lakes, authority of commissioner concerning -- Stocking requirement -- Permits -- Revocation of license. </catch_line><order_by>660</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person may establish a pay lake subject to the approval of the commissioner of the Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources, who shall have the authority to approve or reject the establishment of pay lakes and issue to the owners or lessees of lakes a license for their operation. All pay lakes shall be stocked at least twice per calendar year with not less than five hundred (500) pounds of adult fish per surface acre of water. </section><section prefix="2">When a pay lake is licensed by the department, the commissioner shall issue to the licensee, consecutively numbered permits to be issued, without cost, to pay lake patrons. The permits shall only be valid for fishing any licensed pay lake within the state and shall be valid for one (1) year beginning January 1. </section><section prefix="3">No person, except those exempted elsewhere in this chapter, shall fish in a licensed pay lake without possessing a valid special pay lake permit or a valid statewide fishing license. No owner or operator of a licensed pay lake shall allow any patron to fish who is not properly licensed or permitted. </section><section prefix="4">Any pay lake licensee that fails to comply with the laws or regulations governing the operation of a pay lake may have his operator's license revoked by the commissioner. </section></text><history> Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 353, sec. 9, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 365, sec. 16, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 93, sec. 2, effective May 18, 1956. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2055</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>