<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="403" order_by="403">DISSOLUTION OF MARRIAGE -- CHILD CUSTODY </unit></structure><section_number>403.751</section_number><catch_line>Entry of summons or order of protection issued pursuant to KRS403.715 to 403.785 into Law Information Network of Kentucky.  </catch_line><order_by>751</order_by><text>(1)All forms, affidavits, and orders of protection issued or filed pursuant to KRS403.715 to 403.785 which require entry into the Law Information Network ofKentucky shall be entered on forms prescribed by the Administrative Office ofthe Courts after consultation with the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet. If theprovisions of an order of protection are contained in an order which is narrativein nature, the prescribed form shall be used in addition to the narrative order.(2)The circuit clerk, in cooperation with the court, shall cause a copy of eachsummons or order issued pursuant to KRS 403.715 to 403.785, or foreignprotective order, fully completed and authenticated pursuant to KRS 403.715 to403.785, to be forwarded, by the most expedient means reasonably availableand within twenty-four (24) hours following its filing with the clerk, to theappropriate agency designated for entry of orders of protection into the LawInformation Network of Kentucky and to the agency assigned service. Anyorder or court record superseding, modifying, or otherwise affecting the statusof an earlier summons or order shall likewise be forwarded by the circuit clerkto the appropriate Law Information Network of Kentucky entering agency andto the agency assigned service, if service is required. The clerk and the courtshall comply with all provisions and guidelines of the Law Information Networkof Kentucky for entry of the records.(3)Each agency designated for entry of summonses and orders issued pursuantto KRS 403.715 to 403.785, or foreign protective orders authenticated pursuantto this chapter, into the Law Information Network of Kentucky shall, consistentwith the provisions and guidelines of the Law Information Network of Kentucky,enter the records immediately upon receipt of copies forwarded to the agencyin accordance with subsection (2) of this section.</text><history>Repealed and reenacted 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 9, effective January1, 2016. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1996.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:32</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44757</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>