<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="275" order_by="275">LIMITED LIABILITY COMPANIES </unit></structure><section_number>275.350</section_number><catch_line>Approval of proposed merger -- No right of dissent. </catch_line><order_by>350</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Unless otherwise provided in a written operating agreement, a limited liability company that is a party to a proposed merger shall approve the plan of merger in KRS 275.355 by a majority-in-interest of the members. </section><section prefix="2">Each business entity that is a party to a proposed merger shall approve the plan of merger in the manner and by the vote required by the laws applicable to the business entity. </section><section prefix="3">Each business entity that is a party to the merger shall have the rights to abandon the merger as provided for in the plan of merger or in the laws applicable to the business entity. </section><section prefix="4">Unless otherwise provided in the articles of organization, a written operating agreement, or a written agreement and plan of merger, no member of a limited liability company shall have the right to dissent from a merger. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 123, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 123, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 341, sec. 40, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 389, sec. 70, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 183, provides, "The specific textual provisions of Sections 1 to 178 of this Act which reflect amendments made to those sections by 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137 shall be deemed effective as of June 26, 2007, and those provisions are hereby made expressly retroactive to that date, with the remainder of the text of those sections being unaffected by the provisions of this section." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13900</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>