<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="260" order_by="260">MARKETING OF AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS </unit></structure><section_number>260.664</section_number><catch_line>Duties of commission. </catch_line><order_by>664</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Subject to the availability of funds, the commission shall: <section prefix="a">Counsel with the Commissioner of Agriculture on matters pertaining to dairy production and the marketing and distribution of raw milk and Kentucky dairy products; </section><section prefix="b">Employ the appropriate experts, professionals, consultants, or others to assist members in carrying out duties of the commission; </section><section prefix="c">Undertake the research needed to determine how other states support their dairy farmers and dairy industry; </section><section prefix="d">Support investigations, studies, and scientific research to eliminate and alleviate specific problems affecting the dairy industry in the state; </section><section prefix="e">Participate in studies and investigations of problems particular to milk producers and milk processors in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="f">Collect information to determine the actual cost of transporting milk used in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="g">Coordinate with the Cabinet for Health and Family Services to increase awareness at the consumer level of where dairy products are produced; </section><section prefix="h">Coordinate with the Cabinet for Economic Development to explore economic incentives that would help sustain Kentucky's dairy industry; and </section><section prefix="i">Recommend a program of minimum milk pricing protection for dairy farmers for consideration by the General Assembly, if the federal milk marketing order system is abolished. </section></section><section prefix="2">In addition to the responsibilities set out in subsection (1) of this section, the commission also shall: <section prefix="a">Subject to the availability of funds, create a plan to assist Kentucky dairy farmers that would be equitable to all parties in the state dairy industry. The plan should examine and offer recommendations to improve, streamline, and enhance all aspects of the dairy production and distribution system in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="b">Submit the proposed plan to the Governor, the Commissioner of Agriculture, and the Legislative Research Commission for their review; </section><section prefix="c">Publicize the plan in a way to allow individuals or entities the opportunity to offer comments; </section><section prefix="d">Promulgate administrative regulations necessary to carry out the plan, once reviewed and approved by the Governor and the Commissioner of Agriculture, and finalized by the commission; and </section><section prefix="e">Monitor the progress of the plan and report on the progress annually to the Governor, the Commissioner of Agriculture, and the Legislative Research Commission. </section></section><section prefix="3">The Kentucky Milk Commission established under KRS 260.662 shall have no authority to promulgate administrative regulations to establish pricing on milk or milk products. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 140, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 67, sec. 5, effective June 25, 2009. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12611</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>