<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="342" order_by="342">WORKERS' COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>342.792</section_number><catch_line>Consideration, reopening, and filing of claims of miners who were last exposed to hazards on certain dates -- Benefits -- Administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>792</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The claim of any miner last exposed to the occupational hazards of coal workers' pneumoconiosis between December 12, 1996, and July 15, 2002, shall nonetheless be governed by the provisions of KRS 342.732 and notwithstanding the provisions of KRS 342.125 all claims for benefits which were filed for last injurious occupational exposure to coal dust occurring between December 12, 1996, and July 15, 2002, shall be considered pursuant to the provisions of KRS 342.732 and administrative regulations promulgated by the commissioner, and closed claims, except claims dismissed for reasons other than failure to meet medical eligibility standards, may be reopened by the claimant. Income or retraining incentive benefits shall be awarded thereon as if the entitlement standards established by the amendments to KRS 342.732 were effective at the time of last exposure. Any benefits previously granted by an award or settlement shall be credited against any subsequent award or settlement and no interest shall be payable on additional benefits. A previous grant of retraining incentive benefits shall be credited only to the extent that the benefits were actually paid. All income or retraining incentive benefits greater than those which would have been awarded were not these new provisions applicable shall be paid without interest from the Kentucky coal workers' pneumoconiosis fund, the provisions of KRS 342.1242 notwithstanding. </section><section prefix="2">The original claim of any miner last exposed to the occupational hazards of coal workers' pneumoconiosis prior to December 12, 1996, which was subject to a university evaluation pursuant to KRS 342.315 and was dismissed upon a finding that the miner did not prove the presence of coal workers' pneumoconiosis radiographically may be reopened by the claimant notwithstanding the provisions of KRS 342.125, pursuant to administrative regulations adopted by the commissioner. Income benefits may be awarded thereon pursuant to entitlement standards effective as of the date of last exposure, except the income or retraining benefits shall be paid without interest from the Kentucky coal workers' pneumoconiosis fund, the provisions of KRS 342.1242 notwithstanding. </section><section prefix="3">Notwithstanding the provisions of KRS 342.316(4)(a), the coal workers' pneumoconiosis claim of any miner last exposed between December 12, 1996, and July 15, 2002, may be filed with the commissioner on or before December 12, 2003, or within the time frame prescribed by KRS 342.316(4)(a), whichever is longer. All income or retraining incentive benefits greater than those which would have been awarded were not these new provisions applicable shall be paid by the Kentucky coal workers' pneumoconiosis fund without interest, the provisions of KRS 342.1242 notwithstanding. </section><section prefix="4">Administrative regulations promulgated by the commissioner pursuant to subsections (1) and (2) of this section shall provide that chest X-rays previously taken at university medical schools pursuant to KRS 342.315 shall be obtained by the commissioner and forwarded to three (3) randomly selected "B" readers for determination of consensus pursuant to KRS 342.316(3)(b)4.e. The claim shall be assigned to an administrative law judge for determination of whether the claim should be reopened and the award of additional benefits, if any. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1851, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 340, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32556</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>