<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="70" order_by="70">SHERIFFS, CONSTABLES, AND COUNTY POLICE FORCE </unit></structure><section_number>70.045</section_number><catch_line>Special deputies. </catch_line><order_by>045</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The sheriff of a county with a population of ten thousand (10,000) or more may appoint and have sworn in and entered on the county clerk order book one (1) special deputy for each two thousand five hundred (2,500) residents or part thereof in his county, to assist him with general law enforcement and maintenance of public order. The sheriff of a county with a population of less than ten thousand (10,000) may appoint and have sworn in and entered on the county clerk order book one (1) special deputy for each one thousand (1,000) residents or part thereof in his county, to assist him with general law enforcement and maintenance of public order. The population of the county shall be determined by the most recent count or estimate by the Federal Bureau of Census. </section><section prefix="2">The sheriff in each county may appoint and have sworn in, and entered on the county clerk order book, as many special deputies as needed to assist him in the execution of his duties and office in preparation for or during an emergency situation, such as fire, flood, tornado, storm, or other such emergency situations. For purposes of this section only, an emergency situation is a condition which, in the judgment of the sheriff, requires a response immediately necessary for the preservation of public peace, health or safety, utilizing special deputies previously appointed in preparation for the contingency. </section><section prefix="3">The special deputy shall: <section prefix="a">Be appointed and dismissed on the authority of the sheriff; </section><section prefix="b">Not receive any monetary compensation for his time or services; </section><section prefix="c">Serve at the request of the sheriff, unless personal conditions rule otherwise; </section><section prefix="d">Be answerable to and under the supervision of the sheriff, who shall be responsible for the actions of the special deputy; and </section><section prefix="e">Be appointed regardless of race, color, creed, or position. </section></section><section prefix="4">The position of special deputy as created and defined in subsections (1), (2), and (3) is subject to the provisions of this section only. </section></text><history> Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 140, sec. 2, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 158, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 1, effective March 25, 1982. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24190</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>