<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.370</section_number><catch_line>Passing stopped school or church bus prohibited -- Application to properly marked vehicles -- Rebuttable presumption as to identity of violator. </catch_line><order_by>370</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If any school or church bus used in the transportation of children is stopped upon a highway for the purpose of receiving or discharging passengers, with the stop arm and signal lights activated, the operator of a vehicle approaching from any direction shall bring his vehicle to a stop and shall not proceed until the bus has completed receiving or discharging passengers and has been put into motion. The stop requirement provided for in this section shall not apply to vehicles approaching a stopped bus from the opposite direction upon a highway of four (4) or more lanes. </section><section prefix="2">Subsection (1) of this section shall be applicable only when the bus displays the markings and equipment required by Kentucky minimum specifications for school buses. </section><section prefix="3">If any vehicle is witnessed to be in violation of subsection (1) of this section and the identity of the operator is not otherwise apparent, it shall be a rebuttable presumption that the person in whose name the vehicle is registered or leased was the operator of the vehicle at the time of the alleged violation and is subject to the penalties as provided for in KRS 189.990(5). </section></text><history>Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 262, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 443, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 3. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 2. -- Amended 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 96, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739g-46a, 2739g-691. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1988 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6379</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>