<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="353" order_by="353">MINERAL CONSERVATION AND DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>353.745</section_number><catch_line>Location of well's gathering lines to be marked.   </catch_line><order_by>745</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For gathering lines installed across terrain with a slope of greater than twenty degrees (20รยบ), the well operator shall mark the location of the gathering lines with line markers at interval distances not to exceed two hundred fifty (250) feet. </section><section prefix="2">The Division of Oil and Gas shall make available on its Web site maps or other relevant information showing the location of gathering lines, as filed by the well operator, within thirty (30) days of the information being filed. </section><section prefix="3">Prior to the issuance of a permit to drill, the division shall determine whether the proposed well will intersect an active mining area by reviewing the pertinent mine maps filed with the Division of Mine Safety. If the proposed well will intersect with an active mining area, the Division of Oil and Gas shall: <section prefix="a">Determine whether the coal mine permittee has been properly notified pursuant to KRS 353.050; and </section><section prefix="b">Issue the permit to drill on the condition that a directional survey be performed pursuant to KRS 353.739(1). </section></section><section prefix="4">In order to perform the duties under this section, the Division of Oil and Gas shall create and adequately staff the positions required to perform the duties. The division may charge an administrative fee not to exceed fifty dollars ($50) per permit application to perform its duties under this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 87, sec. 38, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1914, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 7, effective June 25, 2009. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44555</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>