<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.748</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of board. </catch_line><order_by>748</order_by><text>The board shall have the following powers, functions, and duties: <section prefix="1">To provide loan guarantees, upon terms and conditions the board may prescribe within the limitations provided by KRS 164.740 to 164.770, and the federal act in respect of loans to eligible borrowers. The board may require additional security, including endorsers it deems necessary and desirable and is not in contravention of the federal act. The purpose of the loans shall be to assist individuals in meeting the expense of their education. </section><section prefix="2">To enter into agreements and undertakings with the secretary as may be required and necessary pursuant to the federal act in order to constitute the authority as a state agency qualified and empowered to insure student loans within the meaning of the federal act and to qualify insured student loans for interest payments, reimbursement, reinsurance, and other benefits available under the federal act to the authority. </section><section prefix="3">To issue loan guarantees in respect of loans made to eligible borrowers by participating lenders, including the authority. No loan guarantee shall be issued, executed, and delivered by the authority unless any insured student loan resulting shall be the subject of agreements pursuant to the federal act by which the insured student loan is made the subject of interest payments, reimbursements, reinsurance, and other benefits to the extent provided by the federal act. </section><section prefix="4">To promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A pertaining to insured student loans, loan guarantees, loans, and work-study payments and the awarding of grants, scholarships, and honorary scholarships, as provided in KRS 164.740 to 164.7891. </section><section prefix="5">To enter into contracts with eligible lenders, approved by the state to lend moneys, upon terms and conditions agreed upon between the authority and the eligible lender, to provide for the administration of student financial assistance programs, including, but not by way of limitation, the authority's program of insured student loans. </section><section prefix="6">To enter into contracts with eligible institutions, upon terms and conditions agreed upon between the authority and the eligible institution, to provide for the administration of student financial assistance programs, including, but not by way of limitation, the authority's program of insured student loans. </section><section prefix="7">To receive funds from any source, public or private, by gift, grant, bequest, loan, or otherwise, either absolutely or in trust, and to expend them, on behalf of the authority and for any of its purposes; and to acquire from any source, public or private, by purchase, lease, gift, bequest, or devise, any property, real, personal, or mixed, absolutely or in trust, and to hold, administer, and dispose of it, on behalf of the authority and for any of its purposes. The authority shall not make its debts payable out of any funds except those of the authority. </section><section prefix="8">To administer federal funds allotted to the state in respect of insured student loans, loan guarantees, loans, work-study, grants, scholarships, administrative costs, and related matters. </section><section prefix="9">To sue and be sued in the name of the authority and to plead and be impleaded, and to purchase, on behalf of members of the board or officers and employees of the authority, liability insurance for individual protection from liability for acts and omissions committed in the course and scope of the individual's employment or service. </section><section prefix="10">To collect from individual borrowers loans made by the authority and insured student loans on which the authority has been compelled to meet its loan guarantee obligations following the inability of the participating lender involved to collect the insured student loans. </section><section prefix="11">To gather information on all loans, scholarships, honorary scholarships, grants, and work-study opportunities available to Kentucky residents attending or planning to attend an eligible institution and to disseminate the information through the methods of mass communication necessary to ensure that Kentucky residents are aware of financial resources available to those attending or desiring to attend an eligible institution. </section><section prefix="12">To request reports from each eligible institution or eligible lender necessary for the effective performance of its duties and to publish the information it deems necessary. </section><section prefix="13">To approve, disapprove, limit, suspend, or terminate the participation of, or take emergency action to withhold authority funds and insured student loans from eligible institutions or eligible lenders in programs administered by the board, subject to the provisions of the federal act and this chapter. </section><section prefix="14">To perform other acts necessary or appropriate to carry out effectively the purposes of the authority as provided by KRS 164.740 to 164.7891 and KRS 164A.010 to 164A.380. </section><section prefix="15">If any conflict exists between KRS 164.740 to 164.770 and the federal act, which conflict would result in a loss by the authority of any federal funds, including, but not by way of limitation, federal funds made available to the authority under the federal act, including interest payments and reimbursement for insured student loans in default, to promulgate regulations and policies consistent with the federal act not in derogation of the Constitution and general laws of the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="16">Except where specifically prohibited by law, to secure data from any other Commonwealth of Kentucky agency or instrumentality or from any other source in furtherance of any purposes of the authority related to any program or function administered by the authority. </section><section prefix="17">To enter into contracts with public or private nonprofit agencies, eligible to hold or insure student loans under the federal act, to provide for the exchange of information, not in contravention of any federal or state law, or the provision of services necessary to the administration of the authority's insured student loan programs. </section><section prefix="18">To enter into contracts with the Kentucky Higher Education Student Loan Corporation, the Kentucky Educational Savings Plan Trust, and the Commonwealth postsecondary education prepaid tuition trust fund as necessary or appropriate to facilitate their common administration, operation, and management, as required pursuant to KRS Chapter 164A. </section><section prefix="19">To act as the board of directors of the Commonwealth postsecondary education prepaid tuition trust fund under KRS 164A.700 to 164A.709. </section><section prefix="20">To conduct, in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B, administrative hearings pertaining to any adverse action by the authority affecting participating institutions and lenders, eligible students, and borrowers of loans made by the authority and insured student loans guaranteed by the authority. Wage garnishment hearings and administrative review procedures pertaining to disputes concerning setoff of federal tax refunds shall be exempt under KRS 13B.020 and shall be conducted in accordance with applicable federal law. In an exempt hearing, the board or a hearing officer designated by the board may issue administrative subpoenas for the attendance of witnesses and the production of documents relevant to the issues in dispute. Compliance with the subpoenas shall be enforceable by a court of competent jurisdiction. </section><section prefix="21">To provide upon termination of the retirement plan authorized by Executive Order 75-964 to active and retired employees of the authority who participated in that plan, health insurance premiums and disability insurance benefits as provided to employees who participate in a state-administered retirement system pursuant to KRS 18A.225 to 18A.229, 61.600, and 61.702. </section><section prefix="22">To delegate to the executive director general supervision and direction over the administrative function of the authority and its employees in carrying out the policies, programs, administrative regulations, and directives of the board. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 2, effective July 1, 2005. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 2, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 180, sec. 7, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 55, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 447, sec. 2, effective April 11, 1994. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 403, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 339, sec. 5, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 135, sec. 4. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 93, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4417</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>