<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="322" order_by="322">PROFESSIONAL ENGINEERS AND LAND SURVEYORS </unit></structure><section_number>322.160</section_number><catch_line>Renewal of license or permit -- Duty of executive director -- No renewal fee for years spent in Armed Forces. </catch_line><order_by>160</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Licenses for individuals and permits for business entities shall be valid for not more than two (2) years from the date of issuance, unless renewed. </section><section prefix="2">The executive director shall notify every licensee and permit holder at least one (1) month in advance of the pending expiration date. <section prefix="a">All license renewals shall be completed on or before June 30 of the year of expiration. </section><section prefix="b">All permit renewals shall be completed on or before December 31 of the year of expiration. </section><section prefix="c">Each licensee or permit holder is responsible for notifying the board of any address change. </section><section prefix="d">The responsibility for the timely renewal of a license or permit rests with the licensee or permit holder. </section></section><section prefix="3">The failure to renew shall not deprive a licensee or permit holder of the right of renewal, but the fee to be paid for the renewal shall be increased ten percent (10%) for each month or fraction of a month that payment of renewal is delayed. Any licensee or permit holder who fails to renew within one (1) year after expiration shall furnish the board with: <section prefix="a">Satisfactory evidence of qualification of continued practice. However, the board may require reexamination; and </section><section prefix="b">Evidence of completion of continuing education hours as required by KRS 322.290. </section></section><section prefix="4">No licensee shall be required to pay renewal fees to the board during the time the licensee is on active duty in the Armed Forces of the United States. <section prefix="a">Any licensee who has previously paid any renewal fee covering a period of time spent on active duty shall, upon filing with the board a copy of his or her discharge, be granted a license renewal without the payment of any fee. </section><section prefix="b">The free renewal shall be for as many license years as the licensee was on active duty and which were covered in whole or in part by the previous payment of a renewal fee. </section><section prefix="c">The continuing education requirement under KRS 322.290 shall be waived for those years the licensee was on active duty. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 163, sec. 9, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 134, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 214, sec. 14, effective January 1, 1999. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 291, sec. 15, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 273, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 313, sec. 10, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 1599e-16. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31435</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>