<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>362.2-406</section_number><catch_line>Management rights of general partner. </catch_line><order_by>2-406</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each general partner has equal rights in the management and conduct of the limited partnership's activities. Except as expressly provided in this subchapter, any matter relating to the activities of the limited partnership may be exclusively decided by the general partner or, if there is more than one (1) general partner, by a majority of the general partners. </section><section prefix="2">The consent of each partner is necessary to: <section prefix="a">Amend the partnership agreement; </section><section prefix="b">Amend the certificate of limited partnership to add or, subject to KRS 362.2-960, delete a statement that the limited partnership is a limited liability limited partnership; or </section><section prefix="c">Sell, lease, exchange, or otherwise dispose of all or substantially all of the limited partnership's property, with or without the good will, other than in the usual and regular course of the limited partnership's activities. </section></section><section prefix="3">A limited partnership shall reimburse a general partner for payments made and indemnify a general partner for liabilities incurred by the general partner in the ordinary course of the activities of the partnership or for the preservation of its activities or property. </section><section prefix="4">A limited partnership shall reimburse a general partner for an advance to the limited partnership beyond the amount of capital the general partner agreed to contribute. </section><section prefix="5">A payment or advance made by a general partner which gives rise to an obligation of the limited partnership under subsection (3) or (4) of this section constitutes a loan to the limited partnership which accrues interest from the date of the payment or advance. </section><section prefix="6">A general partner is not entitled to remuneration for services performed for the partnership. </section></text><history> Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 126, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34588</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>