<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="441" order_by="441">JAILS AND COUNTY PRISONERS </unit></structure><section_number>441.135</section_number><catch_line>Canteen for prisoners -- Books of accounts -- Allowable expenditures -- Jail canteen account balance -- Calculation. </catch_line><order_by>135</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The jailer may maintain a canteen for the benefit of prisoners lodged in the jail and may assign such jail employees and prisoners to operate the canteen as are necessary for efficient operation. </section><section prefix="2">All profits from the canteen shall be used for the benefit and to enhance the well-being of the prisoners. The jailer shall keep books of accounts of all receipts and disbursements from the canteen and shall annually report to the county treasurer on the canteen account. </section><section prefix="3">Allowable expenditures from a canteen account shall include but not be limited to recreational, vocational, and medical purposes. </section><section prefix="4">Except in counties containing an urban-county government or a consolidated local government, in order to ensure adequate, ongoing funding of jail canteen accounts, beginning July 1, 2007, and on the first day of each fiscal year thereafter, the jail canteen account balance shall at least equal the following amounts based on the average daily inmate population of the jail: <section prefix="a">300 prisoners or more ...............................................................................$6,000 </section><section prefix="b">200 to 299 prisoners..................................................................................$4,000 </section><section prefix="c">100 to 199 prisoners..................................................................................$2,000 </section><section prefix="d">99 or fewer prisoners.................................................................................$1,000 </section></section><section prefix="5">For purposes of calculating the amount to be transferred to the jail canteen account, the average daily number of inmates shall be equal to the average daily inmate population of the jail in the immediately preceding fiscal year. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 64, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 147, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 171, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 127, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><former-codification> KRS 441.067. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19318</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>