<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.10-120</section_number><catch_line>Preparation of state strategic plan for economic development. </catch_line><order_by>10-120</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The framework for the strategic plan shall include the following elements: <section prefix="a">Mission statement; </section><section prefix="b">Goals; </section><section prefix="c">Principles; </section><section prefix="d">Strategies and objectives; and </section><section prefix="e">Benchmarks. </section></section><section prefix="2">The goals as specified in KRS 154.1-020 should not be considered static, but dynamic, and therefore shall be reviewed for relevancy at least every four (4) years. </section><section prefix="3">Plan horizon and frequency of updates shall be as follows: <section prefix="a">The planning horizon for the Commonwealth's strategic economic development plan shall be for a period of not less than five (5) nor more than ten (10) years. </section><section prefix="b">The board shall prepare and adopt, pursuant to KRS 154.10-030(6), a strategic economic development plan for Kentucky within one (1) year from July 14, 1992, and shall update the plan every two (2) years thereafter. </section></section><section prefix="4">The strategic economic development planning process shall include the broadest participation of all public and private interests including, but not limited to, members of the General Assembly; state agencies; local, regional, and statewide associations with interest in economic development; and members of the various industrial sectors. </section><section prefix="5">In the preparation and finalization of recommendations contained in the Commonwealth's strategic economic development plan: <section prefix="a">The board shall conduct at least one (1) public hearing with due legal notice given in accordance with KRS Chapter 424; </section><section prefix="b">The board may employ consultants and other experts deemed necessary and appropriate for the purposes of this chapter; and </section><section prefix="c">The board shall work cooperatively with the governing authorities of the Kentucky Infrastructure Authority and the Commonwealth's Federal Community Development Block Grant Program to ensure coordination between projects approved by those bodies and the strategic economic development plan. </section></section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 12, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2609</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>