<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>14A.2-100</section_number><catch_line>Filing duty of Secretary of State.  </catch_line><order_by>2-100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If a document delivered to the office of the Secretary of State for filing satisfies the requirements of this chapter and applicable organic law, the Secretary of State shall file it. </section><section prefix="2">The Secretary of State files a document by recording it as filed as provided in KRS 14A.2-070(1)(a). </section><section prefix="3">After filing a document, the Secretary of State shall deliver to the entity or foreign entity or to the person delivering the document for filing or to another person as identified in writing a copy of the document with an acknowledgment of the time and date of filing. </section><section prefix="4">If the Secretary of State refuses to file a document, the Secretary of State shall return it to the filer within five (5) days after the document was delivered, together with a brief, written explanation of the reason for the refusal. </section><section prefix="5">The Secretary of State's delivery of an acknowledgment of filing, an explanation for the reason a document was not filed, or other communication as to a document filed or delivered for filing may be accomplished electronically. </section><section prefix="6">The Secretary of State's duty to file documents under this section shall be ministerial. The filing or refusal to file a document shall not: <section prefix="a">Affect the validity or invalidity of the document in whole or part; </section><section prefix="b">Relate to the correctness or incorrectness of information contained in the document; or </section><section prefix="c">Create a presumption that the document is valid or invalid or that information contained in the document is correct or incorrect. </section></section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 17, effective January 1, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36536</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>