<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="199" order_by="199">PROTECTIVE SERVICES FOR CHILDREN - ADOPTION </unit></structure><section_number>199.8983Kentucky</section_number><catch_line>Child Care Advisory Council.   </catch_line><order_by>8983Kentucky</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created the Kentucky Child Care Advisory Council to be composed of eighteen (18) members. The members appointed by the Governor shall serve a term of three (3) years. The appointed members of the council shall be geographically and culturally representative of the population of the Commonwealth. For administrative purposes, the council shall be attached to the department. The members shall be as follows: <section prefix="a">The commissioner of the department, or designee; </section><section prefix="b">Four (4) members appointed by the Governor representing child-care center providers licensed pursuant to this chapter; </section><section prefix="c">Two (2) members appointed by the Governor representing family child-care home providers licensed pursuant to this chapter; </section><section prefix="d">Three (3) members appointed by the Governor who are parents, de facto custodians, guardians, or legal custodians of children receiving services from child-care centers or family child-care homes licensed pursuant to this chapter; </section><section prefix="e">Three (3) members appointed by the Governor from the private sector who are knowledgeable about education, health, and development of children; </section><section prefix="f">The director of the Division of Child Care within the department, or designee, as a nonvoting ex officio member; </section><section prefix="g">The commissioner of education, Education and Workforce Development Cabinet, or designee, as a nonvoting ex officio member; </section><section prefix="h">The executive director of the Governor's Office of Early Childhood, or designee, as a nonvoting ex officio member; </section><section prefix="i">The commissioner of the Department for Public Health within the cabinet, or designee, as a nonvoting ex officio member; and </section><section prefix="j">The state fire marshal, Public Protection Cabinet, or designee, as a nonvoting ex officio member; </section></section><section prefix="2">The council shall have two (2) co-chairpersons. One (1) co-chairperson shall be the commissioner of the department, or designee, and one (1) co-chairperson shall be elected by the voting members of the council. </section><section prefix="3">Members shall serve until a successor has been appointed. If a vacancy on the council occurs, the Governor shall appoint a replacement for the remainder of the unexpired term. </section><section prefix="4">Members shall serve without compensation but shall be reimbursed for reasonable and necessary expenses in accordance with state travel expenses and reimbursement administrative regulations. </section><section prefix="5">The council shall meet at least quarterly and at other times upon call of the co-chairpersons. </section><section prefix="6">The council shall advise the cabinet on matters affecting the operations, funding, and licensing of child-care centers and family child-care homes. The council shall provide input and recommendations for ways to improve quality, access, and outcomes. </section><section prefix="7">The council shall make an annual report by December 1 that provides summaries and recommendations to address the availability, affordability, accessibility, and quality of child care in the Commonwealth. A copy of the annual report shall be provided to the secretary, the Governor, the Legislative Research Commission, and the Interim Joint Committee on Health and Welfare. </section></text><history> Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 49, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44416</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>