<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.920</section_number><catch_line>Effects of failure of local government to comply with certain specified statutory provisions. </catch_line><order_by>920</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any local government that fails to submit annually a uniform financial information report to the Department for Local Government shall be ineligible to receive county or municipal road aid moneys in accordance with KRS 177.360 or 177.366. Any local government receiving road aid moneys in accordance with KRS 177.365 to 177.369 or KRS 177.320 and 177.360 that fails to comply with the provisions of KRS 65.900 to 65.925 shall immediately have all road aid payments suspended until the local government submits the uniform financial information report to the Department for Local Government. </section><section prefix="2">If a local government receives payments of money from the Commonwealth and fails to comply with the provisions of KRS 65.900 to 65.925 or KRS 92.280(1), the state local finance officer may notify those agencies making payments to the local government of noncompliance, and those agencies shall immediately suspend delivery of all payments to the local government except those payments made pursuant to KRS Chapter 154 or KRS 42.4588, until the state local finance officer determines that the local government has complied with the requirements of KRS 65.900 to 65.925 or KRS 92.280(1). </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 57, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 4, effective June 26, 2007; and ch. 47, sec. 51, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 38, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 186, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23552</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>