<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="78" order_by="78">COUNTY EMPLOYEES' CIVIL SERVICE AND RETIREMENT </unit></structure><section_number>78.445</section_number><catch_line>Disciplinary action by chief. </catch_line><order_by>445</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any officer or employee may be removed, suspended, laid-off, reduced in grade, or fined by the chief for any cause which will promote the efficiency of the service, but before any such action is taken by the chief against any officer or employee, the chief shall furnish the officer or employee concerned with a written statement of the reasons why the described action is taken. The officer or employee may be reduced, removed, suspended, laid-off or fined from the date when such written statement of reasons is served upon him. Each officer or employee removed, suspended, laid-off, reduced in grade, or fined, shall be allowed a period of ten (10) days within which he may file written answer to the charges and reasons which caused his suspension, removal, reduction or fine, which shall be made a part of the official records of the police department. No trial or examination of witnesses shall be required in any such case except in the discretion of the chief. The chief shall likewise furnish a copy of the written charges and reasons for his action to the board. </section><section prefix="2">Any citizen who makes written charges of misconduct, under oath, concerning the actions of any police officer hereunder shall present the charges to the chief of police, who shall investigate said charges. The chief of police shall determine what action, if any, shall be taken against the officer, subject to the limitations set out in this chapter. The citizen may appeal the determination of the chief of police to the board. </section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 198, sec. 5. -- Created 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 4(1), effective March 4, 1952. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:12</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24716</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>