<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="100" order_by="100">PLANNING AND ZONING </unit></structure><section_number>100.982</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 100.982 to 100.984. </catch_line><order_by>982</order_by><text>As used in KRS 100.982 to 100.984, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Person with a disability" means a person with a physical, emotional, or mental disability, including, but not limited to, an intellectual disability, cerebral palsy, epilepsy, autism, deafness or hard of hearing, sight impairments, and orthopedic impairments, but not including convicted felons or misdemeanants on probation or parole or receiving supervision or rehabilitation services as a result of their prior conviction, or mentally ill persons who have pled guilty but mentally ill to a crime or not guilty by reason of insanity to a crime. "Person with a disability" does not include persons with current, illegal use of alcohol or any controlled substance as regulated under KRS Chapter 218A. </section><section prefix="2">"Residential care facility" means a residence operated and maintained by a sponsoring private or governmental agency to provide services in a homelike setting for persons with disabilities. </section><section prefix="3">"Services" means, but is not limited to, supervision, shelter, protection, rehabilitation, personal development, and attendant care. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 66, sec. 2, effective March 25, 2015. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 10, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 405, sec. 12, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 144, sec. 8, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 91, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> March 25, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:12</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43998</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>