<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="313" order_by="313">DENTISTS AND DENTAL SPECIALISTS </unit></structure><section_number>313.050</section_number><catch_line>Procedures which dentist may delegate to dental auxiliary personnel. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A licensed dentist may delegate to competent dental auxiliary personnel those procedures for which the dentist exercises direct supervision and full responsibility as long as the delegated powers do not include any of the following: <section prefix="a">Those procedures which require professional judgment and skill, such as diagnosis and treatment planning and the cutting of hard or soft tissues or any intraoral procedure which will be used directly in the fabrication of an appliance which, when worn by the patient, would come in direct contact with hard or soft tissue; </section><section prefix="b">Those procedures allocated by this chapter to licensed dental hygienists or registered dental assistants; and </section><section prefix="c">No injectable medication or anesthesia shall be administered by auxiliary personnel unless otherwise authorized by law. </section></section><section prefix="2">A licensed dentist may delegate the taking of radiographs to dental auxiliary personnel who have completed a board-approved course in radiography technique and safety. The course completion certificate shall be maintained by the supervising dentist and be available to the board upon request. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 9, effective July 15, 2010. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2636-3. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30814</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>