<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="121" order_by="121">CAMPAIGN FINANCE REGULATION </unit></structure><section_number>121.160</section_number><catch_line>Campaign treasurers -- Duties. </catch_line><order_by>160</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As part of the filing papers each candidate or slate of candidates shall, on a duplicate form prescribed and furnished by the registry, designate a campaign treasurer to act as their agent at the time and at the office with which they file as a candidate or slate of candidates and until this requirement is met the candidate or slate of candidates shall be listed as their own treasurer and accountable as such. The candidate or slate of candidates may appoint themselves or any registered voter in Kentucky as the campaign treasurer. The office with which the candidate or slate of candidates is required to file shall immediately forward to the registry the duplicate copy of the completed form designating the candidate's or slate's campaign treasurer and shall attach the original to the candidate's or slate's filing papers. The office with which the candidate or slate of candidates files shall promptly notify the registry when a candidate withdraws. </section><section prefix="2">The duties of a campaign treasurer shall be to: <section prefix="a">Designate a depository bank in which the primary campaign account shall be maintained and deposit all contributions in that account; </section><section prefix="b">Keep detailed and exact accounts of: <section prefix="1">Contributions of any amount made by a permanent committee, by name and business address of the permanent committee, the date of the contribution, the amount contributed, and a description of the major business, social, or political interest represented by the permanent committee; </section><section prefix="2">Contributions in excess of one hundred dollars ($100) made to a candidate or slate of candidates for a statewide-elected state office, by the date, name, address, occupation, and employer of each contributor and the spouse of the contributor or, if the contributor or spouse of the contributor is self-employed, the name under which he is doing business, and the amount contributed by each contributor; and </section><section prefix="3">Contributions in excess of one hundred dollars ($100) made to any candidate other than those specified in subparagraph 2., by name, address, age if under legal voting age, date of the contribution, amount of the contribution, and the employer and occupation of each other contributor. If the contributor is self-employed, the name under which he is doing business shall be listed. The occupation listed for the contributor shall be specific. A general classification, such as "businessman", shall be insufficient; </section></section><section prefix="c">Make or authorize all expenditures on behalf of a candidate or slate of candidates. Any expenditure in excess of twenty-five dollars ($25) shall be by check and the treasurer's records shall disclose the name, address, and occupation of every person or firm to whom made, and shall list the date and amount of the expenditure and the treasurer shall keep a receipted bill for each; </section><section prefix="d">Maintain all receipted bills and accounts required by this section for a period of six (6) years from the date he files his last report under KRS 121.180(3)(b)1.; and </section><section prefix="e">Make no payment to any person not directly providing goods or services with the intent to conceal payment to another. </section></section><section prefix="3">A candidate or slate of candidates may remove a campaign treasurer at any time. </section><section prefix="4">In case of the death, resignation, or removal of a campaign treasurer, the candidate or slate of candidates shall within three (3) days after receiving notice thereof by certified mail, appoint a successor and shall file his name and address with the registry. The candidate, or slate shall be accountable as their own campaign treasurer if they fail to meet this filing requirement. </section><section prefix="5">A person may serve as campaign treasurer for more than one (1) candidate or slate of candidates, but all reports shall be made separately for each individual candidate or slate. </section><section prefix="6">The candidate or slate of candidates may pay a campaign treasurer a salary for his services which shall be considered a campaign expense and shall comply with the reporting provisions of KRS 121.180 and administrative regulations promulgated by the registry. </section></text><history>Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 458, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1993 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 58, effective November 3, 1993. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 288, sec. 26, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 341, sec. 44, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 69, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 17, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 1. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 188. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:04</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27866</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>