<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="351" order_by="351">DEPARTMENT FOR NATURAL RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>351.242</section_number><catch_line>Mine safety analysis program -- Responsibility and powers of mine safety specialists.   </catch_line><order_by>242</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created in the department a mine safety analysis program. </section><section prefix="2">Mine safety specialists employed in the department and conducting underground or surface mine safety analysis shall satisfy the applicable requirements established in KRS 351.090. </section><section prefix="3">A primary responsibility of the mine safety specialist is to prevent mine accidents and fatalities by observing and evaluating the work habits of persons involved in the direct production of coal and to contact, advise, and assist these persons in correcting their unsafe or potentially hazardous actions. </section><section prefix="4">Each time a mine safety specialist enters a mine to perform mine safety analysis, he or she shall confer with the foreman as to the conditions of the mine and the work practices of the employees. </section><section prefix="5">The mine safety specialist shall keep mine management, representatives of the employees, and the commissioner informed about all hazardous conditions and all matters which may improve the safety of mines. </section><section prefix="6">The division shall assist the department in assessing the effectiveness of miner training programs. </section><section prefix="7">The commissioner shall at his or her discretion assign mine safety specialists to all mines in the state taking into consideration such factors as the history of accidents at the mine, experience of the workforce, physical condition of the mine, and size of the mine. </section><section prefix="8">The commissioner may coordinate the assignment of mine safety specialists with the appropriate federal authorities to minimize duplication of accident prevention efforts. </section><section prefix="9">The commissioner shall report annually to the General Assembly and to the Governor on the effectiveness of the mine safety specialists in improving mine safety. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 87, sec. 26, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 60, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 480, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 18, effective April 9, 1996. -- Created 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note> (4/9/96).  The action taken with respect to this statute by 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 308 was to have become effective April 8, 1996, under Section 51 of that Act. The Act, however, did not become effective until April 9, 1996, when the Governor's signed copy of the Act was filed with the Secretary of State. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44543</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>