<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="403" order_by="403">DISSOLUTION OF MARRIAGE -- CHILD CUSTODY </unit></structure><section_number>403.735</section_number><catch_line>Hearing on petition for order of protection -- Criteria to assessappropriate relief and sanctions -- Continuance of hearing andemergency protective order.  </catch_line><order_by>735</order_by><text>(1)Prior to or at a hearing on a petition for an order of protection:(a)The court may obtain the respondent's Kentucky criminal and protectiveorder history and utilize that information to assess what relief and whichsanctions may protect against danger to the petitioner or other person forwhom protection is being sought, with the information so obtained beingprovided to the parties in accordance with the Rules of Civil Procedure;and(b)If the petitioner or respondent is a minor, the court shall inquire whetherthe parties attend school in the same school system to assist the court inimposing conditions in the order that have the least disruption in theadministration of education to the parties while providing appropriateprotection to the petitioner.(2)(a)If the adverse party is not present at the hearing ordered pursuant to KRS403.730 and has not been served, a previously issued emergencyprotective order shall remain in place, and the court shall direct theissuance of a new summons for a hearing set not more than fourteen (14)days in the future. If service has not been made on the adverse partybefore that hearing or a subsequent hearing, the emergency protectiveorder shall remain in place, and the court shall continue the hearing andissue a new summons with a new date and time for the hearing to occur,which shall be within fourteen (14) days of the originally scheduled datefor the continued hearing. The court shall repeat the process of continuingthe hearing and reissuing a new summons until the adverse party isserved in advance of the scheduled hearing. If service has not been madeon the respondent at least seventy-two (72) hours prior to the scheduledhearing, the court may continue the hearing no more than fourteen (14)days in the future. In issuing the summons, the court shall simultaneouslytransmit a copy of the summons or notice of its issuance and provisions tothe petitioner.(b)The provisions of this section permitting the continuance of an emergencyprotective order shall be limited to six (6) months from the issuance of theemergency protective order. If the respondent has not been served withinthat period, the order shall be rescinded without prejudice. Prior to theexpiration of the emergency protective order, the court shall providenotice to the petitioner stating that, if the petitioner does not file a newpetition, the order shall be rescinded without prejudice.</text><history>Repealed and reenacted 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 5, effective January1, 2016. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 170, sec. 19, effective July 15, 2010. --Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 14, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended1992 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 5, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1984 Ky. Actsch. 152, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1984.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:32</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44753</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>