<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.507</section_number><catch_line>Exemption from matriculation or tuition fee for deceased veteran's spouse or child under age 26. </catch_line><order_by>507</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The nonremarried spouse, regardless of age, and any child, stepchild, or orphan, under the age of twenty-six (26), of a deceased veteran shall not be required to pay any matriculation or tuition fees upon admission to any state-supported university, junior college, or vocational training institute for a period not in excess of forty-five (45) months in order to obtain a diploma, nor in excess of the lesser number of months required for a certificate of completion, if the deceased parent or spouse: <section prefix="a"><section prefix="1">Served in the Armed Forces of the United States during a national emergency, wars declared by Congress, or actions of the United Nations; or </section><section prefix="2">Died while on active duty in the Armed Forces of the United States regardless of wartime service; or </section><section prefix="3">Died as a result of a service-connected disability acquired while on active duty with the Armed Forces of the United States regardless of wartime service; and </section></section><section prefix="b"><section prefix="1">Was a resident of the Commonwealth of Kentucky at the time of death; or </section><section prefix="2">Was married to a resident of Kentucky at the time of death; and </section><section prefix="3">If discharged, was under honorable conditions. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">In order to obtain the benefits conferred by subsection (1), the parent-child relationship must be shown by birth certificate, adoption papers, marriage certificate, or other documentary evidence. A stepchild must have been a member of the veteran's household at the time of the veteran's death. The spousal relationship must be shown by a marriage certificate or other documentary evidence. The parent's or spouse's service and the cause of death must be evidenced by certification from the records of the Kentucky Department of Military Affairs, the Veterans Administration Records, or the Department of Defense of the United States. In the event one so admitted to a state-supported university, junior college, or vocational training institution under this section shall have obtained a cash scholarship paid or payable to the institution, from whatever source, the amount of the scholarship shall be applied to the credit of the applicant in the payment of incidental expenses of attendance at the institution, and any balance, if the terms of the scholarship permit, shall be returned to the applicant. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 41, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 377, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4306</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>