<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.2715</section_number><catch_line>Annual overweight permit for transporting steel products or materials -- Weight and mileage limitations.   </catch_line><order_by>2715</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In order to promote economic development and retain jobs within this state, subject to the provisions of KRS 189.222, the department may promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A governing the issuance of annual permits for the operation of motor vehicles transporting steel products or steel materials in divisible or nondivisible loads to or from a facility manufacturing products in this state or a facility used for storage of those products, whose gross weight exceeds the limits prescribed by this chapter. In no instance shall the gross weight limits issued pursuant to this section exceed one hundred twenty thousand (120,000) pounds. The movement of the products or materials shall be limited to no more than one hundred fifty (150) miles within the state. </section><section prefix="2">A motor carrier transporting steel products or steel materials in divisible or nondivisible loads to or from a facility manufacturing steel products in this state or a facility used for storage of those products, may apply for an annual overweight permit pursuant to subsection (1) of this section. The permit shall be valid twenty-four (24) hours a day, but shall be limited to movements of steel products or steel materials of not more than one hundred fifty (150) miles within the state. The cost of the annual permit shall be two hundred fifty dollars ($250). </section></text><history>Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 112, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 94, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40543</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>