<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.4595</section_number><catch_line>Exemption from local motor vehicle licenses and fees for disabled veterans or Congressional Medal of Honor, Distinguished Service Cross, Navy Cross, or Air Force Cross recipients -- Extension of legal parking period. </catch_line><order_by>4595</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any other provision of law to the contrary notwithstanding, a city, county, town, or other political subdivision of this state shall not require any license or fee from a disabled veteran, recipient of the Congressional Medal of Honor, or recipient of the Distinguished Service Cross, Navy Cross, or Air Force Cross who has been issued a special military-related license plate under KRS 186.041, for the privilege of operating a motor vehicle upon any street or alley. </section><section prefix="2">When a motor vehicle bearing a special military-related license plate for disabled veterans, recipients of the Congressional Medal of Honor, or recipients of the Distinguished Service Cross, Navy Cross, or Air Force Cross is being operated by or for the benefit of the person, the motor vehicle may be parked for a period of two (2) hours in excess of the legal parking period permitted by local authorities unless a local ordinance or police regulation: <section prefix="a">Prohibits parking on a highway for the purpose of creating a fire lane: </section><section prefix="b">Provides for the accommodation of heavy traffic during morning, afternoon, or evening hours; or </section><section prefix="c">Prohibits parking a motor vehicle in a manner as to clearly be a traffic hazard. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 45, sec. 2, effective June 21, 2001. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 453, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> June 21, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6400</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>