<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.32-070</section_number><catch_line>Nonrefundable tax credit for economic development project by approved company. </catch_line><order_by>32-070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For taxable years beginning after December 31, 2009, an approved company may be eligible for a credit of up to one hundred percent (100%) of the Kentucky income tax imposed under KRS 141.020 or 141.040, and the limited liability entity tax imposed under KRS 141.0401, that would otherwise be owed by the approved company to the Commonwealth for the approved company's taxable year, on the income, Kentucky gross profits, or Kentucky gross receipts of the approved company generated by or arising from the economic development project. </section><section prefix="2">The credit allowed the approved company shall be applied against both the income tax imposed by KRS 141.020 or 141.040, and the limited liability entity tax imposed by KRS 141.0401, with credit ordering as provided in KRS 141.0205, for the taxable year for which the tax return of the approved company is filed, subject to the annual maximum set forth in the tax incentive agreement. Any credit not used in the year in which it was first available may be carried forward to subsequent years, provided that no credit may be carried forward beyond the term of the tax incentive agreement. </section><section prefix="3">The approved company shall not be required to pay estimated tax payments as prescribed in KRS 141.042 on the Kentucky taxable income, Kentucky gross receipts, or Kentucky gross profits generated by or arising from the eligible project. </section><section prefix="4">The credit provided by this section shall be determined as provided in KRS 141.415. </section><section prefix="5">The amount of incentives allowed in any year shall not exceed the lesser of the tax liability of the approved company related to the economic development project for that year or the annual maximum approved costs set forth in the tax incentive agreement. The incentives shall be allowed for each fiscal year of the approved company during the term of the tax incentive agreement for which a tax return is filed by the approved company. </section></text><history> Created 2009 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 16, effective June 26, 2009. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2862</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>