<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="278" order_by="278">PUBLIC SERVICE COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>278.504</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 278.505 to 278.507. </catch_line><order_by>504</order_by><text>As used in KRS 278.505 to 278.507, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Intrastate pipeline" means any utility or any other person engaged in natural gas transportation in intrastate commerce, for compensation, to or for another person or to or for the public, but shall not include any part of any pipeline dedicated to storage or gathering or low pressure distribution of natural gas; </section><section prefix="2">"Interstate pipeline" means any person engaged in natural gas transportation subject to the jurisdiction of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission under the Natural Gas Act or the Natural Gas Policy Act of 1978; </section><section prefix="3">"Local distribution company" means any utility or any other person, other than an interstate pipeline or an intrastate pipeline, engaged in transportation or local distribution of natural gas and the sale of natural gas for ultimate consumption, but shall not include any part of any pipeline primarily used for storage or gathering or low pressure distribution of natural gas; </section><section prefix="4">"Intrastate commerce" includes the production, gathering, treatment, processing, transportation and delivery of natural gas entirely within the Commonwealth which is not subject to the jurisdiction of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission under the Natural Gas Act or the Natural Gas Policy Act of 1978; </section><section prefix="5">"Transportation" includes exchange, backhaul, displacement or other means of transportation; and </section><section prefix="6">"Person" includes natural persons, partnerships, corporations, and two (2) or more persons having a joint or common interest. </section></text><history>Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 39, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14134</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>