<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="196" order_by="196">CORRECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>196.720</section_number><catch_line>Plan requirements. </catch_line><order_by>720</order_by><text>Community corrections programs applying for grants under KRS 196.700 to 196.735 shall prepare a community corrections program plan for the judicial circuit, as prescribed by the commission. More than one (1) community corrections program plan may be prepared, submitted, and approved for any one (1) judicial circuit. The plan shall include: <section prefix="1">Objectives of the community corrections program described in the community corrections program plan. </section><section prefix="2">Realistic goals for reduction of offenders committed to prison for each county within the judicial circuit, and a system of monitoring the number of commitments to prison. </section><section prefix="3">Procedures for identifying targeted offenders, and a plan for referral of targeted offenders to the community corrections program. </section><section prefix="4">Procedures for preparing and presenting community penalty plans to the court, when applicable. </section><section prefix="5">Procedures for obtaining services from existing public or private agencies, and a detailed budget for staff, contracted services, and all other costs. </section><section prefix="6">Procedures for monitoring the progress of offenders on community penalty plans and for cooperating with the probation personnel who have supervisory responsibility for the offender, when applicable. </section><section prefix="7">Procedures for returning offenders who do not comply with their community penalty plan to court for action by the court. </section><section prefix="8">Procedures for evaluating the program's effect on numbers of prison commitments and revocations of probation and parole. </section></text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 5, effective June 24, 2003. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 5, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6852</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>