<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>271B.7-210</section_number><catch_line>Voting entitlement of shares. </catch_line><order_by>7-210</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided in subsections (2) and (4) of this section or unless the articles of incorporation provide otherwise, each outstanding share, regardless of class, shall be entitled to one (1) vote on each matter voted on at a shareholders' meeting. Only shares shall be entitled to vote. </section><section prefix="2">Absent special circumstances, the shares of a corporation shall not be entitled to vote if they are owned, directly or indirectly, by an entity, domestic or foreign, and the corporation controls, directly or indirectly, the entity’s determination to vote, and how to vote, the shares. </section><section prefix="3">Subsection (2) of this section shall not limit the power of a corporation to vote any shares, including its own shares, held by it in a fiduciary capacity. </section><section prefix="4">Redeemable shares shall not be entitled to vote after notice of redemption is mailed to the holders and a sum sufficient to redeem the shares has been deposited with a bank, trust company, or other financial institution under an irrevocable obligation to pay the holders the redemption price on surrender of the shares. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 62, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 62, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 57, effective January 1, 1989. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 183, provides, "The specific textual provisions of Sections 1 to 178 of this Act which reflect amendments made to those sections by 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137 shall be deemed effective as of June 26, 2007, and those provisions are hereby made expressly retroactive to that date, with the remainder of the text of those sections being unaffected by the provisions of this section." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13361</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>