<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="7" order_by="7">LEGISLATIVE RESEARCH COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>7.138</section_number><catch_line>Manner of amendment or repeal of KRS sections -- Official or certified version to be used in judicial or administrative proceeding -- Procedure in event of difference between official and certified versions. </catch_line><order_by>138</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any section in the official version of the Kentucky Revised Statutes may be amended or repealed by reference to the section number, without reference to the legislative act from which it was compiled. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">In any judicial or administrative proceeding, the text of any codified Kentucky statute which is submitted or cited by a party or upon which the court or the administrative officer or body relies shall be that text contained in the official version of the Kentucky Revised Statutes or in a certified version of the Kentucky Revised Statutes so designated pursuant to KRS 7.132 and bearing the certification provided for by KRS 7.134. </section><section prefix="b">In the event of a difference between the text of a statute as it appears in the official version of the Kentucky Revised Statutes and as it appears in a certified version of the Kentucky Revised Statutes, the text from the official version shall prevail unless, in response to a written inquiry, the Commission shall provide the court or the administrative officer or body in writing with a statement that the text in the official version is being corrected and with the text of that statute as corrected. </section></section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 46, sec. 6, effective January 1, 1997. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 200, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 431, sec. 2, effective April 13, 1992, and sec. 3, effective July 1, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 88, secs. 89 and 93, effective July 1, 1992. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 16, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 85, secs. (1), (3), and (4), effective June 16, 1966. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 1997 </effective><note>  Amendment of this section by 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 88, secs. 89 and 93 became effective July 1, 1992, in compliance with 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 324, sec. 30. </note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=475</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>