<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="66" order_by="66">ISSUANCE OF BONDS AND CONTROL OF FUNDS </unit></structure><section_number>66.523</section_number><catch_line>Public improvements financing plan -- Contents -- Implementation -- Annual report of board. </catch_line><order_by>523</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall prepare a public improvements financing plan which shall become the basis of all its operations including its requests to the fiscal court for appropriations for improvements and facilities described in KRS 66.520. In preparing the plan the board may use the services of all governmental agencies having any duties in connection with the matters of statewide concern described in KRS 66.520. The plan shall include in detail the sources of revenue to defray the costs of all projects. Revenue from appropriations made under KRS 66.520 and planned revenue from annual rental payments shall not be aggregated with each other or any other sources of revenue for any improvement contemplated.  </section><section prefix="2">The board shall submit its plan to the fiscal court before incurring any obligation (aside from costs incident to preparation of the plan) with respect to any public improvement. If the fiscal court does not disapprove of the plan in part or as a whole within ninety (90) days from the time the board transmits the plan to the fiscal court, the board may implement the plan to the extent it was not disapproved. The failure of the fiscal court to disapprove the plan, or part of it, shall in no way be deemed to make any obligation incurred by the board under the plan an obligation of the fiscal court.  </section><section prefix="3">Annually, at least ninety (90) days prior to the adoption of the proposed county budget pursuant to KRS 68.240, the board shall submit to the fiscal court a report of its affairs. Any supplements or amendments to the board's plan shall be included in the report. The fiscal court shall have ninety (90) days to disapprove of any supplements or amendments. Disapproval or the lack of it for all or any parts of the supplements or amendments shall have the same results as subsection (2) orders for the original plan.  </section><section prefix="4">No amendment or supplement shall reduce or release any prior obligation of the board without consent of the obligees.  </section></text><history>Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 19, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 232, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1980</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23635</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>