<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>355.9-515</section_number><catch_line>Duration and effectiveness of financing statement -- Effect of lapsed financing statement.   </catch_line><order_by>9-515</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as otherwise provided in subsections (2), (5), (6), and (7) of this section, a filed financing statement is effective for a period of five (5) years after the date of filing. </section><section prefix="2">Except as otherwise provided in subsections (5), (6), and (7) of this section, an initial financing statement filed in connection with a public-finance transaction or manufactured-home transaction is effective for a period of thirty (30) years after the date of filing if it indicates that it is filed in connection with a public-finance transaction or manufactured-home transaction. </section><section prefix="3">The effectiveness of a filed financing statement lapses on the expiration of the period of its effectiveness unless before the lapse a continuation statement is filed pursuant to subsection (4) of this section. Upon lapse, a financing statement ceases to be effective and any security interest or agricultural lien that was perfected by the financing statement becomes unperfected, unless the security interest is perfected otherwise. If the security interest or agricultural lien becomes unperfected upon lapse, it is deemed never to have been perfected as against a purchaser of the collateral for value. </section><section prefix="4">A continuation statement may be filed only within six (6) months before the expiration of the five (5) year period specified in subsection (1) of this section or the thirty (30) year period specified in subsection (2) of this section, whichever is applicable. </section><section prefix="5">Except as otherwise provided in KRS 355.9-510, upon timely filing of a continuation statement, the effectiveness of the initial financing statement continues for a period of five (5) years commencing on the day on which the financing statement would have become ineffective in the absence of the filing. Upon the expiration of the five (5) year period, the financing statement lapses in the same manner as provided in subsection (3) of this section, unless, before the lapse, another continuation statement is filed pursuant to subsection (4) of this section. Succeeding continuation statements may be filed in the same manner to continue the effectiveness of the initial financing statement. </section><section prefix="6">If a debtor is a transmitting utility and a filed initial financing statement so indicates, the financing statement is effective until a termination statement is filed. </section><section prefix="7">A record of a mortgage that is effective as a financing statement filed as a fixture filing under KRS 355.9-502(3) remains effective as a financing statement filed as a fixture filing until the mortgage is released or satisfied of record or its effectiveness otherwise terminates as to the real property. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 83, effective July 1, 2013. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 408, sec. 106, effective July 1, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2013 </effective><lrc-note> (3/14/2013). 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 10, secs. 2 and 3 provide that the statutes in Article 9 of the Uniform Commercial Code that were amended or created in 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 132, secs. 60 to 99, are effective July 1, 2013. This statute was one of those sections. Since only the effective date of a prior Act was altered, and not the text of the affected statutes, reference to 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 10 does not appear in the history for this statute.  (7/12/2012). In 2010, the National Conference of Commissioners on Uniform State Laws and the American Law Institute proposed a Uniform Act for adoption by the states that contained revisions to Article 9 of the Uniform Commercial Code. The effective date for all proposed Article 9 revisions was to be July 1, 2013. Those revisions were enacted in 2012 Ky. Acts Chapter 132, Sections 60 to 99. Sections 60 to 90 contained the substantive Article 9 revisions, and Sections 91 to 99 contained the transitional Article 9 revisions created to handle secured transactions made prior to July 1, 2013. Section 91 of that Act (codified as KRS 355.9-801) and Section 102 of that Act (a noncodified effective date provision) both stated, "Sections 91 to 99 of this Act take effect July 1, 2013." The normal effective date for legislation enacted at the 2012 Regular Session of the General Assembly is July 12, 2012. In Opinion of the Attorney General 12-010, issued July 3, 2012, Section 91 (codified as KRS 355.9-801) was determined to have contained a manifest clerical error, and should have instead read, "Sections 60 to 90 of this Act take effect July 1, 2013," thereby making the substantive Article 9 revisions effective on the same date as the transitional Article 9 provisions in conformity with the 2010 Uniform Act proposal and 2012 Ky. Acts Chapter 132, Section 102. This statute was one of the substantive provisions of Article 9 contained in 2012 Ky. Acts Chapter 132, Sections 60 to 90. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40684</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>