<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="79" order_by="79">INTERCITY, INTERCOUNTY AND CITY-COUNTY COMPACTS FOR PURCHASING AND MERIT SYSTEMS -- RETIREMENT AND DISABILITY PLANS FOR EMPLOYEES OF COUNTIES AND CITIES </unit></structure><section_number>79.050</section_number><catch_line>Comptroller -- Appointment -- Powers and duties -- Term of employment. </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The commission shall appoint a comptroller who shall be a certified public accountant or its equivalent, as may be determined by the examiner of his qualifications. He shall also have had some experience in a purchasing division of a city, county, or large private enterprise. This rule shall be adhered to except in those cases where a person with such qualifications cannot be secured, in which case the comptroller who shall be appointed shall serve temporarily unless he agrees to qualify himself to hold the position permanently.  </section><section prefix="2">The comptroller shall assume full charge of the procurement of supplies and may set up a merit system for personnel, except in those cases where cities or counties have already adopted a merit system.  </section><section prefix="3">The comptroller shall serve under contract for a period of not less than two (2) years and if it is desired to remove the comptroller during any fiscal year, that may only be done for cause and by a majority vote of the city or county administrative officials who are parties to the contract. </section></text><history>Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 43, secs. 3, 4, and 6. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:12</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24788</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>