<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="218" order_by="218">A CONTROLLED SUBSTANCES </unit></structure><section_number>218A.170</section_number><catch_line>Sale, distribution, administration, or prescription of controlled substances by licensed manufacturers, distributors, wholesalers, pharmacists, or practitioners. </catch_line><order_by>170</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A duly licensed manufacturer, distributor, or wholesaler may sell or distribute controlled substances, other than samples, to any of the following persons: <section prefix="a">To a manufacturer, wholesaler, or pharmacy; </section><section prefix="b">To a practitioner; </section><section prefix="c">To the administrator in charge of a hospital, but only for use by or in that hospital; </section><section prefix="d">To a person in charge of a laboratory, but only for use in that laboratory for scientific and medical research purposes; </section><section prefix="e">To a person registered pursuant to the federal controlled substances laws. </section></section><section prefix="2">A pharmacist may sell or distribute a controlled substance: <section prefix="a">Pursuant to a prescription that conforms to the requirements of this chapter; or </section><section prefix="b">To a person registered pursuant to the federal controlled substances laws. </section></section><section prefix="3">A practitioner may: <section prefix="a">Administer, dispense, or prescribe a controlled substance only for a legitimate medical purpose and in the course of professional practice; or </section><section prefix="b">Distribute a controlled substance to a person registered pursuant to the federal controlled substance laws. </section></section><section prefix="4">All sales and distributions shall be in accordance with KRS 218A.200 and the federal controlled substances laws, including the requirements governing the use of order forms. </section><section prefix="5">Possession of or control of controlled substances obtained as authorized by this section shall be lawful if in the regular course of business, occupation, profession, employment, or duty of the possessor. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 301, sec. 23, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 18. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9672</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>