<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXI" order_by="31">DEBTOR-CREDITOR RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="376" order_by="376">STATUTORY LIENS </unit></structure><section_number>376.440</section_number><catch_line>Lien on equipment, machinery and motors for work and supplies -- Filing of lien statement. </catch_line><order_by>440</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person engaged in the business of selling, repairing, or furnishing accessories, or supplies for any kind of equipment or machinery, including motors, shall have a lien on the equipment, machine, machinery, or motor, for the reasonable or agreed charges for repairs, work done, accessories, parts, and supplies furnished for the equipment, machine, machinery, or motor until the reasonable or agreed charge therefor has been paid. The lien shall not be lost by the removal of the equipment, machine, machinery or motor from the premises of the person performing labor, repairing, or furnishing accessories, parts or supplies therefor, if the lien shall be asserted within three (3) months by filing in the office of the county clerk a statement showing the amount and cost of materials furnished or labor performed on the equipment, machine, machinery, or motor. This statement shall be filed in the office of the county clerk of the county in which the owner of the equipment, machine, machinery, or motor resides, unless such owner be a nonresident, in which event the lien statement shall be filed in the office of the county clerk of the county in which such equipment, machine, machinery, or motor is at the time being kept or used. </section><section prefix="2">The lien provided for in this section shall attach regardless of whether or not the equipment, machine, machinery, motor, or motors, are ever upon the premises of or in the possession of the person making the repairs, furnishing the parts, or the supplies for such repairs. </section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 505, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1954. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35334</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>