<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="70" order_by="70">SHERIFFS, CONSTABLES, AND COUNTY POLICE FORCE </unit></structure><section_number>70.200</section_number><catch_line>Elisor -- How appointed -- Term of office -- Powers -- Compensation. </catch_line><order_by>200</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If the office of sheriff is vacant in any county, the Circuit Judge may appoint a citizen of the county to act as elisor. The elisor shall hold his office for one (1) year or until a sheriff is qualified, unless removed by the Circuit Judge. </section><section prefix="2">The person appointed shall give bond, to be approved by the county judge/executive, to cover all claims that may come to his hands. The elisor shall take the oath prescribed by law for sheriffs. </section><section prefix="3">The elisor may levy and collect executions, convey and sell land, and perform all acts and duties which are by law, devolved upon sheriffs, except that he shall not collect any kind of taxes or any judgment rendered upon any bonds or the coupons thereof issued or executed for any subscription to the capital stock of any railroad company or in aid of the construction of any railroad. </section><section prefix="4">He shall receive the same fees and compensation as the sheriff and be paid in the same manner. </section></text><history>Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 55, effective January 2, 1978.; and ch. 20, sec. 6, effective January 2, 1978. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 1597, 1598, 1599. </history><metadata><effective>January 2, 1978 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24214</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>