<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="217" order_by="217">FOODS, DRUGS, AND POISONS </unit></structure><section_number>217.182</section_number><catch_line>Sale, distribution, administration, prescription, or possession of legend drugs -- Penalty. </catch_line><order_by>182</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A duly licensed manufacturer, distributor, or wholesaler may sell or distribute a legend drug to any of the following: <section prefix="a">A manufacturer, wholesaler, or distributor; </section><section prefix="b">A pharmacy; </section><section prefix="c">A practitioner; </section><section prefix="d">The administrator in charge of a hospital, but only for use by or in that hospital; and </section><section prefix="e">A person in charge of a laboratory, but only for use in that laboratory for scientific and medical research purposes. </section></section><section prefix="2">A pharmacist may sell or distribute a legend drug: <section prefix="a">Pursuant to a prescription that conforms to the requirements of this chapter; or </section><section prefix="b">To a person licensed to administer, dispense, distribute, or possess a legend drug. </section></section><section prefix="3">A practitioner may: <section prefix="a">Administer, dispense, or prescribe a legend drug for a legitimate medical purpose and in the course of professional practice; or </section><section prefix="b">Distribute a legend drug to a person licensed to administer, dispense, distribute, or possess a legend drug. </section></section><section prefix="4">Possession or control of legend drugs obtained as authorized by this section shall be lawful if it occurred in the regular course of business, occupation, profession, employment, or duty of the possessor. </section><section prefix="5">No person shall traffic in any legend drug except as authorized by this section. </section><section prefix="6">No person shall dispense, prescribe, distribute, or administer any legend drug except as authorized by this section. </section><section prefix="7">No person shall possess any legend drug except as authorized by this section. </section><section prefix="8">Unless another specific penalty is provided in KRS 217.005 to 217.215, any person who violates any provision of subsections (1) to (6) of this section shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor for the first offense and a Class D felony for subsequent offenses. </section><section prefix="9">Unless another specific penalty is provided in KRS 217.005 to 217.215, any person who violates the provision of subsection (7) of this section shall be guilty of a Class B misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="10">A person to whom or for whose use a legend drug has been prescribed or dispensed may lawfully possess it. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 301, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:37</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9310</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>