<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="100" order_by="100">PLANNING AND ZONING </unit></structure><section_number>100.273</section_number><catch_line>Land subdivision regulations by planning commission or fiscal court -- Procedures for urban-county government. </catch_line><order_by>273</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any planning commission which has completed the objectives, land use plan, transportation plan, and community facilities elements of a comprehensive plan may adopt regulations for the subdivision of land within its boundaries, except that, in the case of urban-county governments, the planning commission shall make recommendations to the legislative body of the urban-county government as to the regulations, and it shall take a majority of the entire legislative body to override the recommendation of the planning commission. </section><section prefix="2">A county which does not wish to establish a planning program or form a planning unit may adopt regulations for the subdivision of land within its boundaries. In this case, the county shall be governed by the provisions of KRS 100.111(22), 100.277, 100.281, 100.283, 100.287 and 100.291, but any powers delegated to a planning commission in these sections shall instead be delegated to the fiscal court, any reference to the planning unit shall be considered a reference to the county, and any reference to the chairman of the planning commission shall be considered a reference to the county judge/executive. </section></text><history>Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 25, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986; and ch. 141, sec. 31, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 62. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986 </effective><lrc-note>.  This section was amended by two 1986 Acts which do not appear to be in conflict and have been compiled together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:11</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26756</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>