<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="362" order_by="362">PARTNERSHIPS </unit></structure><section_number>362.415</section_number><catch_line>Formation -- Certificate of limited partnership.   </catch_line><order_by>415</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In order to form a limited partnership, a certificate of limited partnership shall be executed and filed with the Secretary of State. The certificate shall be in the form prescribed by the Secretary of State and shall set forth: <section prefix="a">The name of the limited partnership; </section><section prefix="b">The address of the office and the name and address of the agent for service of process required to be maintained by KRS 14A.4-010 or predecessor law; </section><section prefix="c">The name and the business address of each general partner; </section><section prefix="d">A mailing address for the limited partnership; </section><section prefix="e">The latest date upon which the limited partnership is to dissolve; and </section><section prefix="f">Any other matters the general partners determine to include therein. </section></section><section prefix="2">A limited partnership shall be formed at the time of the filing of the certificate of limited partnership with the Secretary of State or at any later time specified in the certificate of limited partnership, which shall be a date certain and shall not be later than the ninetieth day after the date it is filed, if, in either case, there has been substantial compliance with the requirements of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 110, effective January 1, 2011. -- Repeal the prior repeal contained in 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 239, which was to have been effective January 1, 2008, 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 180, effective June 26, 2007. -- Repealed 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 239, effective January 1, 2008. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 341, sec. 52, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 284, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36756</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>