<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="150" order_by="150">FISH AND WILDLIFE RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>150.360</section_number><catch_line>Restrictions on taking of wildlife -- Discharge of weapon across public roadway prohibited.   </catch_line><order_by>360</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall take any wildlife, whether protected by this chapter or not, except by trapping, snaring, gig, crossbow, bow and arrow, hook and line, nets, gun, gun and dog, dog, falconry, or as expressly prescribed by regulation. </section><section prefix="2">Shotguns used in the taking of wildlife, protected or unprotected, shall not be larger than 10-gauge and shall be fired from the shoulder. No wildlife, except deer, protected or unprotected, shall be taken with or by means of any automatic loading or hand-operated repeating shotgun capable of holding more than three (3) shells, the magazine of which has not been cut off or plugged with a one (1) piece filler incapable of removal through the loading end, in such manner as to reduce the capacity of the gun to not more than three (3) shells at one (1) time in the magazine and chamber combined. </section><section prefix="3">No person shall take or attempt to take any wildlife, protected or unprotected, from an automobile, or other vehicle, unless prescribed by regulation. Boats may be used except as prohibited by state or federal regulation. </section><section prefix="4">No person shall discharge any firearm, bow and arrow, crossbow or other similar device, upon, over, or across any public roadway. </section><section prefix="5">No person shall take wildlife, except opossum, raccoon, fishes and frogs, with lights or other means designed to make wildlife visible at night. </section><section prefix="6">Coyotes may be taken at night with or without the use of lights or other means designed to make wildlife visible at night, as established by administrative regulation. </section></text><history>Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 29, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 474, sec. 6, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 265, sec. 15, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 178, sec. 13, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 38, sec. 18. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 200, sec. 48. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 84, sec. 14. -- Amended 1944 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 9. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 68, sec. 37. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 1954d-56, 1954d-60. </history><metadata><effective>June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41863</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>