<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="42" order_by="42">FINANCE AND ADMINISTRATION CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>42.0171</section_number><catch_line>Office of Administrative Services. </catch_line><order_by>0171</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Office of Administrative Services established in KRS 42.0145 shall be generally responsible for all internal administrative and human resource functions of the cabinet, including but not limited to providing administrative assistance; managing and preparing the cabinet's budget; performing general accounting; managing fiscal, personnel, and payroll functions of the cabinet; providing statewide postal and printing services; providing administrative support to boards and commissions; and performing any additional administrative functions and duties the secretary may assign. </section><section prefix="2">There shall be established in the Office of Administrative Services the Division of Budget and Planning, the Division of Human Resources, the Division of Administrative Support Services, the Division of Postal Services, and the Division of Fleet Management, each of which shall be headed by a division director appointed by the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, subject to the approval of the Governor, and who shall be responsible to the executive director of the Office of Administrative Services. There may be, if needed, sections assigned to specific areas of work, responsible directly to the executive director of the Office of Administrative Services. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 22, effective June 25, 2009. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 9, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 214, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994; ch. 216, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 508, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 393, sec. 22, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 49, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/94).  This section was amended by 1994 Ky. Acts chs. 214, 216, and 508. Where these Acts are not in conflict, they have been codified together. Where a conflict exists between chs. 216 and 508, Acts ch. 508, which was last enacted by the General Assembly, prevails under KRS 446.250. .  This section was amended by 1982 Acts Chapter 183, Section 2 and 1982 Acts Chapter 393, Section 22 which conflict and cannot be compiled together. Pursuant to KRS 446.250, the amendment in Chapter 393 prevails as the later enactment. </lrc-note><former-codification>KRS 42.023. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21951</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>