<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.929</section_number><catch_line>Sponsorship of residency positions -- Approval of sites -- Funding priority -- Policies and procedures for determination of allocation. </catch_line><order_by>929</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All new residency positions shall be sponsored by the University of Kentucky or the University of Louisville. The residency positions created by KRS 164.927 shall be served in sites approved by the appropriate specialty board for certification and by the Council on Postsecondary Education. </section><section prefix="2">Funding priority shall be given to programs in which all or a portion of the residency occurs in sites away from both the University of Kentucky and the University of Louisville. </section><section prefix="3">Each individual serving a residency under KRS 164.927 shall, within the total period of residency, undertake a minimum of three (3) months education in a community facility in Kentucky outside the counties of Fayette and Jefferson, or in any institution serving a medically underserved community as designated by the United States Department of Health, Education and Welfare, subject to the approval of the certifying board in each specialty, provided however that not more than twenty-five percent (25%) of the individuals from each university funded under this section shall be permitted to satisfy the three (3) month requirement in a medically underserved area in the counties of Fayette and Jefferson. </section><section prefix="4">The University of Kentucky and the University of Louisville shall recommend policies and procedures for determining the allocation of new residency positions for approval by the Council on Postsecondary Education using the following criteria: <section prefix="a">The available or expected number and types of qualified faculty necessary for the proper degree of supervision and teaching; </section><section prefix="b">The scope and volume of patient care; </section><section prefix="c">The amount of available physical facilities; </section><section prefix="d">The current number and types of residency positions offered at each university; </section><section prefix="e">Regional needs for the manpower trained under the provisions of KRS 164.927 to 164.933; </section><section prefix="f">The extent of involvement in education in primary care in ambulatory care settings; and </section><section prefix="g">Any other criteria which may be developed by the University of Kentucky and the University of Louisville and accepted by the Council on Postsecondary Education. </section></section></text><history> Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 129, effective May 30, 1997. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 104, effective June 17, 1978; and ch. 384, sec. 49, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 42, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> May 30, 1997 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4488</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>