<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.503</section_number><catch_line>Committee to study basketball tournaments -- Membership -- Meetings and recommendations. </catch_line><order_by>503</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The agency designated by the Kentucky Board of Education to manage interscholastic athletics shall appoint a committee by September 1, 2002, to study the current format and scheduling of the state girls and boys high school basketball tournaments and consider the pros and cons of the scheduling, taking into consideration the physical and mental demands on the players, the impact on the school instructional calendar, the availability of facilities, and other related factors as determined by the committee. </section><section prefix="2">The committee shall consist of the following representatives, one (1) of whom shall be male, and one (1) of whom shall be female, except in paragraphs (f) and (i): <section prefix="a">Two (2) coaches, who may be active or former coaches; </section><section prefix="b">Two (2) current superintendents of school districts that have high school athletic programs; </section><section prefix="c">Two (2) current high school principals; </section><section prefix="d">Two (2) former players, who participated in at least one (1) state tournament; </section><section prefix="e">Two (2) athletic directors, active or former; </section><section prefix="f">Two (2) former members of the board of control of the high school athletic association designated by the state board to govern interscholastic athletics; </section><section prefix="g">Two (2) active referees; </section><section prefix="h">Two (2) citizen members; and </section><section prefix="i">Two (2) members of the General Assembly, one (1) appointed by the Senate President and one (1) appointed by the Speaker of the House. </section></section><section prefix="3">Representation appointed to the committee pursuant to subsection (2)(f) and (i) of this section may be based on gender equity if female candidates are available. </section><section prefix="4">The committee shall meet as needed during the 2002-2003 school year and make recommendations to the board of control of the athletics association prior to the scheduling of the high school tournaments for the 2003-2004 school year. The report shall also be presented to the Interim Joint Committee on Education. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 212, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3216</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>