<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.250</section_number><catch_line>Articles of incorporation. </catch_line><order_by>250</order_by><text> The articles of incorporation of a farm bureau shall be as follows:  "We, the undersigned farmers or landowners, residents of .... County, Kentucky, hereby adopt the following articles of incorporation:  "Article 1. The objects of this incorporation shall be to advance and improve in .... County, Kentucky, the science and art of agriculture, home economics, horticulture and animal industry, cooperating with the State Department of Agriculture, the College of Agriculture of the University of Kentucky and the United States Department of Agriculture.  "Article 2. The name of this corporation shall be the .... County Farm Bureau of .... County, Kentucky.  "Article 3. The affairs of this corporation shall be conducted by a president, a vice president, a secretary and a treasurer, who shall perform the duties usually pertaining to such positions, and by a board of directors of not less than seven members. All officers and directors shall be elected as provided for in the bylaws at an annual meeting and they shall hold office for one year and until their successors are elected, but, so that the terms of all directors shall not expire at the same time, the members, by bylaw or resolution, may provide that at one annual election that the term of half the number of directors, or if there be an uneven number, that the term of one less than the majority or the term of a majority of one, elected at said election, shall be for one year, and the term of the remaining directors elected at said election shall be for two years, and that all elections for directors, after the expiration of the aforesaid specific terms, shall be for two years. We, the said incorporators, have elected the following provisional officers to hold their respective positions until their successors are elected at the annual meeting in the year 19...                                  President ...........................................                                  Vice President ......................................                                  Secretary ...........................................                                  Treasurer ...........................................                                  Board of Directors:                                       1.  ......................                                       2.  ......................                                       3.  ......................                                       4.  ......................                                       5.  ......................                                       6.  ......................                                       7.  ......................  "Article 4. The date of the annual meeting shall be stated in the bylaws. The bylaws shall be adopted by the members of the corporation and may be amended at any annual meeting of the members.  "Article 5. The yearly dues of the members of this corporation shall be not less than five dollars, payable at the time that application for membership is made and by or on the same date annually thereafter. No member who has once paid dues shall forfeit membership until subsequent dues are sixty days in arrears, but so long as any dues owing are unpaid, such member shall have no right to vote in any election or on any matter.  "Article 6. Any citizen of the county owning or operating a farm, or evidencing a primary interest in farming by reason of his position or occupation may become a member of the corporation by paying one year's dues and complying with the articles of incorporation and bylaws.  "Article 7. This corporation shall endure until terminated by operation of law." </text><history>Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 157, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 42d-2. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11616</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>