<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">COUNTY GOVERNMENT (FISCAL COURTS AND COUNTY COMMISSIONERS) </unit></structure><section_number>67.323</section_number><catch_line>Fire department merit system -- Creation -- Scope -- Board -- Definitions -- Applicability.   </catch_line><order_by>323</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any county that has not established a county police merit system, as provided by KRS 78.400 to 78.460 and 78.990 may, by order of its fiscal court, duly made and entered of record, create a county fire department merit system, and for that purpose establish a county fire department merit board, whose duties it shall be to classify and examine applicants seeking employment as firefighters or employees of the fire department of the said county, and, in addition, to promulgate rules and regulations governing the classification, qualification, examination, appointment, promotion, demotion, fine, suspension and other disciplinary action within the said county fire department of all personnel of the county fire department or departments affected as provided in this section and KRS 67.325 and 78.425, and, in addition thereto, to hold such hearings, public and executive, and impose such penalties upon the personnel affected as provided in this section, KRS 67.325 and 78.425. </section><section prefix="2">Fiscal courts affected hereby shall make appropriations of money for the reasonable and necessary expenses of the said board. </section><section prefix="3">KRS 78.410 to 78.460 and 78.990 shall be followed in the establishing of a county fire department merit system as provided in this section. All terms referring to the county police force, by context or definition, shall be taken to mean county fire department. Other terms mean: <section prefix="a">"Board" means the county fire department merit board created by subsection (1). </section><section prefix="b">"Chief" means the chief of the county fire department affected by this section, KRS 67.325 and 78.425. </section><section prefix="c">"Assistant chief" means the next in command to the chief of the county fire department affected by this section, KRS 67.325 and 78.425. </section><section prefix="d">"Secretary" means the executive secretary and examiner employed by the county fire department merit board created by this section, KRS 67.325 and 78.425. </section><section prefix="e">"Officer" means any member of the county fire department affected by this section, KRS 67.325 and 78.425. </section><section prefix="f">"Employee" means all other employees of the county fire department affected by this section, KRS 67.325 and 78.425. </section></section></text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 35, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 5, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 148, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43620</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>