<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="17" order_by="17">PUBLIC SAFETY </unit></structure><section_number>17.151</section_number><catch_line>Centralized criminal history record information system to be developed by Department of Kentucky State Police, in cooperation with specified state agencies -- Contents -- Access -- Identification numbers. </catch_line><order_by>151</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department of Kentucky State Police shall, in cooperation with the Administrative Office of the Courts, the Department of Juvenile Justice, the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, and the Department of Corrections, be responsible for the recording of those data elements that are needed for development of the centralized criminal history record information system. </section><section prefix="2">The database shall at a minimum contain the information required in KRS 27A.310 to 27A.440. </section><section prefix="3">The Department of Kentucky State Police shall provide access to the Administrative Office of the Courts, the Department of Juvenile Justice, the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, and the Department of Corrections to its database. </section><section prefix="4">The Department of Kentucky State Police, the Department of Juvenile Justice, the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, and the Department of Corrections shall assign the same identification number or other variable to each person whose name appears in the database. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 84, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 90, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 606, sec. 12, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 6, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 389, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><lrc-note> (6/26/2007).  The numbering of subsections in this section has been altered by the Reviser of Statutes from the numbering in 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 84, under the authority of KRS 7.136. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1210</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>