<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="177" order_by="177">STATE AND FEDERAL HIGHWAYS -- LIMITED ACCESS FACILITIES -- TURNPIKES -- ROAD BONDS -- BILLBOARDS -- RECYCLERS </unit></structure><section_number>177.0738</section_number><catch_line>Logo signs for eligible businesses. </catch_line><order_by>0738</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any camping facility that has been authorized by the commissioner of the Department of Highways to attach its logo sign to the face of a specific service sign erected on a fully controlled access highway, pursuant to the Federal Highway Administration's Manual on Uniform Traffic Control Devices, may make application to the commissioner of the Department of Highways to have its logo sign attached to the face of a specific service sign erected on any road as defined in KRS 177.010. </section><section prefix="2">The commissioner of the Department of Highways shall promulgate administrative regulations, pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A, to provide for the erection of specific service signs on roads, as defined in KRS 177.010. The specific service signs as herein required to be erected shall include, but not be limited to, the display of logo signs that provide identification of and directional information to camping facilities. The administrative regulations shall conform with the Federal Highway Administration's Manual on Uniform Traffic Control Devices (MUTCD) and shall include, but not be limited to, criteria for the following: <section prefix="a">Selection of eligible businesses; </section><section prefix="b">Distances to eligible businesses; </section><section prefix="c">Acceptance of logo signs that conform to the MUTCD; </section><section prefix="d">Removing or covering logo signs during off-seasons for eligible businesses operated on a seasonal basis; </section><section prefix="e">Defining the circumstances in which specific service signs are erected; and </section><section prefix="f">Determining the costs to eligible businesses for initial installation, annual maintenance, and removal of logo signs. </section></section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5258</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>