<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="507" order_by="507">CRIMINAL HOMICIDE </unit></structure><section_number>507.030</section_number><catch_line>Manslaughter in the first degree.   </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of manslaughter in the first degree when: <section prefix="a">With intent to cause serious physical injury to another person, he causes the death of such person or of a third person; </section><section prefix="b">With intent to cause the death of another person, he causes the death of such person or of a third person under circumstances which do not constitute murder because he acts under the influence of extreme emotional disturbance, as defined in subsection (1)(a) of KRS 507.020; or </section><section prefix="c">Through circumstances not otherwise constituting the offense of murder, he or she intentionally abuses another person or knowingly permits another person of whom he or she has actual custody to be abused and thereby causes death to a person twelve (12) years of age or less, or who is physically helpless or mentally helpless. </section></section><section prefix="2">Manslaughter in the first degree is a Class B felony. </section></text><history>Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 64, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2015. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 62, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective>June 24, 2015</effective><lrc-note> (6/24/2015). 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 64, sec. 3 provides that the amendments to this statute and KRS 507.010 made in 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 64, secs. 1 and 2 may be cited as "Conner’s Law." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44471</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>