<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="61" order_by="61">GENERAL PROVISIONS AS TO OFFICES AND OFFICERS -- SOCIAL SECURITY FOR PUBLIC EMPLOYEES -- EMPLOYEES RETIREMENT SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>61.373</section_number><catch_line>Restoration of public employee to position after military duty -- Right to leave of absence -- Appeals. </catch_line><order_by>373</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any public employee who leaves a position after June 16, 1966, voluntarily or involuntarily, in order to perform military duty, and who is relieved or discharged from such duty under conditions other than dishonorable, and who has not been absent from public employment due to military duty in time of war or national or state emergency for a period of time longer than the duration of the war or national or state emergency plus six (6) months or in time of peace for a period of time not longer than six (6) years, and makes application for reemployment within ninety (90) days after he is relieved from military duty or from hospitalization or treatment continuing after discharge for a period of not more than one (1) year: <section prefix="a">If still physically qualified to perform the duties of his position, shall be restored to such position if it exists and is not held by a person with greater seniority, otherwise to a position of like seniority, status and pay; </section><section prefix="b">If not qualified to perform the duties of his position by reason of disability sustained during such service, the public employee shall be placed in another position, the duties of which he is qualified to perform and which will provide him like seniority, status and pay, or the nearest approximation thereof consistent with the circumstances of his case. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Officers and employees of this state, or any department or agency thereof, shall be granted a leave of absence by their employers for the period required to perform active duty or training in the National Guard or any reserve component of the Armed Forces of the United States. </section><section prefix="b">Upon the officer's or employee's release from a period of active duty or training, except as provided in KRS 61.394, he or she shall be permitted to return to his or her former position of employment or a position with equivalent seniority, status, pay, and any other rights or benefits that would have been bestowed if he or she had not been absent. </section><section prefix="c">An officer or employee who is not permitted to return to his or her former position may appeal the dismissal in accordance with KRS Chapter 18A. </section></section><section prefix="3">In the case of any person who is entitled to be restored to a position in accordance with KRS 61.371 to 61.379, if the personnel board finds that the department or agency with which such person was employed immediately prior to his military duty: <section prefix="a">Is no longer in existence and its functions have not been transferred to any other agency; or </section><section prefix="b">For any reason it is not feasible for such person to be restored to employment by the department or agency, the board shall determine whether or not there is a position in any other department or agency of the same public employer for which the person is qualified and which is either vacant or held by a person having a temporary appointment thereto. In any case in which the board determines that there is such a position, the person shall be restored to the position by the department or agency in which the position exists. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 153, sec. 13, effective April 13, 2010. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> April 13, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22928</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>