<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="317" order_by="317">A COSMETOLOGISTS </unit></structure><section_number>317A.050</section_number><catch_line>Fees and qualifications for licenses.   </catch_line><order_by>050</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cosmetologist board shall issue an apprentice cosmetologist license to any person who: <section prefix="a">Is of good moral character and temperate habit; </section><section prefix="b">Is at least sixteen (16) years of age; </section><section prefix="c">Has a high school diploma, General Educational Development (GED) diploma, or the results from the Test for Adult Basic Education indicating a score equivalent to the twelfth grade of high school; </section><section prefix="d">Has official certification from the state board or agency that certifies cosmetology schools that the applicant has graduated from a licensed school of cosmetology requiring one thousand eight hundred (1,800) hours within ten (10) years of submitting an application for licensure; </section><section prefix="e">Has passed an examination prescribed by the board to determine fitness to practice as an apprentice cosmetologist; and </section><section prefix="f">Has paid a fee of twenty-five dollars ($25). </section></section><section prefix="2">The cosmetologist board shall issue a cosmetologist license to any person who: <section prefix="a">Has a high school diploma, General Educational Development (GED) diploma, or the results from the Test for Adult Basic Education indicating a score equivalent to the twelfth grade of high school; </section><section prefix="b">Has practiced as a licensed cosmetology apprentice for at least six (6) months under the immediate supervision of a licensed cosmetologist; </section><section prefix="c">Has satisfactorily passed an examination prescribed by the board to determine fitness to practice cosmetology; and </section><section prefix="d">Has paid a fee of twenty-five dollars ($25). </section></section><section prefix="3">The cosmetologist board shall issue a license to act as a nail technician to any person who: <section prefix="a">Is of good moral character and temperate habit; </section><section prefix="b">Has official certification from the state board or agency that certifies cosmetology schools that the applicant has completed satisfactorily a nail technician course of study of six hundred (600) hours in a licensed school of cosmetology within ten (10) years of submitting an application for licensure; </section><section prefix="c">Has satisfactorily passed an examination prescribed by the board to determine fitness to practice as a nail technician; </section><section prefix="d">Has a high school diploma, General Educational Development (GED) diploma, or the results from the Test for Adult Basic Education indicating a score equivalent to the twelfth grade of high school; and </section><section prefix="e">Has paid a fee of twenty-five dollars ($25). </section></section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">The cosmetologist board shall issue a license to operate a beauty salon to any licensed cosmetologist upon receipt of the completed application, accompanied by a fee of thirty-five dollars ($35). The board may refuse to issue a license if the applicant fails to comply with the provisions of this chapter or the administrative regulations promulgated by the board. If an owner is not a licensed cosmetologist, he or she shall have a licensed cosmetologist manage the beauty salon at all times. A new license shall be purchased if the salon's owner, manager, or location changes. </section><section prefix="b">The cosmetologist board shall issue a license to operate a nail salon to any licensed nail technician upon receipt of the completed application and payment of a fee of thirty-five dollars ($35). The board may refuse to issue a license if the applicant fails to comply with the provisions of this chapter or administrative regulations promulgated by the board pursuant to this chapter. An owner who is not a licensed nail technician shall have a licensed nail technician or cosmetologist as manager of the nail salon at all times. If the owner, manager, or location of a nail salon changes, a new license shall be purchased. </section><section prefix="c">Any person who leases or rents space in a beauty salon or nail salon shall be considered an independent owner and shall meet the qualifications for the respective salon owner as set out in paragraphs (a) and (b) of this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="5">The cosmetologist board shall issue an apprentice license to teach cosmetology to any person who: <section prefix="a">Has paid a fee of thirty-five dollars ($35); </section><section prefix="b">Has a high school diploma, General Educational Development (GED) diploma, or the results from the Test for Adult Basic Education indicating a score equivalent to the twelfth grade of high school and one (1) year experience as a licensed cosmetologist; and </section><section prefix="c">Has submitted an application that has been signed by the owners of the school in which the applicant will study. The course of instruction shall be for a period of one thousand (1,000) hours and not less than six (6) months at one (1) school providing this instruction. The school owner shall verify to the board the completion of one thousand (1,000) hours. For out-of-state verification, an applicant shall provide official certification from the board or agency that certifies schools in that other state of licensure verifying the applicant has completed a course of instruction consisting of at least one thousand (1,000) hours and not less than six (6) months at one (1) school providing the instruction. </section></section><section prefix="6">The cosmetologist board shall issue a license to teach cosmetology to any person who: <section prefix="a">Is of good moral character and temperate habit; </section><section prefix="b">Has a high school diploma, General Educational Development (GED) diploma, or the results from the Test for Adult Basic Education indicating a score equivalent to the twelfth grade of high school; </section><section prefix="c">Has held an apprentice instructor license for at least six (6) months; </section><section prefix="d">Has satisfactorily passed the examination for the teaching of cosmetology as prescribed by the board; and </section><section prefix="e">Has paid a fee of fifty dollars ($50). </section></section><section prefix="7">The cosmetologist board may issue a license to operate a school of cosmetology to any person who: <section prefix="a">Has complied with the administrative regulations promulgated by the board including but not limited to administrative regulations governing the necessary equipment, supplies, and facilities; </section><section prefix="b">Has furnished proof to the board that the school of cosmetology is needed, that he or she is otherwise qualified to operate a school of cosmetology, and that he or she intends to establish a bona fide school for the education and training of competent cosmetologists and that he or she will employ a sufficient number of licensed instructors of cosmetology to conduct the school; </section><section prefix="c">Has as manager at all times a person who is: <section prefix="1">Licensed as an instructor; </section><section prefix="2">Charged with the responsibility of ensuring that all applicable statutes and administrative regulations are complied with; and </section><section prefix="3">Responsible for having a sufficient number of licensed instructors of cosmetology to conduct the school. </section></section> The designated manager shall be approved by the board before a license may be issued; <section prefix="d">Complies with the administrative regulations promulgated by the board including but not limited to those regarding courses, curriculum, and hours of instruction; </section><section prefix="e">Otherwise complies with this chapter; </section><section prefix="f">Has paid a fee of one thousand five hundred dollars ($1,500); </section><section prefix="g">Has been a resident of Kentucky for five (5) years, if the applicant is an individual. If the applicant is a firm or corporation, it shall be a Kentucky corporation or licensed or qualified to do business in Kentucky and shall have been in existence for a period of at least five (5) years; </section><section prefix="h">Any student enrolling in the school shall pay a fee of fifteen dollars ($15) to the board before enrollment in the school shall be allowed; and </section><section prefix="i">The transfer of any license to operate a school of cosmetology shall require the board's approval and shall become effective upon filing a new application with the board and paying a fee of one thousand five hundred dollars ($1,500). </section></section><section prefix="8">Licenses and permits issued by the board may be renewed upon receipt, beginning July 1 through July 31 of each year. The application for renewal shall be completed in full and accompanied by the appropriate renewal fee required by subsection (9) of this section. Applications for renewal shall comply with the provisions of this chapter and the administrative regulations promulgated by the board. Any license application received or postmarked after July 31 shall be considered expired, and the appropriate restoration fee required by subsection (11) of this section shall apply. </section><section prefix="9">The annual renewal license or permit fee for each type of license or permit renewal shall be as follows: <section prefix="a">Apprentice cosmetologist -- $20; </section><section prefix="b">Cosmetologist -- $20; </section><section prefix="c">Nail technician -- $20; </section><section prefix="d">Beauty salon -- $25; </section><section prefix="e">Nail salon -- $25; </section><section prefix="f">Apprentice instructor of cosmetology -- $25; </section><section prefix="g">Instructor of cosmetology -- $35; </section><section prefix="h">Cosmetology school -- $150; </section><section prefix="i">Threading permit -- $20; and </section><section prefix="j">Threading facility permit -- $25. </section></section><section prefix="10">Applications for examinations required by this section shall be accompanied by an examination fee as follows: <section prefix="a">Apprentice cosmetologist -- $75; </section><section prefix="b">Cosmetologist -- $75; </section><section prefix="c">Nail technician -- $75; </section><section prefix="d">Instructor of cosmetology -- $100; </section><section prefix="e">Cosmetologist out-of-state -- $120; and </section><section prefix="f">Instructor out-of-state -- $200. </section></section><section prefix="11">The fee for the restoration of an expired license where the period of expiration does not exceed five (5) years from date of expiration, shall be as follows: <section prefix="a">Apprentice cosmetologist -- $75; </section><section prefix="b">Cosmetologist -- $75; </section><section prefix="c">Nail technician -- $75; </section><section prefix="d">Beauty salon -- $75; </section><section prefix="e">Nail salon -- $75; </section><section prefix="f">Cosmetology school -- $750; </section><section prefix="g">Instructor -- $100; and </section><section prefix="h">Apprentice instructor -- $75. </section></section><section prefix="12">The requirements for a new license for any person whose license has expired for a period exceeding five (5) years shall be as follows: <section prefix="a">Cosmetologists shall retake and pass the practical examination only; </section><section prefix="b">Apprentice cosmetologists shall complete four hundred fifty (450) additional hours training in a licensed school of cosmetology and pass all the prescribed examinations; </section><section prefix="c">Instructors of cosmetology shall retake and pass both the practical and theory examination; </section><section prefix="d">Nail technicians shall retake and pass the practical and theory examination; and </section><section prefix="e">The appropriate restoration fee as set forth in subsection (11) of this section shall be required. </section></section><section prefix="13">Guest artists or demonstrators appearing and demonstrating before persons other than licensed hairdressers, cosmetologists, and nail technicians shall pay a fee of fifty dollars ($50) for a permit that shall be in effect for ten (10) days. Guest artists performing before a nonprofit, recognized professional hairdressers, cosmetologists, cosmetology school, or nail technicians group shall apply for a permit, but shall not be required to pay the fee. </section><section prefix="14">The board shall issue a permit for threading and may promulgate administrative regulations that set out requirements for the practice of threading upon payment of a fee of twenty dollars ($20). Threading shall be conducted in a licensed beauty salon or facility permitted to engage in threading, and the board may promulgate administrative regulations for facilities and the required sanitation standards. </section><section prefix="15">The fee for certification shall be twenty dollars ($20). </section><section prefix="16">The fee for a duplicate license shall be twenty-five dollars ($25). </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 5, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 96, sec. 3, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 91, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 1, effective March 31, 1988. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 435, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 202, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 354, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40882</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>