<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171">STATE LIBRARIES -- LIBRARIANS -- STATE ARCHIVES AND RECORDS </unit></structure><section_number>171.396</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 171.396, 171.3961, and 171.397. </catch_line><order_by>396</order_by><text>As used in this section and KRS 171.3961 and 171.397: <section prefix="1">"Certified historic structure" means a structure that is located within the Commonwealth of Kentucky that is: <section prefix="a">Listed individually on the National Register of Historic Places; or </section><section prefix="b">Located in a historic district listed on the National Register of Historic Places and is certified by the council as contributing to the historic significance of the district; </section></section><section prefix="2">"Certified rehabilitation" means a completed substantial rehabilitation of a certified historic structure that the council certifies meets the United States Secretary of the Interior's Standards for Rehabilitation; </section><section prefix="3">"Certified rehabilitation credit cap" means an annual amount of: <section prefix="a">Three million dollars ($3,000,000) for applications received prior to April 30, 2010; and </section><section prefix="b">Five million dollars ($5,000,000) for applications received on or after April 30, 2010; </section></section> plus any amount added to the certified rehabilitation credit cap pursuant to KRS 171.397(2)(c); <section prefix="4">"Council" means the Kentucky Heritage Council; </section><section prefix="5">"Disqualifying work" means work that is performed within three (3) years of the completion of the certified rehabilitation that, if performed as part of the rehabilitation certified under KRS 171.397, would have made the rehabilitation ineligible for certification; </section><section prefix="6">"Exempt entity" means any tax exempt organization pursuant to sec. 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code, any political subdivision of the Commonwealth, any state or local agency, board, or commission, or any quasi-governmental entity; </section><section prefix="7">"Local government" means a city, county, urban-county, charter county, or consolidated local government; </section><section prefix="8">"Owner-occupied residential property" means a building or portion thereof, condominium, or cooperative occupied by the owner as his or her principal residence; </section><section prefix="9">"Qualified rehabilitation expense" means any amount that is properly chargeable to a capital account, whether or not depreciation is allowed under Section 168 of the Internal Revenue Code, and is expended in connection with the certified rehabilitation of a certified historic structure. It shall include the cost of restoring landscaping and fencing that contributes to the historic significance of this structure, but shall not include the cost of acquisition of a certified historic structure, enlargement of or additions to an existing building, or the purchase of personal property; </section><section prefix="10">"Substantial rehabilitation" means rehabilitation of a certified historic structure for which the qualified rehabilitation expenses, during a twenty-four (24) month period selected by the taxpayer or exempt entity, ending with or within the taxable year, exceed: <section prefix="a">Twenty thousand dollars ($20,000) for an owner-occupied residential property; or </section><section prefix="b">For all other property, the greater of: <section prefix="1">The adjusted basis of the structure; or </section><section prefix="2">Twenty thousand dollars ($20,000); </section></section></section><section prefix="11">"Taxpayer" means any individual, corporation, limited liability company, business development corporation, partnership, limited partnership, sole proprietorship, association, joint stock company, receivership, trust, professional service organization, or other legal entity through which business is conducted that: <section prefix="a">Elects to claim the credit on a return and receive a refund as provided in KRS 171.397(2)(b)2.a.; or </section><section prefix="b">Is the recipient of a credit which is transferred as provided in KRS 171.397(2)(b)2.b.; and </section></section><section prefix="12">"Qualified purchased historic home" means any substantially rehabilitated certified historic structure if: <section prefix="a">The taxpayer claiming the credit authorized under KRS 171.397 is the first purchaser of the structure after the date of completion of the substantial rehabilitation; </section><section prefix="b">The structure or a portion thereof will be the principal residence of the taxpayer; and </section><section prefix="c">No credit was allowed to the seller under this section. </section></section> A qualified purchased historic home shall be deemed owner-occupied residential property for purposes of this section. </text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 19, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2009 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 33, effective June 26, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 224, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 168, sec. 150, effective March 18, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><lrc-note> (3/18/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts ch.168, sec. 165, provides that this section shall apply to tax years beginning on or after January 1, 2005. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43412</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>