<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="213" order_by="213">VITAL STATISTICS </unit></structure><section_number>213.061</section_number><catch_line>Flagged birth certificate of child reported missing. </catch_line><order_by>061</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon notification by the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet that a child born in the Commonwealth is missing, the state registrar of vital statistics shall flag the birth certificate record of the child in such a manner that whenever a copy of the birth certificate or information regarding the birth record is requested, the state registrar shall be alerted to the fact that the certificate is that of a missing child. </section><section prefix="2">Upon notification by the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet that a missing child has been recovered, the state registrar shall remove the flag from the child's birth certificate record. </section><section prefix="3">In response to any inquiry for a copy of a flagged birth certificate of a missing child, the state registrar shall not provide a copy of the birth certificate except as approved by the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet. </section><section prefix="4">When a copy of a flagged birth certificate is requested in person, the state registrar or the designee accepting the request shall inform the person making the request that a copy of a certificate will be mailed to the requester. The state registrar shall, upon the departure of the requesting person, immediately notify the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet as to the request and the information obtained pursuant to this subsection. </section><section prefix="5">When a copy of a flagged birth certificate is requested in writing, the state registrar shall immediately notify the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet as to the request and shall provide a copy of the written request. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 245, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 369, sec. 11, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8720</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>