<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="177" order_by="177">STATE AND FEDERAL HIGHWAYS -- LIMITED ACCESS FACILITIES -- TURNPIKES -- ROAD BONDS -- BILLBOARDS -- RECYCLERS </unit></structure><section_number>177.020</section_number><catch_line>State primary roads to be designated and controlled by the Department of Highways -- Notice to fiscal court and affected citizens -- Rural secondary road system -- Maintenance -- Administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The state primary road system shall consist of such public roads and city streets within the state as the Department of Highways determines shall be established, constructed, or maintained by the Department of Highways. </section><section prefix="2">The department shall, in its discretion, determine which public roads, or city streets, shall be established, constructed, or maintained by it, and shall determine the type of construction or maintenance for that road or city street. </section><section prefix="3">In the establishment of the state primary road system, the Department of Highways is authorized to select new routes, deviate from an existing route whenever it deems such deviation proper, eliminate from the state primary system roads or city streets which have been replaced as proper part of the system by the construction of a new facility or the selection of a new route. No permanent ingress or egress ramp of the state primary road system on fully controlled access facilities shall be closed, except for repairs, unless a public hearing is first held in the area to be affected by the closing. The Department of Highways shall, at least twenty (20) days before the hearing, advertise in a newspaper of general circulation in the area to be affected by the closing, the date, time, and place of the hearing. </section><section prefix="4">Prior to the advertisement for bids on any highway construction project, the Department of Highways shall meet with the fiscal court in the jurisdiction of the construction project for the purpose of advising the fiscal court of any state road or road segment which the department may seek to eliminate from the state primary road system upon completion of that highway construction project. The requirement of this subsection shall be in addition to the requirements of subsection (5) of this section. </section><section prefix="5">The department shall notify the fiscal court of the county at least four (4) months before it eliminates a road, road segment, bridge, or street in that county from the state primary road system. Upon receiving notice, the fiscal court may reject title and notify the department that the road shall not become part of the county road system. If the fiscal court declines, the department shall give notice to all private persons entitled to a necessary access over this road of their rights under this chapter; and, by petition of any private party entitled to such access, the road shall be deemed a discontinued state road and shall be closed to public use but remain open in accordance with its condition and use for the access of the private parties involved. In the absence of such petition, title shall be transferred to the owner or owners of the tract or tracts of land to which the road originally belonged. </section><section prefix="6">As used in this section, the term "rural secondary roads" shall mean the system of roads in this state which are usually considered farm-to-market roads and that are classified as part of the rural secondary road system by the Department of Highways. The roads in the rural secondary system shall be maintained with the proceeds of the provisions of KRS 177.320(1) and in no case shall the rural secondary system, as defined in this subsection, be less than eleven thousand eight hundred (11,800) miles. </section><section prefix="7">The establishment, construction, or maintenance of the state primary road system shall be under the direction and control of the Department of Highways. The commissioner of highways is authorized to adopt regulations necessary to the administration of this authority. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 13, sec. 9, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 98, sec. 6, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 174, sec. 18, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 243, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. IV, sec. 20(1). -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 242, sec. 1. -- Created 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 23, secs. 2 and 3. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><former-history>Repealed 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 3. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 4356t-5, 4356t-17-2a, 4356t-17-2b, 4356t-17-2c, 4356t-17-2d. </former-history><former-history-former-name>KRS 177.020: </former-history-former-name><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5231</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>