<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VII" order_by="7">PUBLIC PROPERTY AND PUBLIC PRINTING</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="58" order_by="58">ACQUISITION AND DEVELOPMENT OF PUBLIC PROJECTS THROUGH REVENUE BONDS </unit></structure><section_number>58.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in KRS 58.010 to 58.140, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Public project" means any lands, buildings, or structures, works or facilities (a) suitable for and intended for use as public property for public purposes or suitable for and intended for use in the promotion of the public health, public welfare or the conservation of natural resources, including medical office buildings contiguous to hospital facilities, and shall also include the planning of any such lands, buildings, structures, works or facilities; or (b) suitable for and intended for use for the purpose of creating or increasing the public recreational, cultural and related business facilities of a community, including such structures as concert halls, museums, stadiums, theaters and other public facilities, together with related and appurtenant parking garages, offices and office buildings for rental in whole or in part to private tenants, dwelling units and apartment buildings for rental in whole or in part to private tenants, commercial and retail businesses, stores or other establishments, and any structure or structures or combination of the foregoing, or other structures having as their primary purpose the creation, improvement, revitalization, renewal or modernization of a central business or shopping community, and shall also include existing lands, buildings, structures, works and facilities, as well as improvements or additions to any such lands, buildings, structures, works or facilities. </section><section prefix="2">"Public project" as defined herein shall include projects intended for use as public property for public purposes by another governmental agency, including the United States government, other than the governmental agency acquiring the land or constructing the building, structure or facility. </section><section prefix="3">"Governmental agency" means the Commonwealth of Kentucky as such acting by or through any department, instrumentality or agency thereof, or any county, city, agency, or instrumentality, including a regional wastewater commission established under KRS 65.8901 to 65.8923, or other political subdivision of the Commonwealth. </section></text><history>Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch.98, sec.16, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 41, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 1. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 1. -- Created 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39889</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>