<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="281" order_by="281">A COMMERCIAL DRIVER'S LICENSES </unit></structure><section_number>281A.150</section_number><catch_line>Applicants to apply in person -- Fees. </catch_line><order_by>150</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every person seeking a commercial driver's license or a commercial driver's instruction permit shall first apply in person to the circuit clerk of the county in which the applicant resides or in the county where the person is enrolled in a driver training school if the applicant is not a resident. The application shall be in the form prescribed by KRS 281A.140 as provided by the cabinet. Except as provided in KRS 281A.160(6), each time a person applies for a commercial driver's license, an instruction permit, or seeks to upgrade or change his or her commercial driver's license, the person shall be required to: <section prefix="a">Update the application; and </section><section prefix="b">Submit the appropriate fee to the circuit clerk. </section></section><section prefix="2">The cabinet shall set fees by administrative regulation, pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A, for the following applications that shall not exceed: <section prefix="a">Except as provided in paragraph (g) of this subsection, forty dollars ($40) for each application for a commercial driver's license. The fee shall be based on the class, type of license, endorsement, restriction, or tests to be taken; </section><section prefix="b">Thirty-five dollars ($35) for each application for a commercial driver's instruction permit; </section><section prefix="c">Fifteen dollars ($15) for each application for a change or addition in class or type of license, endorsement, or restriction; </section><section prefix="d">Forty dollars ($40) for each application for a duplicate if it is the first duplicate applied for within the time period for which the original license was issued. Sixty dollars ($60) for a second or subsequent duplicate applied for within the time period for which the original license was issued. The fees required for a duplicate shall be in addition to fees charged under subsection (2)(c) of this section; </section><section prefix="e">Thirty-five dollars ($35) for each application for renewal of a commercial driver's license; </section><section prefix="f">Sixty dollars ($60) for each application for a transfer of a commercial driver's license; and </section><section prefix="g">Twenty dollars ($20) for each application for an initial and renewal commercial driver's license with an "S" endorsement. </section></section><section prefix="3">All fees remitted to the clerk shall be nonrefundable regardless of whether the applicant completes the requirements for a commercial driver's license or is tested. </section><section prefix="4">All fees collected for the issuance of a commercial driver's license or a commercial driver's instruction permit shall be deposited into trust and agency accounts to be used exclusively for the administration and implementation of this chapter, except as prescribed in subsection (5) of this section. The accounts shall not lapse but shall be continuing from year to year. </section><section prefix="5">All fees collected pursuant to this section, shall be allocated between the Transportation Cabinet and Department of Kentucky State Police, except a fifty cent ($0.50) issuance fee shall be allocated during the first two (2) years following the effective date of January 1, 1991, to the Administrative Office of the Courts in a trust and agency account for the use of the circuit clerks and thereafter allocated to the general fund from issuance of a commercial driver's license permit. A three dollar ($3) issuance fee shall be allocated during the first two (2) years following the effective date of January 1, 1991, to the Administrative Office of the Courts in a trust and agency account for the use of the circuit clerks and thereafter allocated to the general fund from issuance of a commercial driver's license. </section><section prefix="6">Any applicant who seeks reinstatement of his or her commercial driving privilege after a suspension, withdrawal, revocation, or disqualification shall pay a reinstatement fee of fifty dollars ($50) in addition to those fees required by subsection (2) of this section and shall satisfy the requirements of KRS 281A.160. This fee shall not be required if his or her commercial driving privilege was withdrawn only as a result of the withdrawal of his or her privilege to drive a noncommercial motor vehicle. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 28, sec. 4, effective June 26, 2007; and ch. 85, sec. 287, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 204, sec. 7, effective April 5, 2002. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 2, effective February 20, 1992; and ch. 274, sec. 4, effective April 7, 1992. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 455, sec. 15, effective January 1, 1991. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><lrc-note> (6/26/2007).  This section was amended by 2007 Ky. Acts chs. 28 and 85, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14474</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>