<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17-040</section_number><catch_line>Required provisions -- Captions -- Omissions -- Substitutions. </catch_line><order_by>17-040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided in subsection (2) of this section, each such policy delivered or issued for delivery to any person in this state shall contain the provisions specified in KRS 304.17-050 to 304.17-160, inclusive, in the words in which the same appear; except, that the insurer may at its option, substitute for one (1) or more of such provisions corresponding provisions of different wording approved by the commissioner which are in each instance not less favorable in any respect to the insured or the beneficiary. Each such provision shall be preceded individually by the applicable caption shown, or, at the option of the insurer, by such appropriate individual or group captions or subcaptions as the commissioner may approve. </section><section prefix="2">If any such provision is in whole or in part inapplicable to or inconsistent with the coverage provided by a particular form of policy, the insurer, with the approval of the commissioner, shall omit from such policy any inapplicable provision or part of a provision, and shall modify any inconsistent provision or part of a provision in such manner as to make the provision as contained in the policy consistent with the coverage provided by the policy. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1202, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 301, subtit. 17, sec. 4, effective June 18, 1970. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:06</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17289</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>