<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXII" order_by="32">OWNERSHIP AND CONVEYANCE OF PROPERTY</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="381" order_by="381">TITLE TO PROPERTY AND RESTRICTIONS ON USE, OWNERSHIP, AND ALIENATION </unit></structure><section_number>381.9193</section_number><catch_line>Lien for assessments.   </catch_line><order_by>9193</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The association shall have a lien on a unit for any assessment levied against that unit or fines imposed against its unit owner from the time the assessment or fine becomes due and, if the assessment is payable in installments, the lien shall be for the full amount of the assessment at the time the first installment becomes due. The association's lien may be foreclosed in like manner as a mortgage on real estate. Unless the declaration otherwise provides, fees, charges, late charges, reasonable collection costs, attorney fees, fines, and interest charged pursuant to KRS 381.9167(1)(j) to (l), shall be secured by the lien and enforceable as assessments under this section. </section><section prefix="2">A lien under this section shall take priority over all other liens and encumbrances on a unit, except: <section prefix="a">Liens and encumbrances recorded before the recordation of the declaration; </section><section prefix="b">A mortgage on the unit recorded before the date on which the assessment sought to be enforced became delinquent; and </section><section prefix="c">Liens for real estate taxes and other governmental assessments or charges against the unit. </section></section><section prefix="3">Unless the declaration otherwise provides, if two (2) or more associations have liens for assessments created at any time on the same real estate, those liens shall have equal priority. </section><section prefix="4">Recording of the declaration constitutes record notice and perfection of the lien. No further recordation of any claim of lien for assessment under this section shall be required. </section><section prefix="5">A lien for unpaid assessments shall be extinguished unless proceedings to enforce the lien are instituted within five (5) years after the full amount of the assessments becomes due. </section><section prefix="6">Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit actions or suits to recover sums for which subsection (1) of this section creates a lien or to prohibit an association from taking a deed in lieu of foreclosure. </section><section prefix="7">A judgment or decree in any action brought under this section shall include costs and reasonable attorney's fees for the prevailing party. </section><section prefix="8">The association shall, upon written request, provide a unit owner a recordable statement setting forth the amount of unpaid assessments against his or her unit. The statement shall be delivered within ten (10) business days after receipt of the request and shall be binding on the association, the executive board, and every unit owner. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 97, sec. 47, effective January 1, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36861</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>