<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.7043</section_number><catch_line>Purposes of KRS 65.7041 to 65.7083.   </catch_line><order_by>7043</order_by><text>The purposes of KRS 65.7041 to 65.7083 are as follows: <section prefix="1">KRS 65.7047 provides authority for cities and counties to establish local development areas for the development of previously undeveloped land within their jurisdictional boundaries and to devote local resources to support the development of projects in those local development areas. Local development areas established under KRS 65.7047 and projects within local development areas shall not be eligible for participation by the Commonwealth; and </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">KRS 65.7049, 65.7051, and 65.7053 provide a framework for cities and counties: <section prefix="1">To establish development areas for: <section prefix="a">The redevelopment of previously developed land within their jurisdictional boundaries; and </section><section prefix="b">The development of previously undeveloped land, if: i. The project proposed for the development area includes an  arena as part of the proposed development; ii. The project is a mixed-use development located in a  university research park; iii. The project is a mixed-use development located within three </section></section></section></section><section prefix="3">miles of a military base that houses, deploys, or employs </section>any combination of at least twenty-five thousand  (25,000) military personnel, their families, military retirees,  or civilian employees; or iv. The project is a mixed-use development which includes either or both significant public storm water and sanitary sewer facilities designed to comply with a community-wide court decree mandating corrective action by the local government or an agency thereof; and 2. To devote local resources to providing redevelopment assistance and supporting projects in those development areas. (b) Projects within development areas established pursuant to KRS 65.7049, 65.7051, and 65.7053 shall be eligible for participation by the Commonwealth if such projects meet the requirements for Commonwealth participation established by Subchapter 30 of KRS Chapter 154. </text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 1, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2009 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 56, effective June 26, 2009. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 178, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 2, effective March 23, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42363</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>