<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="35" order_by="35">MILITARY JUSTICE </unit></structure><section_number>35.725</section_number><catch_line>Frauds against the government.   </catch_line><order_by>725</order_by><text>Any person subject to this code who: <section prefix="1">Knowing it to be false or fraudulent: <section prefix="a">Makes any claim against the United States, the state, or any officer thereof; or </section><section prefix="b">Presents to any person in the civil or military service thereof, for approval or payment, any claim against the United States, the state, or any officer thereof; </section></section><section prefix="2">For the purposes of obtaining the approval, allowance, or payment of any claim against the United States, the state, or any officer thereof: <section prefix="a">Makes or uses any writing or other paper knowing it to contain any false or fraudulent statements; </section><section prefix="b">Makes any oath, affirmation, or certification to any fact or to any writing or other paper knowing the oath, affirmation, or certification to be false; or </section><section prefix="c">Forges or counterfeits any signature upon any writing or other paper, or uses any such signature knowing it to be forged or counterfeited; </section></section><section prefix="3">Having charge, possession, custody, or control of any money, or other property of the United States or the state, furnished or intended for the Armed Forces of the United States or the state military forces, knowingly delivers to any person having authority to receive it, any amount thereof less than that for which he or she receives a certificate or receipt; or </section><section prefix="4">Being authorized to make or deliver any paper certifying the receipt of any property of the United States or the state, furnished or intended for the Armed Forces of the United States or the state military forces, makes or delivers to any person such writing without having full knowledge of the truth of the statements therein contained and with intent to defraud the United States or the state; </section>shall, upon conviction, be punished as a court-martial may direct. </text><history> Created 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 136, effective June 25, 2013. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42019</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>