<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.071</section_number><catch_line>Delegation of taking evidence and writing recommendation of disposition to hearing officer or panel -- Compensatory time for staff conducting school facility public hearings. </catch_line><order_by>071</order_by><text>The Kentucky Board of Education may, any statute to the contrary notwithstanding, delegate the taking of evidence, and the rendition of a written recommendation of disposition to the full board, to a panel of the board, to a single member of the board acting as a hearing officer, or to a hearing officer appointed by the board relative to any hearing, appeal, or decision, judicial or quasi-judicial in nature, which the board is empowered or directed, by this or any other chapter, to conduct, hear, or make; provided, the full board, as provided by statute, makes the final decision or determination, based upon the evidence submitted. For the purpose of serving as a hearing officer for the board, the board and the Department of Education shall not enter into a personal service contract; employ additional staff; or provide additional compensation to existing staff, except for compensatory time for staff who conduct school facility public hearings outside of their regular working hours. </text><history>Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 147, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Repealed and reenacted 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 364, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 349, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3109</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>