<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="351" order_by="351">DEPARTMENT FOR NATURAL RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>351.140</section_number><catch_line>Duties and authority of mine inspectors -- Frequency of inspections. </catch_line><order_by>140</order_by><text>Each mine inspector shall give his entire time and attention to the duties of his office, which shall consist of the following: <section prefix="1">Inspecting mines and aiding, under the direction of the commissioner, in carrying out and enforcing the provisions of the law relating to the inspection of mines; </section><section prefix="2">Training officials and workmen in and about the mines in first aid and mine rescue methods; </section><section prefix="3">Advising officials and workmen in methods pertaining to safety in all its phases and in methods pertaining to the prevention of mine fires and explosions; </section><section prefix="4">Taking charge of mine rescue and recovery work whenever a mine fire, mine explosion or other serious accident occurs within his district, and the commissioner is not present, and assisting in such work in other districts when so directed by the commissioner; </section><section prefix="5">Reopening mines or portions of mines that have been sealed on account of fire or any other cause, when directed by the commissioner to do so; </section><section prefix="6">Inspecting each underground coal mine in his district at least six (6) times a year and all other mines once every six (6) months. For underground coal mines, two (2) of the six (6) general inspections conducted annually shall be full electrical inspections. The commissioner may cause inspections more often if practicable and if funds permit, and whenever any danger to the workmen may exist; making a personal examination of the interior of each mine with respect to ventilation, drainage, roof control, blasting, electricity, escapeways, and general security, and also a personal examination of the outside facilities of the mine; and in gassy mines below the water table, inspections shall be more frequent, and as often as practical whenever any danger to workmen is indicated by a previous inspection. Such inspections shall involve at least two (2) inspectors. The inspectors shall locate themselves in different sections of the mine in order to determine the effectiveness and reliability of the ventilation system. Each section of the mine shall be so inspected; </section><section prefix="7">It shall be permissible for a mine inspector to inspect any coal preparation plant or surface facility of any mining operation of coal including any overland coal belts; and </section><section prefix="8">A mine inspector shall have the express authority to enter upon the premises of and inspect any coal mine, including any overland coal belts, at any reasonable time. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 94, sec. 9, effective January 1, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 185, sec. 10, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 14, effective April 9, 1996. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 301, sec. 7, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 8, sec. 18. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 174, sec. 3. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 298, sec. 11. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 11, effective March 5, 1952. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 3. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739-17, 2739-18. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2009 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, A, 13, (16) at 614.  See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, E, 3, (2) at 637. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><lrc-note> (4/9/96).  The action taken with respect to this statute by 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 308 was to have become effective April 8, 1996, under Section 51 of that Act. The Act, however, did not become effective until April 9, 1996, when the Governor's signed copy of the Act was filed with the Secretary of State. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32923</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>