<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="508" order_by="508">ASSAULT AND RELATED OFFENSES </unit></structure><section_number>508.130</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 508.130 to 508.150.  (Effective January 1, 2016)</catch_line><order_by>130</order_by><text>As used in KRS 508.130 to 508.150, unless the context requires otherwise:(1)(a)To "stalk" means to engage in an intentional course of conduct:1.Directed at a specific person or persons;2.Which seriously alarms, annoys, intimidates, or harasses the personor persons; and3.Which serves no legitimate purpose.(b)The course of conduct shall be that which would cause a reasonableperson to suffer substantial mental distress.(2)"Course of conduct" means a pattern of conduct composed of two (2) or moreacts, evidencing a continuity of purpose. One (1) or more of these acts mayinclude the use of any equipment, instrument, machine, or other device bywhich communication or information is transmitted, including computers, theInternet or other electronic network, cameras or other recording devices,telephones or other personal communications devices, scanners or othercopying devices, and any device that enables the use of a transmitting device.Constitutionally protected activity is not included within the meaning of "courseof conduct." If the defendant claims that he was engaged in constitutionallyprotected activity, the court shall determine the validity of that claim as a matterof law and, if found valid, shall exclude that activity from evidence.(3)"Protective order" means:(a)An emergency protective order or domestic violence order issued underKRS 403.715 to 403.785;(b)A foreign protective order, as defined in KRS 403.720 and 456.010;(c)An order issued under KRS 431.064;(d)A restraining order issued in accordance with KRS 508.155;(e)An order of protection as defined in KRS 403.720 and 456.010; and(f)Any condition of a bond, conditional release, probation, parole, or pretrialdiversion order designed to protect the victim from the offender.</text><history>Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 45, effective January 1, 2016. --Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended2002 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky.Acts ch. 401, sec. 13, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 443,sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44793</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>