<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="12" order_by="12">ADMINISTRATIVE ORGANIZATION </unit></structure><section_number>12.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>In this chapter, and throughout the Kentucky Revised Statutes where applicable and appropriate unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Organizational unit" means any unit of organization in the executive branch of the state government that is not an administrative body, including but not limited to any agency, program cabinet, department, bureau, division, section or office; </section><section prefix="2">"Department" means that basic unit of administrative organization of state government, by whatever name called, designated by statute or by statutorily authorized executive action as a "department," such organization to be headed by a commissioner; </section><section prefix="3">"Division" means a major subdivision of a department established by statute or by statutorily authorized administrative action, such to be headed by a director; </section><section prefix="4">"Branch" means a small grouping of logical workforce personnel, such to be headed by a manager; </section><section prefix="5">"Section" means a smaller grouping within a branch, such to be headed by a supervisor; </section><section prefix="6">"Unit" means the smallest grouping of coordinated employees, such to be headed by a leader; </section><section prefix="7">"Office" means a staff support or administrative function and shall be a major subdivision of a program cabinet only, such to be headed by an executive director; </section><section prefix="8">"Administrative body" means any multi-member body in the executive branch of the state government, including but not limited to any board, council, commission, committee, authority or corporation, but does not include "branch," "section," "unit" or "office"; </section><section prefix="9">"Program cabinet" means a group of departments, or departments and administrative bodies, designated by statute or statutorily authorized executive action as a "program cabinet." </section></text><history>Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 393,sec. 3, effective July 15, 1982; and ch. 447, sec. 1, effective April 12, 1982. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. I, sec. 4. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 106, Art. I, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4618-69. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1982</effective><lrc-note>This section was amended by two 1982 Acts which do not appear to be in conflict and have been compiled together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:13</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=618</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>