<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.982</section_number><catch_line>Grant program eligibility and compliance. </catch_line><order_by>982</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Subject to available funds, a nonprofit organization is eligible to receive a grant under KRS 247.980 to 247.986 if the organization: <section prefix="a">Has at least five (5) years of experience coordinating a statewide network of food banks and charitable organizations that serve counties of this state; </section><section prefix="b">Operates a program that coordinates the collection and transportation of surplus agricultural commodities to a statewide network of food banks that provide food to needy or low-income individuals; and </section><section prefix="c">Submits to the department, in a manner and time prescribed by the department, a proposal for the collection and distribution of agricultural commodities to food banks and other charitable organizations for use in providing food for needy or low-income individuals, including: <section prefix="1">A description of the proposal; </section><section prefix="2">A schedule of projected costs for the proposal; </section><section prefix="3">Measurable goals for the proposal; and </section><section prefix="4">A plan for evaluating the success of the proposal. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">A nonprofit organization that receives a grant under KRS 247.980 to 247.986 shall comply with the following requirements: <section prefix="a">Purchases shall be made from Kentucky farmers, growers, and vendors; </section><section prefix="b">Agricultural commodities collected and distributed shall be culls or those designated as surplus or unmarketable, and not primary agricultural commodities. Surplus or unmarketable agricultural commodities or culls shall be purchased at production cost or below market price from produce auctions, farmers, growers, and vendors; and </section><section prefix="c">Donations of culls or surplus or unmarketable agricultural commodities from farmers' markets, cooperatives, farmers, and growers shall be encouraged. Persons making the donations may be reimbursed for picking, packaging, processing, transportation, storage, distribution, or other costs. </section></section></text><history> Created 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 3, effective June 25, 2009. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11884</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>