<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="236" order_by="236">BOILER AND PRESSURE VESSEL SAFETY </unit></structure><section_number>236.250</section_number><catch_line>Exceptions to permit requirements -- Payment of permit to repair fees -- Emergency repairs.   </catch_line><order_by>250</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall make repairs affecting the strength or safety of boilers or pressure vessels without first securing a permit from the department unless repairs have been authorized by a boiler inspector or special boiler inspector pending issuance of the permit or unless such repairs are emergency repairs authorized by the department, a special boiler inspector or a boiler inspector pending issuance of the permit. No permit will be required for emergency items not affecting the strength of the boiler or pressure vessel, when performed by qualified welders regularly employed by firms utilizing properly qualified welding procedures. Permits shall only be issued to persons licensed under the provisions of this chapter. A permit fee shall be paid directly to the department, and shall accompany the repair application. </section><section prefix="2">Payment of permit to repair fees shall be required from operating companies performing pressure vessel repairs in accordance with the National Board of Boiler and Pressure Vessel Inspectors inspection code and utilizing properly qualified welding procedures and regularly employing qualified welders to weld on boilers owned and operated by such firm. </section><section prefix="3">For emergency repairs authorized by a boiler inspector or special boiler inspector, a repair permit shall be obtained and filed with the department within thirty (30) days of repair completion. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 17, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 530, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 207, sec. 19, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 209, sec. 6. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:37</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40120</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>