<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="344" order_by="344">CIVIL RIGHTS </unit></structure><section_number>344.210</section_number><catch_line>Notice of complaint -- Hearing procedures. </catch_line><order_by>210</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Within sixty (60) days after a complaint other than a complaint alleging a discriminatory housing practice is filed, unless the commission has issued an order dismissing the complaint or stating the terms of a conciliation agreement or within thirty (30) days after an application for review is filed under subsection (3) of KRS 344.200, the commission shall serve on the respondent by certified mail a written notice, together with a copy of the complaint as it may have been amended, requiring the respondent to answer the allegations of the complaint at a hearing held in accordance with this chapter and the provisions of KRS Chapter 13B. A copy of the notice shall be furnished to the complainant, the Attorney General, and any other public officers and persons that the commission deems proper. </section><section prefix="2">A member of the commission who filed the complaint or endeavored to eliminate the alleged unlawful practice by conference, conciliation, or persuasion shall not participate in the hearing or in the subsequent deliberation of the commission. </section><section prefix="3">The respondent shall file an answer with the commission by certified mail within twenty (20) days after receipt by the respondent of service under KRS 344.200. The commission or the complainant may amend a complaint and the respondent may amend an answer at any time prior to the issuance of final order pursuant to this section based on the complaint, but no final order shall be issued unless the respondent has had the opportunity of a hearing on the complaint or amendment on which the final order is based. </section><section prefix="4">An administrative hearing on a discriminatory housing practice shall be held pursuant to this section and KRS 344.640 and administrative regulations promulgated pursuant to this chapter. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 318, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 378, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 282, sec. 15, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 96, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 2, Art. 5, sec. 504. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32624</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>