<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="81" order_by="81">A ANNEXATION </unit></structure><section_number>81A.510</section_number><catch_line>Annexation of unincorporated territory in which industrial plants are located -- Public policy stated -- Prerequisites -- Protest and hearing. </catch_line><order_by>510</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The General Assembly, recognizing that the general welfare and prosperity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky is very greatly dependent upon continued industrial development and expansion; and, further recognizing that reasonable assurances of fair treatment will greatly increase industrial development and expansion in Kentucky, it hereby is declared to be the public policy of the Commonwealth of Kentucky to encourage the location of new industries and the expansion of existing industries in Kentucky by prohibiting unfair and unreasonable annexation by municipal corporations of industries now or hereafter located in unincorporated areas. However, it is not the intent of the General Assembly to prohibit, restrict or hamper normal expansion of municipal boundaries if such normal development and expansion extends to and embraces such industrial properties. </section><section prefix="2">No unincorporated territory in which is located an industrial plant or plants shall be annexed by any municipality unless such territory is embraced within a broad, comprehensive plan of annexation. The territory to be annexed shall be contiguous to the boundary line or lines of such municipality, and the territory or area to be annexed shall be both compact and contiguous. The number of registered voters duly qualified to vote in the territory proposed to be annexed shall equal or exceed fifty percent (50%) of the average number of persons employed by industrial plants within such territory during the next preceding calendar year, the number of such registered voters to be determined by taking the total of such voters from the last closed registration books in the county clerk's office. </section><section prefix="3">Nothing herein shall be construed as prohibiting any municipality from annexing any industrial plant or plants or its properties if the duly authorized representatives of such industrial plant or plants consent to or request such action. </section><section prefix="4">Any person or persons within the area proposed to be annexed shall have the right to file a protest and to have the protest heard and determined as now provided by existing statutes. </section></text><history>Created 1956 (4th Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 1, effective May 2, 1956. </history><metadata><effective>May 2, 1956 </effective><former-codification> KRS 81.280. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:11</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=25021</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>