<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="341" order_by="341">UNEMPLOYMENT COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>341.070</section_number><catch_line>Subject employer. </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context clearly requires otherwise, "subject employer" means: <section prefix="1">Any employing unit which in any calendar quarter in either the current or preceding calendar year paid for service in covered employment wages of fifteen hundred dollars ($1,500) or more. </section><section prefix="2">Any employing unit which for some portion of a day in each of twenty (20) different calendar weeks, whether or not such weeks are consecutive, in either the current or the preceding calendar year, had in covered employment at least one (1) worker (irrespective of whether the same worker was in employment in each such day). </section><section prefix="3">Any employing unit for which service in covered employment, as defined in paragraph (d) of subsection (1) of KRS 341.050, is performed. </section><section prefix="4">Any employing unit for which service in covered employment, as defined in paragraph (e) or (h) of subsection (1) of KRS 341.050, is performed. </section><section prefix="5">Any employing unit for which service in covered employment, as defined in paragraph (f) or (h) of subsection (1) of KRS 341.050, is performed. </section><section prefix="6">Any employing unit for which service in covered employment, as defined in paragraph (g) or (h) of subsection (1) of KRS 341.050, is performed. </section><section prefix="7">Any employing unit that succeeds to or acquires the organization, trade, or business, or substantially all of the assets of another employing unit which at the time of such succession or acquisition is a subject employer, or which succeeds to or acquires a portion of the organization, trade, or business of another employing unit, which portion, if treated as a separate employing unit, would be, at the time of the succession or acquisition, a subject employer under subsection (1), (2), or (5) of this section. </section><section prefix="8">Any employing unit for which service is or was performed with respect to which such employing unit is liable for any federal tax against which credit may be taken for contributions required to be paid into a state unemployment fund; or which, as a condition for approval of this chapter for full tax credit against the tax imposed by the Federal Unemployment Tax Act, is required, pursuant to such act, to be a "subject employer" under this chapter. </section><section prefix="9">Any employing unit which has elected to become subject to this chapter, pursuant to subsection (3) of KRS 341.250. </section><section prefix="10">For purposes of subsections (1) through (6) of this section, covered employment shall include service which would constitute covered employment but for the fact that such service is deemed to be performed entirely within another state pursuant to an election under an arrangement entered into (in accordance with KRS 341.145) by the secretary and an agency charged with the administration of any other state or federal unemployment compensation law. </section><section prefix="11">Any employing unit which, having become a subject employer under subsections (1) through (9) of this section, has not ceased to be a subject employer under KRS 341.250. </section><section prefix="12">For purposes of subsections (2), (4), and (5) of this section, if any week includes both December 31 and January 1, the days of that week up to January 1 shall be deemed one (1) calendar week and the days beginning January 1 another week. </section><section prefix="13">Notwithstanding the provisions of this section or any other provision of this chapter, no employing unit shall be initially determined a subject employer on the basis of covered employment performed more than five (5) calendar years prior to the year in which such determination is made, unless the secretary can show that the records of such employment experience were fraudulently concealed or withheld for the purpose of escaping liability under this chapter. </section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 389, sec. 9, effective July 1, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(21). -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 21, sec. 5. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 1. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 5. -- Amended 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 1. -- Amended 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 216, sec. 2. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4748g-3. </history><metadata><effective>July 1, 1978</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32241</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>