<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.990</section_number><catch_line>Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>990</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person who violates any of the provisions of KRS 186.020, 186.030, 186.040, 186.045(4), 186.050, 186.056, 186.060, 186.073, 186.110, 186.130, 186.140, 186.160, 186.170, 186.180(1) to (4)(a), 186.210(1), 186.230, or KRS 186.655 to 186.680 shall be guilty of a violation. </section><section prefix="2">Any person who violates any of the provisions of KRS 138.465, 186.072, 186.190, 186.200, or 186.210(2) shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="3">A person who violates the provisions of KRS 186.450(4), (5), or (6) or 186.452(3), </section><section prefix="4">, or (5) shall be guilty of a violation. A person who violates any of the other </section>provisions of KRS 186.400 to 186.640 shall be guilty of a Class B misdemeanor. (4) Any clerk or judge failing to comply with KRS 186.550(1) shall be guilty of a violation. <section prefix="5">If it appears to the satisfaction of the trial court that any offender under KRS 186.400 to 186.640 has a driver's license but in good faith failed to have it on his or her person or misplaced or lost it, the court may, in its discretion, dismiss the charges against the defendant without fine, imprisonment, or cost. </section><section prefix="6">Any person who steals a motor vehicle registration plate or renewal decal shall be guilty of a Class D felony. Displaying a canceled registration plate on a motor vehicle shall be prima facie evidence of guilt under this section. </section><section prefix="7">Any person who violates the provisions of KRS 186.1911 shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="8">Any person who makes a false affidavit to secure a license plate under KRS 186.172 shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="9">Any person who violates any provision of KRS 186.070 or 186.150 shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="10">Any person who operates a vehicle bearing a dealer's plate upon the highways of this Commonwealth with intent to evade the motor vehicle usage tax or registration fee shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor for the first offense and a Class D felony for each subsequent offense. </section><section prefix="11">Any person, other than a licensed dealer or manufacturer, who procures a dealer's plate with intent to evade the motor vehicle usage tax or registration fee shall be guilty of a Class D felony. </section><section prefix="12">Any resident who unlawfully registers, titles, or licenses a motor vehicle in any state other than Kentucky with intent to evade the motor vehicle usage tax or the registration fee shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor if the amount of tax due is less than one hundred dollars ($100), or of a Class D felony if the amount of tax due is more than one hundred dollars ($100), and in addition shall be liable for all taxes so evaded with applicable interest and penalties. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 15, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2008; and 176, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 8, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 103, sec. 5, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 441, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 198, sec. 17, effective October 1, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 463, sec. 20, July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 104, effective July 1, 1987; ch. 431, sec. 14, effective July 15, 1986; and ch. 498, sec. 6, effective April 1, 1987. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 373, sec. 7(1) to(9), effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 303, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 296, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1979 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 2, effective July 1, 1979. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 58. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 83, sec. 2. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 37, sec. 5. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 70, sec. 28. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 4. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739g-5c, 2739g-6, 2739g-7, 2739g-65, 2739g-103, 2739g-104, 2739m-36, 2739m-48, 2739m-59, 2739m-69. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><lrc-note>(7/15/2008).  This section was amended by 2008 Ky. Acts chs. 15 and 176, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together.(6/24/2003).  2000 Ky. Acts ch. 408, sec. 178, renumbered the former subsection (2) of KRS 186.045 as subsection (1), but that Act failed to include a conforming amendment to change the reference to that subsection in subsection (1) of this statute. Under KRS 7.136(1)(e), that change has now been made. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6128</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>