<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIII" order_by="33">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS AND ESTATES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="387" order_by="387">GUARDIANS -- CONSERVATORS -- CURATORS OF CONVICTS </unit></structure><section_number>387.290</section_number><catch_line>Curator for convict -- Appointment -- Powers and duties. </catch_line><order_by>290</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The District Court of the county from which the convict was sent to the penitentiary, or of the county of his residence if he had one in this state, may, upon the application of anyone interested, appoint a suitable curator of the estate of any person over the age of twenty-one (21) years confined in the penitentiary. </section><section prefix="2">If the convict has a spouse the District Court shall appoint the spouse curator if the spouse can give satisfactory security, and if not, then the person the spouse selects in person or by written direction to the court. </section><section prefix="3">The curator shall execute a bond similar to that required of curators in a case of contest concerning a will. He shall be clothed with like powers, have like privileges, discharge like duties, and be liable to like responsibilities as are provided in the case of the curator of an estate pending a contest concerning a will, except that he shall, out of the effects held by him, provide for the support of the family and the education of the minor children of the convict. He shall expend in these respects the sum authorized by the District Court, and he shall account with the convict when he is discharged from the penitentiary. </section></text><history>Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 343, effective January 2, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 386, sec. 71. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 1383, 1384, 1385. </history><metadata><effective>January 2, 1978</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36034</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>