<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="227" order_by="227">FIRE PREVENTION AND PROTECTION -- ELECTRICIANS </unit></structure><section_number>227.555</section_number><catch_line>Smoke-detector and egress requirements for manufactured or mobile homes -- Notices of requirements and penalty -- Limitation on enforceability -- Relationship to local ordinances -- Specific penalty. </catch_line><order_by>555</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every manufactured or mobile home as defined in KRS 227.550 shall have: <section prefix="a">At least one (1) working smoke detector located inside the home near the bedroom areas on each floor level; and </section><section prefix="b">At least two (2) operable means of egress, if the home was originally equipped with at least two (2) means. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction, through the promulgation of administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A, shall design and cause to be placed: <section prefix="a">At each vehicle entrance to a manufactured home park or community as defined in KRS 219.320, a notice stating the requirements set out in subsection (1) of this section, the penalty for noncompliance set out in subsection (5) of this section, and any other information it deems necessary to effect the purposes of this section; and </section><section prefix="b">In each county clerk's office, a notice stating the requirements set out in subsection (1) of this section, the penalty for noncompliance set out in subsection (5) of this section, and any other information it deems necessary to effect the purposes of this section. </section></section><section prefix="3">No public servant with the authority to issue a citation shall enter a manufactured or mobile home solely for the purpose of determining whether or not the manufactured or mobile home is in compliance with this section. </section><section prefix="4">No ordinance contrary to subsections (1) and (3) of this section may be enacted by any unit of local government, and the provisions of subsections (1) and (3) shall supersede any local ordinance to the contrary. The provisions of this subsection shall not apply to any city which has adopted or may in the future adopt the Uniform Residential Landlord and Tenant Act under KRS Chapter 383. </section><section prefix="5">The owners of manufactured homes and mobile homes located within a manufactured home park or community which do not comply with subsection (1) of this section shall be responsible for the correction of any violation. </section><section prefix="6">Any person who violates subsection (1) of this section shall be guilty of a violation. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 412, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 74, sec. 2, effective July 13, 2004. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 66, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10678</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>