<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="18" order_by="18">A STATE PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>18A.015</section_number><catch_line>Creation of Personnel Cabinet -- Provision for administrative costs. </catch_line><order_by>015</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There shall be created by KRS 18A.005 to 18A.200 a Personnel Cabinet headed by a secretary who shall be appointed by the Governor. </section><section prefix="2">Appropriations shall be made from the general expenditure fund to the cabinet to meet the estimated pro rata share of the cost of administering the provisions of this chapter for departments, commissions, boards, or agencies which receive their sole support from the general expenditure fund. </section><section prefix="3">The secretary shall maintain accurate records reflecting the cost of administering the provisions of this chapter. At the close of each quarter year period he shall summarize the cost and shall bill each department, commission, board, or agency which receives support from sources other than the general expenditure fund, except the Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources, for a pro rata share of the administrative cost based on the relationship between the quarterly average number of employees in the service of such department, commission, board, or agency and the quarterly average number of employees in the service of all the departments, commissions, boards, and agencies for the appropriate calendar quarter. </section><section prefix="4">All departments, commissions, boards, or agencies which receive support from other than the general expenditure fund, except the Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources, shall include in their budgets sufficient amounts to meet their pro rata shares of the cost of administering KRS 18A.005 to 18A.200 and shall remit such shares quarterly to the department in the manner provided by law. </section><section prefix="5">The cabinet is authorized and directed to accept on behalf of the state any grant or contribution, federal or otherwise, made to assist in meeting the cost of carrying out the purposes of KRS 18A.005 to 18A.200. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1998. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended as KRS 18A.015, 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 448, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 3, effective June 17, 1978; and ch. 269, sec. 3, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 86, sec. 4, effective March 29, 1976. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 9. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 13, sec. 3. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 63, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, C, 2, (2) at 628.  See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, D, 10, (1) at 636. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><former-codification> KRS 18.160. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1339</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>