<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="278" order_by="278">PUBLIC SERVICE COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>278.216</section_number><catch_line>Site compatibility certificate -- Site assessment report -- Commission action on application. </catch_line><order_by>216</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except for a utility as defined under KRS 278.010(9) that has been granted a certificate of public convenience and necessity prior to April 15, 2002, no utility shall begin the construction of a facility for the generation of electricity capable of generating in aggregate more than ten megawatts (10MW) without having first obtained a site compatibility certificate from the commission. </section><section prefix="2">An application for a site compatibility certificate shall include the submission of a site assessment report as prescribed in KRS 278.708(3) and (4), except that a utility which proposes to construct a facility on a site that already contains facilities capable of generating ten megawatts (10MW) or more of electricity shall not be required to comply with setback requirements established pursuant to KRS 278.704(3). A utility may submit and the commission may accept documentation of compliance with the National Environmental Policy Act (NEPA) rather than a site assessment report. </section><section prefix="3">The commission may deny an application filed pursuant to, and in compliance with, this section. The commission may require reasonable mitigation of impacts disclosed in the site assessment report including planting trees, changing outside lighting, erecting noise barriers, and suppressing fugitive dust, but the commission shall, in no event, order relocation of the facility. </section><section prefix="4">The commission may also grant a deviation from any applicable setback requirements on a finding that the proposed facility is designed and located to meet the goals of this section and KRS 224.10-280, 278.010, 278.212, 278.214, 278.218, and 278.700 to 278.716 at a distance closer than those provided by the applicable setback requirements. </section><section prefix="5">Nothing contained in this section shall be construed to limit a utility's exemption provided under KRS 100.324. </section><section prefix="6">Unless specifically stated otherwise, for the purposes of this section, "utility" has the same meaning as in KRS 278.010(3)(a) or (9). </section></text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 3, effective June 24, 2003. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 365, sec. 13, effective April 24, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14078</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>