<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIV" order_by="34">DESCENT, WILLS, AND ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="396" order_by="396">CLAIMS AGAINST DECEDENTS' ESTATES </unit></structure><section_number>396.075</section_number><catch_line>Payment of claims. </catch_line><order_by>075</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon the expiration of six (6) months from the date of his appointment, the personal representative may proceed to pay the claims allowed against the estate in the order of priority prescribed, after making appropriate provision for exemptions and allowances provided by law, for claims already presented which have not yet been allowed and for unbarred claims which may yet be presented, including costs and expenses of administration. By petition to the court in a proceeding for the purpose, a claimant whose claim has been allowed but not paid as provided herein may secure an order directing the personal representative to pay the claim to the extent that funds of the estate are available for the payment. </section><section prefix="2">The personal representative at any time may pay any just claim which has not been barred, with or without formal presentation, but he is personally liable to any other claimant whose claim is allowed and who is injured by such payment if: <section prefix="a">The payment was made before the expiration of the time limit stated in subsection (1) of this section and the personal representative failed to require the payee to give adequate security for the refund of any of the payment necessary to pay other claimants; or </section><section prefix="b">The payment was made, due to the negligence or willful fault of the personal representative, in such manner as to deprive the injured claimant of his priority. </section></section></text><history>Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 90, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1988 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:32</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36418</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>