<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">A DRIVING UNDER THE INFLUENCE </unit></structure><section_number>189A.345</section_number><catch_line>Penalties for violation of KRS 189A.420 governing ignition interlock devices.   </catch_line><order_by>345</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall operate a motor vehicle or motorcycle without a functioning ignition interlock device when prohibited to do so under KRS 189A.420. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">No person shall start a motor vehicle or motorcycle equipped with an ignition interlock device for the purpose of providing an operable motor vehicle or motorcycle to a person subject to the prohibition established in KRS 189A.420. </section><section prefix="b">Any person who violates paragraph (a) of this subsection shall: <section prefix="1">For a first offense, be guilty of a Class B misdemeanor; and </section><section prefix="2">For a second or subsequent offense, be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. </section></section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">No person shall: <section prefix="1">Knowingly install a defective ignition interlock device on a motor vehicle or motorcycle; or </section><section prefix="2">Tamper with an installed ignition interlock device with the intent of rendering it defective. </section></section><section prefix="b">Any person who violates paragraph (a) of this subsection shall: <section prefix="1">For a first offense, be guilty of a Class B misdemeanor; and </section><section prefix="2">For a second or subsequent offense, be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor and be prohibited from installing ignition interlock devices or directing others in the installation of ignition interlock devices. </section></section></section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">No person shall direct another person to install a defective ignition interlock device on a motor vehicle or motorcycle when the person giving the direction knows that the ignition interlock device is defective. </section><section prefix="b">Any person who violates paragraph (a) of this subsection shall: <section prefix="1">For a first offense, be guilty of a Class B misdemeanor; and </section><section prefix="2">For a second or subsequent offense, be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor and be prohibited from directing others in the installation of ignition interlock devices or installing ignition interlock devices. </section></section></section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 124, sec. 9, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 9, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 173, sec. 31, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 171, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 467, sec. 28, effective October 1, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44686</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>