<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="16" order_by="16">STATE POLICE </unit></structure><section_number>16.582</section_number><catch_line>Disability retirement.   </catch_line><order_by>582</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">Total and permanent disability means a disability which results in the member's incapacity to engage in any occupation for remuneration or profit. Loss by severance of both hands at or above the wrists, or both feet at or above the ankles, or one (1) hand above the wrist and one (1) foot above the ankle, or the complete, irrevocable loss of the sight of both eyes shall be considered as total and permanent. </section><section prefix="b">Hazardous disability means a disability which results in the member's total incapacity to continue as a regular full-time officer or as an employee in a hazardous position, as defined in KRS 61.592, but which does not result in the member's total and permanent incapacity to engage in other occupations for remuneration or profit. </section><section prefix="c">In determining whether the disability meets the requirement of this section, any reasonable accommodation provided by the employer as provided in 42 U.S.C. sec. 12111(9) and 29 C.F.R. Part 1630 shall be considered. </section><section prefix="d">If the board determines that the total and permanent disability of a member receiving a retirement allowance under this section has ceased, then the board shall determine if the member has a hazardous disability. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any person may qualify to retire on disability, subject to the following: <section prefix="a">The person shall have sixty (60) months of service, twelve (12) of which shall be current service credited under KRS 16.543(1), 61.543(1), or 78.615(1). The service requirement shall be waived if the disability is a total and permanent disability or a hazardous disability and is a direct result of an act in line of duty; </section><section prefix="b">For a person whose membership date is prior to August 1, 2004, the person shall not be eligible for an unreduced retirement allowance; </section><section prefix="c">The person's application shall be on file in the retirement office no later than twenty-four (24) months after the person's last day of paid employment, as defined in KRS 16.505, as a regular full-time officer or in a regular full-time hazardous position under KRS 61.592; </section><section prefix="d">The person shall receive a satisfactory determination pursuant to KRS 61.665; and </section><section prefix="e">A person's disability application based on the same claim of incapacity shall be accepted and reconsidered for disability if accompanied by new objective medical evidence. The application shall be on file in the retirement office no later than twenty-four (24) months after the person's last day of paid employment as a regular full-time officer or in a regular full-time hazardous position. </section></section><section prefix="3">Upon the examination of the objective medical evidence by licensed physicians pursuant to KRS 61.665, it shall be determined that: <section prefix="a">The incapacity results from bodily injury, mental illness, or disease. For purposes of this section, "injury" means any physical harm or damage to the human organism other than disease or mental illness; </section><section prefix="b">The incapacity is deemed to be permanent; and </section><section prefix="c">The incapacity does not result directly or indirectly from: <section prefix="1">Injury intentionally self-inflicted while sane or insane; </section><section prefix="2">Injury or disease resulting from military service; or </section><section prefix="3">Bodily injury, mental illness, disease, or condition which pre-existed membership in the system or reemployment, whichever is most recent, unless: <section prefix="a">The disability results from bodily injury, mental illness, disease, or a condition which has been substantially aggravated by an injury or accident arising out of or in the course of employment; or </section><section prefix="b">The person has at least sixteen (16) years' current or prior service for employment with employers participating in the retirement systems administered by the Kentucky Retirement Systems. </section></section> For purposes of this subparagraph, "reemployment" shall not mean a change of employment between employers participating in the retirement systems administered by the Kentucky Retirement Systems with no loss of service credit. </section></section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a"><section prefix="1">An incapacity shall be deemed to be permanent if it is expected to result in death or can be expected to last for a continuous period of not less than twelve (12) months from the person's last day of paid employment in a position as regular full-time officer or a hazardous position. </section><section prefix="2">The determination of a permanent incapacity shall be based on the medical evidence contained in the member's file and the member's residual functional capacity and physical exertion requirements. </section></section><section prefix="b">The person's residual functional capacity shall be the person's capacity for work activity on a regular and continuing basis. The person's physical ability shall be assessed in light of the severity of the person's physical, mental, and other impairments. The person's ability to walk, stand, carry, push, pull, reach, handle, and other physical functions shall be considered with regard to physical impairments. The person's ability to understand, remember, and carry out instructions and respond appropriately to supervision, coworkers, and work pressures in a work setting shall be considered with regard to mental impairments. Other impairments, including skin impairments, epilepsy, visual sensory impairments, postural and manipulative limitations, and environmental restrictions, shall be considered in conjunction with the person's physical and mental impairments to determine residual functional capacity. </section><section prefix="c">The person's physical exertion requirements shall be determined based on the following standards: <section prefix="1">Sedentary work shall be work that involves lifting no more than ten (10) pounds at a time and occasionally lifting or carrying articles such as large files, ledgers, and small tools. Although a sedentary job primarily involves sitting, occasional walking and standing may also be required in the performance of duties. </section><section prefix="2">Light work shall be work that involves lifting no more than twenty (20) pounds at a time with frequent lifting or carrying of objects weighing up to ten (10) pounds. A job shall be in this category if lifting is infrequently required but walking and standing are frequently required, or if the job primarily requires sitting with pushing and pulling of arm or leg controls. If the person has the ability to perform substantially all of these activities, the person shall be deemed capable of light work. A person deemed capable of light work shall be deemed capable of sedentary work unless the person has additional limitations such as the loss of fine dexterity or inability to sit for long periods. </section><section prefix="3">Medium work shall be work that involves lifting no more than fifty (50) pounds at a time with frequent lifting or carrying of objects weighing up to twenty-five (25) pounds. If the person is deemed capable of medium work, the person shall be deemed capable of light and sedentary work. </section><section prefix="4">Heavy work shall be work that involves lifting no more than one hundred (100) pounds at a time with frequent lifting or carrying of objects weighing up to fifty (50) pounds. If the person is deemed capable of heavy work, the person shall also be deemed capable of medium, light, and sedentary work. </section><section prefix="5">Very heavy work shall be work that involves lifting objects weighing more than one hundred (100) pounds at a time with frequent lifting or carrying of objects weighing fifty (50) or more pounds. If the person is deemed capable of very heavy work, the person shall be deemed capable of heavy, medium, light, and sedentary work. </section></section></section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">The disability retirement allowance shall be determined as provided in KRS 16.576, except if the member's total service credit on his last day of paid employment in a regular full-time position is less than twenty (20) years, service shall be added beginning with his last date of paid employment and continuing to his fifty-fifth birthday. The maximum service credit added shall not exceed the total service the member had on his last day of paid employment, and the maximum service credit for calculating his retirement allowance, including his total service and service added under this section, shall not exceed twenty (20) years. </section><section prefix="b">For a member whose participation begins on or after August 1, 2004, but prior to January 1, 2014, the disability retirement allowance shall be the higher of twenty-five percent (25%) of the member's monthly final rate of pay or the retirement allowance determined in the same manner as for retirement at his normal retirement date with years of service and final compensation being determined as of the date of his disability. </section><section prefix="c">For a member who begins participating on or after January 1, 2014, in the hybrid cash balance plan as provided by KRS 16.583, the disability retirement allowance shall be the higher of twenty-five percent (25%) of the member's monthly final rate of pay or the retirement allowance determined in the same manner as for retirement at his or her normal retirement date under KRS 16.583. </section></section><section prefix="6">If the member receives a satisfactory determination of total and permanent disability or hazardous disability pursuant to KRS 61.665 and the disability is the direct result of an act in line of duty, the member's retirement allowance shall be calculated as follows: <section prefix="a">For the disabled member, benefits as provided in subsection (5) of this section except that the monthly retirement allowance payable shall not be less than twenty-five percent (25%) of the member's monthly final rate of pay; and </section><section prefix="b">For each dependent child of the member on his disability retirement date, who is alive at the time any particular payment is due, a monthly payment equal to ten percent (10%) of the disabled member's monthly final rate of pay; however, total maximum dependent children's benefit shall not exceed forty percent (40%) of the member's monthly final rate of pay. The payments shall be payable to each dependent child, or to a legally appointed guardian or as directed by the system. </section></section><section prefix="7">No benefit provided in this section shall be reduced as a result of any change in the extent of disability of any retired member who is age fifty-five (55) or older. </section><section prefix="8">If a regular full-time officer or hazardous position member has been approved for benefits under a hazardous disability, the board shall, upon request of the member, permit the member to receive the hazardous disability allowance while accruing benefits in a nonhazardous position, subject to proper medical review of the nonhazardous position's job description by the system's medical examiner. </section><section prefix="9">For a member of the State Police Retirement System, in lieu of the allowance provided in subsection (5) or (6) of this section, the member may be retained on the regular payroll and receive the compensation authorized by KRS 16.165, if he is qualified. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 120, sec. 41, effective July 1, 2013. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 33, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004; and ch. 36, sec. 4, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 385, sec. 4, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 167, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 485, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42669</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>