<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.540</section_number><catch_line>Advisory Council for Medical Assistance -- Membership -- Expenses -- Meetings -- Qualifications of members. </catch_line><order_by>540</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An Advisory Council for Medical Assistance shall be established in the state government. The council shall consist of eighteen (18) members. The secretary for health and family services shall be an ex officio member. The other seventeen (17) members of the council shall be appointed by the Governor and shall hold office for a term of four (4) years and until their successors are appointed and qualify, except that the members appointed to fill the first vacancy occurring for a term beginning on July 1, 1960, shall be as follows: Two (2) members shall be appointed for one (1) year, two (2) for two (2) years, two (2) for three (3) years, and three (3) for four (4) years, and the respective terms of the first members shall be designated by the Governor at the time of their appointments. Upon the expiration of the respective terms of the members first appointed, the term of each successor shall be for four (4) years and until his successor is appointed and qualified. Ten (10) of the appointments shall be made one (1) from each list of three (3) nominees submitted by the following organizations: the Kentucky State Medical Association; the Kentucky Dental Association; the Kentucky Hospital Association; the Kentucky Pharmacists Association; the Kentucky Association of Health Care Facilities; the Kentucky Nurses' Association; the State Board of Podiatry; the Kentucky Home Health Association; the Kentucky Optometric Association; and the Kentucky Association of Nonprofit Homes and Services for the Aging, Inc. The other seven (7) appointive members shall be health-care advocates knowledgeable about health care and the health-care industry, and shall include three (3) medical assistance recipients, one (1) representative of a recognized consumer advocacy group representing the elderly; and three (3) representatives of recognized consumer advocacy groups whose membership includes low-income persons, children and youth, women, minorities, and disabled persons. </section><section prefix="2">Each appointive member of the council shall serve without compensation but each council member not otherwise compensated for his time or expenses shall be entitled to reimbursement for his actual and necessary expenses in carrying out his duties with reimbursement for expenses being made in accordance with state regulations relating to travel reimbursement. </section><section prefix="3">Vacancies shall be filled for the unexpired term in the same manner as original appointments, maintaining representations as set out in subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="4">The council shall elect a chairman, vice chairman, and secretary from among its members at its first regular meeting in each fiscal year and shall adopt rules governing its proceedings. The council shall hold a meeting at least once every three (3) months and such other special or regular meetings as may be desired. </section><section prefix="5">No consumer member of the council shall have a fiduciary relationship or interest in any health-care facility or service. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 230, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 196, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 259, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 91, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 248, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 36, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, secs. 48 and 107(1), (15), (16); and ch. 225, sec. 2 -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 203, sec. 42. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 2. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 1. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 68, Art. VII, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7704</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>