<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="42" order_by="42">FINANCE AND ADMINISTRATION CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>42.455</section_number><catch_line>Local Government Economic Assistance Program -- Grants for priority expenditures -- Administrative regulations -- Public hearings -- Reports -- Directory of coal road system. </catch_line><order_by>455</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is established within the Department for Local Government a Local Government Economic Assistance Program to consist of a system of grants to local governments to improve the environment for new industry and to improve the quality of life for the residents. </section><section prefix="2">Grants obtained under this program shall be used for priority expenditures. Thirty percent (30%) of all moneys in the fund shall be spent on the coal haul road system as described in subsection (7) of this section. The remaining seventy percent (70%) of the fund shall be spent on priority categories limited to the following, but in no event shall grants obtained under this program be used for expenses related to administration of government: <section prefix="a">Public safety, including law enforcement, fire protection, ambulance service, and other related services; </section><section prefix="b">Environmental protection, including sewage disposal, sanitation, solid waste, and other related programs; </section><section prefix="c">Public transportation, including mass transit systems, streets, and roads; </section><section prefix="d">Health; </section><section prefix="e">Recreation; </section><section prefix="f">Libraries and educational facilities; </section><section prefix="g">Social services for the poor, the elderly, and individuals with disabilities; </section><section prefix="h">Industrial and economic development; </section><section prefix="i">Vocational education; </section><section prefix="j">Workforce training; and </section><section prefix="k">Secondary wood industry development. </section></section><section prefix="3">The use of entitlement funds for repayment of debt as related to long-term bond issues is permissible as long as the revenue from the bond issues is expended on priority categories. </section><section prefix="4">Grants obtained under this program may be used as local portion to secure federal programs as long as program expenditures are in the priority category area. Interest earned on funds received by local units of government shall be considered available for use by the local unit of government in the priority expenditure categories. </section><section prefix="5">The Department for Local Government shall be responsible for the promulgation of rules and regulations necessary to implement the grants programs authorized by this section. </section><section prefix="6">The Department for Local Government shall assure that a public hearing is held on the expenditure of funds received under KRS 42.450 to 42.495. Advertisement of the public hearing shall be published at least once but may be published two (2) or more times, provided that one (1) publication occurs not less than seven (7) days nor more than twenty-one (21) days before the scheduled date of the public hearing. The Department for Local Government shall submit an annual report to the Governor indicating how the grants were used and an evaluation of the program's effectiveness in improving the economy of the units of government receiving assistance. </section><section prefix="7">On or before August 15, 1980, and each year thereafter, the Transportation Cabinet shall publish and furnish to the Department for Local Government a directory, including supporting maps and other documents, designating the official state coal road system in coal-impact and coal-producing counties which shall include all public highways, roads, and streets over which quantities of coal, sufficient to significantly affect the condition and state of repair of highways, roads, and streets, have been transported in the immediately preceding fiscal year. The cabinet shall further publish the total county mileage of the official state coal road system and the total ton/miles within each coal-impact and coal-producing county for said preceding fiscal year. </section><section prefix="8">Every person shipping or transporting coal, and every carrier for hire or common carrier hauling coal over the public highways, roads, and streets shall file with the Transportation Cabinet such information and at intervals as the cabinet shall designate by regulation duly adopted for the purpose of identifying those highways, roads, and streets comprising the coal haul road system and the quantities of coal transported thereon, in order that the cabinet can accurately calculate total ton/miles within each coal-impact and coal-producing county. </section><section prefix="9">The Department of Revenue shall make available to the Transportation Cabinet coal severance and processing tax data for use in verifying and supplementing the information furnished under the provisions of subsection (8) of this section. The information shall be furnished in such a manner as to conceal the identity of individual taxpayers; if the data cannot be furnished without revealing the identity of individual taxpayers, it shall be withheld. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 24, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 18, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 53, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994; ch. 224, sec. 17, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 405, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 107, sec. 2, effective July 1, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 50, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 374, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 393, sec. 29, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 394, sec. 2, effective July 1, 1980. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22033</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>