<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="117" order_by="117">REGULATION OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>117.187</section_number><catch_line>Training regarding election laws for state and county officials -- Training and compensation for election officers and training for certified challengers. </catch_line><order_by>187</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The State Board of Elections shall regularly provide special training regarding the election laws and methods of enforcement to all members of county boards of elections, county attorneys, Commonwealth's attorneys, and certain members of the Department of Kentucky State Police. </section><section prefix="2">The county board of elections shall provide special training before each primary and regular election, and any special election held during a year in which no elections are scheduled, to all election officers, alternates, and certified challengers regarding their duties and the penalties for failure to perform. Election officers, including alternates, and certified challengers shall attend the training session, unless excused by the county board of elections for reason of illness or other emergency. Any person who fails to attend a training session without being excused shall be prohibited from serving as an election officer or challenger for a period of five (5) years. The training provided by the county board of elections shall include but not be limited to the following: <section prefix="a">Operation of the voting machine or ballot cards; </section><section prefix="b">Posting of necessary signs and notices at the polling place; </section><section prefix="c">Voter assistance; </section><section prefix="d">Maintaining precinct rosters; </section><section prefix="e">Confirmation of a voter's identity; </section><section prefix="f">Challenge of a voter; </section><section prefix="g">Completing changes of address or name at the polling place; </section><section prefix="h">Qualifications for voting in a primary election; </section><section prefix="i">Electioneering and exit polling; </section><section prefix="j">Write-in voting procedures; </section><section prefix="k">Persons who may be in the voting room; </section><section prefix="l">Election violations and penalties; </section><section prefix="m">Assistance which may be provided by law enforcement officers; </section><section prefix="n">Election reports; </section><section prefix="o">Disability awareness; </section><section prefix="p">Provisional voting process; </section><section prefix="q">Election emergency contingency plan; and </section><section prefix="r">Elections and voting equipment security plan. </section></section><section prefix="3">The county attorney shall attend the training session for election officers to assist in explaining the duties and penalties for failure to perform. </section><section prefix="4">Compensation in the minimum amount of ten dollars ($10) for reimbursement of actual expenses shall be paid by the county to the election officers for attending the training session. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 176, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 158, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 7, sec. 2, effective March 8, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 3, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 243, sec. 10, effective April 1, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 394, sec. 15, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 288, sec. 50, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 341, sec. 12, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27397</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>