<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XV" order_by="15">ROADS, WATERWAYS, AND AVIATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="175" order_by="175">B KENTUCKY PUBLIC TRANSPORTATION INFRASTRUCTURE AUTHORITY </unit></structure><section_number>175B.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in this chapter: <section prefix="1">"Authority" means the state authority, or a bi-state authority, or a project authority, unless the specific use requires that it apply only to the state authority, or a bi-state authority, or a project authority; </section><section prefix="2">"Bi-state authority" means an authority created under KRS 175B.030; </section><section prefix="3">"Cabinet" means the Transportation Cabinet; </section><section prefix="4">"Commonwealth" means the Commonwealth of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="5">"Cost" means: <section prefix="a">The cost of construction of the project, including the acquisition of land, rights-of-way, property, rights in land, easements, and interests acquired by the authority for construction of a project; </section><section prefix="b">The cost of preparing land or property, including demolishing or removing any buildings or structures, and the cost of acquiring any lands to which those buildings or structures may be moved; </section><section prefix="c">The pro-rata value of all machinery and equipment used in construction of the project; </section><section prefix="d">Financing charges and provisions for working capital in an amount the authority determines to be reasonable; </section><section prefix="e">Interest prior to and during construction and, if approved by the authority, for a period up to two (2) years after completion of construction; </section><section prefix="f">The cost of traffic estimates and of engineering, financial and legal services, plans, specifications, surveys, estimates of cost and revenues, or other expenses necessary or incidental to determining the feasibility or practicability of constructing any project; </section><section prefix="g">The cost and expense of the relocation or removal of public utilities impacted by a project, including the cost of installing the facilities in a new location, the cost of any lands or any rights or interests in lands, and the cost of any other rights acquired to accomplish the relocation or removal; </section><section prefix="h">Administrative expenses and any other expenses that are necessary for or incidental to the construction of a project, the financing of the construction, and the placing of the project in operation; and </section><section prefix="i">The cost of maintenance of the completed project. </section></section> Any obligation or expense incurred by and reimbursed to the Commonwealth in connection with any of the items of cost set out in this subsection may be regarded as a part of that cost; <section prefix="6">"Department" means the Department of Highways; </section><section prefix="7">"Developing authority" means the authority involved in the development of a project; </section><section prefix="8">"Issuing authority" means the authority that will issue or has issued debt associated with a project; </section><section prefix="9">"Local government" means a consolidated local government, an urban-county government, a charter county government, a unified local government, or a county; </section><section prefix="10"><section prefix="a">"Project" means: <section prefix="1">Any highway or section of a highway designated as part of the federal interstate highway system; or </section><section prefix="2">Any highway or section of highway built to the standards of the interstate highway system; </section></section> that would be designated a mega-project by the Federal Highway Administration; <section prefix="b">"Project" includes all bridges, tollhouses, garages, and other buildings and facilities which the authority deems necessary for the operation of the project, together with all property, rights, easements, and interests which may be acquired by the authority or by the Commonwealth for the construction and operation of a project; </section></section><section prefix="11">"Project authority" means an authority created pursuant to KRS 175B.035; </section><section prefix="12">"Project revenue bonds" means revenue funding bonds, revenue refunding bonds, notes, or other financial obligations issued under this chapter by the issuing authority; </section><section prefix="13">"Public utility facilities" means tracks, pipes, mains, conduits, cables, wires, towers, poles, and other equipment and appliances of any public utility in, on, along, over, or under any project; and </section><section prefix="14">"State authority" means the Kentucky Public Transportation Infrastructure Authority created under KRS 175B.015. </section></text><history> Created 2009 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 76, effective June 26, 2009. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5135</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>