<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="200" order_by="200">ASSISTANCE TO CHILDREN </unit></structure><section_number>200.703</section_number><catch_line>Duties of Early Childhood Advisory Council -- Implementation of programs -- Plan for identification of early childhood development funding priorities -- Disbanding or suspension of councils -- Expiration of authority, councils, and initiatives --  Requests for proposals.   </catch_line><order_by>703</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Early Childhood Advisory Council is responsible for the following: <section prefix="a">Promoting the vision for Kentucky's early childhood system; </section><section prefix="b">Advocating for improved quality of early childhood services; </section><section prefix="c">Promoting the definition of school readiness and the expanded and appropriate use of the early childhood standards; </section><section prefix="d">Strengthening state, regional, and local level coordination and collaboration among the various sectors and settings of early childhood programs in the state; </section><section prefix="e">Identifying opportunities and strategies to reduce barriers to coordination and collaboration among existing private, federal, and state-funded early childhood programs; </section><section prefix="f">Developing and implementing recommendations for: <section prefix="1">Increasing overall participation of children in existing federal, state, and local child care and early education programs, including outreach to underrepresented and special populations; </section><section prefix="2">Establishing or improving core elements of the state early childhood system; </section><section prefix="3">Enhancing the professional development system and career ladder for early childhood educators and caregivers; and </section><section prefix="4">Promoting high-quality state early learning standards and undertaking efforts to ensure the development and use of high-quality comprehensive early learning standards, as appropriate; </section></section><section prefix="g">Assessing the capacity and effectiveness of institutes of higher education in the state toward supporting the development of early childhood educators; </section><section prefix="h">Facilitating the development or enhancement of high-quality systems of early childhood care and education designed to improve school readiness through one (1) or more of the following activities: <section prefix="1">Promoting school preparedness of children from birth through school entry; </section><section prefix="2">Supporting professional development, recruitment, and retention   initiatives for early childhood educators and caregivers; </section><section prefix="3">Enhancing existing early childhood education and development programs and services; </section><section prefix="4">Carrying out other activities consistent with the state's plan and application; and </section><section prefix="5">Establishing priorities for programs and the expenditure of funds that include but are not limited to the following: <section prefix="a">Implementation of public health initiatives identified by the General Assembly, including those listed in KRS 211.690 and 199.8945; </section><section prefix="b">Provision of preconception and prenatal vitamins, with priority for folic acid for the prevention of neural tube defects; </section><section prefix="c">Voluntary immunization for children not covered by public or private health insurance; </section><section prefix="d">Expanding availability of high-quality, affordable early child-care and education options; and </section><section prefix="e">Increasing public awareness of the importance of the early childhood years for the well-being of all of Kentucky's citizens; </section></section></section><section prefix="i">Requesting reports and issuing progress updates on state and federally funded services that impact the quality of Kentucky's early childhood system; </section><section prefix="j">Receiving, requesting, and utilizing, consistent with this section, federal, state, and private funds, including from philanthropic sources; </section><section prefix="k">Involving the corporate community, county judge/executives, and mayors in supporting issues of importance to working families with young children in the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="l">Collecting and disseminating information about the various ways business and local government can become involved in supporting early childhood; and </section><section prefix="m">Other duties and responsibilities as designated by the Governor. </section></section><section prefix="2">The council shall develop a state plan on a biennial basis that identifies early childhood development funding priorities. Every two (2) years the council shall review its priorities and make necessary adjustments to its state plan. The state plan shall incorporate priorities included in the final report and recommendations of the Governor's Task Force on Early Childhood Development and Education, November 2010, and recommendations identified by the community early childhood councils. The council shall file a report on the state plan with the Governor and the Legislative Research Commission by July 15 of odd-numbered years. </section><section prefix="3">Programs funded by the council shall be implemented by the appropriate agencies within the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet, the Finance and Administration Cabinet, or other appropriate administrative agency. </section><section prefix="4">The council shall assure that a public hearing is held on the expenditure of funds. Advertisement of the public hearing shall be published at least once but may be published two (2) more times, if one (1) publication occurs not less than seven (7) days nor more than twenty-one (21) days before the scheduled date of the public hearing. </section><section prefix="5">The council shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to: <section prefix="a">Coordinate and improve early childhood development services, outcomes, and policies; </section><section prefix="b">Establish procedures that relate to its governance; </section><section prefix="c">Designate service areas of the Commonwealth where the community early childhood councils may be established to identify and address the early childhood development needs of young children and their families for the communities that they serve; </section><section prefix="d">Establish procedures that relate to the monitoring of grants, services, and activities of the community early childhood councils and their governance; </section><section prefix="e">Establish procedures for accountability and measurement of the success of programs that receive funds from the council; and </section><section prefix="f">Establish standards for the payment of funds to a designated service provider and grantee of a community early childhood council. These standards shall include requirements relating to: <section prefix="1">The financial management of funds paid to grantees; </section><section prefix="2">The maintenance of records; and </section><section prefix="3">An independent audit of the use of grant funds. </section></section></section><section prefix="6">The council may disband or suspend a community early childhood council, and may remove one (1) or more members for nonperformance or malfeasance. The council may also recover funds that have been determined by the council to have been misappropriated or misspent in relation to a grant award. </section><section prefix="7">An appeal to the council may be made by a community early childhood council as to a decision made by the council on the disbanding or suspension of a community early childhood council, service provider, or grantee on a determination that funds have been misappropriated or misspent and are subject to recovery. The appeal shall be conducted in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section><section prefix="8">The council, community early childhood councils established by the council, and initiatives funded by the council with expenditures from the early childhood development fund shall expire when: <section prefix="a">Funds are no longer designated to the Commonwealth from the master settlement agreement signed on November 22, 1998, between the participating tobacco manufacturers and the forty (40) settling states or related federal legislation; or </section><section prefix="b">Funds are no longer designated to the early childhood development fund from gifts, grants, or federal funds to fund the council, the community early childhood councils established by the council, or any programs that had been funded by the council with expenditures from the early childhood development fund. </section></section><section prefix="9">The council shall develop a request for proposal process by which local early childhood councils may request any funding appropriated to the council for use by the councils. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 57, sec. 7, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 62, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 120, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 50, effective June 20, 2005; ch. 127, sec. 7, effective March 18, 2005. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><lrc-note> (6/20/2005)  2005 Ky. Acts ch. 127, which included an amendment to this section, KRS 200.703, provides that the Act shall be cited as the "Read to Achieve Act of 2005." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42144</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>