<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="227" order_by="227">FIRE PREVENTION AND PROTECTION -- ELECTRICIANS </unit></structure><section_number>227.702</section_number><catch_line>Consumer fireworks defined. </catch_line><order_by>702</order_by><text>As used in KRS 227.700 to 227.750, "consumer fireworks" means fireworks that are suitable for use by the public, designed primarily to produce visible effects by combustion, and that comply with the construction, chemical composition, and labeling regulations of the United States Consumer Product Safety Commission. The types, sizes, and amount of pyrotechnic contents of these devices are limited as enumerated in this section. Some small devices designed to produce audible effects are included, such as whistling devices, ground devices containing fifty (50) mg. or less of explosive composition, and aerial devices containing one hundred thirty (130) mg. or less of explosive composition. Consumer fireworks are further defined by the Consumer Product Safety Commission in CPSC, 16 C.F.R. pts. 1500 and 1507, are classified as Division 1.4G explosives by the United States Department of Transportation, and include the following: <section prefix="1">Ground and hand-held sparkling devices. <section prefix="a">Dipped stick-sparkler or wire sparkler. These devices consist of a metal wire or wood dowel that has been coated with pyrotechnic composition. Upon ignition of the tip of the device, a shower of sparks is produced. Sparklers may contain up to one hundred (100) grams of pyrotechnic composition per item. Those devices containing any perchlorate or chlorate salts may not exceed five (5) grams of pyrotechnic composition per item. Wire sparklers which contain no magnesium and which contain less than one hundred (100) grams of composition per item are not included in this category, in accordance with DOT regulations; </section><section prefix="b">Cylindrical fountain. Cylindrical tube containing not more than seventy-five (75) grams of pyrotechnic composition. Upon ignition, a shower of colored sparks, and sometimes a whistling effect or smoke, is produced. This device may be provided with a spike for insertion into the ground (spike fountain), a wood or plastic base for placing on the ground (base fountain), or a wood or cardboard handle, if intended to be hand-held (handle fountain). When more than one (1) tube is mounted on a common base, total pyrotechnic composition may not exceed two hundred (200) grams, or five hundred (500) grams if the tubes are separated from each other on the base by a distance of at least one-half (1/2) inch; </section><section prefix="c">Cone fountain. Cardboard or heavy paper cone containing up to fifty (50) grams of pyrotechnic composition. The effect is the same as that of a cylindrical fountain. When more than one (1) cone is mounted on a common base, the total pyrotechnic composition may not exceed two hundred (200) grams, or five hundred (500) grams if the tubes are separated from each other on the base by a distance of at least one-half (1/2) inch; </section><section prefix="d">Illuminating torch. Cylindrical tube containing up to one hundred (100) grams of pyrotechnic composition. Upon ignition, colored fire is produced. May be spike, base or hand-held. When more than one (1) tube is mounted on a common base, total pyrotechnic composition may not exceed two hundred (200) grams, or five hundred (500) grams if the tubes are separated from each other on the base by a distance of at least one-half (1/2) inch; </section><section prefix="e">Wheel. A device attached to a post or tree by means of a nail or string. A wheel may have one (1) or more drivers, each of which may contain not more than sixty (60) grams of pyrotechnic composition. No wheel may contain more than two hundred (200) grams total pyrotechnic composition. Upon ignition, the wheel revolves, producing a shower of color and sparks and, sometimes, a whistling effect; </section><section prefix="f">Ground spinner. Small device containing not more than twenty (20) grams of pyrotechnic composition, similar in operation to a wheel but intended to be placed on the ground and ignited. A shower of sparks and color is produced by the rapidly spinning device; </section><section prefix="g">Flitter sparkler. Narrow paper tube attached to a stick or wire and filled with not more than one hundred (100) grams of pyrotechnic composition that produces color and sparks upon ignition. The paper at one (1) end of the tube is ignited to make the device function; and </section><section prefix="h">Toy smoke device. Small plastic or paper item containing not more than one hundred (100) grams of pyrotechnic composition that, upon ignition, produces white or colored smoke as the primary effect; </section></section><section prefix="2">Aerial devices. <section prefix="a">Sky rockets and bottle rockets. Cylindrical tube containing not more than twenty (20) grams of pyrotechnic composition. Sky rockets contain a wooden stick for guidance and stability and rise into the air upon ignition. A burst of color or noise or both is produced at the height of flight; </section><section prefix="b">Missile-type rocket. A device similar to a sky rocket in size, composition, and effect that uses fins rather than a stick for guidance and stability; </section><section prefix="c">Helicopter, aerial spinner. A tube containing up to twenty (20) grams of pyrotechnic composition. A propeller or blade is attached, which, upon ignition, lifts the rapidly spinning device into the air. A visible or audible effect is produced at the height of flight; </section><section prefix="d">Roman candles. Heavy paper or cardboard tube containing up to twenty (20) grams of pyrotechnic composition. Upon ignition, up to ten (10) "stars" (pellets of pressed pyrotechnic composition that burn with bright color) are individually expelled at several second intervals; </section><section prefix="e">Mine, shell. Heavy cardboard or paper tube usually attached to a wood or plastic base and containing up to sixty (60) grams of total chemical composition (lift charge, burst charge, and visible or audible effect composition). Upon ignition, "stars," components producing reports containing up to one hundred thirty (130) milligrams of explosive composition per report, or other devices are propelled into the air. The term "mine" refers to a device with no internal components containing a bursting charge, and the term "shell" refers to a device that propels a component that subsequently bursts open in the air. A mine or shell device may contain more than one (1) tube provided the tubes fire in sequence upon ignition of one (1) external fuse. The term "cake" refers to a dense-packed collection of mine or shell tubes. Total chemical composition including lift charges of any multiple tube devices may not exceed two hundred (200) grams. The maximum quantity of lift charge in any one (1) tube of a mine or shell device shall not exceed twenty (20) grams, and the maximum quantity of break or bursting charge in any component shall not exceed twenty-five percent (25%) of the total weight of chemical composition in the component. The tube remains on the ground; and </section><section prefix="f">Aerial shell kit, reloadable tube. A package kit containing a cardboard, high-density polyethylene (HDPE), or equivalent launching tube with multiple-shot aerial shells. Each aerial shell is limited to a maximum of sixty (60) grams of total chemical composition (lift charge, burst charge, and visible or audible effect composition), and the maximum diameter of each shell shall not exceed one and three-fourths (1-3/4) inches. In addition, the maximum quantity of lift charge in any shell shall not exceed twenty (20) grams, and the maximum quantity of break or bursting charge in any shell shall not exceed twenty-five percent (25%) of the total weight of chemical composition in the shell. The total chemical composition of all the shells in a kit, including lift charge, shall not exceed four hundred (400) grams. The user lowers a shell into the launching tube, at the time of firing, with the fuse extending out of the top of the tube. After the firing, the tube is then reloaded with another shell for the next firing. All launching tubes shall be capable of firing twice the number of shells in the kit without failure of the tube. Each package of multiple-shot aerial shells must comply with all warning label requirements of the Consumer Product Safety Commission; and </section></section><section prefix="3">Audible ground devices. <section prefix="a">Firecrackers, salutes. Small paper-wrapped or cardboard tube containing not more than fifty (50) mg. of pyrotechnic composition. Those used in aerial devices may contain not more than one hundred thirty (130) milligrams of explosive composition per report. Upon ignition, noise and a flash of light is produced; and </section><section prefix="b">Chaser. Small paper or cardboard tube that travels along the ground upon ignition. A whistling effect, or other noise, is often produced. The explosive composition used to create the noise may not exceed fifty (50) mg. </section></section></text><history>Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 66, sec. 3, effective March 16, 2011. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 436, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective>March 16, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39503</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>