<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="506" order_by="506">INCHOATE OFFENSES </unit></structure><section_number>506.070</section_number><catch_line>Incapacity of solicitee or co-conspirator. </catch_line><order_by>070</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It is no defense to a prosecution for criminal solicitation that the person solicited could not be guilty of the crime solicited because of:  <section prefix="a">Criminal irresponsibility or other legal incapacity or exemption; or  </section><section prefix="b">Unawareness of the criminal nature of the conduct solicited or of the defendant's criminal purpose; or  </section><section prefix="c">Any other factor precluding the mental state required for the commission of the crime solicited.  </section></section><section prefix="2">It is no defense to a prosecution for criminal conspiracy that a co-conspirator could not be guilty of the conspiracy or the crime contemplated by the conspiracy because of:  <section prefix="a">Criminal irresponsibility or other legal incapacity or exemption; or  </section><section prefix="b">Unawareness of the criminal nature of the conspiracy or the conduct contemplated by the conspiracy or of the defendant's criminal purpose; or  </section><section prefix="c">Any other factor precluding the mental state required for the commission of the conspiracy or the crime contemplated by the conspiracy.  </section></section><section prefix="3">A defendant cannot be convicted of conspiracy if all of his co-conspirators have been acquitted or discharged under circumstances amounting to an acquittal.  </section></text><history>Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 55, efffective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective>January 1, 1975</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19707</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>