<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="334" order_by="334">A SPEECH-LANGUAGE PATHOLOGISTS AND AUDIOLOGISTS </unit></structure><section_number>334A.180</section_number><catch_line>Licenses, causes for revocation, suspension or denial. </catch_line><order_by>180</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board may refuse to issue a license, suspend or revoke the license of any licensee, or fine a licensee an amount agreed upon by a two-thirds (2/3) vote of the board in an amount not to exceed one thousand dollars ($1,000), and the board may take action against a license and fine a licensee if he or she has been guilty of unprofessional conduct which has endangered or is likely to endanger the health, welfare, or safety of the public. Such unprofessional conduct may include: <section prefix="a">Obtained the license by means of fraud, misrepresentation, or concealment of material facts; </section><section prefix="b">Has been guilty of unprofessional conduct as defined by the rules established by the board, or has violated the code of ethics adopted and published by the board; </section><section prefix="c">Has violated any lawful order, rule, or regulation rendered or adopted by the board; </section><section prefix="d">Has represented that the professional services or advice of a physician has been used, or has used the words "doctor," "clinic," or similar words, abbreviations, or symbols while failing to affix the word, term, or initials pertaining to "audiology," "audiologic," "audiologist," "doctor of audiology," "speech-language pathologist," "speech-language pathology," "Au.D.," "Ph.D.," or "Sc.D."; </section><section prefix="e">Has failed to affix the word, term, or initials specified in paragraph (d) of this subsection in any sign, written communication, or advertising media in which the term "doctor" or the abbreviation "Dr." is used in relation to the audiologist or speech-language pathologist holding a doctoral degree; or </section><section prefix="f">Has violated any provisions of this chapter. </section></section><section prefix="2">The board shall deny an application for, or suspend or revoke, or impose probationary conditions upon, a license as ordered by the board in any decision made after hearing as provided in this chapter. One (1) year from the date of revocation of a license under this chapter, application may be made to the board for reinstatement. The board shall have discretion to accept or reject an application for reinstatement. </section><section prefix="3">A person applying for reinstatement of licensure shall provide evidence of completion of continuing professional education in speech-language pathology or audiology as prescribed by the board. </section><section prefix="4">A plea or verdict of guilty or a conviction following a plea of nolo contendere made to a charge of a felony is deemed to be a conviction within the meaning of this chapter. At the direction of the board, the license shall be suspended or revoked, or shall decline to issue a license when the time for appeal has elapsed, or the judgment of conviction has been affirmed on appeal, or when an order granting probation is made suspending the imposition of sentence irrespective of a subsequent order under the provisions of the penal code allowing such person to withdraw his plea of guilty and to enter a plea of not guilty, or setting aside the verdict of guilty, or dismissing the acquisition, information or indictment. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 12, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 236, sec. 18. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2008).  Two manifest clerical or typographical errors have been corrected in this statute during codification under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(h). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31910</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>