<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="227" order_by="227">FIRE PREVENTION AND PROTECTION -- ELECTRICIANS </unit></structure><section_number>227.605</section_number><catch_line>Class B1 seal required prior to sale or use as a dwelling of previously owned manufactured or mobile home transported into Commonwealth -- Homes installed before July 13, 2004, excepted. </catch_line><order_by>605</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall transport into the Commonwealth of Kentucky any previously owned manufactured or mobile home for the purpose of resale or use as a dwelling in the Commonwealth of Kentucky unless the previously owned manufactured or mobile home has a B1 Seal attached to it prior to resale or use as a dwelling. The application and certification procedures for the attachment of the B1 Seal prior to the resale or occupancy of the manufactured or mobile home shall be set out by the board through the promulgation of administrative regulations in accordance with the provisions of KRS Chapter 13A. Nothing in this section shall require a person who owns a manufactured or mobile home in another state and who transports that manufactured or mobile home into the Commonwealth of Kentucky to use as that person's dwelling to obtain a Class B seal. </section><section prefix="2">Except for manufactured or mobile homes installed within the Commonwealth of Kentucky before July 13, 2004, no person shall sell, lease, rent, or furnish for use as a dwelling in the Commonwealth of Kentucky any previously owned manufactured or mobile home that does not bear a B1 Seal and which is not installed in compliance with the manufacturer's instructions, if available, or ANSI 225.1, Manufactured Home Installations. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 418, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 74, sec. 13, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10685</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>