<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="237" order_by="237">FIREARMS AND DESTRUCTIVE DEVICES </unit></structure><section_number>237.060</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 237.060 to 237.090 and certain other sections. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text>The following definitions apply in KRS 237.060 to 237.090 and KRS 197.170, 218A.992, 244.125, 244.990, and 514.110, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Handgun" means any pistol or revolver originally designed to be fired by the use of a single hand, or any other firearm originally designed to be fired by the use of a single hand. </section><section prefix="2">"Firearm" means any weapon which will expel a projectile by the action of an explosive. </section><section prefix="3">"Licensed gun dealer" means a person who has a federal firearms license and any business license required by a state or local government entity. </section><section prefix="4">"Loaded" with respect to a firearm means: <section prefix="a">There is ammunition in the chamber of the firearm; or </section><section prefix="b">There is ammunition in the cylinder of the firearm; or </section><section prefix="c">There is ammunition in the magazine of a firearm, if the magazine is attached to the firearm. </section></section><section prefix="5">"Juvenile" means a person who has not attained his eighteenth birthday. </section><section prefix="6">"Ammunition" means loaded ammunition designed for use in any firearm. </section><section prefix="7">"Armor-piercing ammunition" means a projectile or projectile core which may be used in a handgun and which is constructed entirely (excluding the presence of traces of other substances) from one (1) or a combination of tungsten alloys, steel, iron, brass, bronze, beryllium copper, or depleted uranium. "Armor piercing ammunition" does not include shotgun shot required by federal or state environmental or game regulations for hunting purposes, a frangible projectile designed for target shooting, a projectile which the Secretary of the Treasury of the United States finds is primarily intended to be used for sporting purposes, or any other projectile or projectile core which the Secretary of the Treasury of the United States finds is intended to be used for industrial purposes, including a charge used in an oil and gas well perforating device. </section><section prefix="8">"Flanged ammunition" means ammunition with a soft lead core and having sharp flanges which are designed to expand on impact. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11123</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>