<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.376</section_number><catch_line>Housing and security policy for safe residence facilities for students with a disability. </catch_line><order_by>376</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, unless the context requires otherwise, "disability" has the same meaning as the definition given in KRS 344.010. </section><section prefix="2">The Council on Postsecondary Education shall develop guidelines for the adoption of policies by postsecondary education institutions with residence facilities that provide students with a disability a safe environment in which to live and study. </section><section prefix="3">Each institution shall develop a housing and security policy in compliance with the council's guidelines that shall be visibly posted in each residence facility, made available on campus computer networks to which students have access, and included in all student housing information. The policies shall include, but not be limited to, an appeals process that may be used by students, their parents, or their advocates when they have reason to believe that the institution's policy or the student's housing assignment does not reasonably accommodate the student's disability or endangers the student's safety or health. The appeals process shall mandate that the body assigned to hear the appeal shall not include representatives of the original department that made the housing assignment that is being appealed. </section><section prefix="4">Each institution shall prepare at the beginning of each semester a list with the name and residency assignment of each student with a disability, as reported to the institution by the student or the student's parent or advocate, as appropriate. The list shall be given to the campus housing and security authorities to be used in an emergency to identify, locate, and act to help, protect, and if necessary, rescue the student with a disability. </section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4281</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>