<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="342" order_by="342">WORKERS' COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>342.650</section_number><catch_line>Exemptions of particular classes of employees from coverage. </catch_line><order_by>650</order_by><text>The following employees are exempt from the coverage of this chapter: <section prefix="1">Any person employed as a domestic servant in a private home by an employer who has less than two (2) employees each regularly employed forty (40) or more hours a week in domestic servant employment; </section><section prefix="2">Any person employed, for not exceeding twenty (20) consecutive work days, to do maintenance, repair, remodeling, or similar work in or about the private home of the employer, or if the employer has no other employees subject to this chapter, in or about the premises where that employer carries on his or her trade, business, or profession; </section><section prefix="3">Any person performing services in return for aid or sustenance only, received from any religious or charitable organization; </section><section prefix="4">Any person for whom a rule of liability for injury or death is provided by the laws of the United States, except those persons covered under Title IV, Public Law 91-173, 91st Congress, commonly referred to as the Black Lung Benefits of the Federal Coal Mine Health and Safety Act of 1969, or as amended; </section><section prefix="5">Any person employed in agriculture; </section><section prefix="6">Any person who would otherwise be covered but who elects not to be covered in accordance with the administrative regulations promulgated by the commissioner; </section><section prefix="7">Any person participating as a driver or passenger in a voluntary vanpool or carpool program while that person is on the way to or from his or her place of employment. For the purposes of this subsection, carpool or vanpool means any method by which two (2) or more employees are transported from their residences to their places of employment; and </section><section prefix="8">Members of a religious sect or division that is an adherent of established tenets or teachings by reason of which members are conscientiously opposed to acceptance of the benefits of any public or private insurance which makes payments in the event of death, disability, old age, or retirement, or makes payments toward the cost of, or provides services for, medical bills, including the benefits of any insurance system established by the Federal Social Security Act, 42 U.S.C. secs. 301 et seq., and it is the practice, and has been for ten (10) or more years, for members of the sect or division to make reasonable provision for their dependent members. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1837, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1996 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 81, effective December 12, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 181, Part 15, sec. 92, effective April 4, 1994. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 7, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 5. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32535</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>