<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="352" order_by="352">MINING REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>352.251</section_number><catch_line>Magazines for storage of explosives -- Requirements for construction and operation. </catch_line><order_by>251</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Separate surface magazines shall be provided for the storage of explosives and detonators. </section><section prefix="2">Surface magazines for storing and distributing explosives in amounts exceeding one hundred twenty-five (125) pounds shall be: <section prefix="a">Reasonably bulletproof and constructed of incombustible material or covered with fire-resistive material. The roofs of magazines so located that it is impossible to fire bullets directly through the roof from the ground need not be bulletproof, but where it is possible to fire bullets directly through them, roofs shall be made bullet-resistant by material construction, or by ceiling that forms a tray containing not less than a four (4) inch thickness of sand, or by other methods; </section><section prefix="b">Provided with doors constructed of three-eighths (3/8) inch steel plate lined with a two (2) inch thickness of wood, or the equivalent; </section><section prefix="c">Provided with dry floors made of wood or other nonsparking material and have no metal exposed inside the magazine; </section><section prefix="d">Provided with suitable warning signs so located that a bullet passing directly through the face of a sign will not strike the magazine; </section><section prefix="e">Provided with properly screened ventilators; </section><section prefix="f">Equipped with no openings except for entrance and ventilation; </section><section prefix="g">Kept locked securely when unattended. </section></section><section prefix="3">Surface magazines for storing detonators shall be in accordance with other provisions for storing explosives. </section><section prefix="4">The location of magazines shall be not less than two hundred (200) feet from any mine opening, occupied building, or public road. Where compliance with this provision is not practicable, the magazine shall be effectively barricaded. Where practicable, as determined by the mine inspector, future explosives magazines shall be placed in open pits, ravines or other recessed areas. </section><section prefix="5">The supply kept in distribution magazines shall be limited to approximately one (1) day's requirements, and such supplies of explosives and detonators may be distributed from the same magazine, if separated by at least a four (4) inch substantially fastened hardwood partition or the equivalent. </section><section prefix="6">The area surrounding magazines for not less than twenty-five (25) feet in all directions shall be kept free of rubbish, dry grass, or other materials of a combustible nature. </section><section prefix="7">Only permissible lights, worn or carried, shall be used inside magazines. </section><section prefix="8">Only nonmetallic tools shall be used for opening wooden containers. Extraneous materials shall not be stored in an explosives or detonator magazine. </section><section prefix="9">Smoking, carrying smokers' articles, or open flame shall be prohibited in or near any magazine. </section></text><history>Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 303, sec. 23. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33005</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>