<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.31-010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for subchapter. </catch_line><order_by>31-010</order_by><text>As used in this subchapter: <section prefix="1">"Agreement" means an agreement entered into pursuant to KRS 154.31-030 between the authority and an approved company; </section><section prefix="2">"Approved company" means an eligible company that has received approval from the authority for a sales and use tax incentive under this subchapter; </section><section prefix="3">"Approved recovery amount" means the maximum sales and use tax incentive recoverable by an approved company as established in the agreement; </section><section prefix="4">"Authority" means the Kentucky Economic Development Finance Authority; </section><section prefix="5">"Department" means the Department of Revenue; </section><section prefix="6">"Economic development project" means: <section prefix="a"><section prefix="1">The acquisition or construction of a new facility; or </section><section prefix="2">The expansion or rehabilitation of an existing facility; and </section></section><section prefix="b">The installation and equipping of the facility; </section></section> by an eligible company at a specific site in the Commonwealth to be used in a service or technology, manufacturing, or tourism attraction activity conducted by the approved company; <section prefix="7">"Electronic processing" means the use of technology having electronic, digital, magnetic, wireless, optical, electromagnetic, or similar capabilities, now in existence or later developed to perform a service or technology activity; </section><section prefix="8"><section prefix="a">"Eligible company" means any corporation, limited liability company, partnership, limited partnership, sole proprietorship, business trust, or other legal entity that is primarily engaged in manufacturing or service or technology activities, or in operating or developing a tourism attraction. </section><section prefix="b">"Eligible company" does not include any company whose primary activity is retail sales; </section></section><section prefix="9">"Eligible expenses" means the amount expended for: <section prefix="a">Building and construction materials permanently incorporated as an improvement to real property as part of an economic development project; or </section><section prefix="b">Equipment used for research and development or electronic processing at an economic development project; </section></section> if the Kentucky sales and use tax imposed by KRS Chapter 139 is paid on the purchase of the materials or equipment at the time of purchase; <section prefix="10"><section prefix="a">"Equipment" means tangible personal property which is subject to depreciation under Sections 167 and 168 of the Internal Revenue Code, including assets which are expensed under Section 179 of the Internal Revenue Code, and that is used in the operation of a business. </section><section prefix="b">"Equipment" does not include any tangible personal property used to maintain, restore, mend, or repair machinery or equipment, consumable operating supplies, office supplies, or maintenance supplies; </section></section><section prefix="11"><section prefix="a">"Manufacturing" means to make, assemble, process, produce, or perform any activity that changes the form or conditions of raw materials and other property, and shall include any ancillary activity to the manufacturing process, such as storage, warehousing, distribution, and related office facilities. </section><section prefix="b">"Manufacturing" does not include any activity involving the performance of work classified by the divisions, including successor divisions, of mining in accordance with the "North American Industry Classification System," as revised by the United States Office of Management and Budget from time to time, or any successor publication; </section></section><section prefix="12">"Project term" means the time for which an agreement shall be in effect. The project term shall be established in the agreement and shall not exceed seven (7) years; </section><section prefix="13"><section prefix="a">"Research and development" means experimental or laboratory activity that has as its ultimate goal the development of new products, the improvement of existing products, the development of new uses for existing products, or the development or improvement of methods for producing products. </section><section prefix="b">"Research and development" does not include testing or inspection of materials or products for quality control purposes, efficiency surveys, management studies, consumer surveys or other market research, advertising or promotional activities, or research in connection with literary, historical, or similar projects; and </section></section><section prefix="14">"Service or technology" means any nonretail activity using technology or providing a service, including but not limited to: <section prefix="a">Administration and processing activities; </section><section prefix="b">Research and development; </section><section prefix="c">Telephone or Internet sales or services; </section><section prefix="d">Distribution or fulfillment of orders; </section><section prefix="e">Data processing; and </section><section prefix="f">Similar activities; </section></section> provided to customer or affiliate entities primarily outside the Commonwealth and designed to serve a multistate, national, or international market. </text><history> Created 2009 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 20, effective June 26, 2009. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:54</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2853</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>