<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="527" order_by="527">OFFENSES RELATING TO FIREARMS AND WEAPONS </unit></structure><section_number>527.100</section_number><catch_line>Possession of handgun by minor. </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of possession of a handgun by a minor when, being under the age of eighteen (18) years, he possesses, manufactures, or transports a handgun as defined by KRS 527.010, except when the person is: <section prefix="a">In attendance at a hunter's safety course or a firearms safety course; </section><section prefix="b">Engaging in practice in the use of a firearm, or target shooting at an established firing range, or any other area where the discharge of a firearm is not prohibited; </section><section prefix="c">Engaging in an organized competition involving the use of a firearm, or participating in or practicing for a performance by a group organized under Section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code or any successor thereto which uses firearms as a part of the performance; </section><section prefix="d">Hunting or trapping pursuant to a valid license issued to him pursuant to the statutes or administrative regulations of this Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="e">Traveling to or from any activity described in paragraphs (a) to (d) of this subsection with any unloaded handgun in his possession; </section><section prefix="f">On real property which is under the control of an adult and has the permission of that adult and his parent or legal guardian to possess a handgun; or </section><section prefix="g">At his residence and with the permission of his parent or legal guardian possesses a handgun and is justified under the principles of justification set forth in KRS Chapter 503 in using physical force or deadly physical force. </section></section><section prefix="2">For the purposes of subsection (1) of this section, a handgun is "loaded" if: <section prefix="a">There is a cartridge in the chamber of the handgun; or </section><section prefix="b">There is a cartridge in the cylinder of the handgun, if the handgun is a revolver; or </section><section prefix="c">There is a cartridge in the magazine of a semiautomatic handgun, if the magazine is attached to the handgun; or </section><section prefix="d">The handgun and the ammunition for the handgun, are carried on the person of one under the age of eighteen (18) years or are in such close proximity to him that he could readily gain access to the handgun and the ammunition and load the handgun. </section></section><section prefix="3">Possession of a handgun by a minor is a Class A misdemeanor for the first offense and a Class D felony for each subsequent offense. </section></text><history> Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 30, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19964</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>