<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="314" order_by="314">REGISTERED NURSES -- PRACTICAL NURSES </unit></structure><section_number>314.142</section_number><catch_line>Sexual Assault Nurse Examiner Program -- Advisory council. </catch_line><order_by>142</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Board of Nursing shall promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A to create a Sexual Assault Nurse Examiner Program. These administrative regulations shall address, at a minimum: <section prefix="a">Educational requirements for sexual assault nurse examiners and statewide standards for provision of the education; </section><section prefix="b">The application process through which registered nurses who submit documentation of required education and clinical experience and who remit the designated application fee may apply to the board to be credentialed as a "Sexual Assault Nurse Examiner"; </section><section prefix="c">Continuing education requirements for maintenance of the sexual assault nurse examiner credential; </section><section prefix="d">Methods of monitoring overall program implementation; and </section><section prefix="e">Procedures for obtaining input from the Sexual Assault Response Team Advisory Committee established under KRS Chapter 403 prior to proposing amendments to any provision of the administrative regulations promulgated under this section or KRS 314.131. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any person in this state who holds a credential as a Sexual Assault Nurse Examiner as defined in KRS 314.011(14) shall have the right to use the title "Sexual Assault Nurse Examiner" and the abbreviation "SANE". No other person shall assume the title or use the abbreviation or any other words, letters, signs, or figures to indicate that the person using the same is a Sexual Assault Nurse Examiner. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 50, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 547, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 427, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1997 (1st Extra Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 145, effective May 30, 1997. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 260, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30931</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>