<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="312" order_by="312">CHIROPRACTORS </unit></structure><section_number>312.991</section_number><catch_line>Penalties -- Injunction or restraining order. </catch_line><order_by>991</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person who shall practice or attempt to practice chiropractic in violation of the provisions of this chapter, or any person who shall buy, sell or fraudulently obtain any diploma or license to practice chiropractic, whether recorded or not; or any person who shall use the title to induce the public to believe that he is engaged in the practice of chiropractic, without first complying with the provisions of this chapter, shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, and upon conviction thereof shall be punished by a fine of not more than five hundred dollars ($500) or by imprisonment in the county jail for not more than six (6) months or both. Each adjustment or treatment shall constitute a separate offense.  </section><section prefix="2">Any advertisement or sign of whatsoever nature to induce the public to believe that one is a chiropractor or practices chiropractic shall be prima facie evidence of a violation of this chapter, provided the person displaying such sign or causing such advertisement has not been licensed to practice chiropractic as provided in this chapter.  </section><section prefix="3">Whenever in the judgment of the board any person has engaged or is about to engage in the acts or practices that constitute, or will constitute, a violation of any of the provisions of this chapter or the rules and regulations adopted by the board, the board may make application to the Franklin Circuit Court for an order enjoining such acts or practices.  Upon a showing by the board that such person has engaged, or is about to engage, in any such acts or practices, an injunction, restraining order, or such other order as may be appropriate shall be granted by such court.  Any order of the Franklin Circuit Court shall be enforceable and shall be valid anywhere in this state and the order of the court shall be reviewable as provided in the Rules of Civil Procedure in the case of other injunctions and restraining orders.  </section></text><history>Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 359, sec. 20, effective June 19, 1976. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 179, sec. 20. </history><metadata><effective> June 19, 1976</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30805</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>