<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="363" order_by="363">WEIGHTS, MEASURES, AND MILLERS' TOLLS </unit></structure><section_number>363.904</section_number><catch_line>Requirements for sale and use of articles and commodities as motor fuel in Kentucky -- Labeling and testing of shipments of motor fuels. </catch_line><order_by>904</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No article or commodity shall be sold or offered for sale and use in Kentucky as motor fuel unless it conforms to the following: <section prefix="a">The motor fuel shall be labeled and posted in accordance with applicable federal and state laws; and </section><section prefix="b">The motor fuel shall conform to the latest ASTM specifications for that particular type, class, and grade of motor fuel, except: <section prefix="1">As provided by KRS 363.902(3); and </section><section prefix="2">For gasoline containing up to ten percent (10%) ethanol, in which case the vapor pressure limit for each class shall be increased by one (1) pound per square inch and ASTM V/L (vapor to liquid ratio) specification is waived. Additionally, the department shall adopt a minimum temperature for fifty percent (50%) distillation of gasoline containing up to ten percent (10%) ethanol through the promulgation of an administrative regulation in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">The motor fuel compliance with ASTM shall be determined in accordance with the test methods prescribed in the latest ASTM publications. </section><section prefix="3">All shipments of motor fuel shall state on either the bill of lading or invoice the destination of the shipment and that the shipment meets the standards and specifications required in this section. The division may obtain a sample of any shipment of motor fuel for testing. Motor fuel blending components shall be exempt from this section until they are offered for sale as motor fuel by the refiner or manufacturer. </section></text><history> Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 88, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34710</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>