<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="118" order_by="118">CONDUCT OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>118.730</section_number><catch_line>Writ for special election for member of General Assembly -- Location where voting to be conducted when only one candidate nominated -- Exceptions. </catch_line><order_by>730</order_by><text><section prefix="1">When a vacancy exists in either house of the General Assembly during its session, the presiding officer of the house in which the vacancy exists shall issue a writ of election; when the General Assembly is not in session, the writ shall be issued by the Governor. The writ shall be signed by the officer issuing it, shall designate the day for holding the election, and shall be directed to the proper sheriff or sheriffs. </section><section prefix="2">If a writ of election has been issued to fill a vacancy in either house of the General Assembly and only one (1) candidate has been nominated under KRS 118.760 and 118.770 and no candidate has filed a declaration of intent to be a write-in candidate for the vacancy under KRS 117.265(2), the county clerks of the counties in the territory in which the special election is to be held shall conduct voting in only one (1) of the following: <section prefix="a">The county clerk's office; or </section><section prefix="b">Other place or places designated by the county board of elections and approved by the State Board of Elections. </section></section><section prefix="3">Subsection (2) of this section shall not apply when the writ of election calls for the election to be held on either: <section prefix="a">The day of a primary or general election; or </section><section prefix="b">The same day as any other special election, except an uncontested special election to fill a vacancy in either house of the General Assembly. </section></section></text><history>Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 8, sec. 2, effective March 28, 2012. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 149, effective June 21, 1974. </history><metadata><effective>March 28, 2012 </effective><lrc-note> (3/28/2012).  2012 Ky. Acts ch. 8, sec. 5, provides that the amendments to this statute in 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 8 shall be cited as "The Dewayne Bunch Act." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39978</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>