<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="353" order_by="353">MINERAL CONSERVATION AND DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>353.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Active mining area" means the area within two hundred (200) feet surrounding current mine works under development, inclusive of the area of five (5) year projections, as indicated on the annually filed mine license map. </section><section prefix="2">"Barrel" or "barrel of oil" means forty-two (42) standard United States liquid measure gallons of two hundred thirty-one (231) cubic inches per gallon, computed at a temperature of sixty (60) degrees Fahrenheit. </section><section prefix="3">"Casing" means a string or strings of pipe commonly placed in wells drilled for natural gas and petroleum. </section><section prefix="4">"Cement" means hydraulic cement properly mixed with water only. </section><section prefix="5">"Coal operator" means any person who proposes to or does operate a coal mine. </section><section prefix="6">"Cubic feet of gas" means the volume of gas contained in one (1) cubic foot of space at a standard pressure base of fourteen and seventy-three hundredths (14.73) pounds per square inch and a temperature base of sixty (60) degrees Fahrenheit. </section><section prefix="7">"Department" means the Department for Natural Resources. </section><section prefix="8">"Directional survey" means a survey performed while drilling using continuous measuring technology, a survey made through drilling tools, or other surveys at such intervals to accurately determine the location of the deviated wellbore. </section><section prefix="9">"Gas" means natural gas. </section><section prefix="10">"Gas well" means any well which: <section prefix="a">Produces natural gas not associated or blended with crude petroleum oil any time during production; or </section><section prefix="b">Produces more than ten thousand (10,000) cubic feet of natural gas to each barrel of crude petroleum oil from the same producing horizon. </section></section><section prefix="11">"Inclination survey" means a survey performed to measure deviation from the true vertical, irrespective of direction, expressed in degrees. </section><section prefix="12">"NAD 83" means the North American Datum, 1983 version, using feet units. </section><section prefix="13">"Oil" means petroleum. </section><section prefix="14">"Oil well" means any well which produces one (1) barrel or more of oil to each ten thousand (10,000) cubic feet of natural gas. </section><section prefix="15">"Plat" means a map, drawing, or print showing the location of a well. </section><section prefix="16">"Single Zone Projection" means the Kentucky Single Zone State Plane Coordinate System of 1983, based on Lambert Conformal Conic map projection with double standard parallels on the North American Datum, 1983 version, as established in 10 KAR 5:010. </section><section prefix="17">"True vertical" means the orientation of the well at ninety degrees (90°) from the horizontal plane at the surface elevation. </section><section prefix="18">"Unit" means any tract or tracts which the department has determined is underlaid by a pool or pools of oil and associated gas, and is not a "drilling unit" as defined in KRS 353.510(19). </section><section prefix="19">"Well" means a borehole drilled or proposed to be drilled for the purpose of producing natural gas or petroleum, or one through which natural gas or petroleum is being produced. </section><section prefix="20">"Well operator" means any person who proposes to or does locate, drill, operate, or abandon any well. </section><section prefix="21">"Workable bed" means: <section prefix="a">A coal bed actually being operated commercially; </section><section prefix="b">A coal bed that the department decides can be operated commercially and the operation of which can reasonably be expected to commence within not more than ten (10) years; or </section><section prefix="c">Any coal bed that, from outcrop indication or other definite evidence, proves to the satisfaction of the department to be workable and, when operated, will require protection if wells are drilled through it. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 14, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 63, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 431, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 3766b-5. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33050</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>