<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXII" order_by="32">OWNERSHIP AND CONVEYANCE OF PROPERTY</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="385" order_by="385">UNIFORM TRANSFERS TO MINORS ACT </unit></structure><section_number>385.032</section_number><catch_line>Nomination of custodian. </catch_line><order_by>032</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person having the right to designate the recipient of property transferable upon the occurrence of a future event may revocably nominate a custodian to receive the property for a minor beneficiary upon the occurrence of the event by naming the custodian followed in substance by the words:  "as custodian for ---------- (name of minor) under the Kentucky Uniform Transfers to Minors Act."  The nomination may name one (1) or more persons as substitute custodians to whom the property must be transferred in the order named, if the first nominated custodian dies before the transfer or is unable, declines, or is ineligible to serve.  The nomination may be made in a will, a trust, a deed, an instrument exercising a power of appointment, or in a writing designating a beneficiary of contractual rights which is registered with or delivered to the payor, issuer, or other obligor of the contractual rights. </section><section prefix="2">A custodian nominated under this section must be a person to whom a transfer of property of that kind may be made under KRS 385.092(1). </section><section prefix="3">The nomination of a custodian under this section does not create custodial property until the nominating instrument becomes irrevocable or a transfer to the nominated custodian is completed under KRS 385.092. Unless the nomination of a custodian has been revoked, upon the occurrence of the future event the custodianship becomes effective and the custodian shall enforce a transfer of the custodial property pursuant to KRS 385.092. </section></text><history>Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35778</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>