<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="352" order_by="352">MINING REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>352.650</section_number><catch_line>Mine maps -- Posting -- Escape drills -- Frequency -- Locations -- Information. </catch_line><order_by>650</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A map shall be posted or readily accessible to all miners in each working section, and in each area where mechanized equipment is being installed or removed. The map shall show the designated escapeways from the working section to the locations where miners must travel to satisfy the escapeway drill specified in subsection (4) of this section. </section><section prefix="2">A map showing the main escapeways shall be posted at the surface location of the licensed facility where miners congregate. </section><section prefix="3">All maps shall be kept up-to-date. Any changes in routes of travel, locations of doors, or directions of airflow shall be shown on the maps by the end of the shift. Miners affected by the changes shall be informed of the changes before entering the underground areas of the mine. Miners on a shift underground when any change is made shall be immediately notified of the change. </section><section prefix="4">At least once every ninety (90) days, each miner, including those miners with working stations located between the working sections and main escapeways, shall participate in a practice escapeway drill. </section><section prefix="5">During the drill, miners that do not have working stations located between the working sections and the main escapeways shall travel the greater distance of the two (2) following choices: <section prefix="a">A path from the primary or alternate escapeway from the miner's working section or from the area where mechanized mining equipment is being installed or removed, to the area where the split of air ventilating the working section intersects a main air course; or </section><section prefix="b">A path which is two thousand (2,000) feet outby the section loading point. </section></section><section prefix="6">Those miners who have working stations located between the working sections and the main escapeways shall participate in the escapeway drill by traveling in the primary or alternate escapeway for a distance of two thousand (2,000) feet from their working station toward the nearest escape facility or drift opening. </section><section prefix="7"><section prefix="a">At least once every six (6) weeks and for each shift, at least two (2) miners on each coal-producing working section who work on that section, accompanied by the section foreman, shall participate in a practice escapeway drill and shall travel the primary or alternate escapeway: <section prefix="1">From the location specified in paragraph (a) of subsection (5) of this section to the surface; </section><section prefix="2">To mechanical escape facilities; or </section><section prefix="3">To an underground entrance to a shaft or slope to the surface. </section></section><section prefix="b">Systematic rotation of section personnel shall be used so that all miners participate in this drill. </section></section><section prefix="8"><section prefix="a">At least once every six (6) weeks, at least two (2) miners on each maintenance shift and a foreman or assistant foreman shall participate in a practice escapeway drill and shall travel the primary or alternate escapeway: <section prefix="1">From the location specified in paragraph (a) of subsection (5) of this section to the surface; </section><section prefix="2">To mechanical escape facilities; or </section><section prefix="3">To an underground entrance to a shaft or slope to the surface. </section></section><section prefix="b">Systematic rotation of maintenance personnel and working sections shall be used so that all miners participate in the drill and so that the escapeways from all sections are traveled. </section></section><section prefix="9">For all escapeway drills required by this section, an escapeway drill shall not be conducted in the same escapeway as the drill proceeding immediately thereafter. </section><section prefix="10">Before or during practice escapeway drills, miners shall be informed of the locations of fire doors, check curtains, changes in the routes of travel, caches of self-rescuers, and plans for diverting smoke from escapeways. </section></text><history> Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 185, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=33046</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>