<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="244" order_by="244">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- PROHIBITIONS, RESTRICTIONS, AND REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>244.130</section_number><catch_line>Advertising to comply with regulations of board -- Types of advertising not prohibited. </catch_line><order_by>130</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except in conformity with regulations of the board, no licensee under KRS 243.020 to 243.670 shall advertise or cause or permit to be advertised in any manner any product which he or she is licensed to manufacture or sell. </section><section prefix="2">Subsection (1) of this section shall not prohibit: <section prefix="a">Advertising in newspapers, magazines, or periodicals having a general circulation; </section><section prefix="b">Promotional advertising on radio or television limited to no more than the name of the licensee and the products the licensee is permitted to manufacture or sell; </section><section prefix="c">Promotional advertising containing the names of establishments or products displayed on uniforms or equipment of sporting teams; or </section><section prefix="d">Promotional advertising mailed or delivered to a consumer's residence. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 28, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 58, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 21, effective June 17, 1978. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2554b-164. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11446</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>