<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="61" order_by="61">GENERAL PROVISIONS AS TO OFFICES AND OFFICERS -- SOCIAL SECURITY FOR PUBLIC EMPLOYEES -- EMPLOYEES RETIREMENT SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>61.600</section_number><catch_line>Disability retirement. </catch_line><order_by>600</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person may qualify to retire on disability, subject to the following conditions: <section prefix="a">The person shall have sixty (60) months of service, twelve (12) of which shall be current service credited under KRS 16.543(1), 61.543(1), or 78.615(1); </section><section prefix="b">For a person whose membership date is prior to August 1, 2004, the person shall not be eligible for an unreduced retirement allowance; </section><section prefix="c">The person's application shall be on file in the retirement office no later than twenty-four (24) months after the person's last day of paid employment, as defined in KRS 61.510, in a regular full-time position, as defined in KRS 61.510 or 78.510; and </section><section prefix="d">The person shall receive a satisfactory determination pursuant to KRS 61.665. </section></section><section prefix="2">A person's disability reapplication based on the same claim of incapacity shall be accepted and reconsidered for disability if accompanied by new objective medical evidence. The reapplication shall be on file in the retirement office no later than twenty-four (24) months after the person's last day of paid employment in a regular full-time position. </section><section prefix="3">Upon the examination of the objective medical evidence by licensed physicians pursuant to KRS 61.665, it shall be determined that: <section prefix="a">The person, since his last day of paid employment, has been mentally or physically incapacitated to perform the job, or jobs of like duties, from which he received his last paid employment. In determining whether the person may return to a job of like duties, any reasonable accommodation by the employer as provided in 42 U.S.C. sec. 12111(9) and 29 C.F.R. Part 1630 shall be considered; </section><section prefix="b">The incapacity is a result of bodily injury, mental illness, or disease. For purposes of this section, "injury" means any physical harm or damage to the human organism other than disease or mental illness; </section><section prefix="c">The incapacity is deemed to be permanent; and </section><section prefix="d">The incapacity does not result directly or indirectly from bodily injury, mental illness, disease, or condition which pre-existed membership in the system or reemployment, whichever is most recent. For purposes of this subsection, reemployment shall not mean a change of employment between employers participating in the retirement systems administered by the Kentucky Retirement Systems with no loss of service credit. </section></section><section prefix="4">Paragraph (d) of subsection (3) of this section shall not apply if: <section prefix="a">The incapacity is a result of bodily injury, mental illness, disease, or condition which has been substantially aggravated by an injury or accident arising out of or in the course of employment; or </section><section prefix="b">The person has at least sixteen (16) years' current or prior service for employment with employers participating in the retirement systems administered by the Kentucky Retirement Systems. </section></section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a"><section prefix="1">An incapacity shall be deemed to be permanent if it is expected to result in death or can be expected to last for a continuous period of not less than twelve (12) months from the person's last day of paid employment in a regular full-time position. </section><section prefix="2">The determination of a permanent incapacity shall be based on the medical evidence contained in the member's file and the member's residual functional capacity and physical exertion requirements. </section></section><section prefix="b">The person's residual functional capacity shall be the person's capacity for work activity on a regular and continuing basis. The person's physical ability shall be assessed in light of the severity of the person's physical, mental, and other impairments. The person's ability to walk, stand, carry, push, pull, reach, handle, and other physical functions shall be considered with regard to physical impairments. The person's ability to understand, remember, and carry out instructions and respond appropriately to supervision, coworkers, and work pressures in a work setting shall be considered with regard to mental impairments. Other impairments, including skin impairments, epilepsy, visual sensory impairments, postural and manipulative limitations, and environmental restrictions, shall be considered in conjunction with the person's physical and mental impairments to determine residual functional capacity. </section><section prefix="c">The person's physical exertion requirements shall be determined based on the following standards: <section prefix="1">Sedentary work shall be work that involves lifting no more than ten (10) pounds at a time and occasionally lifting or carrying articles such as large files, ledgers, and small tools. Although a sedentary job primarily involves sitting, occasional walking and standing may also be required in the performance of duties. </section><section prefix="2">Light work shall be work that involves lifting no more than twenty (20) pounds at a time with frequent lifting or carrying of objects weighing up to ten (10) pounds. A job shall be in this category if lifting is infrequently required but walking and standing are frequently required, or if the job primarily requires sitting with pushing and pulling of arm or leg controls. If the person has the ability to perform substantially all of these activities, the person shall be deemed capable of light work. A person deemed capable of light work shall be deemed capable of sedentary work unless the person has additional limitations such as the loss of fine dexterity or inability to sit for long periods. </section><section prefix="3">Medium work shall be work that involves lifting no more than fifty (50) pounds at a time with frequent lifting or carrying of objects weighing up to twenty-five (25) pounds. If the person is deemed capable of medium work, the person shall be deemed capable of light and sedentary work. </section><section prefix="4">Heavy work shall be work that involves lifting no more than one hundred (100) pounds at a time with frequent lifting or carrying of objects weighing up to fifty (50) pounds. If the person is deemed capable of heavy work, the person shall also be deemed capable of medium, light, and sedentary work. </section><section prefix="5">Very heavy work shall be work that involves lifting objects weighing more than one hundred (100) pounds at a time with frequent lifting or carrying of objects weighing fifty (50) or more pounds. If the person is deemed capable of very heavy work, the person shall be deemed capable of heavy, medium, light, and sedentary work. </section></section></section></text><history> Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 36, sec. 15, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 52, sec. 25, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 385, sec. 19, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 167, sec. 12, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 485, sec. 16, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 240, sec. 30, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 349, sec. 19, effective July 15, 1988; and ch. 387, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 232, sec. 6, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 128, sec. 20, effective March 26, 1974. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 116, sec. 37. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 5. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 35, sec. 9. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 58, sec. 11. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 165, Part II, sec. 8. - Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 19. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22993</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>