<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.6485</section_number><catch_line>State child health plan -- Eligibility criteria -- Schedule of benefits -- Premium contributions -- Access. </catch_line><order_by>6485</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall prepare a state child health plan meeting the requirements of Title XXI of the Federal Social Security Act, for submission to the Secretary of the United States Department of Health and Human Services within such time as will permit the state to receive the maximum amounts of federal matching funds available under Title XXI. The cabinet shall, by administrative regulation promulgated in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A, establish the following: <section prefix="a">The eligibility criteria for children covered by the Kentucky Children's Health Insurance Program. However, no person eligible for services under Title XIX of the Social Security Act 42 U.S.C. 1396 to 1396v, as amended, shall be eligible for services under the Kentucky Children's Health Insurance Program except to the extent that Title XIX coverage is expanded by KRS 205.6481 to 205.6495 and KRS 304.17A-340; </section><section prefix="b">The schedule of benefits to be covered by the Kentucky Children's Health Insurance Program, which shall include preventive services, vision services including glasses, and dental services including at least sealants, extractions, and fillings, and which shall be at least equivalent to one (1) of the following: <section prefix="1">The standard Blue Cross/Blue Shield preferred provider option under the Federal Employees Health Benefit Plan established by U.S.C. sec. 8903(1); </section><section prefix="2">A mid-range health benefit coverage plan that is offered and generally available to state employees; or </section><section prefix="3">Health insurance coverage offered by a health maintenance organization that has the largest insured commercial, non-Medicaid enrollment of covered lives in the state; </section></section><section prefix="c">The premium contribution per family of health insurance coverage available under the Kentucky Children's Health Insurance Program with provisions for the payment of premium contributions by families of children eligible for coverage by the program based upon a sliding scale relating to family income. Premium contributions shall be based on a six (6) month period not to exceed: <section prefix="1">Ten dollars ($10), to be paid by a family with income between one hundred percent (100%) to one hundred thirty-three percent (133%) of the federal poverty level; </section><section prefix="2">Twenty dollars ($20), to be paid by a family with income between one hundred thirty-four percent (134%) to one hundred forty-nine percent (149%) of the federal poverty level; and </section><section prefix="3">One hundred twenty dollars ($120), to be paid by a family with income between one hundred fifty percent (150%) to two hundred percent (200%) of the federal poverty level, and which may be made on a partial payment plan of twenty dollars ($20) per month or sixty dollars ($60) per quarter; </section></section><section prefix="d">The level of copayments for services provided under the Kentucky Children's Health Insurance Program that shall not exceed those allowed by federal law; and </section><section prefix="e">The criteria for health services providers and insurers wishing to contract with the Commonwealth to provide the children's health insurance coverage. However, the cabinet shall provide, in any contracting process for the preventive health insurance program, the opportunity for a public health department to bid on preventive health services to eligible children within the public health department's service area. A public health department shall not be disqualified from bidding because the department does not currently offer all the services required by paragraph (b) of this subsection. The criteria shall be set forth in administrative regulations under KRS Chapter 13A and shall maximize competition among the providers and insurers. The Cabinet for Finance and Administration shall provide oversight over contracting policies and procedures to assure that the number of applicants for contracts is maximized. </section></section><section prefix="2">Within twelve (12) months of federal approval of the state's Title XXI child health plan, the Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall assure that a KCHIP program is available to all eligible children in all regions of the state. If necessary, in order to meet this assurance, the cabinet shall institute its own program. </section><section prefix="3">KCHIP recipients shall have direct access without a referral from any gatekeeper primary care provider to dentists for covered primary dental services and to optometrists and ophthalmologists for covered primary eye and vision services. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 261, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 253, sec. 3, effective April 2, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, G, 3, b, (11) at 643. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7786</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>