<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.30-060</section_number><catch_line>Commonwealth Participation Program for Mixed-Use Redevelopment in Blighted Urban Areas -- Definitions -- Criteria for state participation -- Qualifying expenditures -- Authority review -- Required determinations by the authority -- Pledge limitations -- Tax incentive agreement required. </catch_line><order_by>30-060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Commonwealth Participation Program for Mixed-Use Redevelopment in Blighted Urban Areas is hereby established. </section><section prefix="2">State participation under this program shall be limited to the support of approved public infrastructure costs and costs associated with land preparation, demolition, and clearance determined to be necessary to support private investment or private development projects that benefit the public, where project economics are unable to support or secure necessary financing to undertake the public improvements, land preparation, demolition, and clearance. </section><section prefix="3">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Mixed-use" means a project: <section prefix="1">That includes at least two (2) qualified uses; or </section><section prefix="2">That meets the requirements established by paragraph (b)2.b. of this subsection; </section></section><section prefix="b"><section prefix="1">"Qualified use" means: <section prefix="a">Retail; </section><section prefix="b">Residential; </section><section prefix="c">Office; </section><section prefix="d">Restaurant; or </section><section prefix="e">Hospitality. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Except as otherwise provided in paragraph (b)2.b. of this subsection, to be a qualified use the use must comprise at least twenty percent (20%) of the total finished square footage of the proposed project or represent twenty percent (20%) of the total capital investment; and </section><section prefix="b">In any location within the territory of a consolidated local government or an urban-county government, a project whose uses do not meet the requirements of paragraph (b)2.a. of this subsection may qualify as a mixed-use project if all of the following apply: i. The project includes at least three (3) of the uses listed in paragraph (b)1. of this subsection; ii. One (1) of those uses meets the requirements of paragraph (b)2.a. of this subsection; and iii. The other uses, when combined, jointly comprise at least twenty percent (20%) of the total finished square footage of the proposed project or represent twenty percent (20%) of the total capital investment; and </section></section></section><section prefix="c">"Retail" means an establishment predominantly engaged in the sale of tangible personal property subject to the tax imposed by KRS Chapter 139, but shall not include restaurants. </section></section><section prefix="4">To be considered for state participation under this program, a project shall: <section prefix="a">Be located in an area that has three (3) or more of the conditions listed in KRS 65.7049(3)(a), or be a project described in KRS 65.7049(3)(b); </section><section prefix="b">Be a mixed-use project; </section><section prefix="c">Represent new economic activity in the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="d">Result in a capital investment between twenty million dollars ($20,000,000) and two hundred million dollars ($200,000,000); </section><section prefix="e">Not include any retail establishment that exceeds twenty thousand (20,000) square feet of finished square footage; </section><section prefix="f">Include pedestrian amenities and public space; and </section><section prefix="g">Result in a net positive economic impact to the Commonwealth, taking into consideration any substantial adverse impact on existing Commonwealth businesses. The net positive impact shall be certified to the authority as required by KRS 154.30-030(6)(b). </section></section><section prefix="5">The following costs may be recovered pursuant to this section: <section prefix="a">Up to one hundred percent (100%) of approved public infrastructure costs; and </section><section prefix="b">Up to one hundred percent (100%) of expenses for land preparation, demolition, and clearance necessary for the development to occur. </section></section><section prefix="6">The commission shall review the application, the certification required by KRS 154.30-030, and supporting information as provided in KRS 154.30-030. </section><section prefix="7">The authority shall specifically identify the state taxes from which incremental revenues will be pledged. The authority may pledge up to eighty percent (80%) of the incremental revenues from the identified state tax revenues from the footprint of the project, provided that the maximum amount of incremental revenues that may be pledged for a project during the term of the tax incentive agreement from all approved state taxes shall not exceed the costs and expenses determined under subsection (5) of this section. </section><section prefix="8">As part of the approval process, the authority shall determine the following: <section prefix="a">The footprint of the project; </section><section prefix="b">That the proposed project meets the requirements established by subsection (4) of this section; </section><section prefix="c">The maximum amount of approved public infrastructure costs and expenses for land preparation, demolition, and clearance; </section><section prefix="d">That the local revenues pledged to support the public infrastructure of the project and local revenues pledged to support the overall project are of a sufficient amount to warrant participation of the Commonwealth in the project; </section><section prefix="e">The termination date of the tax incentive agreement; and </section><section prefix="f">Any adjustments to be made to old revenues, in determining incremental revenues during each year of the term of the tax incentive agreement. </section></section><section prefix="9">If state income taxes or local occupational licenses taxes are included for a project that includes office space, the authority shall consider the impact of pledging these taxes on the ability to utilize other economic development projects at a later date. </section><section prefix="10">The pledge of state incremental tax revenues of the Commonwealth by the authority shall be implemented through the execution of a tax incentive agreement between the Commonwealth and the agency, city, or county in accordance with KRS 154.30-070. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 4, effective June 8, 2011. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 178, sec. 19, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 19, effective March 23, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><former-codification> KRS 65.7077. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:54</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43431</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>