<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VIII" order_by="8">OFFICES AND OFFICERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="64" order_by="64">FEES AND COMPENSATION OF PUBLIC OFFICERS AND EMPLOYEES </unit></structure><section_number>64.185</section_number><catch_line>Coroners and deputies. </catch_line><order_by>185</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Coroners shall receive out of the county, consolidated local government, charter county government, urban-county government, or unified local government treasury, whichever is appropriate, the monthly compensation the fiscal court of each county shall fix, subject to the following minimums: </section>    County     Monthly Minimum   Population        Compensation  (a) 10,000 or less  $200  (b) 10,001 to  20,000  300  (c) 20,001 to  40,000  350  (d) 40,001 to  60,000  400  (e) 60,001 to 100,000  450  (f) 100,001 to 150,000  800  (g) 150,001 or more  1,000  Coroners who hold a current certificate of continuing education, issued jointly by the Department of Criminal Justice Training, Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, and the Office of the Kentucky State Medical Examiner, Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, shall be paid the following minimum monthly compensation set forth in this subsection in recognition of the training:     County     Monthly Minimum   Population        Compensation  (a) 10,000 or less  $400  (b) 10,001 to 20,000  500  (c) 20,001 to 40,000  650  (d) 40,001 to 60,000  750  (e) 60,001 to 100,000  850  (f) 100,001 to 150,000  1,100  (g) 150,001 or more  1,300 <section prefix="2">Deputy coroners who hold a current certificate of continuing education, as described in subsection (1) of this section, shall receive out of the county, consolidated local government, charter county government, urban-county government, or unified local government treasury, whichever is appropriate, the monthly compensation the fiscal court of each county shall fix, subject to the following minimums: </section>    County     Monthly Minimum   Population        Compensation  (a) 10,000 or less  $200  (b) 10,001 to 20,000  250  (c) 20,001 to 40,000  275  (d) 40,001 to 60,000  300  (e) 60,001 to 100,000  400  (f) 100,001 to 150,000  900  (g) 150,001 or more  1,100 <section prefix="3">The fiscal court of any county, or the legislative body of a consolidated local government, charter county government, urban-county government, or unified local government may compensate coroners and deputy coroners an additional amount of up to three hundred dollars ($300) per month as an expense allowance. </section><section prefix="4">The initial course of continuing education required under subsection (1) of this section shall consist of a basic training course prescribed by the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet. Annually thereafter the coroner shall attend and successfully complete at least eighteen (18) hours of approved training in order to be compensated in accordance with subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="5">If a deputy coroner assumes the office of coroner after receiving the training stipulated in this section, the deputy coroner shall be compensated in accordance with the compensation schedule set forth in subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="6">The number of deputy coroners in a county shall not exceed one (1) for each twenty-five thousand (25,000) inhabitants, or fraction thereof, according to the most recent federal census, but every coroner may, subject to the approval of the legislative body of the county, consolidated local government, charter county government, urban-county government, or unified local government, appoint additional deputy coroners, regardless of population. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 74, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 138, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 424, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 465, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 248, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 195, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 93, sec. 19, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 387, sec. 2, effective July 1, 1974. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 68. -- Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 143, sec. 1. -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 125, secs. 1, 2, and 3. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23208</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>