<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="91" order_by="91">A FINANCE AND REVENUE OF CITIES </unit></structure><section_number>91A.350</section_number><catch_line>Local tourist and convention commissions -- Continued funding.   </catch_line><order_by>350</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The local governing bodies of counties containing cities of the first class and the local governing bodies of the cities of the first class located therein may, by joint or separate action, establish tourist and convention commissions for the purpose of promoting convention and tourist activity. The local governing body of a consolidated local government may establish or maintain tourist and convention commissions for the purpose of promoting convention and tourist activity. </section><section prefix="2">Except in a county containing a consolidated local government, the local governing bodies of counties containing an urban-county government and counties containing cities of the home rule class and the local governing bodies of the cities of the home rule class located therein may, by joint or separate action, establish tourist and convention commissions for the purpose of promoting and developing convention and tourist activities and facilities. </section><section prefix="3">The local governing bodies of two (2) or more counties may jointly establish tourist and convention commissions for the purpose of promoting convention and tourist activities and facilities. </section><section prefix="4">The local governing bodies of two (2) or more counties, which may include a consolidated local government, may jointly establish tourist and convention commissions for the purpose of promoting convention and tourist activities and facilities. </section><section prefix="5">Tourist and convention commissions may continue to fund recreational activities or projects not related to tourism or conventions that were funded by the commission prior to July 13, 1990, at a level no greater than that provided by the commission in the 1990 fiscal year. </section><section prefix="6">For the purpose of promoting recreational, convention, and tourist activity in cities and counties served by joint playground and recreation boards established under KRS 97.035; to provide the boards with the same authority to issue revenue bonds granted to cities by KRS 58.010 to 58.150 and 103.200 to 103.285; and to authorize the boards to build and issue bonds for facilities located on leasehold and permithold land. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 90, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 102, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 344, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 56, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 302, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 324, sec. 1. -- Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 138, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><former-codification> KRS 83.340. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:10</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43675</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>