<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17A-812</section_number><catch_line>Initial and continuing financial solvency requirements. </catch_line><order_by>17A-812</order_by><text><section prefix="1">This section applies to a group applying for and holding a certificate of filing as a self-insured employer-organized association group. </section><section prefix="2">To obtain and to maintain its certificate of filing, a self-insured employer-organized association group shall have sufficient financial strength to pay all public or professional liabilities covered by the group, including known claims and expenses and incurred but unreported claims and expenses. </section><section prefix="3">The commissioner shall require the following of a self-insured employer-organized association group: <section prefix="a">An actuarial certification by a member of the American Academy of Actuaries of the adequacy of the proposed rates funding arrangements of the group; </section><section prefix="b">Specific reinsurance ensuring the solvency of the funding arrangement; </section><section prefix="c">A demonstration of capital and surplus as follows: <section prefix="1">Initial financial requirements. Every self-insured employer-organized association shall demonstrate initial capital and surplus equal to the greater of: <section prefix="a">Five hundred thousand dollars ($500,000); </section><section prefix="b">Two percent (2%) of projected annual contribution revenues on the first one hundred fifty million dollars ($150,000,000) of contributions and one percent (1%) of projected annual contributions on the contributions in excess of one hundred fifty million dollars ($150,000,000); or </section><section prefix="c">An amount equal to the sum of eight percent (8%) of projected annual health care expenditures except those paid on a capitated basis or managed hospital payment basis and four percent (4%) of projected annual hospital expenditures paid on a managed hospital payment basis. </section></section><section prefix="2">Continuing financial requirements. Every self-insured employer-organized association shall demonstrate ongoing capital and surplus equal to the greater of: <section prefix="a">Five hundred thousand dollars ($500,000); </section><section prefix="b">Two percent (2%) of annual contribution revenues, as reported on the most recent annual financial statement filed with the commissioner, on the first one hundred fifty million dollars ($150,000,000) of contributions and one percent (1%) of annual premiums on the contributions in excess of one hundred fifty million dollars ($150,000,000); or </section><section prefix="c">An amount equal to the sum of eight percent (8%) of projected annual health care expenditures except those paid on a capitated basis or managed hospital payment basis and four percent (4%) of annual hospital expenditures paid on a managed hospital payment basis, as reported on the most recent financial statement filed with the commissioner; and </section></section></section><section prefix="d">A fidelity bond for the administrator and a fidelity bond for the service company in forms and amounts prescribed by the commissioner. </section></section><section prefix="4">The commissioner, if not satisfied with the financial strength of a self-insured employer-organized association group, may require any or all of the following of a self-insured employer-organized association group: <section prefix="a">Security in the form and amount prescribed by the commissioner as follows: <section prefix="1">A surety bond issued by a corporate surety authorized to transact business in the Commonwealth of Kentucky; or </section><section prefix="2">Any financial security endorsement issued as part of an acceptable excess insurance contract issued by an authorized insurer, which may be used to meet all or part of the security requirement. </section></section> The bond or financial security endorsement shall be solely for the benefit of the insured creditors to pay claims and associated expenses and shall be payable upon the failure of the group to pay professional or public liability claims the group is legally obligated to pay. The commissioner may establish and adjust the requirements for the amount of security based on differences among groups in their size, types of business, years in existence, or other relevant factors. <section prefix="b">Specific and aggregate excess insurance in a form and amount issued by an insurer acceptable to the commissioner. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1261, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 7, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29367</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>