<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="441" order_by="441">JAILS AND COUNTY PRISONERS </unit></structure><section_number>441.064</section_number><catch_line>Responsibilities of department -- Jail inspections -- Access to jails -- Reports.   </catch_line><order_by>064</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The department shall employ the jail consultants, inspectors, and other employees necessary to administer and enforce the provisions of KRS 441.055 to 441.075. </section><section prefix="2">The department shall inspect each jail biannually and may inspect jails more frequently. </section><section prefix="3">The department shall be granted access at any reasonable time to any jail facility or part of any jail facility and shall be granted access to all books, records, and data pertaining to any jail which the department deems necessary for the administration and enforcement of the provisions of KRS 441.055 to 441.075. </section><section prefix="4">Following an inspection of a jail, the department shall make notification of the inspection by certified or electronic mail of any deficiencies which are discovered and documented. If the deficiencies are related to health or safety, the notification shall be sent within ten (10) working days, excluding weekends and holidays. The department shall submit an annual written report of the findings of its inspections and the condition of the jail to: <section prefix="a">The jailer and the fiscal court in counties where the jail is governed by the county; </section><section prefix="b">The jail administrator and the governing authority for a jail governed by an urban-county or metro government; and </section><section prefix="c">The jail administrator, the regional board authority, and the fiscal courts of the counties represented in counties where the jail is governed by a regional jail board. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 4, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 107, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 108, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 116, effective July 14, 1992; and ch. 262, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 385, sec. 7, effective July 1, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><former-codification> KRS 441.012. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44696</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>