<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171">STATE LIBRARIES -- LIBRARIANS -- STATE ARCHIVES AND RECORDS </unit></structure><section_number>171.420</section_number><catch_line>State Archives and Records Commission. </catch_line><order_by>420</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The State Archives and Records Commission is hereby created and shall be a seventeen (17) member body constituted as follows: <section prefix="a">The state librarian or his designee, who shall be the chairman of the commission; </section><section prefix="b">The secretary of the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet or his designee; </section><section prefix="c">The Auditor of Public Accounts or his designee; </section><section prefix="d">The Chief Justice of the Supreme Court or his designee; </section><section prefix="e">The director of the Legislative Research Commission or his designee; </section><section prefix="f">The Attorney General or his designee; </section><section prefix="g">The director of the Office for Policy and Management in the Office of the Controller or his designee; </section><section prefix="h">The executive director of the Commonwealth Office of Technology or her or his designee; </section><section prefix="i">One (1) member appointed by the Governor from a list of three (3) persons submitted by the president of the University of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="j">One (1) member appointed by the Governor from a list of three (3) persons submitted by the president of the Kentucky Historical Society; </section><section prefix="k">One (1) member appointed by the Governor from a list of three (3) persons submitted by the president of the Kentucky Library Association; </section><section prefix="l">One (1) member appointed by the Governor from a list of seven (7) persons with one (1) name submitted by each of the presidents of the state universities and colleges; </section><section prefix="m">Four (4) citizens at large; and </section><section prefix="n">One (1) member appointed by the Governor from a list of three (3) persons, with one (1) name submitted by each of the presidents of the Kentucky League of Cities, the Kentucky Association of Counties, and the Kentucky Association of School Administrators. </section></section><section prefix="2">Vacancies shall be filled by the Governor in the same manner as initial appointments are made. All members shall serve for a term of four (4) years, provided that one (1) of the initial appointments shall be for a term of four (4) years, one (1) for three (3) years, one (1) for two (2) years, and one (1) for one (1) year. </section><section prefix="3">The commission shall advise the Department for Libraries and Archives on matters relating to archives and records management. The commission shall have the authority to review and approve schedules for retention and destruction of records submitted by state and local agencies. In all cases, the commission shall determine questions which relate to destruction of public records, and their decision shall be binding on the parties concerned and final, except that the commission may reconsider or modify its actions upon the agreement of a simple majority of the membership present and voting. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 56, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 111, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 602, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 506, sec. 20, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 536, sec. 20, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 209, sec. 18, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 185, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 245, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 120, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 242, sec. 1. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. II, sec. 9(2); and ch. 257, sec. 5. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 33. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 106, Art. V, sec. 3. -- Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 49, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2006).  Under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(c) and for the sake of clarity, the Reviser of Statutes has divided this statute as contained in 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 111, into numbered subsections and paragraphs. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4820</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>