<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XLII" order_by="42">MISCELLANEOUS PRACTICE PROVISIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="456" order_by="456">CIVIL ORDERS OF PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>456.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for chapter.  </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in this chapter:(1)"Dating relationship" means a relationship between individuals who have orhave had a relationship of a romantic or intimate nature. It does not include acasual acquaintanceship or ordinary fraternization in a business or socialcontext. The following factors may be considered in addition to any otherrelevant factors in determining whether the relationship is or was of a romanticor intimate nature:(a)Declarations of romantic interest;(b)The relationship was characterized by the expectation of affection;(c)Attendance at social outings together as a couple;(d)The frequency and type of interaction between the persons, includingwhether the persons have been involved together over time and on acontinuous basis during the course of the relationship;(e)The length and recency of the relationship; and(f)Other indications of a substantial connection that would lead areasonable person to understand that a dating relationship existed;(2)"Dating violence and abuse" means physical injury, serious physical injury,stalking, sexual assault, or the infliction of fear of imminent physical injury,serious physical injury, sexual abuse, or assault occurring between personswho are or have been in a dating relationship;(3)"Foreign protective order" means any judgment, decree, or order of protectionwhich is entitled to full faith and credit pursuant to 18 U.S.C. sec. 2265 whichwas not issued on the basis of domestic violence and abuse;(4)"Global positioning monitoring system" means a system that electronicallydetermines a person's location through a device worn by the person whichdoes not invade his or her bodily integrity and which transmits the person'slatitude and longitude data to a monitoring entity;(5)"Order of protection" means any interpersonal protective order, including thoseissued on a temporary basis, and includes a foreign protective order;(6)"Sexual assault" refers to conduct prohibited as any degree of rape, sodomy,or sexual abuse under KRS Chapter 510 or incest under KRS 530.020;(7)"Stalking" refers to conduct prohibited as stalking under KRS 508.140 or508.150; and(8)"Substantial violation" means criminal conduct which involves actual orthreatened harm to the person, family, or property of an individual protected byan order of protection.</text><history>Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 19, effective January 1, 2016.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:24</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44767</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>