<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>271B.8-310</section_number><catch_line>Director conflict of interest. </catch_line><order_by>8-310</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A conflict of interest transaction shall be a transaction with the corporation in which a director of the corporation has a direct or indirect interest. A conflict of interest transaction shall not be voidable by the corporation solely because of the director's interest in the transaction if any one (1) of the following is true: <section prefix="a">The material facts of the transaction and the director's interest were disclosed or known to the board of directors or a committee of the board of directors and the board of directors or committee authorized, approved, or ratified the transaction; </section><section prefix="b">The material facts of the transaction and the director's interest were disclosed or known to the shareholders entitled to vote and they authorized, approved, or ratified the transaction; or </section><section prefix="c">The transaction was fair to the corporation. </section></section><section prefix="2">For purposes of this section, a director of the corporation shall have an indirect interest in a transaction if: <section prefix="a">Another entity in which he has a material financial interest or in which he is a general partner is a party to the transaction; or </section><section prefix="b">Another entity of which he is a director, officer, or trustee is a party to the transaction and the transaction is or should be considered by the board of directors of the corporation. </section></section><section prefix="3">For purposes of subsection (1)(a) of this section, a conflict of interest transaction shall be considered authorized, approved, or ratified if it receives the affirmative vote of a majority of the directors on the board of directors (or on the committee) who have no direct or indirect interest in the transaction, but a transaction shall not be authorized, approved, or ratified under this section by a single director. If a majority of the directors who have no direct or indirect interest in the transaction vote to authorize, approve, or ratify the transaction, a quorum shall be present for the purpose of taking action under this section. The presence of, or a vote cast by, a director with a direct or indirect interest in the transaction shall not affect the validity of any action taken under subsection (1)(a) of this section if the transaction is otherwise authorized, approved, or ratified as provided in that subsection. </section><section prefix="4">For purposes of subsection (1)(b) of this section, a conflict of interest transaction shall be considered authorized, approved, or ratified if it receives the vote of a majority of the shares entitled to be counted under this subsection. Shares owned by or voted under the control of a director who has a direct or indirect interest in the transaction, and shares owned by or voted under the control of an entity described in subsection (2)(a) of this section, may not be counted in a vote of shareholders to determine whether to authorize, approve, or ratify a conflict of interest transaction under subsection (1)(b) of this section. The vote of those shares, however, shall be counted in determining whether the transaction is approved under other sections of this chapter. A majority of the shares that are entitled to be counted in a vote on the transaction under this subsection shall constitute a quorum for the purpose of taking action under this section. </section></text><history>Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 86, effective January 1, 1989; and ch. 224, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1988 </effective><former-codification> KRS 271A.206. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:23</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13390</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>