<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.702</section_number><catch_line>Exemptions from requirements of KRS 198B.700 to 198B.738. </catch_line><order_by>702</order_by><text>KRS 198B.700 to 198B.738 shall apply to an individual who conducts home inspections for compensation, but shall not apply to the following: <section prefix="1">An individual who is acting within the scope of the individual's employment as: <section prefix="a">A code enforcement official for the state or a political subdivision of the state; or </section><section prefix="b">A representative of a state or local housing agency or an individual acting under the authority of the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development; </section></section><section prefix="2">An individual who is acting within the scope of the individual's license as a licensed: <section prefix="a">Architect under KRS Chapter 323; </section><section prefix="b">Professional engineer under KRS Chapter 322; </section><section prefix="c">Plumbing contractor or journeyman plumber under KRS Chapter 318; </section><section prefix="d">Electrician, master electrician, or electrical contractor under KRS Chapter 227A; </section><section prefix="e">Liquefied petroleum gas dealers under KRS Chapter 234; </section><section prefix="f">Master heating, ventilation, and air conditioning contractor, journeyman heating, ventilation, and air conditioning mechanic, or an apprentice heating, ventilation, and air conditioning mechanic under this chapter; or </section><section prefix="g">Fire protection sprinkler contractor, fire protection system certificate holder, or certified fire sprinkler inspector under this chapter; </section></section><section prefix="3">An individual licensed under KRS Chapter 324 as a real estate broker, broker-salesperson, or salesperson and is acting within the scope of the individual's license; </section><section prefix="4">An individual who is licensed under KRS Chapter 324A as a real estate appraiser and is acting within the scope of the individual's license; </section><section prefix="5">An individual who holds a license under KRS Chapter 304 as an insurance adjuster and is acting within the scope of the individual's license; </section><section prefix="6">An individual who holds a permit, certificate, or license to: <section prefix="a">Use and apply pesticides; or </section><section prefix="b">Make diagnostic inspections and reports for wood destroying pests and fungi under KRS Chapter 217B and is acting within the scope of the individual's certificate or license; </section></section><section prefix="7">An individual who holds a license from a political subdivision as a tradesperson or home builder and is acting within the scope of the individual's license; </section><section prefix="8">An individual who holds a current and valid license, certificate, or permit under KRS 227.550 to 227.660 and is acting within the scope of the individual's license, certificate, or permit as a: <section prefix="a">Manufactured home retailer; </section><section prefix="b">Manufactured home certified retailer; or </section><section prefix="c">Manufactured home certified installer; or </section></section><section prefix="9">A person not subject to licensure by the Commonwealth who is engaged in providing estimates for remodeling or repair to a residential dwelling. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 4, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 298, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 2, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39900</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>