<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.602</section_number><catch_line>Nominating commission for appointments to board of directors. </catch_line><order_by>602</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There shall be a nominating commission for each college board of directors required under KRS 164.600 to provide names of nominees to the Governor for appointment to the board of directors. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Each nominating commission shall be composed of five (5) members appointed by the Governor who shall reside in the service area of the college at the time of their appointment. Commission members shall have no conflict of interest in accordance with KRS 45A.340 or have a relative employed by a public postsecondary institution, the Council on Postsecondary Education, the Kentucky Higher Education Assistance Authority, the Kentucky Higher Education Student Loan Corporation, or the Kentucky Authority for Educational Television. </section><section prefix="b">Members of the nominating commission shall serve four (4) year terms, or until a successor shall be appointed, except the initial appointments shall be as follows:  <section prefix="1">One (1) member shall serve a one (1) year term; </section><section prefix="2">Two (2) members shall serve a two (2) year term; </section><section prefix="3">One (1) member shall serve a three (3) year term; and </section><section prefix="4">One (1) member shall serve a four (4) year term. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">The Governor shall appoint commission members who reflect, inasmuch as possible, equal representation of the two (2) sexes and in the context of the total membership of all of the commissions, shall approximate the proportional representation of the two (2) leading political parties and the minority racial composition of the state. </section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">The nominating commission shall submit to the Governor the names of three (3) nominees for each position on the board of directors who meet the eligibility criteria for membership under KRS 164.600. </section><section prefix="b">In the selection of the nominees, the nominating commission shall consider the needs of the respective college, locate potential appointees, review candidates' qualifications and references, conduct interviews, and carry out other search and screening activities as necessary. The commission shall consider the goals for diversity of membership as set out in subsection (3) of this section. </section><section prefix="c">Each appointment to the board of directors shall be made thirty (30) days prior to the expiration of a term or as soon as practicable following an unforeseen vacancy. The Governor may reject all names of nominees and request the submission of three (3) additional names for consideration. </section></section><section prefix="5">The members of the commissions shall be reimbursed for actual and necessary expenditures incurred in the performance of their duties. </section><section prefix="6">The nominating commissions shall be attached to the Kentucky Community and Technical College System and the Governor's office staff shall provide staffing and administrative assistance. </section></text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 56, sec. 6, effective June 24, 2003. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 214, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4350</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>