<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.442</section_number><catch_line>Suspension or revocation of license or driving privileges in another jurisdiction -- Persons eligible for restricted license -- Issuance of license valid only in Kentucky -- Removal of restrictions -- Inapplicability to commercial driver's license. </catch_line><order_by>442</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The circuit clerk shall, before issuing or renewing a Kentucky operator's license, verify through the National Drivers Register that the person applying for an initial or renewal Kentucky operator's license does not currently have his or her operator's license or driving privilege suspended or revoked in another licensing jurisdiction. </section><section prefix="2">If the person's operator's license or driving privilege is currently suspended or revoked in another licensing jurisdiction for a traffic offense where the conviction for the offense is less than five (5) years old, the circuit clerk shall not issue the person an initial or renewal Kentucky operator's license until the person resolves the matter in the other licensing jurisdiction and complies with the provisions of this chapter. </section><section prefix="3">A person whose operator's license has been suspended or revoked in another licensing jurisdiction, or the holder of a Kentucky operator's license whose driving privileges have been suspended in another licensing jurisdiction, may be issued a Kentucky license, or may renew a Kentucky license if: <section prefix="a">The conviction causing the suspension or revocation is more than five (5) years old; </section><section prefix="b">The conviction is for a traffic offense other than a felony traffic offense or a habitual violator offense; and </section><section prefix="c">The person has been a resident of the Commonwealth for at least five (5) years prior to the date of application for issuance or renewal. </section></section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">A person applying for an operator's license under subsection (3) of this section shall submit an application to the Transportation Cabinet in Frankfort or a Transportation Cabinet field office. </section><section prefix="b">The Transportation Cabinet shall, within fifteen (15) days of receipt of the application, determine if the person is eligible to receive a license under subsection (3) of this section. </section><section prefix="c">If the Transportation Cabinet determines the person may be issued a license under subsection (3) of this section, the cabinet shall issue the person an official form that the applicant shall present to the circuit clerk of the county where the person resides. Upon receipt of this notice, and completion of any examinations required under KRS 186.480, the circuit clerk shall issue the applicant a license under subsection (3) of this section. </section></section><section prefix="5">A person issued a Kentucky operator's license in accordance with subsection (3) of this section shall be issued an operator's license marked "Valid in Kentucky Only" and shall sign a statement that the person understands that he or she may be subject to arrest and detention if stopped by a law enforcement officer in another state while operating a motor vehicle on this restricted license. </section><section prefix="6">If a person granted a license under subsection (3) of this section satisfies the requirements to have the suspension or revocation in another state lifted, the person shall apply to the circuit clerk to be issued a new license without the restrictions outlined in subsection (3) of this section. </section><section prefix="7">The provisions of subsection (3) of this section shall not apply to a commercial driver's license. </section></text><history> Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 189, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6057</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>