<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="352" order_by="352">MINING REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>352.145</section_number><catch_line>Restrictions on work where hazardous conditions exist -- Requirement of visible warning devices and enclosed operator's cabs at stockpiles with underground feeders or draw-off tunnels -- Barrier requirements for haulage roadways -- Examinations and equipment checks. </catch_line><order_by>145</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No employee of a surface coal mining operation shall be assigned, allowed, or required to perform work alone in any area where hazardous conditions exist that would endanger his safety unless he can communicate with others, can be heard, or can be seen. </section><section prefix="2">At stockpiles with underground feeders or draw-off tunnels, the licensee shall install and maintain a visible warning device that shall be activated when the feeders are in operation. </section><section prefix="3">The operator's cab of all equipment being operated on or in the immediate area of a stockpile with underground feeders or draw-off tunnels shall be enclosed by a compartment and shall be furnished with a self-contained self-rescuer that is capable of providing oxygen for a period of not less than one (1) hour. </section><section prefix="4">On all haulage roadways, berms, guardrails, concrete barriers, or other suitable devices shall be installed in such a manner that they extend to at least the mid-wheel height of the highest vehicle or equipment that regularly travels that type of roadway. </section><section prefix="5">A surface preshift examination shall be conducted within three (3) hours prior to men working. A certified foreman shall check the areas where men are required to work or travel during the shift. Roadways, pit areas, highwalls, and dumping points shall be checked. If any hazardous conditions are found, they shall be corrected prior to men working in the area. A suitable record book shall be kept in the control of the mine foreman. Immediately after the examination of the mine or portion thereof, the mine foreman shall enter and sign a record of the examination in the book with ink. The record shall clearly show any danger discovered at the mine, and the action taken to correct the dangerous conditions. The record book shall, at all times during the working hours, be accessible to the mine inspector or analyst and the miner or his representative. </section><section prefix="6">All equipment operators shall conduct a preoperational check of their equipment. All preoperational checks shall be recorded by the equipment operator and kept with the equipment and, if a hazard is found to exist on any piece of equipment that would render it unsafe to operate, the hazardous condition shall be reported to the mine foreman or mine superintendent. All appropriate repairs shall be made before the equipment is put back into operation, except for moving the equipment to a safe place for repairs. The record book of all hazardous conditions and repairs made shall be kept in the control of the mine foreman or mine superintendent at all times. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 94, sec. 16, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 478, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 410, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32988</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>