<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="334" order_by="334">SPECIALISTS IN HEARING INSTRUMENTS </unit></structure><section_number>334.150</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of the board. </catch_line><order_by>150</order_by><text>The powers and duties of the board shall be as follows: <section prefix="1">To authorize all disbursements necessary to carry out provisions of this chapter. </section><section prefix="2">To prepare and administer qualifying examinations to test the knowledge and proficiency of applicants for licensing. </section><section prefix="3">To license persons who apply to the board and who are qualified to practice the fitting of hearing instruments. </section><section prefix="4">To purchase and maintain or rent audiometric equipment and facilities necessary to carry out the examination of applicants for licensing. </section><section prefix="5">To issue and renew licenses. </section><section prefix="6">To suspend, revoke, refuse to issue, or renew licenses, impose probationary or supervisory conditions, issue letters of reprimand, or levy fines against a licensee, or any combination thereof. </section><section prefix="7">To appoint representatives to conduct or supervise the examination of applicants for licensing. </section><section prefix="8">To designate the time and place for examining applicants. </section><section prefix="9">To promulgate administrative regulations consistent with the laws of this Commonwealth which are necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter. </section><section prefix="10">To require the periodic inspection of audiometric testing equipment and to carry out the periodic inspection of facilities of persons who practice the fitting of hearing instruments. </section><section prefix="11">To employ secretaries, attorneys, inspectors, clerks, or any other employees that the board may deem necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter. The board may employ or discharge at its discretion. </section><section prefix="12">To initiate a formal educational program consistent with the intent of this chapter in that the consumer public shall be served by the specialist in hearing instruments trained in the latest technology in fitting hearing instruments. </section><section prefix="13">To promulgate administrative regulations establishing requirements and standards for continuing education. </section><section prefix="14">To administer oaths and to require the attendance of witnesses, the production of books, records and papers pertinent to any matters coming before the board by the issuance of process which shall be served and returned in the same manner as in civil actions and for the disobedience of which the board shall have by resort to a court of competent jurisdiction the power to invoke the same rights as are provided in the event of disobedience of a subpoena or subpoena duces tecum in a civil action. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 460, sec. 15, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 276, sec. 6. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 15. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31882</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>