<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXII" order_by="32">OWNERSHIP AND CONVEYANCE OF PROPERTY</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="382" order_by="382">CONVEYANCES AND ENCUMBRANCES </unit></structure><section_number>382.210</section_number><catch_line>General index of real property records in courthouse districts -- Contracts for indexing work. </catch_line><order_by>210</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In counties in which a courthouse district has been created and provisions made for appointment of commissioners in that district, the commissioners may direct that the clerk of such county shall, in such district, in addition to the alphabetical cross-index provided for in KRS 382.200, have made in books prepared for that purpose, general indexes to the records of all the real property in the district by placing under the heads of the original surveyed sections or surveys, or parts of a section or survey, squares, subdivisions, or lots on the left page of such index book:  <section prefix="a">A plat showing the survey, or part of section thereof, subdivision, square, or lots indexed on the page;  </section><section prefix="b">The name of the grantor or grantors;  </section><section prefix="c">Next to the right the name of the grantee or grantees;  </section><section prefix="d">The number and page of the record where the instrument is found recorded;  </section><section prefix="e">The character of the instrument, to be followed by a pertinent description of the property conveyed by the deed, lease, or assignment of lease or other instrument of writing affecting the lot or land described; and  </section><section prefix="f">On the opposite page, in like manner, all the mortgages, liens or other encumbrances affecting such real estate.  </section></section><section prefix="2">The clerk of each county having a courthouse district shall, when so directed by the commissioners, prepare the proper specifications for an additional indexing system to bring up and complete the system to the date the new system is installed. He shall advertise for bids for the work under the specifications prepared and shall, with the approval of the commissioners, enter into a contract with the lowest and best bidder for the work. Before entering into contract with the successful bidder, the clerk shall require him to give bond for the faithful performance of the contract in a sum fixed by the commissioners and the bond shall be approved by the commissioners. The cost or expense of the work shall be paid by the commissioners out of the funds of the courthouse district.  </section><section prefix="3">When the general indexes are completed, they shall constitute the official indexes, and the clerk of the county shall keep them up by indexing therein all conveyances in the district within one (1) month from the time they are lodged for record, and when so indexed the alphabetical cross-index of such instruments need no longer be preserved. When such records or any part of them become defaced or injured, the clerk shall transcribe them into new books, which shall be as valid in law as the original record, and the transcript therefrom shall be received and taken as of the same force and effect. The cost of such transcription shall be paid for out of the funds of the courthouse district.  </section><section prefix="4">In courthouse districts in which additional sectional indexes have been prepared, the commissioners may employ a competent person to keep up the indexes, in order that such additional indexes may be kept correctly and accurately. The commissioners shall pay such person a salary of not over two thousand four hundred dollars ($2,400) per annum out of the funds of the courthouse district. </section></text><history>Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 513. </history><metadata><effective>October 1, 1942</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35602</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>