<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="323" order_by="323">ARCHITECTS </unit></structure><section_number>323.130</section_number><catch_line>Hearing in disciplinary action -- Appeal. </catch_line><order_by>130</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In any action taken pursuant to KRS 323.120, the board shall conduct a hearing in accordance with the provisions of this chapter and KRS Chapter 13B. The hearing may be conducted by the full board or at its designation, a member thereof, a panel of the board, a hearing officer, or a combination of the foregoing; </section><section prefix="2">If the hearing is conducted by less than a majority of the full board, or by a hearing officer, the board members or hearing officer, as the case may be, may only issue a recommended order, and the recommended order shall be subject to review by a majority of the full board, which shall issue a final order; and </section><section prefix="3">The board may proceed against a licensee on its own initiative, on the basis of either information contained in its own records or information obtained through its informal investigation. If a formal complaint verified by affidavit is filed with the board by a responsible citizen or organization, containing allegations that if true would warrant action pursuant to KRS 323.120, the board may proceed against the licensee. </section><section prefix="4">Any final order of the board may be appealed to Franklin Circuit Court in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 287, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 190, sec. 8, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 79, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 315, sec. 58. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 218, sec. 11. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 73-12. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31495</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>