<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="324" order_by="324">REAL ESTATE BROKERS AND SALESMEN </unit></structure><section_number>324.310</section_number><catch_line>Delivery of sales associate's license to commission when association terminated -- Placing license in escrow with commission. </catch_line><order_by>310</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If any sales associate is discharged or terminates his or her association with the principal broker, it shall be the duty of the broker to immediately deliver or mail to the commission the sales associate's license in a manner that complies with KRS 324.312, along with the release statement signed by the principal broker. The broker shall, at the time of mailing the sales associate's license to the commission, address a communication to the last known residence address of the sales associate, which shall advise the sales associate that his or her license has been delivered or mailed to the commission. A copy of the communication to the sales associate shall accompany the license when mailed or delivered to the commission. It shall be unlawful for any sales associate to perform any of the acts contemplated by this chapter either directly or indirectly under authority of the sales associate's license from and after the date of receipt of the license from the broker by the commission. </section><section prefix="2">A licensee may place his or her license in escrow with the commission provided that: <section prefix="a">The licensee does not engage in any real estate activity for others during the term of escrow of the license; and </section><section prefix="b">The licensee pays the annual license renewal fees for each year the license is in escrow. </section></section><section prefix="3">At the request of the licensee, upon the meeting of requirements applicable to active licensees and completion of all continuing education requirements, a license placed in escrow shall be automatically converted to an active license upon payment of the established change fee. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 58, sec. 10, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 488, sec. 27, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 448, sec. 26, effective July 14, 1992 -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 352, sec. 11, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 196, sec. 29, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 10, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 22. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 315, sec. 64. -- Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 184, secs. 3 and 11. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 3990e-5. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31609</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>