<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="272" order_by="272">COOPERATIVE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>272.480</section_number><catch_line>Other corporations may become livestock protective associations -- Procedure. </catch_line><order_by>480</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any corporation or association organized under previously existing statutes may, by a majority vote of its members, be brought under the provisions of KRS 272.360 to 272.510 by limiting its membership and adopting the other restrictions as provided herein. It shall make out in duplicate a statement signed and sworn to by its directors to the effect that the corporation or association has, by a majority vote of the members, decided to accept the benefits and be bound by the provisions of KRS 272.360 to 272.510 and has authorized all changes accordingly. Articles of incorporation shall be filed as herein required except that they shall be signed by the members of the then board of directors. The filing fee shall be the same as for filing an amendment to articles of incorporation.  </section><section prefix="2">Where any association may be incorporated under KRS 272.360 to 272.510, all contracts heretofore made by or on behalf of same by the promoters thereof in anticipation of such association becoming incorporated under the laws of this state, whether such contracts be made by or in the name of some corporation organized elsewhere and when same would have been valid if entered into subsequent to the passage of KRS 272.360 to 272.510, are hereby validated as if made after the passage of those sections. </section></text><history>Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 88, sec. 14. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13581</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>