<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">A JUSTICE AND PUBLIC SAFETY CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>15A.340</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Agency for Substance Abuse Policy (KY-ASAP) -- Organization -- Purpose -- Oversight by Office of Drug Control Policy -- Members of KY-ASAP Board -- Duties of board.   </catch_line><order_by>340</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section and KRS 15A.342 and 15A.344, "KY-ASAP" means the Kentucky Agency for Substance Abuse Policy. </section><section prefix="2">The Office of Drug Control Policy shall administer an endowment from interest generated through funds appropriated or gifts, donations, or funds received from any source. The Office of Drug Control Policy may expend endowment principal, if necessary in its discretion, to carry out the purposes of this section and KRS 15A.342 and 15A.344. These expenditures from the endowment principal are hereby appropriated for this purpose. </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">The Office of Drug Control Policy shall oversee the activities specified in this section and KRS 15A.342 and 15A.344 and provide administrative support to the seventeen (17) member KY-ASAP Board, which is created to oversee the activities of KY-ASAP. Membership of the board shall be appointed by the Governor and shall consist of the following: <section prefix="1">One (1) member representing the Kentucky Family Resource Youth Services Coalition, or a designee; </section><section prefix="2">One (1) member representing the Kentucky Health Department Association, or a designee; </section><section prefix="3">The secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, or designee; </section><section prefix="4">The secretary of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, or a designee; </section><section prefix="5">One (1) member representing the Division of Behavioral Health within the Department for Behavioral Health, Developmental and Intellectual Disabilities, Cabinet for Health and Family Services, or a designee; </section><section prefix="6">The commissioner of the Department for Public Health, Cabinet for Health and Family Services, or a designee; </section><section prefix="7">The commissioner of the Department of Alcoholic Beverage Control, or a designee; </section><section prefix="8">The commissioner of the Department of Education; </section><section prefix="9">The director of the Administrative Office of the Courts, or a designee; </section><section prefix="10">One (1) member representing the Kentucky Association of Regional Programs, or a designee; </section><section prefix="11">One (1) member representing the Kentucky Heart Association, or a designee; </section><section prefix="12">One (1) member representing the Kentucky Lung Association, or a designee; </section><section prefix="13">One (1) member representing the Kentucky Cancer Society, or a designee; </section><section prefix="14">Two (2) members representing local tobacco addiction and substance abuse advisory and coordination boards; and </section><section prefix="15">Two (2) members representing private community-based organizations, whether for-profit or nonprofit, with experience in programs involving smoking cessation or prevention or alcohol or substance abuse prevention and treatment. </section></section><section prefix="b">Members shall serve for a term of four (4) years, may be reappointed, and may serve no more than two (2) consecutive terms. Members shall not be compensated but shall receive reimbursement for expenses incurred while performing board business. </section><section prefix="c">The board shall meet at least quarterly. A quorum of nine (9) members shall be required for the transaction of business. Meetings shall be held at the call of the chair, or upon the written request of two (2) members to the chair. </section><section prefix="d">The board shall: <section prefix="1">Oversee deposits and expenditures from the endowment; </section><section prefix="2">Request, in its discretion, an audit relating to the expenditure of endowment funds; </section><section prefix="3">Receive quarterly reports from the commissioner of the Department of Alcoholic Beverage Control regarding KY-ASAP's activities; </section><section prefix="4">Progress toward development and implementation of the strategic plan; </section><section prefix="5">Recommend to KY-ASAP the most efficient means for using public funds to coordinate, supplement, and support high quality and ongoing programs of all public agencies and private service providers related to smoking cessation and prevention and alcohol and substance abuse prevention and treatment; </section><section prefix="6">Recommend matters for review and analysis by KY-ASAP; and </section><section prefix="7">Perform other duties as necessary for the oversight of KY-ASAP. </section></section></section><section prefix="4">The Office of Drug Control Policy and KY-ASAP shall promote the implementation of research-based strategies that target Kentucky's youth and adult populations. </section><section prefix="5">The Office of Drug Control Policy and KY-ASAP shall vigorously pursue the philosophy that tobacco in the hands of Kentucky's youth is a drug abuse problem because of the addictive qualities of nicotine, and because tobacco is the most prevalent gateway drug that leads to later and escalated drug and alcohol abuse. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2012; and ch. 158, sec. 5, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 20, effective July 15, 2010. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 10, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 10, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 536, sec. 25, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note>(7/12/2012). This statute was amended by 2012 Ky. Acts chs. 146 and 158, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><former-codification> KRS 12.330. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40741</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>