<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="234" order_by="234">LIQUEFIED PETROLEUM GAS AND OTHER FLAMMABLE LIQUIDS </unit></structure><section_number>234.330</section_number><catch_line>Dealer's license requirement. </catch_line><order_by>330</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A license shall be required of each liquefied petroleum gas motor fuel dealer. </section><section prefix="2">Application for a license shall be made to the department upon forms prepared and furnished by the department. The application shall contain such information as the department deems necessary. </section><section prefix="3">Concurrently with the filing of an application for a license, a liquefied petroleum gas motor fuel dealer shall file with the department a bond as required under KRS 234.340. No license shall be issued to any person unless such person has furnished a bond as provided in KRS 234.340 to secure payment of taxes, penalties and interest imposed by KRS 234.310 to 234.440. </section><section prefix="4">The application in proper form having been accepted for filing, the bond, if required, having been accepted and approved and the other conditions and requirements of this section having been complied with, the department shall issue a license. However, if an application for a license is filed by any person whose license has at any time previously been revoked for cause by the department, or if the department is of the opinion that the person who makes the application as a subterfuge for the real party in interest whose license, prior to the time of filing the application, has been revoked for cause, or that the application is not for any other reason filed in good faith or is not for sufficient cause, the department may, after a hearing of which the applicant shall be given ten (10) days' notice in writing and in which he shall have the right to appear in person or by counsel and present testimony, refuse to issue a license to that person. </section><section prefix="5">All licenses shall be valid and remain in full force and effect until suspended or revoked for cause or otherwise canceled. </section><section prefix="6">A license shall not be assignable or transferable and shall be valid only for the person in whose name it is issued. </section><section prefix="7">The department shall keep and file all applications and bonds, with an alphabetical index thereof. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 636, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 6, effective July 13, 1984. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 176, sec. 4, effective July 1, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11028</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>