<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="241" order_by="241">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- ADMINISTRATION AND CONTROL </unit></structure><section_number>241.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS Chapters 241, 242, and 243. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in this chapter and in KRS Chapters 242 and 243, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Alcohol" means ethyl alcohol, hydrated oxide of ethyl or spirit of wine, from whatever source or by whatever process it is produced; </section><section prefix="2">"Alcoholic beverage" means every liquid or solid, whether patented or not, containing alcohol in an amount in excess of more than one percent (1%) of alcohol by volume, which is fit for beverage purposes. It includes every spurious or imitation liquor sold as, or under any name commonly used for, alcoholic beverages, whether containing any alcohol or not. It does not include the following products: <section prefix="a">Medicinal preparations manufactured in accordance with formulas prescribed by the United States Pharmacopoeia, National Formulary, or the American Institute of Homeopathy; </section><section prefix="b">Patented, patent, and proprietary medicines; </section><section prefix="c">Toilet, medicinal, and antiseptic preparations and solutions; </section><section prefix="d">Flavoring extracts and syrups; </section><section prefix="e">Denatured alcohol or denatured rum; </section><section prefix="f">Vinegar and preserved sweet cider; </section><section prefix="g">Wine for sacramental purposes; and </section><section prefix="h">Alcohol unfit for beverage purposes that is to be sold for legitimate external use; </section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">"Alcohol vaporizing device" or "AWOL device" means any device, machine, or process that mixes liquor, spirits, or any other alcohol product with pure oxygen or by any other means produces a vaporized alcoholic product used for human consumption; </section><section prefix="b">"Alcohol vaporizing device" or "AWOL device" does not include an inhaler, nebulizer, atomizer, or other device that is designed and intended by the manufacturer to dispense a prescribed or over-the-counter medication or a device installed and used by a licensee under this chapter to demonstrate the aroma of an alcoholic beverage; </section></section><section prefix="4">"Automobile race track" means a facility primarily used for vehicle racing that has a seating capacity of at least thirty thousand (30,000) people; </section><section prefix="5">"Board" means the State Alcoholic Beverage Control Board created by KRS 241.030; </section><section prefix="6">"Bottle" means any container which is used for holding alcoholic beverages for the use and sale of alcoholic beverages at retail; </section><section prefix="7">"Brewer" means any person who manufactures malt beverages or owns, occupies, carries on, works, or conducts any brewery, either alone or through an agent; </section><section prefix="8">"Brewery" means any place or premises where malt beverages are manufactured for sale, and includes all offices, granaries, mash rooms, cooling rooms, vaults, yards, and storerooms connected with the premises; or where any part of the process of the manufacture of malt beverages is carried on; or where any apparatus connected with manufacture is kept or used; or where any of the products of brewing or fermentation are stored or kept; </section><section prefix="9">"Building containing licensed premises" means the licensed premises themselves and includes the land, tract of land, or parking lot in which the premises are contained, and any part of any building connected by direct access or by an entrance which is under the ownership or control of the licensee by lease holdings or ownership; </section><section prefix="10">"Caterer" means a corporation, partnership, or individual that operates the business of a food service professional by preparing food in a licensed and inspected commissary, transporting the food and alcoholic beverages to the caterer's designated and inspected banquet hall or to a location selected by the customer, and serving the food and alcoholic beverages to the customer's guests; </section><section prefix="11">"Charitable organization" means a nonprofit entity recognized as exempt from federal taxation under section 501(c) of the Internal Revenue Code (26 U.S.C. sec. 501(c)) or any organization having been established and continuously operating within the Commonwealth of Kentucky for charitable purposes for three (3) years and which expends at least sixty percent (60%) of its gross revenue exclusively for religious, educational, literary, civic, fraternal, or patriotic purposes; </section><section prefix="12">"Cider" means any fermented fruit-based beverage containing seven percent (7%) or more alcohol by volume and includes hard cider and perry cider; </section><section prefix="13">"City administrator" means city alcoholic beverage control administrator; </section><section prefix="14">"Commercial airport" means an airport through which more than five hundred thousand (500,000) passengers arrive or depart annually; </section><section prefix="15">"Commissioner" means the commissioner of the Department of Alcoholic Beverage Control; </section><section prefix="16">"Convention center" means any facility which, in its usual and customary business, provides seating for a minimum of one thousand (1,000) people and offers convention facilities and related services for seminars, training and educational purposes, trade association meetings, conventions, or civic and community events or for plays, theatrical productions, or cultural exhibitions; </section><section prefix="17">"Convicted" and "conviction" means a finding of guilt resulting from a plea of guilty, the decision of a court, or the finding of a jury, irrespective of a pronouncement of judgment or the suspension of the judgment; </section><section prefix="18">"County administrator" means county alcoholic beverage control administrator; </section><section prefix="19">"Department" means the Department of Alcoholic Beverage Control; </section><section prefix="20">"Dining car" means a railroad passenger car that serves meals to consumers on any railroad or Pullman car company; </section><section prefix="21">"Distilled spirits" or "spirits" means any product capable of being consumed by a human being which contains alcohol in excess of the amount permitted by KRS Chapter 242 obtained by distilling, mixed with water or other substances in solution, except wine, hard cider, and malt beverages; </section><section prefix="22">"Distiller" means any person who is engaged in the business of manufacturing distilled spirits at any distillery in the state and is registered in the Office of the Collector of Internal Revenue for the United States at Louisville, Kentucky; </section><section prefix="23">"Distillery" means any place or premises where distilled spirits are manufactured for sale, and which are registered in the office of any collector of internal revenue for the United States. It includes any United States government bonded warehouse; </section><section prefix="24">"Distributor" means any person who distributes malt beverages for the purpose of being sold at retail; </section><section prefix="25">"Dry" means a territory in which a majority of the electorate voted to prohibit all forms of retail alcohol sales through a local option election held under KRS Chapter 242; </section><section prefix="26">"Election" means: <section prefix="a">An election held for the purpose of taking the sense of the people as to the application or discontinuance of alcoholic beverage sales under KRS Chapter 242; or </section><section prefix="b">Any other election not pertaining to alcohol; </section></section><section prefix="27">"Field representative" means any employee or agent of the department who is regularly employed and whose primary function is to travel from place to place for the purpose of visiting taxpayers, and any employee or agent of the department who is assigned, temporarily or permanently, by the commissioner to duty outside the main office of the department at Frankfort, in connection with the administration of alcoholic beverage statutes; </section><section prefix="28">"Horse racetrack" means a facility licensed to conduct a horse race meeting under KRS Chapter 230; </section><section prefix="29">"Hotel" means a hotel, motel, or inn for accommodation of the traveling public, designed primarily to serve transient patrons; </section><section prefix="30">"License" means any license issued pursuant to KRS Chapters 241 to 244; </section><section prefix="31">"Licensee" means any person to whom a license has been issued, pursuant to KRS Chapters 241 to 244; </section><section prefix="32">"Limited restaurant" means: <section prefix="a">A facility where the usual and customary business is the serving of meals to consumers, which has a bona fide kitchen facility, which receives at least seventy percent (70%) of its gross receipts from the sale of food, which maintains a minimum seating capacity of one hundred (100) persons for dining, and which is located in a wet or moist territory under KRS 242.1244(2); or </section><section prefix="b">A facility where the usual and customary business is the serving of meals to consumers, which has a bona fide kitchen facility, which receives at least seventy percent (70%) of its gross receipts from the sale of food, which maintains a minimum seating capacity of fifty (50) persons for dining, which has no open bar, which requires that alcoholic beverages be sold in conjunction with the sale of a meal, and which is located in a wet or moist territory under KRS 242.1244; </section></section><section prefix="33">"Malt beverage" means any fermented undistilled alcoholic beverage of any name or description, manufactured from malt wholly or in part, or from any substitute for malt, and includes weak cider; </section><section prefix="34">"Manufacture" means distill, rectify, brew, bottle, and operate a winery; </section><section prefix="35">"Manufacturer" means a winery, distiller, rectifier, or brewer, and any other person engaged in the production or bottling of alcoholic beverages; </section><section prefix="36">"Minor" means any person who is not twenty-one (21) years of age or older; </section><section prefix="37">"Moist" means a territory in which a majority of the electorate voted to permit limited alcohol sales by any one (1) or a combination of special limited local option elections authorized by KRS 242.022, 242.123, 242.1238, 242.124, 242.1242, 242.1244, or 242.1292; </section><section prefix="38">"Premises" means the land and building in and upon which any business regulated by alcoholic beverage statutes is operated or carried on. "Premises" shall not include as a single unit two (2) or more separate businesses of one (1) owner on the same lot or tract of land, in the same or in different buildings if physical and permanent separation of the premises is maintained, excluding employee access by keyed entry and emergency exits equipped with crash bars, and each has a separate public entrance accessible directly from the sidewalk or parking lot. Any licensee holding an alcoholic beverage license on July 15, 1998, shall not, by reason of this subsection, be ineligible to continue to hold his or her license or obtain a renewal, of the license; </section><section prefix="39">"Private club" means a nonprofit social, fraternal, military, or political organization, club, or entity maintaining or operating a club room, club rooms, or premises from which the general public is excluded; </section><section prefix="40">"Public nuisance" means a condition that endangers safety or health, is offensive to the senses, or obstructs the free use of property so as to interfere with the comfortable enjoyment of life or property by a community or neighborhood or by any considerable number of persons; </section><section prefix="41">"Qualified historic site" means a contributing property with dining facilities for at least fifty (50) persons at tables, booths, or bars where food may be served within a commercial district listed in the National Register of Historic Places, or a site that is listed as a National Historic Landmark or in the National Register of Historic Places with dining facilities for at least fifty (50) persons at tables, booths, or bars where food may be served. Notwithstanding the provisions of this subsection: <section prefix="a">A distillery which is listed as a National Historic Landmark and which conducts souvenir retail package sales under KRS 243.0305; and </section><section prefix="b">A not-for-profit or nonprofit facility listed on the National Register of Historic Places; </section></section> shall be deemed a "qualified historic site" under this section; <section prefix="42">"Rectifier" means any person who rectifies, purifies, or refines distilled spirits or wine by any process other than as provided for on distillery premises, and every person who, without rectifying, purifying, or refining distilled spirits by mixing alcoholic beverages with any materials, manufactures any imitations of or compounds liquors for sale under the name of whiskey, brandy, gin, rum, wine, spirits, cordials, bitters, or any other name; </section><section prefix="43">"Repackaging" means the placing of alcoholic beverages in any retail container irrespective of the material from which the container is made; </section><section prefix="44">"Restaurant" means a facility where the usual and customary business is the serving of meals to consumers, that has a bona fide kitchen facility, and that receives at least fifty percent (50%) of its food and beverage receipts from the sale of food; </section><section prefix="45">"Retail container" means any bottle, can, barrel, or other container which, without a separable intermediate container, holds alcoholic beverages and is suitable and destined for sale to a retail outlet, whether it is suitable for delivery to the consumer or not; </section><section prefix="46">"Retail outlet" means retailer, hotel, motel, restaurant, railroad dining car, club, and any facility where alcoholic beverages are sold directly to the consumers; </section><section prefix="47">"Retail sale" means any sale where delivery is made in Kentucky to any consumers; </section><section prefix="48">"Retailer" means any person who sells at retail any alcoholic beverage for the sale of which a license is required; </section><section prefix="49">"Riverboat" means any boat or vessel with a regular place of mooring in this state that is licensed by the United States Coast Guard to carry one hundred (100) or more passengers for hire on navigable waters in or adjacent to this state; </section><section prefix="50">"Sale" means any transfer, exchange, or barter for consideration, and includes all sales made by any person, whether principal, proprietor, agent, servant, or employee, of any alcoholic beverage; </section><section prefix="51">"Service bar" means a bar, counter, shelving, or similar structure used for storing or stocking supplies of alcoholic beverages that is a workstation where employees prepare alcoholic beverage drinks to be delivered to customers away from the service bar. A service bar shall be located in an area where the general public, guests, or patrons are prohibited; </section><section prefix="52">"Sell" includes solicit or receive an order for, keep or expose for sale, keep with intent to sell, and the delivery of any alcoholic beverage; </section><section prefix="53">"Small farm winery" means a winery producing wines, in an amount not to exceed fifty thousand (50,000) gallons in a calendar year; </section><section prefix="54">"Souvenir package" means a special package of Kentucky straight bourbon whiskey available for retail sale at a licensed Kentucky distillery where the whiskey was produced or bottled that is available from a licensed retailer; </section><section prefix="55">"State director" means the director of the Division of Distilled Spirits or the director of the Division of Malt Beverages, or both, as the context requires; </section><section prefix="56">"State park" means a state park that has a: <section prefix="a">Nine (9) or eighteen (18) hole golf course; or </section><section prefix="b">Full-service lodge and dining room, and may include a nine (9) or eighteen (18) hole golf course; </section></section><section prefix="57">"Supplemental bar" means a bar, counter, shelving, or similar structure used for serving and selling distilled spirits or wine by the drink for consumption on the licensed premises to guests and patrons from additional locations other than the main bar. A supplemental bar shall be continuously constructed and accessible to patrons for distilled spirits or wine sales or service without physical separation by walls, doors, or similar structures; </section><section prefix="58">"Territory" means a county, city, district, or precinct; </section><section prefix="59">"Vehicle" means any device or animal used to carry, convey, transport, or otherwise move alcoholic beverages or any products, equipment, or appurtenances used to manufacture, bottle, or sell these beverages; </section><section prefix="60">"Warehouse" means any place in which alcoholic beverages are housed or stored; </section>(61) "Weak cider" means any fermented fruit-based beverage containing more than one percent (1%) but less than seven percent (7%) alcohol by volume; (62) "Wet" means a territory in which a majority of the electorate voted to permit all forms of retail alcohol sales by a local option election under KRS 242.050, 242.125, or 242.1292 on the following question: "Are you in favor of the sale of alcoholic beverages in (name of territory)?"; (63) "Wholesale sale" means a sale to any person for the purpose of resale; (64) "Wholesaler" means any person who distributes alcoholic beverages for the purpose of being sold at retail, but it shall not include a subsidiary of a manufacturer or cooperative of a retail outlet; (65) "Wine" means the product of the normal alcoholic fermentation of the juices of fruits, with the usual processes of manufacture and normal additions, and includes champagne and sparkling and fortified wine of an alcoholic content not to exceed twenty-four percent (24%) by volume. It includes sake, cider, hard cider, and perry cider and also includes preparations or mixtures vended in retail containers if these preparations or mixtures contain not more than fifteen percent (15%) of alcohol by volume. It does not include weak cider; and (66) "Winery" means any place or premises in which wine is manufactured from any fruit, or brandies are distilled as a by-product of wine or other fruit, or cordials are compounded, except a place or premises that manufactures wine for sacramental purposes exclusively. </text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014; and ch. 22, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 125, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 549, effective July 15, 2010.-- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 28, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 179, sec. 6, effective January 1, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 645, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 2, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 435, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 474, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 44, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 381, sec. 6. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 94, sec. 1. -- Amended 1944 Ky. Acts ch. 154, secs. 1, 2 and 3. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2554b-98. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><lrc-note>(7/15/2014). This statute was amended by 2014 Ky. Acts chs. 20 and 22, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together.</lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43024</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>