<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="79" order_by="79">INTERCITY, INTERCOUNTY AND CITY-COUNTY COMPACTS FOR PURCHASING AND MERIT SYSTEMS -- RETIREMENT AND DISABILITY PLANS FOR EMPLOYEES OF COUNTIES AND CITIES </unit></structure><section_number>79.310</section_number><catch_line>Cooperative compact between a city of the first class and county containing that city -- Term -- Amendment -- Termination -- Renewal. </catch_line><order_by>310</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Within one hundred and twenty (120) days of July 15, 1986, there shall be entered into by each city of the first class and a county containing such city of the first class a cooperative compact pursuant to this section and KRS 79.315 to 79.330. Such compact shall provide a framework for cooperation between the city and the county and shall contain such provisions as are required by this section and KRS 79.315 to 79.330 and may contain any other provisions which are not in conflict with this section and KRS 79.315 to 79.330 as may be agreed upon by the city and the county. The compact shall be executed by the mayor of the city of the first class with the consent of the legislative body of the city and the county judge/executive of the county with the consent of the fiscal court. </section><section prefix="2">The compact entered into pursuant to subsection (1) of this section shall be for a period of twelve (12) years, except that if any mandatory provision of the compact or 1986 Acts Chapter 77 is adjudicated invalid or if any provision of this section or KRS 79.315 to 79.330 is amended or repealed by subsequent act of the General Assembly, the compact shall immediately terminate. </section><section prefix="3">Upon the expiration or termination of the cooperative compact entered into according to subsection (1) of this section, a city of the first class and a county containing a city of the first class may renew the cooperative compact according to this section and KRS 79.315 to 79.330. Any cooperative compact renewed in accordance with this subsection shall be for a term of ten (10) years, and shall provide a framework for cooperation between the city and the county, shall contain the provisions as required by this section and KRS 79.315 to 79.330, and may contain any other provisions which are not in conflict with this section and KRS 79.315 to 79.330 as may be agreed to by the city and the county. To become effective, the compact shall be executed by the mayor of the city of the first class with approval by the legislative body of the city and the county judge/executive of the county containing a city of the first class, with the approval by the fiscal court. </section><section prefix="4">Any compact entered into pursuant to this section and KRS 79.315 to 79.330 may be amended by the city and the county, provided that no such amendment shall conflict with the provisions of this section and KRS 79.315 to 79.330. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 1, effective June 1, 1998. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> June 1, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:12</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24803</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>