<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="92" order_by="92">FINANCE AND REVENUE OF CITIES OTHER THAN THE FIRST CLASS </unit></structure><section_number>92.300</section_number><catch_line>Exemptions from city taxation in urban-county government and city of home rule class -- Regulation of ministers.   </catch_line><order_by>300</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The legislative body of an urban-county government and any city of the home rule class may by ordinance exempt manufacturing establishments from city taxation for a period not exceeding five (5) years as an inducement to their location in the urban-county government, or city. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">No city of the home rule class or urban-county government may impose or collect any license tax upon: <section prefix="1">Any bank, trust company, combined bank and trust company, or trust, banking and title insurance company organized and doing business in this state; </section><section prefix="2">Any savings and loan association whether state or federally chartered; or </section><section prefix="3">The provision of multichannel video programming services or communications services as defined in KRS 136.602. It is the intent of the General Assembly to continue the exemption from local license fees and occupational taxes that existed on January 1, 2006, for providers of multichannel video programming services or communications services as defined in KRS 136.602 that were taxed under KRS 136.120 prior to January 1, 2006. If only a portion of an entity's business is providing multichannel video programming services or communications services including products or services that are related to and provided in support of the multichannel video programming services or communications services, this exclusion applies only to that portion of the business that provides multichannel video programming services or communications services including products or services that are related to and provided in support of the multichannel video programming services or communications services. </section></section><section prefix="b">No city of the home rule class or urban-county government may impose or collect any license tax upon income received: <section prefix="1">By members of the Kentucky National Guard for active duty training, unit training assemblies and annual field training; or </section><section prefix="2">By precinct workers for election training or work at election booths in state, county, and local primary, regular, or special elections. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">Pursuant to KRS 92.281, no city shall regulate any aspect of the manner in which any duly ordained, commissioned, or denominationally licensed minister of religion may perform his or her duties and activities as a minister of religion. Duly ordained, commissioned, or denominationally licensed ministers of religion shall be subject to the same license fees imposed on others in the city enacted pursuant to KRS 92.281. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 98, effective January 1, 2015. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 167, sec. 4, effective July 1, 2005; and ch. 168, sec. 124, effective January 1, 2006. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 509, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 301, sec. 5. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 3. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2741s, 2741w-1, 3074, 3278, 3490-16, 3490-32. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:12</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43683</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>