<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.751</section_number><catch_line>Distinguished Student Recognition and Scholarship Award Program -- Selection committee -- Award selection criteria. </catch_line><order_by>751</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Higher Education Assistance Authority may expend such funds as appropriated and exercise the powers otherwise granted to administer the Kentucky Distinguished Student Recognition and Scholarship Award Program to reward academic excellence among the state's talented students by providing financial assistance to encourage attendance at the state's public universities, nonprofit degree granting colleges, and community colleges. Awards and scholarships shall be offered to students who demonstrate the highest potential for successful college study. Recognition awards shall be awarded only once to an individual and shall come solely from the authority. Scholarships shall be an equal match of funds between the authority and the university and may be offered annually to eligible students. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">The Governor shall appoint a nine (9) member selection committee whose members are representative of the geographic regions of the state and have varied university affiliations. Members shall be appointed for a term of four (4) years though the initial appointments may be less than four (4) years to establish staggered terms. The selection committee shall elect a chairman at its first meeting and annually thereafter. The executive director of the authority, or his designee, shall serve as secretary to the committee. The committee shall meet at least semiannually and more often as necessary. Members shall serve without salary but shall be reimbursed for actual and necessary expenses in the same manner as state employees. Members may be reappointed to the committee; </section><section prefix="b">The authority shall promulgate regulations for the administration of the recognition award and scholarship programs. The regulations shall include but not be limited to the following: <section prefix="1">Eligibility requirements which shall include requirements that students must be Kentucky citizens who have declared an intention to attend a participating institution; </section><section prefix="2">Award selection criteria including but not limited to the student's rank in his class, grade-point average, leadership and service potential, and the submission of a written essay; </section><section prefix="3">Award amounts; </section><section prefix="4">Selection committee, qualifications and duties; </section><section prefix="5">Fund distribution formula; </section><section prefix="6">Application deadlines; and </section><section prefix="7">Administrative procedures. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">The applicant pool for the recognition and scholarship awards shall be made up of the following Kentucky students: <section prefix="a">High school students who take one (1) of the tests required for admission to the state's public institutions of higher education in the spring or summer as a junior or in the fall as a senior shall automatically become part of the applicant pool for awards. Students scoring in the ninety-eighth or ninety-ninth percentile on these tests shall receive invitations to submit applications for a recognition award and a scholarship award; </section><section prefix="b">High school students nominated by the principal of an accredited high school which is not represented by a student described in paragraph (a) of this subsection. The nominees shall receive an invitation to apply for the awards; and </section><section prefix="c">High school graduates who have scores in the ninety-eighth or ninety-ninth percentile on prior years' tests and who have not attended college may apply for the awards. </section></section><section prefix="4">The authority shall present recognition awards to the highest ranking students in accordance with the award selection criteria. The amount and number of awards shall be determined by the authority and shall depend on the amount of funds available. No more than twenty percent (20%) of the awards shall be awarded to students who choose to attend an independent institution. </section><section prefix="5">The scholarships shall be an equal match between authority funds and institutional funds which may include any form of gift aid except state grant funds. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 37, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 473, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4420</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>