<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.12-240</section_number><catch_line>Regulatory Expediting Center. </catch_line><order_by>12-240</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Regulatory Expediting Center is established within the cabinet to assist industries and businesses proposing to locate or expand existing operations in Kentucky with applications for permits, licenses, certificates, registration, and any other form of authorization or permit required by a state, federal, or local agency to engage in a particular business activity or act. </section><section prefix="2">The center shall train and deploy persons with knowledge and skills essential to expediting a request for assistance by a prospective or expanding business or industry with applications for permits, licenses, certificates, registration, and any other form of authorization required by a state, federal, or local governmental agency to engage in a particular business activity or act. </section><section prefix="3">Assistance given by the center regarding federal and local regulations and requirements necessary to engage in the proposed business activity or act shall be limited to providing the business or industrial entity with copies of application forms and other written information provided by the appropriate federal and local agencies. </section><section prefix="4">Priority shall be given to business or industrial development or expansion proposals by businesses or industrial entities participating in an approved business network. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2014. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 390, sec. 12, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43343</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>