<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.1-300</section_number><catch_line>Pollution control facility -- Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>1-300</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For purposes of KRS 224.1-300 and 224.1-310 only, "pollution control facility" shall mean and include: <section prefix="a">Any property designed, constructed, or installed as a component part of any commercial or industrial premises for the primary purpose of eliminating or reducing the emission of, or ground level concentration of, particulate matter, dust, fumes, gas, mist, smoke, vapor, or odorous substances, or any combination thereof which renders air harmful or inimical to the health of persons or to property within this Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="b">Any disposal system or any treatment works, pretreatment works, appliance, equipment, machinery, or installation constructed, used, or placed in operation primarily for the purpose of reducing, controlling, or eliminating thermal pollution or water pollution caused by industrial waste, or what would be industrial waste, if discharged into the waters of the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="c">Any disposal system or any appliance, equipment, machinery or installation constructed, used or placed in operation primarily for disposing of waste, converting waste into an item of real economic value or converting hazardous waste to nonhazardous waste; </section><section prefix="d">Any property designed, constructed, or installed as a component part of any commercial or industrial premises for the primary purpose of eliminating or reducing the emission of sound which is harmful or inimical to the health of persons or to property, or materially reduces the quality of the environment in this Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="e">Any property designed, constructed, or installed for the primary purpose of removing substances from raw materials, which substances, if permitted to become a component part of the finished product, would have a deleterious effect on the environment when the finished product was utilized. </section></section><section prefix="2">"Industrial waste" means any liquid, gaseous, or solid waste substance resulting from any process of industry, manufacture, trade, or business, or from the development, processing, or recovery of any natural resource, together with such sewage as is present, which pollutes the waters of the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="3">"Solid waste" means any garbage, refuse, sludge from a waste treatment plant, water supply treatment plant, or air pollution control facility and other discarded material, including solid, liquid, semi-solid, or contained gaseous material resulting from industrial, commercial, mining (excluding coal mining waste), and agricultural operations, and from community activities, but does not include solid or dissolved material in domestic sewage, or solid or dissolved materials in irrigation return flows or industrial discharges which are point sources subject to permits under Section 402 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act, as amended (86 Stat. 880), or source, special nuclear, or by-product material as defined by the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, as amended (68 Stat. 923). </section><section prefix="4">"Treatment works" means any plant, disposal field, lagoon, dam, pumping station, incinerator, or other works used for the purpose of treating, stabilizing, or holding sewage, industrial waste, or other wastes. </section><section prefix="5">"Water pollution" shall mean the placing of any noxious or deleterious substances in any waters of the Commonwealth which render such waters harmful or inimical to aquatic life, or to the use of such waters for domestic water supply, or industrial or agricultural purposes or for recreation. </section><section prefix="6">"Waters of the Commonwealth" means all streams, lakes, ponds, marshes, watercourses, waterways, wells, springs, irrigation systems, drainage systems, and all other bodies or accumulations of water, surface and underground, natural or artificial, which are situated wholly or partly within, or border upon, this Commonwealth, or are within its jurisdiction, except those private waters which do not combine or effect a junction with natural surface or underground waters. </section><section prefix="7">"Cabinet" shall mean the Kentucky Energy and Environment Cabinet. </section><section prefix="8">"Pollution control tax exemption certificate" shall mean that certificate issued by the cabinet pursuant to KRS 224.1-310. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 347, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 284, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 8, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 1(1) to (8), effective June 21, 1974. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 224.850. KRS 224.01-300. </former-codification><former-codification-former-code>224.01-300</former-codification-former-code><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41562</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>