<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XLII" order_by="42">MISCELLANEOUS PRACTICE PROVISIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="456" order_by="456">CIVIL ORDERS OF PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>456.060</section_number><catch_line>Ruling on petition for interpersonal protective order -- Duration oforder.  </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text>(1)Following a hearing ordered under KRS 456.040, if a court finds by apreponderance of the evidence that dating violence and abuse, sexual assault,or stalking has occurred and may again occur, the court may issue aninterpersonal protective order:(a)Restraining the adverse party from:1.Committing further acts of dating violence and abuse, stalking, orsexual assault;2.Any unauthorized contact or communication with the petitioner orother person specified by the court;3.Approaching the petitioner or other person specified by the courtwithin a distance specified in the order, not to exceed five hundred(500) feet;4.Going to or within a specified distance of a specifically describedresidence, school, or place of employment or area where such aplace is located; and5.Disposing of or damaging any of the property of the parties;(b)Directing or prohibiting any other actions that the court believes will be ofassistance in eliminating future acts of dating violence and abuse,stalking, or sexual assault, except that the court shall not order thepetitioner to take any affirmative action; and(c)Directing that either or both of the parties receive counseling servicesavailable in the community in dating violence and abuse cases.(2)In imposing a location restriction described in subsection (1)(a)4. of thissection, the court shall:(a)Afford the petitioner and respondent, if present, an opportunity to testifyon the issue of the locations and areas from which the respondent shouldor should not be excluded;(b)Only impose a location restriction where there is a specific, demonstrabledanger to the petitioner or other person protected by the order;(c)Specifically describe in the order the locations or areas prohibited to therespondent; and(d)Consider structuring a restriction so as to allow the respondent transitthrough an area if the respondent does not interrupt his or her travel toharass, harm, or attempt to harass or harm the petitioner.(3)An interpersonal protective order shall be effective for a period of time fixed bythe court, not to exceed three (3) years, and may be reissued upon expirationfor subsequent periods of up to three (3) years each. The fact that an order hasnot been violated since its issuance may be considered by a court in hearing arequest for a reissuance of the order.</text><history>Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 24, effective January 1, 2016.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:24</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44772</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>