<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6">THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY </unit></structure><section_number>6.910</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties -- Confidentiality of working papers and other information -- Closed meetings authorized. </catch_line><order_by>910</order_by><text>The committee shall have the power and duty to: <section prefix="1">Make studies of the operations of state agencies to ascertain that sums appropriated have been, or are being, expended for the purposes for which such appropriations were made and to evaluate the effectiveness of programs in accomplishing legislative intent; </section><section prefix="2">Study on a continuing basis the operations, practices, and duties of state agencies, as they relate to efficiency in the utilization of space, personnel, equipment, and facilities; </section><section prefix="3">Make such special studies and reports of the operations and functions of state agencies as it deems appropriate and as may be requested by the General Assembly; </section><section prefix="4">Make such reports on its findings and recommendations at such time and in such manner as the committee deems proper, submitting such reports to the agencies concerned, to the Governor and to the General Assembly.  Such reports shall relate to the following matters: <section prefix="a">Whether any state agency is carrying out only those activities or programs authorized by legal or administrative action; or </section><section prefix="b">Whether the programs and activities of a state agency, or a particular program or activity is being operated efficiently, effectively, or in accordance with legislative or administrative intent; or </section><section prefix="c">Whether there is a need for change in any authorized activity or program of a state agency; or </section><section prefix="d">Whether any reorganization of a state agency, or group of state agencies, is needed or justified to accomplish the results of programs or activities; or </section><section prefix="e">Any combination of the purposes specified in this or any other section of KRS 6.905 to 6.935. </section></section><section prefix="5">Information obtained or prepared by the committee or its staff shall be treated as confidential working papers subject to release according to the operating rules and procedures adopted by the committee. The committee may close certain planning meetings and project briefings to protect research and to allow the exchange of confidential materials.  Any information protected by confidentiality agreements or federal, state, or local laws shall not be subject to public release. </section><section prefix="6">Consider and act on requests for studies submitted by legislators, legislative committees, elected officials of state government, state cabinet secretaries, and department and agency heads. Requests shall be submitted in writing and shall state reasons to support the request.  The decision of the committee to grant or deny such a request shall be final; </section><section prefix="7">Conduct studies directed by joint resolution of the General Assembly; </section><section prefix="8">When the General Assembly is not in session, conduct studies: <section prefix="a">Initiated by a majority vote of the committee; or </section><section prefix="b">Requested by the Legislative Research Commission or an interim joint committee thereof. In the event two (2) or more studies are requested, the priority among them shall be determined by the committee. </section></section><section prefix="9">Before voting to undertake a review under subsection (8)(a) of this section, the committee shall notify the chairman of the committee of relevant jurisdiction for his comment. </section><section prefix="10">The committee shall notify the Legislative Research Commission periodically of the committee's activities, and at any time a new study is to commence. Any study conducted by the committee shall be deemed within its lawful duties and jurisdiction unless notified to the contrary by the Legislative Research Commission. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 3, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 328, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 254, sec. 2, effective March 30, 1978. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=413</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>