<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">A JUSTICE AND PUBLIC SAFETY CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>15A.020</section_number><catch_line>Organization of Justice and Public Safety Cabinet.     </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Justice and Public Safety Cabinet shall have the following departments: <section prefix="a">Department of Corrections; </section><section prefix="b">Department of Criminal Justice Training, which shall have the following divisions: <section prefix="1">Training Operations Division; </section><section prefix="2">Administrative Division; and </section><section prefix="3">Training Support Division; </section></section><section prefix="c">Department of Juvenile Justice, which shall have the following divisions: <section prefix="1">Division of Medical Services; </section><section prefix="2">Division of Western Region; </section><section prefix="3">Division of Central Region; </section><section prefix="4">Division of Eastern Region; </section><section prefix="5">Division of Southeastern Region; </section><section prefix="6">Division of Administrative Services; </section><section prefix="7">Division of Program Services; </section><section prefix="8">Division of Placement Services; </section><section prefix="9">Division of Professional Development; and </section><section prefix="10">Division of Community and Mental Health Services; </section></section><section prefix="d">Department of Kentucky State Police, which shall have the following divisions: <section prefix="1">Administrative Division; </section><section prefix="2">Operations Division; </section><section prefix="3">Technical Services Division; and </section><section prefix="4">Commercial Vehicle Enforcement Division; and </section></section><section prefix="e">Department for Public Advocacy, which shall have the following divisions: <section prefix="1">Protection and Advocacy Division; </section><section prefix="2">Division of Law Operations; </section><section prefix="3">Division of Trial Services; </section><section prefix="4">Division of Post-Trial Services; and </section><section prefix="5">Division of Conflict Services. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">Each department, except for the Department for Public Advocacy, shall be headed by a commissioner who shall be appointed by the secretary of justice and public safety with the approval of the Governor as required by KRS 12.040. Each commissioner shall be directly responsible to the secretary and shall have such functions, powers, and duties as provided by law and as the secretary may prescribe. The Department for Public Advocacy shall be headed by the public advocate, appointed as required by KRS 31.020, who shall be directly responsible to the Public Advocacy Commission. The Department for Public Advocacy is an independent state agency which shall be attached to the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet for administrative purposes only. The Justice and Public Safety Cabinet shall not have control over the Department for Public Advocacy's information technology equipment and use unless granted access by court order. </section><section prefix="3">The Justice and Public Safety Cabinet shall have the following offices: <section prefix="a">Office of the Secretary, which shall be headed by a deputy secretary appointed pursuant to KRS 12.050 and responsible for the direct administrative support for the secretary and other duties as assigned by the secretary, and which, with the approval of the secretary, may employ such staff as necessary to perform the duties, functions, and responsibilities of the office; </section><section prefix="b">Office of Management and Administrative Services, which shall be headed by an executive director appointed pursuant to KRS 12.050 who shall be responsible to and report to the secretary and be responsible for all matters relating to human resources, state and federal grants management, including but not limited to the administration of KRS 15A.060, fiscal functions, management and daily operations of the information processing activities for the cabinet, and management and daily administrative services for the cabinet; and who, with the approval of the secretary, may employ such staff as necessary to perform the duties, functions, and responsibilities of the office; </section><section prefix="c">Office of Legal Services, which shall be headed by an executive director appointed pursuant to KRS 12.050 and 12.210, that: <section prefix="1">Shall provide legal representation and services for the cabinet; and </section><section prefix="2">May investigate all complaints regarding the facilities, staff, treatment of juveniles, and other matters relating to the operation of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet. If it appears that there is a violation of statutes, administrative regulations, policies, court decisions, the rights of juveniles who are subject to the orders of the department, or any other matter relating to the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, the office shall report to the secretary of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet who shall, if required, refer the matter to a law enforcement agency, Commonwealth's attorney, county attorney, the Attorney General, or federal agencies, as appropriate. The office may be used to investigate matters in which there is a suspicion of violation of written policy, administrative regulation, or statutory law within the Department for Public Advocacy only when the investigation will have no prejudicial impact upon a person who has an existing attorney-client relationship with the Department for Public Advocacy. Notwithstanding the provisions of this subparagraph, investigation and discipline of KRS Chapter 16 personnel shall continue to be conducted by the Department of Kentucky State Police pursuant to KRS Chapter 16. The office shall conduct no other investigations under the authority granted in this subparagraph. The secretary may, by administrative order, assign the investigative functions in this subparagraph to a branch within the office. </section></section> The executive director shall be directly responsible to and report to the secretary and, with the approval of the secretary, may employ such attorneys appointed pursuant to KRS 12.210 and other staff as necessary to perform the duties, functions, and responsibilities of the office; <section prefix="d">Office of Legislative and Intergovernmental Services, which shall be headed by an executive director appointed pursuant to KRS 12.050 who shall be responsible for all matters relating to the provision of support to the Criminal Justice Council, legislative liaison services, and functions and duties vested in the Criminal Justice Council as described in KRS 15A.030. The executive director shall be directly responsible to and report to the secretary and may employ such staff as necessary to perform the duties, functions, and responsibilities of the office; </section><section prefix="e">Office of the Kentucky State Medical Examiner, which shall be headed by a chief medical examiner appointed pursuant to KRS 72.240 who shall be responsible for all matters relating to forensic pathology and forensic toxicology and other duties as assigned by the secretary. The executive director appointed pursuant to KRS 12.050 shall be responsible for all matters related to the administrative support of the Office of the State Medical Examiner. The executive director shall report directly to the secretary and with the approval of the secretary may employ such administrative support staff as necessary to perform the administrative duties, functions, and responsibilities of the office. The chief medical examiner shall be directly responsible to and report to the secretary and may employ such staff as necessary to perform the forensic duties, functions, and responsibilities of the office; and </section><section prefix="f">Office of Drug Control Policy, which shall be headed by an executive director appointed pursuant to KRS 12.050 who shall be responsible for all matters relating to the research, coordination, and execution of drug control policy and for the management of state and federal grants, including but not limited to the prevention and treatment related to substance abuse. By December 31 of each year, the Office of Drug Control Policy shall review, approve, and coordinate all current projects of any substance abuse program which is conducted by or receives funding through agencies of the executive branch. This oversight shall extend to all substance abuse programs which are principally related to the prevention or treatment, or otherwise targeted at the reduction, of substance abuse in the Commonwealth. The Office of Drug Control Policy shall promulgate administrative regulations consistent with enforcing this oversight authority. The executive director shall be directly responsible to and report to the secretary and may employ such staff as necessary to perform the duties, functions, and responsibilities of the office. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 72, sec. 10, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 15, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2009; and ch. 75, sec. 12, effective June 25, 2009 -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 40, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 64, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 227, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 64, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 343, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. V. sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><lrc-note> (6/26/2007).  Although 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 40, contains references to the "Department of Public Advocacy," the entity created by 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, secs. 7 and 40, and Executive Order 2006-805 is the "Department for Public Advocacy." In accordance with 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 335, and KRS 7.136, the erroneous references in this section have been corrected in codification.  (6/26/2007).  Although subsection (3)(d) of this section states that the Criminal Justice Council is "described in KRS 15A.030," the Criminal Justice Council is actually created and described in 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 37, codified as KRS 15A.075. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42292</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>