<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">G KENTUCKY OFFICE OF HOMELAND SECURITY </unit></structure><section_number>39G.010</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Office of Homeland Security executive director -- Duties -- Delegation of duties -- Notification of disaster or emergency.   </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Office of Homeland Security shall be attached to the Office of the Governor and shall be headed by an executive director appointed by the Governor. </section><section prefix="2">The executive director shall: <section prefix="a">Publicize the findings of the General Assembly stressing the dependence on Almighty God as being vital to the security of the Commonwealth by including the provisions of KRS 39A.285(3) in its agency training and educational materials. The executive director shall also be responsible for prominently displaying a permanent plaque at the entrance to the state's Emergency Operations Center stating the text of KRS 39A.285(3); </section><section prefix="b">Establish and chair an interagency working group composed of the chair of the Senate Veterans, Military Affairs, and Public Protection Committee, the chair of the House of Representatives Seniors, Military Affairs, and Public Safety Committee, state agency representation, and private agency representation. The working group shall have the purpose of identifying risks and needs and making a complete assessment of the preparedness of the Commonwealth to respond to acts of war or terrorism, including nuclear, biological, chemical, electromagnetic pulse, agro-, eco-, or cyber-terrorism; </section><section prefix="c">Serve as the State Appointed Administrator for the United States Department of Homeland Security; </section><section prefix="d">Implement all homeland security presidential and gubernatorial directives, including directives pertaining to state and local compliance with the National Incident Management System; </section><section prefix="e">Coordinate the efforts of the Kentucky Office of Homeland Security with the efforts of the federal Department of Homeland Security; </section><section prefix="f">Accept and allocate any homeland security funds in compliance with applicable federal and state laws and administrative regulations; and </section><section prefix="g">Inform the members of the General Assembly of the process by which a public agency applies for a federal homeland security grant and shall provide the following information to the members at least ninety (90) days before an application deadline: <section prefix="1">The application deadline; </section><section prefix="2">How a public agency can obtain an application form; </section><section prefix="3">How a public agency can obtain assistance in filling out an application form; and </section><section prefix="4">Any other information that would be helpful to a public agency interested in applying for a federal homeland security grant. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">The executive director may delegate responsibilities created under this section to another executive branch agency. </section><section prefix="4">The Kentucky Office of Homeland Security shall: <section prefix="a">Develop and publish a comprehensive statewide homeland security strategy that coordinates state and local efforts to detect, deter, mitigate, and respond to a terrorist incident; </section><section prefix="b">Develop a comprehensive strategy addressing how state and federal funds and other assistance will be allocated within the state to purchase specialized equipment required to prevent and respond effectively and safely to terrorist incidents; </section><section prefix="c">Urge the state and local governments to exceed minimum federal requirements for receiving assistance in preparing to respond to acts of war or terrorism in the hope that the Commonwealth will become a national leader in this preparation; </section><section prefix="d">Provide information explaining how individuals and private organizations, including volunteer and religious organizations, can best prepare for and respond to incidents contemplated by this section and to other threatened, impending, or declared emergencies and whom to contact should they desire to volunteer help or services during such an emergency. The program shall identify and encourage these private organizations to specifically commit to provide food, shelter, personnel, equipment, materials, consultation, and advice, or other services needed to respond to these incidents; </section><section prefix="e">Administer the Kentucky Intelligence Fusion Center and coordinate its operations with other federal, state, and local agencies; and </section><section prefix="f">Promulgate any administrative regulations necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter. </section></section><section prefix="5">The adjutant general, or his or her designee, shall concurrently notify the Governor and the executive director of the Office of Homeland Security of a disaster or emergency involving homeland security. The adjutant general, or his or her designee, shall be the Governor's primary point of contact for managing and responding to a disaster or emergency involving homeland security. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 2, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 193, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41876</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>