<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.165</section_number><catch_line>Exchange of one special license plate for another -- Transfer of special license plate to another vehicle.   </catch_line><order_by>165</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, "owner" means a person who has purchased or leased a motor vehicle that is registered under the provisions of KRS 186.050(1) or (3)(a). </section><section prefix="2">The provisions of this chapter relating to special license plates to the contrary notwithstanding, if a vehicle has been issued a special license plate and the owner of the vehicle wishes to surrender the plate and exchange it for a different special license plate, the owner may, at the time he or she renews the vehicle's annual registration, exchange the special plate without being required to obtain a regular registration plate. </section><section prefix="3">An owner requesting to exchange a special license plate shall be required to surrender the special license plate issued to the vehicle and the appropriate certificate of registration to the county clerk of the county where the person lives. Upon payment of the fee established in subsection (4) of this section, the county clerk shall immediately exchange the special license plate and issue a new special license plate and certificate of registration without placing further requirements upon the owner. </section><section prefix="4">The fee to exchange a special license plate under this section shall be the fee charged under this chapter for the particular special license plate which is being requested. </section><section prefix="5">If a motor vehicle that has been issued a special license plate is sold prior to the expiration of the registration, the owner may, pursuant to KRS 186.190, transfer the plate to another vehicle the owner has obtained. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 5, effective January 1, 2013. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2014 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2012).The amendment of this statute in 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 5 was to be effective January 1, 2013, pursuant to Section 7 of that Act. However, in 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 1, 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 5, sec. 7, was repealed, and a new effective date of January 1, 2014, was established for the 2011 amendment of this statute, pursuant to 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 2. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39946</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>