<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="362" order_by="362">PARTNERSHIPS </unit></structure><section_number>362.180</section_number><catch_line>Rules for determining the existence of a partnership. </catch_line><order_by>180</order_by><text>In determining whether a partnership exists, these rules shall apply: <section prefix="1">Except as provided by KRS 362.225 persons who are not partners as to each other are not partners as to third persons. </section><section prefix="2">Joint tenancy, tenancy in common, tenancy by the entireties, joint property, common property, or part ownership does not of itself establish a partnership, whether such co-owners do or do not share any profits made by the use of the property. </section><section prefix="3">The sharing of gross returns does not of itself establish a partnership, whether or not the persons sharing them have a joint or common right or interest in any property from which the returns are derived. </section><section prefix="4">The receipt by a person of a share of the profits of a business is prima facie evidence that he is a partner in the business, but no such inference shall be drawn if such profits were received in payment: <section prefix="a">As a debt by installments or otherwise, </section><section prefix="b">As wages of an employee or rent to a landlord, </section><section prefix="c">As an annuity to a widow, or widower or representative of a deceased partner, </section><section prefix="d">As interest on a loan, though the amount of payment vary with the profits of the business, </section><section prefix="e">As the consideration for the sale of a goodwill of a business or other property by installments or otherwise. </section></section></text><history>Repeal the prior repeal contained in 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 239, which was to have been effective January 1, 2008, 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 180, effective June 26, 2007. -- Repealed 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 239, effective January 1, 2008. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 386, sec. 66. -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 38, sec. 7, effective June 17, 1954. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34295</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>