<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">A STATEWIDE EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>39A.210</section_number><catch_line>Qualifications and oath of persons connected with disaster and emergency response organizations. </catch_line><order_by>210</order_by><text>No person shall be employed or associated in any capacity in any disaster and emergency response organization established under this chapter who advocates a change by force or violence in the constitutional form of the government of the United States or in this state or the overthrow of any government in the United States by force or violence, or who has been convicted of or is under indictment or information charging any subversive act against the United States. Each person who is appointed to serve in an organization for disaster and emergency response shall, before entering upon his or her duties, take an oath, in writing, before a person authorized to administer oaths in this Commonwealth, which shall be as follows:  "I do solemnly swear (or affirm) that I will support the Constitution of the United States and the Constitution of this Commonwealth and be faithful and true to the Commonwealth of Kentucky so long as I continue a citizen thereof, and that I will faithfully execute, to the best of my ability, the office of emergency management director according to law;  And I do further solemnly swear (or affirm) that since the adoption of the present Constitution, I, being a citizen of this state, have not fought a duel with deadly weapons within this state, nor out of it, nor have I sent or accepted a challenge to fight a duel with deadly weapons, nor have I acted as second in carrying a challenge, nor aided or assisted any person thus offended, so help me God." </text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 20, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21715</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>