<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="I" order_by="1">SOVEREIGNTY AND JURISDICTION OF THE COMMONWEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="3" order_by="3">GRANTS TO UNITED STATES OF LANDS AND RIGHTS TO ACQUIRE </unit></structure><section_number>3.080</section_number><catch_line>Consent to acquisition of national forest reserves -- Jurisdiction. </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Kentucky consents to the acquisition by the United States, by purchase or gift, or by condemnation, of such lands within the boundaries of Kentucky as in the opinion of the United States are needed for the establishment of national forest reserves within prescribed areas. Before such establishment the written approval and consent of the Governor of Kentucky, recorded in his office, shall be given as to the area of lands acquired by the United States. </section><section prefix="2">When forest reserves are established by the United States, either under existing federal statutes or any hereinafter enacted, then consent of Kentucky is given for Congress to pass such laws and to make or provide for the making of such rules and regulations, of both civil and criminal nature, and provide punishment therefor, as in its judgment may be necessary for the management, control and protection of the land as may be acquired by the United States under the provisions of this section. </section></text><history>Amended 1944 Ky. Acts ch. 173, sec. 2, effective June 13, 1944. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 3766e-30, 3766e-31. </history><metadata><effective>June 13, 1944</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=90</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>