<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="11" order_by="11">A EXECUTIVE BRANCH CODE OF ETHICS </unit></structure><section_number>11A.231</section_number><catch_line>Activities excepted from KRS 11A.211 and 11A.216. </catch_line><order_by>231</order_by><text><section prefix="1">KRS 11A.211 and 11A.216 do not apply to efforts to influence executive agency decisions or conduct executive agency lobbying activity by any of the following: <section prefix="a">Appearances at public hearings of the committees or interim committees of the General Assembly, at court proceedings, at rule-making or adjudication proceedings, or at other public meetings; </section><section prefix="b">News, editorial, and advertising statements published in newspapers, journals, or magazines, or broadcast over radio or television; </section><section prefix="c">The gathering and furnishing of information and news by bona fide reporters, correspondents, or news bureaus to news media described in subsection (1)(b) of this section; or </section><section prefix="d">Publications primarily designed for and distributed to members of associations or charitable or fraternal nonprofit corporations. </section></section><section prefix="2">Nothing in KRS 11A.201 to 11A.246 requires the reporting of, or prohibits an elected executive official from soliciting or accepting, a contribution from or an expenditure by any person if the contribution or expenditure is reported in accordance with KRS Chapter 121. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 15, effective March 16, 2005. -- Created 1993 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 51, effective September 16, 1993. </history><metadata><effective> March 16, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=612</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>