<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="318" order_by="318">PLUMBERS AND PLUMBING </unit></structure><section_number>318.030</section_number><catch_line>License and general liability insurance required. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall engage in plumbing or engage in or work at the trade of plumbing: <section prefix="a">Unless he or she is the holder of a valid and effective active master plumber's license duly issued by the department in accordance with the provisions of this chapter; or </section><section prefix="b">Unless he or she is the holder of a valid and effective journeyman plumber's license duly issued by the department in accordance with the provisions of this chapter. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">No person, firm, or corporation shall engage in plumbing or engage in or work at the trade of plumbing unless the person, firm, or corporation maintains general liability insurance in an amount not less than two hundred fifty thousand dollars ($250,000) and submits proof of compliance with workers' compensation and unemployment insurance laws of the Commonwealth. </section><section prefix="b">Proof of insurance required in this subsection shall be submitted to the department prior to issuance or renewal of the active master plumber license required under this chapter. </section><section prefix="c">No license shall be valid without insurance as required in this subsection, and insurance carriers shall notify the department upon cancellation of the insurance of any licensee required to maintain insurance. </section><section prefix="d">The insurance required in this subsection shall not apply to an employee of a person, firm, or corporation engaged in plumbing as defined in this chapter. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1672, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 3. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 3. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 222, sec. 4. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 3909b. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31186</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>