<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="148" order_by="148">PARKS AND TOURISM </unit></structure><section_number>148.570</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Center for African-American Heritage -- Purpose -- Members -- Meetings -- Powers and duties. </catch_line><order_by>570</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Center for African-American Heritage is hereby created to educate the public and to preserve and research the cultural heritage of African-Americans by establishing a center to showcase the contributions of Kentucky African-Americans to the Commonwealth, the nation, and the world. In addition to exhibit space, the center shall provide performance space for activities, such as but not limited to plays, poetry readings, and concerts. </section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Center for African-American Heritage shall be governed by a board of directors who represent various African-American heritage interests. The board shall also reflect significant membership from the African-American community. On June 8, 2011, the board of directors of the African-American Heritage Foundation, Inc., the secretary of the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet or his or her designee, and the chair of the Kentucky African-American Heritage Commission shall be the initial board of directors of the center, and shall serve four (4) year terms. Upon the expiration of the four (4) year term of the initial board of directors, the membership of the board of directors shall be as follows: <section prefix="a">The secretary of the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet or the secretary's designee; </section><section prefix="b">The chair of the Kentucky African-American Heritage Commission; </section><section prefix="c">One (1) member from an institution of higher learning; </section><section prefix="d">One (1) member who is an expert in African-American history; </section><section prefix="e">One (1) member from the arts community; </section><section prefix="f">Four (4) members with expertise in Kentucky, United States, or world history with an emphasis on the African-American experience. Of the four (4) members required by this paragraph, there shall be one (1) from central Kentucky, one (1) from northern Kentucky, one (1) from western Kentucky, and one (1) from eastern Kentucky; </section><section prefix="g">One (1) member at large with expertise in Kentucky, United States, or world history with an emphasis on the African-American experience; </section><section prefix="h">Five (5) members from the metro Louisville area. The mayor of Louisville shall submit five (5) separate lists of three (3) names for each of the appointments provided for in this paragraph. One (1) member shall be appointed from each list of names. At least one (1) of the members appointed from the mayor's lists shall have experience in Kentucky, United States, or world history with an emphasis on the African-American experience; and </section><section prefix="i">Ten (10) members from the public at large. </section></section><section prefix="3">Members listed in subsection (2)(c) to (i) of this section shall be appointed by the Governor. Twelve (12) of the Governor's initial appointees shall serve two (2) year terms. Eleven (11) of the Governor's initial appointees shall serve four (4) year terms. Subsequent appointments by the Governor shall be for four (4) year terms, and members may be reappointed for subsequent terms. Any vacancy shall be filled by appointment of the Governor for the remainder of the unexpired term. </section><section prefix="4">Board members shall serve without compensation but may be reimbursed for actual and necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their duties. </section><section prefix="5">The board shall elect by a majority vote a chair, a vice chair, and any other officers deemed necessary. </section><section prefix="6">The board shall meet at least three (3) times per year. Notice of the time and location of each meeting shall be provided in writing to each member at least ten (10) days in advance of the meeting. </section><section prefix="7">A majority of the members shall constitute a quorum. </section><section prefix="8">Committees may be formed at the direction of the chair. </section><section prefix="9">The Kentucky Center for African-American Heritage may seek and accept grants or raise funds from any available source, public or private, to accomplish its responsibilities and achieve its objectives. </section><section prefix="10">The Kentucky Center for African-American Heritage shall be attached for administrative purposes to the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet, whose responsibilities shall include but are not limited to designating a staff person to coordinate board needs and providing other staff and services requested by the board to achieve its objectives under KRS 148.572. </section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch.84, sec.1, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39839</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>