<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="367" order_by="367">CONSUMER PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>367.667</section_number><catch_line>Prohibited acts and practices in charitable solicitations. </catch_line><order_by>667</order_by><text>The following acts and practices in the conduct of charitable solicitation shall be considered unfair, false, misleading, or deceptive in violation of KRS 367.170: <section prefix="1">Representing or leading anyone in any manner to believe that a solicitation is for or on behalf of a charitable organization; or utilizing any emblem, device, or printed matter belonging to or associated with a charitable organization; or otherwise representing that any part of the contributions received will be donated to a charitable organization without first being authorized in writing to do so by the charitable organization; </section><section prefix="2">Utilizing a name, symbol, or statement so closely related or similar to that used by another charitable organization, public official, or public agency that its use would tend to confuse or mislead a solicited person; or </section><section prefix="3">Representing when soliciting funds that a charity will be the recipient of the funds when the professional solicitor or his employer pursuant to a contract is allowed to or will receive more than fifty percent (50%) of the gross receipts of the funds solicited as his compensation. It shall be a defense in any action brought to enforce this subsection for the professional solicitor to show that he disclosed in a clear and conspicuous manner to the prospective donor the percentage of the funds which he was allowed by contract to receive. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1994. – Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 457, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35035</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>