<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="244" order_by="244">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- PROHIBITIONS, RESTRICTIONS, AND REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>244.040</section_number><catch_line>Sales for cash only. </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A brewer or distributor shall not sell alcoholic beverages to any person in this state for any consideration except for cash paid at or before the time of delivery. <section prefix="a">The use of electronic transfers shall be voluntary and shall be agreed to by the </section><section prefix="b">The brewer shall not pay or credit back in any way to the distributor any share </section><section prefix="c">The distributor shall not pay or credit back in any way to the retailer any share </section><section prefix="d">The transfer of funds shall be initiated by the brewer or the distributor; </section><section prefix="e">The distributor may debit the retailer's bank account for the exact amount due </section><section prefix="f">Electronic fund transfers that are rejected or denied at the time of sale for any </section><section prefix="g">Each participating retail licensee and each distributor maintain accurate </section></section> For purposes of this section, "cash" includes the sale of malt beverages by electronic transfers if the following conditions are met: affected brewer, distributor, and retailer; of the cost that is attributable to the electronic transfer; of the cost that is attributable to the electronic fund transfer; based on the amount of alcoholic beverages delivered; reason shall be treated in the same manner as checks drawn on insufficient funds; and records of all electronic fund transfers in accordance with department statutes and administrative regulations. <section prefix="2">A brewer or distributor shall not furnish or deliver any returnable bottled malt beverage without collecting a minimum container charge or deposit of sixty cents ($0.60) per case of twenty-four (24) twelve-ounce bottles or its equivalent in the same manner that the price of the malt beverage is collected. </section><section prefix="3">This section shall not prohibit a licensee from crediting to a purchaser the actual prices charged for packages or containers returned by the original purchaser as a credit on any sale, or from refunding to any purchaser the amount paid by the purchaser for containers or as a deposit on containers when the title is retained by the vendor, if the containers or packages have been returned to the brewer or distributor. </section><section prefix="4">No right of action shall exist to collect any claim for credit extended contrary to this section. </section><section prefix="5">This section shall not apply to sales by wholesalers or distributors to licensees that are private clubs or voluntary associations. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 585, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 522, sec. 16, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 28, effective June 17, 1978. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2554b-156. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11432</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>