<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.271</section_number><catch_line>Preliminary educational requirements for practitioners of healing arts. </catch_line><order_by>271</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall be eligible for licensure to practice any healing art in this state unless and until he furnishes satisfactory evidence to the appropriate licensing agency, that prior to being licensed by the respective state agency that he was credited with not less than sixty (60) transferable units of study by a college or university accredited by the Southern Association of Colleges and Schools or an accrediting agency recognized by the Southern Association of Colleges and Schools or any successor to the powers of either; provided, however, that the transferability of credits from colleges and universities located outside the United States and Canada shall be determined by the appropriate licensing agency. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">The term "healing art," as used herein, includes the practices of medicine, osteopathy, dentistry, chiropody (podiatry), optometry, and chiropractic, but does not include the practices of Christian Science or midwifery. </section><section prefix="b">The term "transferable units of study" means semester hour (or equivalent) credits and may include advance placement credits. </section></section><section prefix="3">This section shall not apply to any student who is enrolled in any school of medicine, osteopathy, dentistry, chiropody (podiatry), optometry, or chiropractic on June 13, 1968, nor shall it affect the right of any person who is presently licensed to practice a healing art in this state, to have his license renewed upon compliance with all other requirements of law. </section></text><history>Created 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 53, secs. 1, 2 and 3, effective June 13, 1968. </history><metadata><effective>June 13, 1968</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30473</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>