<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.061</section_number><catch_line>Motor vehicles owned by nonprofit volunteer fire department, volunteer fire prevention unit, or volunteer fire protection unit. </catch_line><order_by>061</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Applications for registration of motor vehicles owned exclusively by any nonprofit volunteer fire department, volunteer fire prevention unit, or volunteer fire protection unit shall be accompanied by a statement from the chief or assistant chief of the volunteer fire department or unit that owns the motor vehicle, certifying that the motor vehicle is exclusively owned and operated by the volunteer fire department or unit. The application and statement shall be forwarded by the county clerk to the cabinet, which shall give special authority to the clerk to register it. Upon receiving that authority, the clerk shall issue a registration receipt and the official number plate described in KRS 186.240(1)(c), and report the registration to the head of the cabinet authorizing the registration. For his services in issuing such certificate of registration and number plate and reporting the same, the county clerk shall be entitled to a fee of three dollars ($3) in each instance, to be paid by the volunteer fire department or unit. </section><section prefix="2">After registration of any vehicle owned exclusively by any nonprofit volunteer fire department, volunteer fire prevention unit, or volunteer fire protection unit and after issuance of a number plate for the vehicle so owned, no subsequent registration or renewal of same, and no subsequent renewal of a number plate of the vehicle shall be necessary so long as the vehicle is owned exclusively by the volunteer fire department or unit except in the case of loss or destruction of the license plate. In the event of loss or destruction, the number plate shall be replaced in the same manner as if no plate had ever been issued. </section><section prefix="3">When a motor vehicle owned exclusively by any nonprofit volunteer fire department, volunteer fire prevention unit, or volunteer fire protection unit is transferred or sold to another nonprofit volunteer fire department, volunteer fire prevention unit, or volunteer fire protection unit or another governmental unit a new license plate shall be issued for the vehicle in the same manner as provided for in subsection (1) of this section and shall have the same effect as given to such license plates in subsection (2) of this section. </section><section prefix="4">No person shall use on a motor vehicle, not exclusively owned by any nonprofit volunteer fire department, volunteer fire prevention unit, or volunteer fire protection unit, any license plate that has been issued for use on a motor vehicle owned by a volunteer fire department or unit. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 428, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 296, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1990; and ch. 498, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 366, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=5945</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>