<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="213" order_by="213">VITAL STATISTICS </unit></structure><section_number>213.141</section_number><catch_line>Fee for certified copies of certificates or records or for a search of records.   </catch_line><order_by>141</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as provided in subsection (2) of this section, the cabinet shall prescribe by regulation a fee not to exceed five dollars ($5), to be paid for certified copies of certificates or records, or for a search of the files or records when no copy is made, or for copies or information provided for research, statistical, or administrative purposes. </section><section prefix="2">The cabinet shall prescribe by administrative regulation pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A a fee not to exceed ten dollars ($10) to be paid for a certified copy of a record of a birth: <section prefix="a">Three dollars ($3) of which shall be used by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services for the sole purpose of contracting for the operation of private, not-for-profit, self-help, education, and support groups for parents who want to prevent or cease physical, sexual, or mental abuse of children; and </section><section prefix="b">One dollar ($1) of which shall be used by the Division of Maternal and Child Health to pay for therapeutic food, formulas, supplements, or low-protein modified foods for all inborn errors of metabolism and genetic conditions if: <section prefix="1">The therapeutic food, formulas, supplements, or low-protein modified food products are medically indicated for the therapeutic treatment of inborn errors of metabolism or genetic conditions and are administered under the direction of a physician; and </section><section prefix="2">The affected person's therapeutic food, formulas, supplements or low-protein foods are not covered under any public or private health benefit plan. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">Fees collected under this section by the state registrar shall be used to help defray the cost of administering the system of vital statistics. </section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">No fee or compensation shall be allowed or paid for furnishing certificates of birth or death required in support of any claim against the government for compensation, insurance, back pay, or other allowances or benefits for any person who has at any time served as a member of the Army, Navy, Marine Corps, or Air Force of the United States. </section><section prefix="b">No fee or compensation shall be allowed or paid for furnishing a certificate of birth to a member of the Kentucky National Guard who has received deployment orders during the sixty (60) days prior to the furnishing of the certificate. </section></section><section prefix="5">The cabinet shall notify the State Board of Elections monthly of the name, address, birthdate, sex, race, and Social Security number of residents of the Commonwealth who died during the previous month. This data shall include only those persons who were over the age of eighteen (18) years at the date of death. No fee or compensation shall be allowed for furnishing these lists. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 158, sec. 47, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 56, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 1, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 457, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 391, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 312, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 369, sec. 27, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2008).  The structure of paragraphs in subsection (2) of this section has been altered by the Reviser of Statutes from the structure set forth in 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 2, under the authority of KRS 7.136. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-16</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40956</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>