<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">A HIGHER EDUCATION FINANCE </unit></structure><section_number>164A.055</section_number><catch_line>Asset Resolution Corporation -- Purpose -- Powers -- Compensation. </catch_line><order_by>055</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Board" means the board of directors of the Kentucky Higher Education Student Loan Corporation acting in the capacity of the board of Asset Resolution Corporation; and </section><section prefix="b">"Corporation" means the Asset Resolution Corporation created in this section. </section></section><section prefix="2">There is hereby created an instrumentality of the Commonwealth to be known as Asset Resolution Corporation for the purpose of promoting higher educational opportunities for the citizens of the Commonwealth by providing debt resolution services for student loan obligations held by the United States Department of Education or other third-party entities and any other related activity to the extent such activity is not limited or prohibited by statute or other governing authority. </section><section prefix="3">The corporation shall be attached to the Kentucky Higher Education Student Loan Corporation for administrative and reporting purposes and shall be governed, managed, and administered as a separate and distinct instrumentality of the Commonwealth in accordance with this section. </section><section prefix="4">The Kentucky Higher Education Student Loan Corporation and its facilities shall be used and employed in the administration of the corporation, including but not limited to the keeping of records and the employment of staff to assist in the performance of the designated activities of the corporation. </section><section prefix="5">The board shall have the power and authority to: <section prefix="a">Sue and be sued; </section><section prefix="b">Promulgate administrative regulations and adopt procedures to implement this section; </section><section prefix="c">Make and enter into contracts necessary for the administration of the corporation; </section><section prefix="d">Adopt a corporate seal and change and amend it from time to time; </section><section prefix="e">Make, execute, and effectuate any and all agreements or other documents with the United States Department of Education, this Commonwealth, any federal or state agency, or any person, corporation, association, partnership, or other organization or entity and perform other acts necessary or appropriate for the effectuation of its rights and duties pursuant to this section; </section><section prefix="f">Delegate to the Kentucky Higher Education Student Loan Corporation general supervision and direction over the administrative function of the corporation and its employees in carrying out the policies, programs, administrative regulations, and directives of the board; </section><section prefix="g">Carry out the duties and obligations of the corporation pursuant to this section, and to have any and all other powers as may be reasonably necessary for the effectuation of the purposes of the corporation; and </section><section prefix="h">Adopt bylaws for the conduct of its business, including the designation of directors, and prescribe rules, regulations, and policies in connection with the performance of its functions and duties. </section></section><section prefix="6">Board members, except officers or employees of the state, shall receive compensation for their services in the amount of one hundred dollars ($100) per day for attendance at each board meeting and shall be entitled to payment of any reasonable and necessary expenses actually incurred in discharging their duties under this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 44, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. -- Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 84, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43238</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>