<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6">THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY </unit></structure><section_number>6.767</section_number><catch_line>Prohibitions against acceptance of campaign contributions from legislative agents at any time and from employers of legislative agents or permanent committees during regular sessions -- Penalties -- Defenses. </catch_line><order_by>767</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A member of the General Assembly, candidate for the General Assembly, or his or her campaign committee shall not accept a campaign contribution from a legislative agent. Violation of this provision is ethical misconduct. </section><section prefix="2">A member of the General Assembly, candidate for the General Assembly, or his or her campaign committee shall not, during a regular session of the General Assembly, accept a campaign contribution from an employer of a legislative agent, or from a permanent committee as defined in KRS 121.015. This subsection shall not apply to candidates for the General Assembly in a special election held during a regular session of the General Assembly. Violation of this provision is ethical misconduct. </section><section prefix="3">It shall be a complete defense under this section if the legislator, candidate, or his or her campaign committee receives a campaign contribution from a legislative agent or, during a regular session, from an employer or from a permanent committee, which fact is unknown to the legislator, candidate, or committee at the time of receipt, if the legislator, candidate, or his or her campaign committee either returns the contribution within thirty (30) days of receipt, and within fourteen (14) additional days makes that fact, together with the name of the contributor, amount of the contribution, and the date of return or payment known, in writing to the commission. It shall also be a defense if a legislator, candidate, or his or her campaign committee receives a campaign contribution from a legislative agent whose name does not yet appear on the list of legislative agents and their employers furnished to the Legislative Research Commission if the legislator, candidate, or his or her campaign committee returns the campaign contribution within thirty (30) days of the Legislative Research Commission's receipt of the list bearing the name of the legislative agent and all employers and makes the written disclosure to the commission required in this subsection. The time periods shall be tolled upon the filing with the commission of a request for an advisory opinion regarding the campaign contribution. Upon the issuance of the opinion or decision not to render an opinion, the time period shall resume. </section></text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 75, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2014. -- Created 1993 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 17, effective September 16, 1993. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43306</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>