<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="LI" order_by="51">UNIFIED JUVENILE CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="610" order_by="610">PROCEDURAL MATTERS </unit></structure><section_number>610.295</section_number><catch_line>Detention costs -- Assessment against parent after hearing -- Payments when adjudication based on status offense or public offense -- Payment schedule and discharge. </catch_line><order_by>295</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any statute to the contrary notwithstanding, detention costs shall not be assessed by a court against a parent unless the court has conducted a hearing and has determined: <section prefix="a">That the child has previously been adjudicated as a habitual truant under KRS Chapter 630, a public offender under KRS Chapter 635, or a youthful offender under KRS Chapter 640, and now stands adjudicated guilty of a subsequent habitual truancy or public offense, or is now being considered for transfer to the Circuit Court for trial as a youthful offender; and </section><section prefix="b">That the failure or neglect of the parent to properly supervise or control the child is a substantial contributing factor of the act or acts of the child upon which the proceeding is based; and </section><section prefix="c">That the parent has the financial ability to pay any fees ordered. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any orders for payment shall direct that payments be made to the fiscal court or legislative body of a consolidated local government, urban-county government, or charter government if detention is based upon adjudication related to a status offense and to the Department of Juvenile Justice if the adjudication is based upon a public offense or transfer as a youthful offender. </section><section prefix="3">The fiscal court or legislative body of a consolidated local government, urban-county government, or charter government or the Department of Juvenile Justice, as appropriate, shall establish a payment schedule for parents against whom detention costs have been assessed, and may discharge any remaining portion of the debt upon proof of substantial change in circumstances of the parent. </section><section prefix="4">The authority granted under subsection (3) of this section may be applied to all pre-existing court orders assessing detention costs in effect on July 15, 2002. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 263, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20166</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>