<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.642</section_number><catch_line>Pervasive developmental disorders -- Definition for KRS 200.654, 200.660, 347.020, and 387.510 -- Waiver application -- Report. </catch_line><order_by>642</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section and KRS 200.654, 200.660, 347.020, and 387.510, "pervasive developmental disorders" has the same meaning as in the Diagnostic and Statistical Manual of Mental Disorders, fourth edition (DSM-IV). The term includes five (5) diagnostic subcategories: <section prefix="a">Autistic disorder; </section><section prefix="b">Pervasive disorder not otherwise specified; </section><section prefix="c">Asperger's disorder; </section><section prefix="d">Rett's disorder; and </section><section prefix="e">Childhood disintegrative disorder. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Department for Medicaid Services shall make application, within three (3) months of July 15, 2002, to the Federal Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services for a waiver to provide services and supports to individuals who: <section prefix="a">Are Medicaid eligible; </section><section prefix="b">Have an Axis I diagnosis of a pervasive developmental disorder; </section><section prefix="c">Are institutionalized or at risk for institutionalization; and </section><section prefix="d">Require a coordinated plan of medically necessary community-based behavioral health services. </section></section><section prefix="3">The waiver application shall include services that are documented to be effective in the treatment of pervasive developmental disorders and consistent with clinical best practices. </section><section prefix="4">The waiver application shall specify the required credentials for the providers of each service. </section><section prefix="5">The cabinet shall cap the number of children served under the waiver program to insure budget neutrality based upon the expenditures for children with Pervasive Developmental Disorders that were served under the IMPACT Plus Program during fiscal years 2001-2002. </section><section prefix="6">The cabinet shall include in the waiver application those items that are necessary to ensure the waiver operates within the designated dollars, including but not limited to a maximum number of individuals to be served and a maximum dollar amount that can be expended for an individual. </section><section prefix="7">The waiver shall be coordinated with and shall not supplant services provided by schools under KRS Chapter 157 or services provided under KRS Chapters 200 and 347. Nothing in this section shall affect or limit a school district's ability to obtain Medicaid reimbursement for school-related health services. </section><section prefix="8">The Department for Medicaid Services shall report to the Governor, the Legislative Research Commission, and the Interim Joint Committee on Health and Welfare on the number of individuals receiving services under the waiver, the cost and type of services received, and any available nonidentifying information pertaining to individual outcomes. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7782</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>