<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="117" order_by="117">REGULATION OF ELECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>117.025</section_number><catch_line>Executive director and assistant -- Staff -- Powers and duties. </catch_line><order_by>025</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The State Board of Elections shall appoint an executive director, who shall be the chief administrative officer for the board. The board shall also appoint an assistant to the director, who shall be of a different political party than the director. The salaries of the director and his assistant shall be set by the board. </section><section prefix="2">The State Board of Elections shall employ, on a bipartisan basis, a staff sufficient to carry out the duties assigned to the board, including legal counsel and a training officer to provide assistance to the county clerks and the county boards of elections in their training of precinct election officers. </section><section prefix="3">The board shall: <section prefix="a">Maintain a complete roster of all qualified registered voters within the state by county and precinct; </section><section prefix="b">For each primary election, furnish each county clerk with a master list of all registered voters in the county, together with three (3) signature rosters of all registered voters in each precinct of the county according to party affiliation, and two (2) lists of all registered voters in each precinct of the county at least five (5) days prior to each primary election; </section><section prefix="c">For each regular election, furnish each county clerk with a master list of all registered voters in the county, together with one (1) signature roster of all registered voters in each precinct of the county on which each voter's party affiliation is identified, and two (2) lists of all registered voters in each precinct of the county at least five (5) days prior to each regular election; </section><section prefix="d">Maintain all information furnished to the board relating to the inclusion or deletion of names from the rosters for four (4) years; </section><section prefix="e">Furnish, at a reasonable price, the state central executive committee of each political party qualifying under KRS 118.015 monthly data of all additions, deletions and changes of registration in each precinct of each county and the state central executive committee shall furnish a county listing to each of the county executive committees of each political party; </section><section prefix="f">Purchase, lease or contract for the use of equipment necessary to properly carry out its duties under the provisions of this chapter and KRS Chapters 116 and 118; </section><section prefix="g">Secure information from any source which may assist the board in carrying out the purposes of this section; </section><section prefix="h">Furnish at a reasonable price any and all precinct lists to duly qualified candidates, political party committees or officials thereof, or any committee that advocates or opposes an amendment or public question. The State Board of Elections may also furnish the precinct lists to other persons at the board's discretion, at a reasonable price. The board shall not furnish precinct lists to persons who intend to use the lists for commercial use. </section></section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 394, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 13, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 185, sec. 6, effective July 13, 1984; and ch. 333, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 457, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 130, sec. 19, effectiive June 21, 1974. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27345</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>