<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.230</section_number><catch_line>Definition of "public agency" for KRS 65.210 to 65.300. </catch_line><order_by>230</order_by><text>As used in KRS 65.210 to 65.300, unless the context otherwise requires, "public agency" means any political subdivision of this state, any agency of the state government or of the United States, a sheriff, any county or independent school district, and any political subdivision of another state. It also means a state-supported or private institution of higher education and a county or independent public school district for the purposes of entering into a joint agreement to establish and operate a program or facility, including a center for child learning and study, designed to help one (1) or more schools meet any of the goals set forth in KRS 158.6451, or for the investment of funds. If a private institution of higher education proposes to participate in an agreement pursuant to the Interlocal Cooperation Act, the Attorney General shall determine if the proposal is compatible with the United States Constitution, as part of the review of the agreement provided in KRS 65.260(2). </text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 464, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 356, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 393, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 87, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 1. -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 216, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23375</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>