<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.111</section_number><catch_line>Division of Administrative Hearings. </catch_line><order_by>111</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Division of Administrative Hearings is created in the Office of Attorney General. </section><section prefix="2">This division shall have the following responsibilities: <section prefix="a">Employing and maintaining a pool of hearing officers for assignment to the individual agencies at their request, for the conduct of administrative hearings. The Attorney General's office may also employ other staff as necessary to carry out functions and responsibilities assigned by KRS Chapter 13B; </section><section prefix="b">Reviewing and approving or disapproving requests from agencies for waivers from provisions of KRS Chapter 13B; </section><section prefix="c">Providing training in administrative hearing procedures for hearing officers as required in KRS 13B.030, either by developing and offering the training, or by contracting with appropriate organizations for the provision of training, or by approving training developed and submitted by the agencies; </section><section prefix="d">Consulting with the Personnel Cabinet and employing agencies in the establishment of relevant and appropriate qualifications for classes of hearing officers; </section><section prefix="e">Establishing, in cooperation with the Division of Consumer Protection, a clearinghouse for complaints concerning the administrative hearing process in Kentucky. Each complaint received shall be referred to the agency that is the subject of the complaint, and the action of the agency to resolve the complaint shall be noted and reported to the division; </section><section prefix="f">Reporting to the Legislative Research Commission by July 1 of each odd-numbered year, the status of the administrative hearing process in Kentucky. The report shall include a compilation of statistical data and other information necessary to assess the effectiveness and efficiency of hearing procedures and recommendations for making improvements to the system. Agencies shall provide the information requested by the Division of Administrative Hearings necessary to complete the report. </section></section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 382, sec. 18, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=887</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>