<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">A AUTOMATED MOTOR VEHICLE REGISTRATION SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>186A.300</section_number><catch_line>Possession of blank, uncompleted or partially executed title and registration documents prohibited -- Exceptions. </catch_line><order_by>300</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person, except as provided in subsection (2) of this section shall have in his possession any blank, uncompleted, or partially executed "certificate of title and registration," "certificate of registration," "certificate of title," or other similarly styled form or document, whether genuine or counterfeit, of this or any other state or country, which is of a type that, when genuine and properly issued, evidences ownership of a vehicle under the laws of this or another state or country, and surrender of which is required in order to sell, transfer, register or title a motor vehicle or trailer in this state. </section><section prefix="2">A person who possesses forms or documents of the type described in subsection (1) of this section, is not in violation of this section if he: <section prefix="a">Is an employee of a manufacturer or printer of such forms or documents and possesses such forms or documents in the normal course of the business of design or manufacture of them in connection with bid invitation, bid, or contract with a governmental agency related to supplying such forms for governmental use. </section><section prefix="b">Is an employee of a shipper, or agency, under whose direction such forms are being shipped or delivered to a state or local agency charged with receiving, distributing or issuing such forms or documents, when they are in a container sealed under governmental direction. </section><section prefix="c">Is an employee of a state agency who possesses such forms or documents in the course of carrying out his official duties when his duties are to handle such forms or documents. </section><section prefix="d">Is a county clerk, or employee of a county clerk whose official work duties require the handling of such forms or documents, and he possesses them within the confines of the county clerk's office or official storage space or immediately incidental to placing them in such places. </section><section prefix="e">Possesses such form or document and it is prominently and indelibly marked on its face either: specimen, or void, or sample. </section></section></text><history>Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 164, sec. 57, effective July 15, 1982. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1982 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6197</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>