<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="11" order_by="11">A EXECUTIVE BRANCH CODE OF ETHICS </unit></structure><section_number>11A.211</section_number><catch_line>Registration statements for executive agency lobbyists, their employers, and real parties in interest -- Fee -- Trust and agency account for commission operations -- Relationship of registration to state contracts. </catch_line><order_by>211</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each executive agency lobbyist, employer, and real party in interest shall file with the commission within ten (10) days following the engagement of an executive agency lobbyist, an initial registration statement showing all of the following: <section prefix="a">The name, business address, and occupation of the executive agency lobbyist; </section><section prefix="b">The name and business address of the employer and of any real party in interest on whose behalf the executive agency lobbyist is acting, if it is different from the employer. However, if a trade association or other charitable or fraternal organization that is exempt from federal income taxation under Section 501(c) of the Internal Revenue Code is the employer, the statement need not list the names and addresses of every member of the association or organization, so long as the association or organization itself is listed; </section><section prefix="c">A brief description of the executive agency decision to which the engagement relates; </section><section prefix="d">The name of the executive agency or agencies to which the engagement relates; and </section><section prefix="e">Certification by the employer and executive agency lobbyist that the information contained in the registration statement is complete and accurate. </section></section><section prefix="2">In addition to the initial registration statement required by subsection (1) of this section, each executive agency lobbyist, employer, and real party in interest shall file with the commission, not later than the last day of July of each year, an updated registration statement that confirms the continuing existence of each engagement described in an initial registration statement and that lists the specific executive agency decisions the executive agency lobbyist sought to influence under the engagement during the period covered by the updated statement, and with it any statement of expenditures required to be filed by KRS 11A.216 and any details of financial transaction required to be filed by KRS 11A.221. </section><section prefix="3">If an executive agency lobbyist is engaged by more than one (1) employer, the executive agency lobbyist shall file a separate initial and updated registration statement for each engagement. If an employer engages more than one (1) executive agency lobbyist, the employer shall file only one (1) updated registration statement under subsection (2) of this section, which shall contain the information required by subsection (2) of this section regarding all executive agency lobbyists engaged by the employer. </section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">A change in any information required by subsection (1)(a), (b), (c), (d), or (2) of this section shall be reflected in the next updated registration statement filed under subsection (2) of this section. </section><section prefix="b">Within thirty (30) days following the termination of an engagement, the executive agency lobbyist who was employed under the engagement shall file written notice of the termination with the commission. </section></section><section prefix="5">Each employer of one (1) or more executive agency lobbyists, and each real party in interest, shall pay a registration fee of one hundred twenty-five dollars ($125) upon the filing of an updated registration statement. All fees collected by the commission under the provisions of this subsection shall be deposited in the State Treasury in a trust and agency fund account to the credit of the commission. These agency funds shall be used to supplement general fund appropriations for the operations of the commission and shall not lapse. No part of the trust and agency fund account shall revert to the general funds of this state. </section><section prefix="6">Upon registration pursuant to this section, an executive agency lobbyist shall be issued a card annually by the commission showing the executive agency lobbyist is registered. The registration card shall be valid from the date of its issuance through the thirty-first day of July of the following year. </section><section prefix="7">The commission shall review each registration statement filed with the commission under this section to determine if the statement contains all of the required information. If the commission determines the registration statement does not contain all of the required information or that an executive agency lobbyist, employer, or real party in interest has failed to file a registration statement, the commission shall send written notification of the deficiency by certified mail to the person who filed the registration statement or to the person who failed to file the registration statement regarding the failure. Any person so notified by the commission shall, not later than fifteen (15) days after receiving the notice, file a registration statement or an amended registration statement that includes all of the required information. If any person who receives a notice under this subsection fails to file a registration statement or an amended registration statement within the fifteen (15) day period, the commission may initiate an investigation of the person's failure to file. If the commission initiates an investigation pursuant to this section, the commission shall also notify each elected executive official and the secretary of each cabinet listed in KRS 12.250 of the pending investigation. </section><section prefix="8">In the biennial report published under KRS 11A.110(13), the commission shall, in the manner and form the commission determines, include a report containing statistical information on the registration statements filed under this section during the preceding biennium. </section><section prefix="9">If an employer who engages an executive agency lobbyist, or a real party in interest on whose behalf the executive agency lobbyist was engaged is the recipient of a contract, grant, lease, or other financial arrangement pursuant to which funds of the state or of an executive agency are distributed or allocated, the executive agency or any aggrieved party may consider the failure of the real party in interest, the employer, or the executive agency lobbyist to comply with this section as a breach of a material condition of the contract, grant, lease, or other financial arrangement. </section><section prefix="10">Executive agency officials may require certification from any person seeking the award of a contract, grant, lease, or financial arrangement that the person, his employer, and any real party in interest are in compliance with this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 542, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1993 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 47, effective September 16, 1993. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=608</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>