<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.6904</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 247.6901 to 247.6957. </catch_line><order_by>6904</order_by><text>As used in KRS 247.6901 to 247.6957, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Commissioner" means the Commissioner of Agriculture; </section><section prefix="2">"Board" means the State Board of Agriculture; </section><section prefix="3">"Producer" means every person who produces and markets ovine or caprine animals; </section><section prefix="4">"New producer" means a producer who was not engaged in the business of producing ovine or caprine animals at the time a referendum was conducted in accordance with the provisions of KRS 247.6901 to 247.6957; </section><section prefix="5">"Marketing year" means from July 1 to June 30; </section><section prefix="6">"Purchaser" means any person buying, accepting for shipment, or otherwise acquiring the property in or to ovine or caprine animals from a producer, and shall include a mortgagee, pledgee, lienor, or other person, public or private, having a claim against the producer, when the actual or constructive possession of the ovine or caprine animals is taken as part payment or in satisfaction of a mortgage, pledge, lien, or claim; </section><section prefix="7">"Marketed" means any quantities that are sold, bartered, or for which other items of value are exchanged; </section><section prefix="8">"Net market price" means the sales price or other value received by a producer for ovine or caprine animals after adjustments have been made for any premium or discount based on grading or quality factors; </section><section prefix="9">"Association" means any commission, council, board, or other body; </section><section prefix="10">"Caprine" means of, or pertaining to, goats; and </section><section prefix="11">"Ovine" means of, or pertaining to, sheep. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 8, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 347, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11781</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>