<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="441" order_by="441">JAILS AND COUNTY PRISONERS </unit></structure><section_number>441.215</section_number><catch_line>Jail budget preparation. </catch_line><order_by>215</order_by><text><section prefix="1">By April 1 of each year, the county judge/executive, county treasurer, and jailer shall prepare and submit to the fiscal court a proposed line item jail budget and an estimate of revenues for jail operations from federal, state, and local sources. The proposed jail budget and estimate of revenues shall be included in the proposed county budget and investigated by the fiscal court as provided in KRS 68.240. </section><section prefix="2">The state local finance officer shall supervise and direct the form and classifications of the line item jail budget and estimate of jail revenues. </section><section prefix="3">The fiscal court shall consult with the jailer prior to any amendment of the jail budget. The fiscal court shall possess sole authority to transfer funds between line items. </section><section prefix="4">If, in the opinion of the jailer, the jail budget as proposed or as amended by the fiscal court, fails to adequately provide for the safe and secure operation of the jail or the care of prisoners, the jailer shall submit a written statement of his concerns along with any available documentation, to the fiscal court and, if the jail holds state prisoners, to the Department of Corrections. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 108, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 123, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 328, sec. 6, effective April 9, 1988. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19331</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>