<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.090</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of secretary. </catch_line><order_by>090</order_by><text>The secretary shall:  <section prefix="1">Appoint county and district boards of health pursuant to KRS 212.020 and 212.850;  </section><section prefix="2">Hear and decide appeals from rulings, decisions and actions of the cabinet, where the aggrieved party makes written request therefor to the secretary within thirty (30) days after the ruling, decision or action complained of;  </section><section prefix="3">Adopt rules and regulations necessary to regulate and control all matters set forth in KRS 211.180 to the extent the regulation and control of same have not been delegated to some other agency of the Commonwealth and adopt such other rules and regulations as may be necessary to effectuate the purposes of this chapter and any other law relating to public health, except as otherwise provided by law;  </section><section prefix="4">Issue or deny hospital licenses;  </section><section prefix="5">Approve or disapprove the establishment of proposed hospital service corporations and contracts for hospital service corporations and contracts for hospital services pursuant to KRS 304.32-030;  </section><section prefix="6">Approve or disapprove of the establishment of proposed medical service plan corporations and contract for medical services pursuant to KRS 304.32-050, 304.32-140, and 304.32-160;  </section><section prefix="7">Enforce the provisions of KRS 311.250, 311.260, 311.375, 311.376.  </section></text><history>Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 203, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 63. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 203, sec. 44(1); and ch. 302, sec. 8. -- Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 157, sec. 7, effective June 17, 1954. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2049, 2050, 2054, 2062a-1. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1980</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8342</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>