<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="40" order_by="40">VETERANS </unit></structure><section_number>40.305</section_number><catch_line>Governor's Advisory Board for Veterans' Affairs -- Membership -- Meetings -- Duties of board and commissioner of Department of Veterans' Affairs. </catch_line><order_by>305</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is created a board to be known as the Governor's Advisory Board for Veterans' Affairs, which shall be attached to the Department of Veterans' Affairs. </section><section prefix="2">The board shall be composed of the following: <section prefix="a">Seven (7) members appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="b">The executive director of the Kentucky Commission on Military Affairs; and </section><section prefix="c">The adjutant general of the Commonwealth. </section></section><section prefix="3">All board members appointed by the Governor shall serve until their successors are appointed, and all appointments shall be for three (3) years. It is further provided that the appointments shall be veterans with service during time of war or hostilities wherein American troops were engaged in conflict with an armed enemy. If practicable, the Governor, in making appointments to the board, shall give due consideration to a fair representation on the board of nationally recognized veterans' organizations active in Kentucky, based on size of the membership of such organizations in this state. The state headquarters of each major veterans' organization may, from time to time, submit a list of not more than three (3) names to the Governor from which list original appointments may be made and vacancies filled in his discretion. </section><section prefix="4">Members of the board shall meet at least quarterly at the Department of Veterans' Affairs, and at such other times as the chairman may designate, and the members shall decide as to the specific meeting date. </section><section prefix="5">Members of the board shall be paid for the actual expenses incurred upon attendance of meetings of the board subject to the Finance and Administration Cabinet regulations. </section><section prefix="6">At its first meeting the members of the board shall select a chairman, vice chairman, and secretary from among the appointed members. </section><section prefix="7">The Department of Veterans' Affairs shall provide administrative support to the board. </section><section prefix="8">The board shall advise the commissioner of the Department of Veterans' Affairs and the Governor on the administration of veterans' services programs. </section><section prefix="9">The commissioner shall advise the Governor on matters relating to veterans' affairs. </section><section prefix="10">The commissioner and the board shall advise the General Assembly on matters relating to veterans' affairs and the administration of veterans' services programs. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 280, secs. 1 and 3, effective July 14, 2000; former KRS 36.310 repealed and reenacted as KRS 40.305 ch. 147, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 244, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. II, sec. 9(1); and ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 33. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 222, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><former-codification> KRS 36.310. </former-codification><lrc-note> (7/14/2000).  In accordance with 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 280, sec. 3, the amendment of the former KRS 36.310 in Section 1 of Acts Chapter 280 has been merged into the repeal and reenactment of that statute as KRS 40.305 by 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 147, sec. 2, notwithstanding KRS 446.260. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21845</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>