<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="161" order_by="161">SCHOOL EMPLOYEES -- TEACHERS' RETIREMENT AND TENURE </unit></structure><section_number>161.017</section_number><catch_line>Executive director of Education Professional Standards Board. </catch_line><order_by>017</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Education Professional Standards Board, established in KRS 161.028, shall be headed by an executive director who shall be responsible for the day to day operations of the board including the following: <section prefix="a">Setting up appropriate organizational structures and personnel policies for approval by the board; </section><section prefix="b">Appointing all staff, including the deputy executive director; </section><section prefix="c">Preparing annual reports on the board's program of work; </section><section prefix="d">Carrying out policy and program directives of the board; </section><section prefix="e">Preparing and submitting to the board for its approval a proposed biennial budget; and </section><section prefix="f">Performing all other duties and responsibilities assigned by state law. </section></section><section prefix="2">When it is necessary to fill the position of executive director, the board shall conduct a comprehensive search for candidates and may employ a search firm if the board deems it necessary. The executive director shall possess broad-based experience in education and teacher development, and have demonstrated leadership skills in addition to other qualifications to be established by the board as authorized in KRS 161.028. </section><section prefix="3">With approval of the board, the executive director may enter into agreements with any state agency or political subdivision of the state, any postsecondary education institution, or any other person or entity to enlist assistance to implement the duties and responsibilities of the board. </section><section prefix="4">The executive director shall have access to the papers, books, and records of education personnel as part of an inquiry or investigation relating to disciplinary actions against a certified employee. </section><section prefix="5">Pursuant to KRS 161.120, the executive director, on behalf of the board, may issue administrative subpoenas for the attendance of witnesses and the production of documents relevant to disciplinary cases under consideration. Compliance with the subpoenas shall be enforceable by the Circuit Court in Franklin County. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 288, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3825</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>