<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="407" order_by="407">INTERSTATE SUPPORT ENFORCEMENT </unit></structure><section_number>407.5201Basis</section_number><catch_line>for jurisdiction over nonresident.   </catch_line><order_by>5201Basis</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In a proceeding to establish or enforce a support order or to determine parentage of a child, a tribunal of this state may exercise personal jurisdiction over a nonresident individual or the individual's guardian or conservator if: <section prefix="a">The individual is personally served with summons, or notice within this state; </section><section prefix="b">The individual submits to the jurisdiction of this state by consent in a record, by entering a general appearance, or by filing a responsive pleading having the effect of waiving any contest to personal jurisdiction; </section><section prefix="c">The individual resided with the child in this state; </section><section prefix="d">The individual resided in this state and provided prenatal expenses or support for the child; </section><section prefix="e">The child resides in this state as a result of the acts or directives of the individual; </section><section prefix="f">The individual engaged in sexual intercourse in this state and the child may have been conceived by that act of intercourse; </section><section prefix="g">The individual asserted parentage of a child in the putative father registry maintained in this state by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; or </section><section prefix="h">There is any other basis consistent with the constitutions of this state and the United States for the exercise of personal jurisdiction. </section></section><section prefix="2">The bases of personal jurisdiction set forth in subsection (1) of this section or in any other law of this state may not be used to acquire personal jurisdiction for a tribunal of this state to modify a child support order of another state unless the requirements of KRS 407.5611 are met, or, in the case of a foreign support order, unless the requirements of KRS 407.5615 are met. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 4, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 642, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 594, effective July 15, 1998.-- Contingent effective date repealed 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 20, effective March 23, 1998. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 365, sec. 16, effective upon contingency. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44080</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>