<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="317" order_by="317">B ESTHETICIANS </unit></structure><section_number>317B.025</section_number><catch_line>Qualifications and fees for esthetician, esthetic salon, and esthetics instructor licenses -- Dual licenses.   </catch_line><order_by>025</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall issue an esthetician license to any person who: <section prefix="a">Is of good moral character and temperate habit; </section><section prefix="b">Is at least eighteen (18) years of age; </section><section prefix="c">Has a high school diploma, General Educational Development (GED) diploma, or the results from the Test for Adult Basic Education indicating a score equivalent to the twelfth grade of high school; </section><section prefix="d">Has satisfactorily completed one thousand (1,000) hours of instruction in a licensed school approved by the board; </section><section prefix="e">Has received a satisfactory grade on an examination prescribed by the board to determine fitness to practice as an esthetician; and </section><section prefix="f">Has paid a fee of at least seventy-five dollars ($75) to be adjusted as needed in administrative regulations promulgated by the board. </section></section><section prefix="2">The board may issue a license to a cosmetologist who seeks dual licensure as an esthetician by offering a dual cosmetologist and esthetician license to individuals who meet licensure criteria for a cosmetologist as in KRS Chapter 317A and licensure criteria for an esthetician as in this chapter. The fee for the dual license for license renewal shall be determined by the board as promulgated in administrative regulations. Nothing in this chapter shall prohibit separate licensure of cosmetologists and estheticians. </section><section prefix="3">The board shall issue licenses as follows: <section prefix="a">A license to operate an esthetic salon shall be issued to any licensed esthetician upon receipt of: <section prefix="1">The completed application; and </section><section prefix="2">A fee of at least one hundred twenty-five dollars ($125) to be adjusted as needed in administrative regulations promulgated by the board. </section></section><section prefix="b">If an owner is not a licensed esthetician, the owner shall have a licensed esthetician manage the esthetic salon at all times. A new license shall be purchased if the salon's owner, manager, or location changes. </section><section prefix="c">Licensed esthetic salons shall have the furnishings and salon equipment required pursuant to administrative regulations adopted by the board. </section><section prefix="d">Any licensed esthetician who leases or rents space or pays a fee to do business in a beauty salon or esthetic salon shall be considered an independent owner and shall meet the qualifications for the respective salon owner as set out in paragraphs (a), (b), and (c) of this subsection. </section><section prefix="e">The board may refuse to issue a license if the applicant fails to comply with this chapter or the administrative regulations promulgated by the board. </section></section><section prefix="4">The board shall issue a license to teach esthetic practices to any person who: <section prefix="a">Is of good moral character and temperate habit; </section><section prefix="b">Is at least eighteen (18) years of age; </section><section prefix="c">Has a high school diploma, General Educational Development (GED) diploma, or the results from the Test for Adult Basic Education indicating a score equivalent to the twelfth grade of high school; </section><section prefix="d">Holds a current cosmetologist and instructor's license; </section><section prefix="e">Has completed fifty (50) hours in esthetics training within the last two (2) years; </section><section prefix="f">Has received a satisfactory grade on the examination for the teaching of esthetics as prescribed by the board; and </section><section prefix="g">Has paid a fee promulgated by the board in administrative regulations. </section></section><section prefix="5">The board may issue a license to teach esthetic practices to an individual with two (2) or more years' experience in teaching esthetic practices in another jurisdiction who meets the requirements of paragraphs (a), (b), and (c) of subsection (3) of this section. </section><section prefix="6">Courses in esthetic practices may be taught at any licensed cosmetology school that complies with the administrative regulations promulgated by the board under this chapter. </section><section prefix="7">Applications for esthetician examinations required by this section shall be accompanied by an examination fee of at least one hundred twenty-five dollars ($125) to be adjusted as needed in administrative regulations promulgated by the board. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 20, effective July 12, 2012. -- Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 4, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:54</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40897</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>