<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="173" order_by="173">CITY, COUNTY, AND REGIONAL LIBRARIES </unit></structure><section_number>173.610</section_number><catch_line>Tax rate change prohibited except by vote of people -- Procedure -- Limitation. </catch_line><order_by>610</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The special ad valorem tax rate for the maintenance and operation of a public library district created pursuant to KRS 173.470 before July 13, 1984, may be increased or decreased by submission to the voters of the district at a general election and approved by a majority of the votes cast on the issue. The board or any one hundred (100) qualified voters residing within the district may file a duly certified copy of a resolution or petition with the clerk of each county within the district and the county clerk shall certify whether the petition is sufficient not later than the second Tuesday in August prior to the election and the clerk shall thereupon cause the question to be prepared to be presented to the voters in substantially the following form: "Are you in favor of increasing (or decreasing) from (insert amount) cents to (insert amount) cents on each one hundred dollars ($100) of the assessed valuation of all property in the (insert name of public library district) public library district the maximum tax which the district can impose for the maintenance and operation of (insert name of district) public library district?" </section><section prefix="2">Any increase provided for in subsection (1) or (3) of this section shall not exceed twenty cents ($0.20) on each one hundred dollars ($100) of the assessed valuation of all property in the district. </section><section prefix="3">The special ad valorem tax rate for the maintenance and operation of a public library district created pursuant to KRS 173.470 before July 13, 1984, may be increased or decreased by the procedure in KRS 173.790. </section></text><history> Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 195, sec. 63, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 13, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 360, sec. 53, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 223, sec. 8. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 17, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1996 </effective><lrc-note>  Although this section was included in 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 245, sec. 16, the change in this section was deleted in the House Committee Substitute adopted by the General Assembly. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4964</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>