<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.850</section_number><catch_line>Federal acts relating to vocational education accepted.   </catch_line><order_by>850</order_by><text>This state accepts and agrees to comply with all the provisions of the Acts of Congress of the United States approved February 23, 1917, and all subsequent acts relating to vocational education, the purpose of which is to provide training, develop skills, abilities, understandings, attitudes, work habits, and appreciation, and to impart knowledge and information needed by workers to enter into and make progress in their chosen vocations. These training opportunities shall be provided for the young people who are enrolled in the regular day schools and, also, for out-of-school youth and adults, both employed and unemployed, who are in need of and can profit by vocational training. </text><history>Repealed, reenacted, and renumbered 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 26, effective June 25, 2013. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended as KRS 151B.145 by 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 470, sec. 28, effective July 1, 1990, which prevailed over the repeal and reenactment of KRS 163.020 by 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 591, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 2. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4526-1. </history><metadata><effective>June 25, 2013 </effective><former-codification> KRS 163.020. KRS 151B.145. </former-codification><former-codification-former-code>151B.145</former-codification-former-code><lrc-note> (7/13/90).  This section has been treated by two 1990 Acts; its repeal and reenactment in Acts ch. 470 renumbered the section into KRS Ch. 151B. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42197</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>