<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="237" order_by="237">FIREARMS AND DESTRUCTIVE DEVICES </unit></structure><section_number>237.120</section_number><catch_line>Program for firearms instructor trainers for concealed deadly weapon training program -- Qualification and certification requirements -- In-service training -- Fee. </catch_line><order_by>120</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department of Criminal Justice Training shall operate and maintain a program for firearms instructor trainers for the concealed deadly weapon training program. Only the General Assembly may eliminate the firearms instructor trainer program. </section><section prefix="2">A firearms instructor trainer shall meet the requirements to be a firearms instructor and shall: <section prefix="a">Possess a high school diploma or GED certificate; </section><section prefix="b">Successfully complete a firearms instructor trainer course of not more than sixteen (16) hours provided by the department; and </section><section prefix="c">Possess at least one (1) of the following valid firearms instructor certifications: <section prefix="1">National Rifle Association Personal Protection Instructor; </section><section prefix="2">National Rifle Association Pistol Marksmanship Instructor; </section><section prefix="3">Certification from a Kentucky or other firearms instructor course offered by a state or federal governmental agency; or </section><section prefix="4">Certification from another firearms instructor training course that has been determined by the Commissioner of the Department of Criminal Justice Training to be equivalent to one (1) of the above listed courses. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">Certification as a firearms instructor trainer shall be valid for a period of three (3) years during which an instructor trainer shall: <section prefix="a">Conduct or assist in at least one (1) firearms instructor course; or </section><section prefix="b">Conduct or assist in at least one (1) applicant training course; and </section><section prefix="c">Attend an instructor trainer/instructor in-service training course of not more than four (4) hours conducted by the department; and </section><section prefix="d">Not have become ineligible to be a firearms instructor trainer. </section></section><section prefix="4">The department shall conduct in-service training for firearms instructor trainers and certified firearms instructors. In-service training courses shall be held not less than twice each year in each congressional district and shall be offered at various times during the year ensuring that the maximum number of persons can attend. Preference shall be given to conducting in-service training classes on a Friday or a Saturday. Notice of the time, date, and location for in-service training for each calendar year shall be sent to each firearms instructor trainer and certified firearms instructor by mail or by e-mail not less than thirty (30) days prior to the beginning of the first class for each calendar year. The cost of the in-service training shall be not more than fifty dollars ($50). </section><section prefix="5">At the end of the certification period, the department shall issue a new firearms instructor trainer certification to a person who has completed the provisions of this section, unless that firearms instructor trainer notifies the department in writing that he or she desires not to be recertified or is otherwise ineligible to be recertified. There shall be no charge for recertification. A firearms instructor trainer who has permitted his or her certification to expire may take the in-service course and be recertified for a period of up to one hundred eighty (180) days from the date of expiration of the certification without having to repeat the requirements of subsection (2) of this section. </section><section prefix="6">The fee for a firearms instructor trainer course shall be not more than one hundred dollars ($100). No portion of the fee shall be refunded to any student who fails or who does not complete the required course of training. </section><section prefix="7">Any state agency or public university which owns a firing range shall make that range available to the department for the conduct of in-service training without charge if the department determines that for any particular year's in-service training that range firing is required. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 240, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 368, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11134</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>