<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="324" order_by="324">A REAL ESTATE APPRAISERS </unit></structure><section_number>324A.150</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 324A.150 to 324A.164.   </catch_line><order_by>150</order_by><text>As used in KRS 324A.150 to 324A.164, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Appraisal management company" means a person who performs the actions necessary to administer a network of state-licensed appraisers to fulfill requests for appraisal management services on behalf of a client, whether directly or through the use of software products or online, including but not limited to any of the following actions: <section prefix="a">Recruiting appraisers; </section><section prefix="b">Contracting with appraisers to perform appraisal services; </section><section prefix="c">Collecting fees from clients; </section><section prefix="d">Negotiating fees with appraisers or reimbursing appraisers for appraisal services; </section><section prefix="e">Receiving appraisal orders and appraisal reports; </section><section prefix="f">Submitting appraisal reports received from appraisers to the company's clients; </section><section prefix="g">Reviewing or verifying appraisal reports; or </section><section prefix="h">Managing the process of having an appraisal performed, including providing related administrative and clerical duties; </section></section><section prefix="2">"Appraisal management services" means conducting business by telephone, by electronic means, by mail, or in person, directly or indirectly for compensation or other pecuniary gain or in the expectation of compensation or other pecuniary gain to: <section prefix="a">Solicit, accept, or offer to accept a request for appraisal services; or </section><section prefix="b">Employ or contract with a licensed or certified appraiser to perform appraisal services; </section></section><section prefix="3">"Appraisal services" means the practice of developing an opinion of the value of real estate in conformity with the minimum USPAP standards; </section><section prefix="4">"Appraiser" means an individual licensed by the board who, for a fee or other consideration, develops and communicates a real estate appraisal or otherwise gives an opinion of the value of real estate or any interest in real estate in conformity with the minimum USPAP standards; </section><section prefix="5">"Appraiser panel" means a group of independent appraisers who have been selected by an appraisal management company to perform appraisal services for the appraisal management company; </section><section prefix="6">"Board" means the Kentucky Real Estate Appraisers Board established by KRS 324A.015; </section><section prefix="7">"Client" means a person that contracts with or otherwise enters into an agreement with an appraisal management company for the performance of appraisal services; </section><section prefix="8">"Controlling person" means an individual employed, appointed, or authorized by an appraisal management company to contract with clients or independent appraisers for the performance of appraisal services; </section><section prefix="9">"Managing principal" has the same meaning as "controlling person"; </section><section prefix="10">"Registrant" means an appraisal management company or person that is registered or seeking registration under KRS 324A.152; and </section><section prefix="11">"USPAP" means the Uniform Standards of Professional Appraisal Practice. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 46, sec. 3, effective June 25, 2013. -- Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 58, sec. 1, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><lrc-note> (6/8/2011).  2011 Ky. Acts ch. 58, sec. 9, provides that KRS 324A.150 to 324A.164 shall be known as the Kentucky Appraisal Management Company Registration Act. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42090</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>