<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>14A.4-010</section_number><catch_line>Registered office and registered agent required.   </catch_line><order_by>4-010</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each entity and each foreign entity qualified to transact business in this Commonwealth shall continuously maintain in this Commonwealth: <section prefix="a">A registered office that may be the same as any of its places of business; and </section><section prefix="b">A registered agent, who may be: <section prefix="1">An individual who resides in this Commonwealth and whose business address is identical with the registered office; or </section><section prefix="2">An entity or foreign entity qualified to transact business in this Commonwealth whose business address is identical with the registered office. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">Unless the registered agent signs the document making the appointment, the appointment of the registered agent or a successor registered agent on whom process may be given is not effective until the agent delivers a statement in writing to the Secretary of State accepting the appointment. </section><section prefix="3">Each entity and each foreign entity maintaining a registered office and agent in this Commonwealth shall provide to its registered agent and update from time to time as necessary the name, business address, and business telephone number of a natural person who is authorized to receive communications from the registered agent. Such person shall be deemed the communications contact for the entity or foreign entity. Every registered agent shall retain in paper or electronic form the information concerning the current communications contact for each entity and each foreign entity for which that registered agent serves as registered agent. If the entity or foreign entity fails to provide the registered agent with a current communications contact, the registered agent may resign as the registered agent for such entity or foreign entity. </section><section prefix="4">This section shall not apply to a domestic or foreign partnership that is not a limited liability partnership. </section><section prefix="5">This section shall not apply to a limited partnership governed as to its internal affairs by the Kentucky Uniform Limited Partnership Act, KRS 362.410 to 362.700. </section><section prefix="6">This section shall not apply to a rural electric cooperative or to a foreign rural electric cooperative that is not required to qualify to transact business by means of a filing with the Secretary of State. </section><section prefix="7">This section shall not apply to a rural telephone cooperative or to a foreign rural telephone cooperative that is not required to qualify to transact business by means of a filing with the Secretary of State. </section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 28, effective January 1, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2011 </effective><lrc-note> (1/1/2011).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 28(5) cites the Kentucky Uniform Limited Partnership Act, KRS 362.410 to 362.700. These sections were repealed in 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 284, sec. 65. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36549</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>