<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="431" order_by="431">GENERAL PROVISIONS CONCERNING CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS </unit></structure><section_number>431.450</section_number><catch_line>Uniform citation. </catch_line><order_by>450</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department of Kentucky State Police in consultation with the Transportation Cabinet shall design, print, and distribute to all law enforcement agencies in the Commonwealth a uniform citation. </section><section prefix="2">The citation shall: <section prefix="a">Be approved by the Supreme Court; </section><section prefix="b">Consist of an original document and five (5) copies; </section><section prefix="c">Be serially numbered in such a manner that the year of issue and the individual citation number may be readily ascertained; and </section><section prefix="d">Contain such other information as may be required by the Supreme Court. </section></section><section prefix="3">The Circuit Court clerk shall maintain a system of accountability for all citations issued in accordance with rules and regulations issued by the Supreme Court to assure that citations are not wrongfully destroyed, tampered with, or otherwise compromised in any manner. </section><section prefix="4">All peace officers in the Commonwealth shall use the uniform citation for all violations of the traffic laws and for all felonies, misdemeanors, and violations. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 311, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 389, sec. 28, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 26, sec. 2, effective March 3, 1978. -- Created 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 36, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><lrc-note>.  Acts 1986, ch. 389, § 29(1) specifies that use of the uniform citation shall be implemented no later than January 1, 1987; § 31, however, provides that it may be implemented at any time prior to that date. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=18622</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>