<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.6481</section_number><catch_line>Legislative findings. </catch_line><order_by>6481</order_by><text>The General Assembly hereby finds that: <section prefix="1">All citizens of the Commonwealth should have access to affordable health care; and </section><section prefix="2">It is estimated by the Legislative Research Commission that one hundred twenty-five thousand (125,000) children in the Commonwealth have no health insurance coverage; and </section><section prefix="3">Of the estimated one hundred twenty-five thousand (125,000) uninsured children in the Commonwealth, ninety-one thousand two hundred fifty (91,250) fall at or below two hundred percent (200%) of the federal poverty level; and </section><section prefix="4">Uninsured children are of particular concern because of their need for preventative and primary care to develop into healthy adulthood; and </section><section prefix="5">Measures not taken now to provide care for uninsured children will result in higher human and financial costs due to the development of more severe conditions; and </section><section prefix="6">Eligible children in this Commonwealth should have access to cost-effective, primary health care programs if they or their parents are unable to afford it on their own; and </section><section prefix="7">It is in the interest of the citizens of the Commonwealth for the General Assembly to foster the development of a children's health insurance program designed to provide basic services to eligible children at minimum cost. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 253, sec. 1, effective April 2, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> April 2, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7784</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>