<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="506" order_by="506">INCHOATE OFFENSES </unit></structure><section_number>506.010</section_number><catch_line>Criminal attempt. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of criminal attempt to commit a crime when, acting with the kind of culpability otherwise required for commission of the crime, he: <section prefix="a">Intentionally engages in conduct which would constitute the crime if the attendant circumstances were as he believes them to be; or </section><section prefix="b">Intentionally does or omits to do anything which, under the circumstances as he believes them to be, is a substantial step in a course of conduct planned to culminate in his commission of the crime. </section></section><section prefix="2">Conduct shall not be held to constitute a substantial step under subsection (1)(b) unless it is an act or omission which leaves no reasonable doubt as to the defendant's intention to commit the crime which he is charged with attempting. </section><section prefix="3">A person is guilty of criminal attempt to commit a crime when he engages in conduct intended to aid another person to commit that crime, although the crime is not committed or attempted by the other person, provided that his conduct would establish complicity under KRS 502.020 if the crime were committed by the other person. </section><section prefix="4">A criminal attempt is a: <section prefix="a">Class C felony when the crime attempted is a violation of KRS 521.020 or 521.050; </section><section prefix="b">Class B felony when the crime attempted is a Class A felony or capital offense; </section><section prefix="c">Class C felony when the crime attempted is a Class B felony; </section><section prefix="d">Class A misdemeanor when the crime attempted is a Class C or D felony; </section><section prefix="e">Class B misdemeanor when the crime attempted is a misdemeanor. </section></section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 477, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 49, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19701</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>