<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17A-754</section_number><catch_line>Application -- Approval and issuance of certificate -- Information to be filed -- Administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>17A-754</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A business entity seeking to obtain a certificate of registration to act as an insurance purchasing outlet shall complete and file with the commissioner of the Kentucky Department of Insurance an application prescribed by the commissioner. </section><section prefix="2">An application shall not be deemed filed until all information necessary to process the application properly has been received by the commissioner. </section><section prefix="3">Within one hundred eighty (180) days of receipt of an application for a certificate of registration, the commissioner shall make a determination concerning the application and provide notice to the applicant. If approved, a certificate of registration, in a form prescribed by the commissioner, shall be provided to the insurance purchasing outlet. </section><section prefix="4">The business entity seeking a certificate of registration to act as an insurance purchasing outlet shall file the following with the commissioner: <section prefix="a">Organizational information, including partnership agreements, articles of incorporation, bylaws, and other applicable documents; </section><section prefix="b">A business plan, including plan of operations, marketing plan, and financial projections of not less than three (3) years; </section><section prefix="c">Appeal procedures for denied enrollment to a health purchasing outlet; </section><section prefix="d">Enrollment procedures; </section><section prefix="e">Payment procedures; </section><section prefix="f">Evidence of financial responsibility to operate as an insurance purchasing outlet in the form of the following: <section prefix="1">A fidelity bond in an amount not less than ten percent (10%) of projected annual premiums collected; and </section><section prefix="2">A certificate of an insurer authorized to write legal liability insurance in Kentucky certifying that the insurer has and will keep in effect on behalf of the insurance purchasing outlet a policy of insurance covering the legal liability of the insurance purchasing outlet as a result of erroneous acts or failure to act in its capacity as an insurance purchasing outlet. The policy shall provide indemnification for the benefit of any aggrieved party as a result of each single occurrence in the sum of not less than ten thousand dollars ($10,000). The policy shall not be terminated unless at least thirty (30) days prior written notice has been given to the commissioner and to the insurance purchasing outlet; </section></section><section prefix="g">Biographical affidavits of owners, partners, officers, and directors of the applicant; </section><section prefix="h">Identification of any contracted company which manages the insurance purchasing outlet, or any administrator which adjusts or settles claims of the insurance purchasing outlet members; </section><section prefix="i">Names and addresses of the principal places of business of the applicants; </section><section prefix="j">Geographic area to be serviced; </section><section prefix="k">Requirements for membership and participation in the insurance purchasing outlet; </section><section prefix="l">Name and address of each participating insurer, if known; </section><section prefix="m">Proposed health benefit plan to be offered, if known; and </section><section prefix="n">Any other information required by the commissioner to evaluate the applicant's suitability as an insurance purchasing outlet. </section></section><section prefix="5">Any information filed by an insurance purchasing outlet pursuant to subsection (4) of this section that changes shall be refiled with the commissioner for approval. </section><section prefix="6">The commissioner may promulgate administrative regulations to establish standards in accordance with subsection (4) of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1252, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 207, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:05</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29352</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>