<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">C STATE AID TO LOCAL EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>39C.110</section_number><catch_line>Workers' compensation coverage -- Limitations. </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text>Local emergency management agencies, including local directors or their deputies, and other local emergency management agency staff personnel and workers, and local emergency management agency-supervised operating units or personnel officially affiliated with the local disaster and emergency services organizations pursuant to KRS 39B.070, paid or volunteer, for the purposes of receiving workers' compensation benefits paid by the division, shall be covered by those benefits when performing emergency assessment, mitigation, preparedness, response, or recovery functions, with the following limitations: <section prefix="1">The local emergency management agencies, including local directors or staff personnel and workers, and local emergency management agency-supervised operating units or personnel, shall not be covered when performing fundraising functions, unless all proceeds of the function are to be dedicated to the administration or operation of the local emergency management agency or operating unit. </section><section prefix="2">No person shall be covered when performing hazardous materials emergency response operations defined in 29 C.F.R. 1910.120 which are above the first-responder operations level, on-scene incident commander level excluded, except as provided in subsection (3) of this section. </section><section prefix="3">A volunteer hazardous materials response team as defined in 29 C.F.R. 1910.120 which meets all provisions of 29 C.F.R. 1910.120(q), operates on a regional basis, and is supervised by a local emergency management agency may, by action of the director pursuant to administrative regulations, be provided Kentucky emergency management workers' compensation coverage. Such hazardous materials response teams shall take no actions involving environmental clean-up, removal, or transportation of hazardous substances or materials except as may be essential for initial emergency control or initial emergency stabilization when there is a clear and evident risk of harm to people. </section><section prefix="4">No person shall be covered unless enrolled on a workers' compensation enrollment form that is filed with the area manager of the division, except when the magnitude of an emergency, or a preparedness exercise activity, is so great that a local director must solicit additional workers. At these times, the local director may develop and maintain a list of workers, to include names, Social Security account numbers, missions assigned, and dates covered, and submit a copy of the list to the area manager within twenty-four (24) hours of the conclusion of the emergency, or the preparedness exercise activity. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 50, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21761</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>