<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="11" order_by="11">THE GOVERNOR </unit></structure><section_number>11.175</section_number><catch_line>Each cabinet to designate small business ombudsman -- Contact information -- Annual report to Commission on Small Business Advocacy. </catch_line><order_by>175</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each cabinet secretary on the Governor's Executive Cabinet, established pursuant to KRS 11.065, shall designate a small business ombudsman from among their respective existing cabinet employees. </section><section prefix="2">The small business ombudsman shall: <section prefix="a">Respond to inquiries from small businesses on administrative regulations and other regulatory matters; and </section><section prefix="b">Provide information regarding the procedure for submitting comments on administrative regulations as provided by KRS 13A.270(1). </section></section><section prefix="3">Each cabinet shall provide contact information for the cabinet's small business ombudsman on the cabinet's Web site, including the ombudsman's name, telephone number, mailing address, and e-mail address. </section><section prefix="4">No later than December 1 of each year, each small business ombudsman shall submit a report to the Commission on Small Business Advocacy, established pursuant to KRS 11.200, summarizing the number and nature of inquiries that the ombudsman has received from small businesses during the previous twelve (12) months. </section></text><history> Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 166, sec. 4, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=545</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>