<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="90" order_by="90">CITY CIVIL SERVICE </unit></structure><section_number>90.200</section_number><catch_line>Investigations by board -- Power to obtain evidence -- General powers of board -- Reports of director. </catch_line><order_by>200</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board may make investigations on its own initiative, or at the direction of the mayor or legislative body of the city, or upon the petition of an employee in the classified service, or of any person on a list kept by the board, concerning the enforcement or violation of or operation under KRS 90.110 to 90.230. In the course of any investigation under the provisions of KRS 90.110 to 90.230, each member of the board shall have the power to administer oaths, and the board is authorized and empowered to subpoena and require the attendance of witnesses and the production by them of books, papers, records and other documentary evidence pertinent to such investigation. In the event that any person should fail or refuse to appear under such subpoena, or to testify, or to attend, or produce the books, papers, records, or other documentary evidence lawfully required, the board may report to the Circuit Court or any judge thereof, such failure or refusal, and apply for a rule, and the Circuit Court, or any judge thereof, may, on such application of the board, compel obedience by proceedings for contempt as in the case of disobedience of the requirements of a subpoena issued from such court. </section><section prefix="2">The board shall perform such other functions as may relate to the efficiency of the personnel under its jurisdiction, including the maintenance of the personnel classification plan, the administration of service ratings, attendance records, training programs, promotions, transfers, lay-offs, suspensions, reinstatements and related activities, and shall prepare appropriate rules for the administration thereof, but such enumeration is not exclusive of other proper functions or activities of the board. </section><section prefix="3">The board shall receive, review and correct, if necessary, and transmit promptly to the mayor and the legislative body of the city, the annual report of the director. Such report of the director may be supplemented by any additional comment, criticism or suggestions for the more effectual accomplishment of the purposes of KRS 90.110 to 90.230, that the board may care to submit. </section></text><history>Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 4. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:10</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=25433</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>