<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIII" order_by="33">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS AND ESTATES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="386" order_by="386">ADMINISTRATION OF TRUSTS -- LEGAL INVESTMENTS -- UNIFORM PRINCIPAL AND INCOME ACT </unit></structure><section_number>386.370</section_number><catch_line>Definition of business trust, business entity, and name of record. </catch_line><order_by>370</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A business trust is an express trust created by a written declaration of trust whereby property is conveyed to one (1) or more trustees, who hold and manage same for the benefit and profit of such persons as may be or become, the holders of transferable certificates evidencing the beneficial interest in the trust estate. For the purposes of KRS 386.370 to 386.440, business trusts shall include but are not limited to "Real Estate Investment Trusts" as defined by and which comply with the Federal Internal Revenue Code of 1986 as amended or such section or sections of any subsequent Internal Revenue Code as may be applicable to real estate investment trusts. </section><section prefix="2">"Business entity" means a domestic or foreign limited liability company, corporation, partnership, limited partnership, business or statutory trust, and not-for-profit unincorporated association. </section><section prefix="3">"Name of record with the Secretary of State" means any real, fictitious, reserved, registered, or assumed name of a business entity. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 164, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 164, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 19, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 183, provides, "The specific textual provisions of Sections 1 to 178 of this Act which reflect amendments made to those sections by 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137 shall be deemed effective as of June 26, 2007, and those provisions are hereby made expressly retroactive to that date, with the remainder of the text of those sections being unaffected by the provisions of this section." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35887</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>