<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="96" order_by="96">UTILITIES IN CITIES </unit></structure><section_number>96.780</section_number><catch_line>Board to control plant -- Superintendent -- Public filing of rates and regulations -- Employees -- Contracts -- Records. </catch_line><order_by>780</order_by><text><section prefix="1">After a board has been appointed and qualified, it shall have charge of the general supervision and control of the acquisition, improvement, operation and maintenance of the electric plant of the municipality. The board shall employ an electric plant superintendent (herein called "superintendent"), who shall be qualified by training and experience for the general superintendence of the acquisition, improvement and operation of the electric plant. His salary shall be fixed by the board. The superintendent shall be removable by the board for inefficiency, neglect of duty, misfeasance, or malfeasance in office. He shall be required to execute a bond, in a sum to be determined and approved by the board, conditioned upon the faithful performance of his official duties. The cost of the bond may be charged as an expense of the operation of the electric plant. </section><section prefix="2">Within the limits of the funds available therefor, all powers of a municipality to acquire, improve, operate and maintain, and to furnish electric service, and all powers necessary or convenient thereto, conferred by KRS 96.550 to 96.900, shall be exercised on behalf of the municipality by the board and the superintendent, respectively. Subject to the provisions of applicable bonds or contracts, the board shall determine programs and make all plans for the acquisition of the electric plant, shall make all determinations as to improvements, rates and financial practices, may establish such rules and regulations as it deems necessary or appropriate to govern the furnishing of electric service, and may disburse all moneys available in the electric plant fund hereinafter established for the acquisition, improvement, operation and maintenance of the electric plant and the furnishing of electric service. </section><section prefix="3">A copy of the schedule of the current rates and charges in effect from time to time and a copy of all rules and regulations of the board relating to electric service shall be kept on public file at the main and all branch offices of the electric plant and also in the office of the municipal clerk or recorder. The superintendent shall have charge of all actual construction, the immediate management and operation of the electric plant and the enforcement and execution of all rules, regulations, programs, plans and decisions made or adopted by the board. </section><section prefix="4">The superintendent shall appoint all employees and fix their duties and compensation subject to and with the approval of the board. Subject to the limitations and provisions of KRS 96.550 to 96.900, the superintendent, with the approval of the board, may acquire and dispose of all property, real and personal, necessary to effectuate the purposes of KRS 96.550 to 96.900. The title to all property purchased or acquired shall be taken in the corporate name of the board. </section><section prefix="5">The superintendent shall let all contracts, subject to the approval of the board, but may, without such approval, obligate the electric plant on purchase orders up to an amount to be fixed by the board, not to exceed twenty thousand dollars ($20,000). All contracts shall be in the corporate name of the board and shall be signed by the superintendent and attested by the secretary-treasurer or chairman of the board. The superintendent shall make and keep or cause to be made and kept full and proper books and records, subject to the supervision and direction of the board, and the provisions of applicable contracts. </section></text><history> Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 127, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 352, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 20. </history><metadata><effective> June 21, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26284</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>