<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="230" order_by="230">HORSE RACING AND SHOWING </unit></structure><section_number>230.3771</section_number><catch_line>Limitations on and conditions for interstate simulcasting and wagering at Thoroughbred tracks, harness tracks, and simulcast facilities.   </catch_line><order_by>3771</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A Thoroughbred track licensed to conduct Thoroughbred racing may receive interstate simulcasts of Thoroughbred, quarter horse, paint horse, Appaloosa, and Arabian horse races, and conduct interstate wagering thereon, subject to the following limitations: <section prefix="a">A Thoroughbred receiving track may receive interstate simulcasts of Thoroughbred races and conduct interstate wagering thereon at any time of day and during any live Thoroughbred horse race meet conducted in the Commonwealth of Kentucky so long as the Thoroughbred receiving track conducting interstate wagering remits to the Thoroughbred host track conducting a live meet, from the first awarded day of its live meet through the last awarded day of the same live meet, the amounts provided in paragraph (j) of this subsection. </section><section prefix="b">A Thoroughbred host track which receives interstate simulcasts and conducts interstate wagering thereon during the period of time from the first awarded day of its live meet through the last awarded day of its live meet shall offer the simulcasts to all Thoroughbred receiving tracks, all harness tracks not subject to the provisions of KRS 230.377(2), and all simulcast facilities through the intertrack wagering system. </section><section prefix="c">Except as otherwise prohibited by law, a receiving track shall conduct intertrack wagering on all live races of all Thoroughbred host tracks on any day on which it receives an interstate simulcast for the purpose of conducting interstate wagering. </section><section prefix="d">No host track shall require that any receiving track or simulcast facility receive the interstate simulcast. </section><section prefix="e">If more than one (1) Thoroughbred track conducts live racing at the same time on the same day, no track or simulcast facility may receive an interstate simulcast of Thoroughbred races unless all Thoroughbred tracks conducting live racing at the same time of day agree upon all interstate simulcasts to be received and the division of the Thoroughbred host track's commission. If more than one (1) Thoroughbred track conducts live racing at different times on the same day, the Thoroughbred host track with the highest average daily handle, based on the preceding year, shall be the host track for purposes of splitting the commissions earned on interstate wagering at receiving tracks within the Commonwealth. For purposes of this subsection, average daily handle includes live handle, intertrack wagering handle, and simulcast facility handle. Also for purposes of this subsection, the time of day during which a host track conducts live racing commences with its first published post time and concludes ten (10) minutes after the published post time of its last race of the day, regardless of actual post times. </section><section prefix="f">Each Thoroughbred track which desires to conduct interstate wagering pursuant to the provisions of this subsection shall during each year make application to the racing commission for no less than one hundred percent (100%) of the number of racing days awarded to the track in 1994 and one hundred percent (100%) of the number of races scheduled to be run by the track in 1993. </section><section prefix="g">Notwithstanding paragraph (f) of this subsection, any Thoroughbred track may apply for less than one hundred percent (100%) of the number of racing days awarded to the track in 1994 or one hundred percent (100%) of the number of races scheduled to be run by the track in 1993, if written approval is obtained from the Kentucky Horsemen's Benevolent and Protective Association and the Kentucky Thoroughbred Owners and Breeders Association, Inc. </section><section prefix="h">A separate accounting on all interstate simulcasting shall be submitted to the racing commission. The accounting shall be submitted in the same format and at the same time that the report for intertrack wagering is submitted. </section><section prefix="i">If the only simulcast or simulcasts a track participating as a host track makes available for interstate wagering through this state's intertrack wagering system on any race day are Thoroughbred horse races designated as graded stakes races by the Graded Stakes Committee of the Thoroughbred Owners and Breeders Association, Inc., then the commission of the receiving track on these interstate wagers shall be split as prescribed by KRS 230.378(3); otherwise, the commission of the receiving track shall be split as prescribed by paragraph (j) of this subsection. Interstate simulcasts received by a Thoroughbred host track under the conditions set forth in this paragraph shall not be subject to the conditions set forth in paragraphs (b), (c), (e), and (f) of this subsection. </section><section prefix="j">A receiving track's commission on interstate wagering, after deduction of applicable taxes and any amounts required to be paid by contract to the track from which the interstate simulcast originated, shall be split as follows: <section prefix="1">Twenty-five percent (25%) to the receiving track where the interstate wagering occurs; </section><section prefix="2">Twenty-five percent (25%) to the Thoroughbred host track designated by paragraphs (a) and (e) of this subsection. However, if the race does not occur between the first awarded day of a live meet and the last awarded day of the same live meet, an additional twenty-five percent (25%) shall be retained by the receiving track where the interstate wagering occurs; </section><section prefix="3">Twenty-five percent (25%) to the purse program of the receiving track where the interstate wagering occurs; and </section><section prefix="4">Twenty-five percent (25%) to the purse program of the Thoroughbred host track designated by paragraphs (a) and (e) of this subsection. However, if the race does not occur between the first awarded day of a live meet and the last awarded day of the same live meet, then an additional twenty-five percent (25%) shall be paid to the purse program of the receiving track where the interstate wagering occurs. </section></section><section prefix="k">A simulcast facility's commission on interstate wagering on Thoroughbred racing, after deduction of applicable taxes and any amounts required to be paid by contract to the track from which the interstate simulcast originated, shall be split as provided in KRS 230.380(9). </section></section><section prefix="2">A harness track licensed to conduct harness racing may receive interstate simulcasts of harness horse, quarter horse, paint horse, Appaloosa, and Arabian horse races and conduct interstate wagering thereon subject to the following limitations: <section prefix="a">A harness receiving track may receive interstate simulcasts of harness races, quarter horse races, paint horse races, Appaloosa races, and Arabian horse races, and conduct interstate wagering thereon at any time of day and during the course of any live harness horse race meet conducted in the Commonwealth of Kentucky so long as the harness receiving track conducting interstate wagering remits to the harness host track conducting a live meet, from the first awarded day of its live meet through the last awarded day of the same live meet, the amounts provided in paragraph (j) of this subsection. </section><section prefix="b">A harness host track which receives an interstate simulcast and conducts interstate wagering thereon during its live race meet shall offer the simulcasts to all Thoroughbred receiving tracks not subject to the provisions of KRS 230.377(2), all harness tracks, and all simulcast facilities through the intertrack wagering system. </section><section prefix="c">Except as otherwise prohibited by law, a harness receiving track or a simulcast facility shall conduct intertrack wagering on all live races of a harness host track on any day it receives an interstate simulcast from a harness host track. </section><section prefix="d">No host track shall require that any receiving track or simulcast facility receive the interstate simulcast. </section><section prefix="e">If more than one (1) harness track conducts live racing at the same time on the same day, no track or simulcast facility may receive an interstate simulcast on harness races unless all harness tracks conducting live racing at that time of day agree upon the interstate simulcast to be received and the division of the harness host track's commission. If more than one (1) harness track conducts live racing at different times on the same day, the harness host track with the highest average daily handle, based on the preceding year, shall be the host track for purposes of splitting the commissions earned on interstate wagering at receiving tracks within the Commonwealth. For purposes of this subsection, average daily handle includes live handle, intertrack wagering handle, and simulcast facility handle. Also for purposes of this subsection, the time of day during which a host track conducts live racing commences with its first published post time and conclude ten (10) minutes after the published post time of its last race of the day, regardless of actual post times. </section><section prefix="f">Each harness track which desires to conduct interstate wagering pursuant to the provisions of this subsection shall during each year make application to the racing commission for no less than one hundred percent (100%) of the number of racing days awarded to the track in 1994 and one hundred percent (100%) of the number of races scheduled to be run by the track in 1993. </section><section prefix="g">Notwithstanding paragraph (f) of this subsection, any harness track may apply for less than one hundred percent (100%) of the number of racing days awarded to the track in 1994 or one hundred percent (100%) of the number of races scheduled to be run by the track in 1993, if written approval is obtained from the Kentucky Harness Horsemen's Association, or its successor. </section><section prefix="h">A separate accounting on all interstate simulcasting shall be submitted to the racing commission. This accounting shall be submitted in the same format and at the same time that the report for intertrack wagering is submitted. </section><section prefix="i">If the only simulcast or simulcasts a track participating as a harness host track makes available for interstate wagering through this state's intertrack wagering system on any race day are harness horse races (both final and elimination) having a final purse in excess of seventy-five thousand dollars ($75,000), then the commission of the receiving track on these interstate wagers shall be split as prescribed by KRS 230.378(3); otherwise, the commission of the receiving track shall be split as prescribed by paragraph (j) of this subsection. Interstate simulcasts received by a harness host track under the conditions set forth in this paragraph shall not be subject to the conditions set forth in paragraphs (b), (c), (e), and (f) of this subsection. </section><section prefix="j">A receiving track's commission on interstate wagering, after deduction of applicable taxes and any amounts required to be paid by contract to the track from which the interstate simulcast originated, shall be split as follows: <section prefix="1">Twenty-five percent (25%) to the receiving track where the interstate wagering occurs; </section><section prefix="2">Twenty-five percent (25%) to the harness host track designated by paragraphs (a) and (e) of this subsection. However, if no live meet is occurring, an additional twenty-five percent (25%) shall be retained by the receiving track where the interstate wagering occurs; </section><section prefix="3">Twenty-five percent (25%) to the purse program of the receiving track where the interstate wagering occurs; and </section><section prefix="4">Twenty-five percent (25%) to the purse program of the harness host track designated by paragraphs (a) and (e) of this subsection. However, if no live meet is occurring, an additional twenty-five percent (25%) shall be paid to the purse program of the receiving track where the interstate wagering occurs. </section></section><section prefix="k">A simulcast facility's commission on interstate wagering on harness races, after deduction of applicable taxes and any amount required to be paid by contract to the track from which the interstate simulcast originated, shall be split as provided in KRS 230.380(9). </section></section><section prefix="3">A harness track may only receive interstate simulcasts of Thoroughbred horse races and conduct interstate wagering thereon as provided in subsection (1)(b) of this section. A Thoroughbred track may only receive interstate simulcasts of harness horse races and conduct interstate wagering thereon as provided in subsection (2)(b) of this section. A simulcast facility may only receive interstate simulcasts of Thoroughbred and harness horse races and conduct interstate wagering thereon as provided in subsections (1)(b) and (2)(b) of this section. </section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">A Thoroughbred track licensed to conduct horse racing may receive interstate simulcasts of quarter horse, paint horse, Appaloosa, and Arabian horse races and conduct interstate wagering thereon, subject to the limitations stated in paragraph (b) of this subsection. </section><section prefix="b">A receiving track's commission on interstate wagering, after deduction of applicable taxes and any amounts required to be paid by contract to the track from which the interstate simulcast originated, shall be split as follows: <section prefix="1">Twenty-five percent (25%) to the receiving track where the interstate wagering occurs; </section><section prefix="2">Twenty-five percent (25%) to the host track; and </section><section prefix="3">Fifty percent (50%) to the Kentucky quarter horse, paint horse, Appaloosa, and Arabian purse fund established by KRS 230.446 to supplement purses for quarter horse, paint horse, Appaloosa, and Arabian horse races in this state. </section></section></section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">A harness track licensed to conduct horse racing may receive interstate simulcasts of quarter horse, paint horse, Appaloosa, and Arabian horse races and conduct interstate wagering thereon, subject to the limitations stated in paragraphs (b) and (c) of this subsection. </section><section prefix="b">A receiving track's commission on interstate wagering, after deduction of applicable taxes and any amounts required to be paid by contract to the track from which the interstate simulcast originated, shall be split as follows: <section prefix="1">Twenty-five percent (25%) to the purse program of the receiving track; </section><section prefix="2">Twenty-five percent (25%) to the purse program of the host track; </section><section prefix="3">Twenty-five percent (25%) to the receiving track; and </section><section prefix="4">Twenty-five percent (25%) to the host track. </section></section><section prefix="c">When a quarter horse, paint horse, Appaloosa, or Arabian horse race is run at a Kentucky race track, the commission to the Kentucky quarter horse, paint horse, Appaloosa, and Arabian purse fund established by KRS 230.446 shall be twenty-two percent (22%) from the host track's purse share. </section></section><section prefix="6">Other provisions of the Kentucky Revised Statutes notwithstanding, any track in a geographic area that contains more than one (1) track within a fifty (50) mile radius of any other track may only receive interstate simulcasts on racing of the same breed of horse as the track was licensed to race on or before July 15, 1998, except any track may receive interstate simulcasts on quarter horse, paint horse, Appaloosa, or Arabian horse races. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 6, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 21, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 477, effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 57, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 33, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 3, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 245, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 438, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44412</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>