<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">A EMERGENCY MEDICAL SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>311A.030</section_number><catch_line>Administrative regulations relating to ambulance services, first-response providers, and emergency medical services training institutions. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text>The board shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to carry out the functions of this chapter, including but not limited to: <section prefix="1">Licensing, inspecting, and regulating of ambulance services and medical first-response providers. The administrative regulations shall address specific requirements for: <section prefix="a">Air ambulance providers, which provide basic or advanced life support services; </section><section prefix="b">Class I ground ambulance providers, which provide basic life support or advanced life support services to all patients for emergencies or scheduled ambulance transportation which is medically necessary; </section><section prefix="c">Class II ground ambulance providers, which provide only basic life support services but do not provide initial response to the general population with medical emergencies and which are limited to providing scheduled ambulance transportation which is medically necessary; </section><section prefix="d">Class III ground ambulance providers, which provide mobile intensive care services at or above the level of advanced life support to patients with critical illnesses or injuries who must be transported between hospitals in vehicles with specialized equipment as an extension of hospital-level care; and </section><section prefix="e">Medical first-response providers, which provide prehospital or advanced life support services, but do not transport patients; and </section></section><section prefix="2">Emergency medical services training institutions. </section>Nothing in this section shall be construed to change or alter the issuance of certificates of need for emergency medical services providers. </text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30722</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>