<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="216" order_by="216">HEALTH FACILITIES AND SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>216.900</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 216.900 to 216.930. </catch_line><order_by>900</order_by><text>As used in KRS 216.900 to 216.930, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Board" means the Kentucky Board of Family Health Care Providers; </section><section prefix="2">"Linkage" means a formal written agreement initiated by a network, between the network and any agency providing emergency, hospital, home health, hospice, long-term care, mental health, substance abuse, aging, social, and educational services, as well as specialized health care services. </section><section prefix="3">"Midlevel health care practitioner" means a person qualified to provide health care services as enumerated by the board. </section><section prefix="4">"Network" means a health care delivery network system which is an integrated system of health care services, including, but not limited to, the direct delivery of basic health services, such as patient histories and physicals, preventive health care, treatment of acute episodes of illness and chronic illness, immunizations, laboratory, X-ray, dental, and pharmacy services. Networks shall be formally linked to emergency, hospital, home health, hospice, long-term care, mental health, substance abuse, aging, social, and educational services as well as specialized services such as oncology, neurology, and surgery. The primary facility of a network shall be a clinic or physician's office only. </section><section prefix="5">"Medical chart auditor" means a person with at least two (2) years of experience with quality assurance review and with knowledge of the board approved protocols and the individual patient's treatment plan contained in the medical record. </section></text><history>Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 482, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9144</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>