<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="210" order_by="210">STATE AND REGIONAL MENTAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>210.780</section_number><catch_line>Duties of Hart-Supported Living Council.   </catch_line><order_by>780</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Hart-Supported Living Council shall be responsible for making recommendations to the cabinet for: <section prefix="a">A budget and priorities for fund allocations for supported living services for persons with disabilities within the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="b">Standards for quality assurance for persons with a disability who receive supported living services in accordance with KRS 210.770 to 210.795; and </section><section prefix="c">The procedure for annual review and approval of and funding recommendations for individual plans for Hart-Supported Living Program grants submitted by any person with a disability, and for the amendment of individual plans during a fiscal year. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Hart-Supported Living Council shall be responsible for: <section prefix="a">Disseminating information about Hart-Supported Living Program grants available under KRS 210.770 to 210.795; </section><section prefix="b">Hearing grievances and providing due process for consumers and providers of supported living services; </section><section prefix="c">Monitoring the overall effectiveness and quality of the program; and </section><section prefix="d">Developing recommendations for improvements. </section></section><section prefix="3">The Hart-Supported Living Council may recommend necessary administrative regulations under KRS Chapter 13A to carry out the purposes of KRS 210.770 to 210.795. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 3, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 97, effective July 12, 2012; and ch. 158, sec. 43, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 3, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 261, sec. 3, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note>(7/12/2012). This statute was amended by 2012 Ky. Acts chs. 146 and 158. Where these Acts are not in conflict, they have been codified together. Where a conflict exists, Acts ch. 146, which was last enacted by the General Assembly, prevails under KRS 446.250. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44643</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>