<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="258" order_by="258">ANIMAL CONTROL AND PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>258.095</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 258.095 to 258.500. </catch_line><order_by>095</order_by><text>As used in KRS 258.095 to 258.500, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Department" means the Department of Agriculture; </section><section prefix="2">"Commissioner" means the Commissioner of Agriculture; </section><section prefix="3">"Board" means the Animal Control Advisory Board created by KRS 258.117; </section><section prefix="4">"Dog" means any domestic canine, six (6) months of age or older; </section><section prefix="5">"Owner," when applied to the proprietorship of a dog, includes every person having a right of property in the dog and every person who keeps or harbors the dog, or has it in his care, or permits it to remain on or about premises owned or occupied by him; </section><section prefix="6">"Attack" means a dog's attempt to bite or successful bite of a human being. This definition shall not apply to a dog's attack of a person who has illegally entered or is trespassing on the dog owner's property in violation of KRS 511.060, 511.070, 511.080, or 511.090; </section><section prefix="7">"Vicious dog" means any individual dog declared by a court to be a vicious dog; </section><section prefix="8">"Animal control officer" means an individual who is employed or appointed by, or has contracted with: <section prefix="a">A city, county, urban-county, charter county, or consolidated local government to enforce the provisions of this chapter, the provisions of the Kentucky Revised Statutes relating to cruelty, mistreatment, or torture of animals, and local animal control ordinances; or </section><section prefix="b">An entity that has contracted with a city, county, urban-county, charter county, or consolidated local government to enforce the provisions of this chapter, the provisions of the Kentucky Revised Statutes relating to cruelty, mistreatment, or torture of animals, and local animal control ordinances; </section></section><section prefix="9">"Designated license facility" means any person, facility, or business designated by resolution of the governing body of the county to collect license fees under KRS 258.135; </section><section prefix="10">"Cat" means any domestic feline three (3) months of age or older; </section><section prefix="11">"Ferret" means any domestic musteline three (3) months of age or older; </section><section prefix="12">"Euthanasia" means the act of putting an animal to death in a humane manner by methods specified as acceptable for that species by the most recent report of the American Veterinary Medical Association Panel on Euthanasia, subject to the requirements provided by KRS 258.505; </section><section prefix="13">"Animal shelter" means any facility used to house or contain animals, operated or maintained by a governmental body, incorporated humane society, animal welfare society, society for the prevention of cruelty to animals, or other nonprofit organization; </section><section prefix="14">"Quarantine" means the confinement of an animal for observation of clinical signs of illness indicating rabies infection, and the prevention of escape or contact with any person or other animal; </section><section prefix="15">"Livestock" means poultry; ratites; and cervine, bovine, ovine, porcine, caprine, or equine animals that are privately owned and raised in a confined area for breeding stock, food, fiber, or other products; and </section><section prefix="16">"Poultry" means chickens, ducks, turkeys, or other domestic fowl. </section></text><history> Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 189, sec. 11, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 179, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 440, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 12, effective June 17, 1954. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12429</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>