<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="151" order_by="151">GEOLOGY AND WATER RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>151.114</section_number><catch_line>Long range water supply plans. </catch_line><order_by>114</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The cabinet shall administer a program for the purpose of developing long range water supply plans for each county and its municipalities and public water systems or for a region composed of more than one (1) county. The plans to be developed shall include an assessment of the existing public and private water resources, both surface and groundwater, of the study area, an examination of present water use in the area, projections of future water requirements, and a determination of possible alternative approaches that can be taken in order to meet future water supply needs. </section><section prefix="2">The plans may be developed by area development districts in conjunction with the counties and its municipalities and public water systems within each district. A county and its municipalities and public water systems may require that the plan be developed for its jurisdictional area only or, if there is agreement between two (2) or more counties, that the plan be developed jointly with other counties. </section><section prefix="3">The plans shall be subject to approval by the cabinet. The cabinet is authorized to approve any water supply plan developed outside of this program which meets the guidelines set out in KRS 151.110 and 151.114 to 151.118 and the criteria established by cabinet regulations. </section></text><history>Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 410, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2080</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>