<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.891</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 164.890 to 164.895. </catch_line><order_by>891</order_by><text><section prefix="1">"Basic coverage compensation fund" means the fund which may be established by the University of Louisville for the purpose of paying claims or judgments for personal injury or death to patients resulting from any tort or breach of duty based on health care services rendered or which should have been rendered by the university or its agents. This fund shall also include all contributions, annual contributions made to the fund by the university together with such income as may be received from time to time from the investment of the funds in said fund by the secretary. </section><section prefix="2">"Secretary" means the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet. </section><section prefix="3">"Agents" means members of the board of trustees of the university, the board of directors of its hospital, its faculty, hospital staff nurses, nurses aides, volunteer workers, employees and students, including residents and interns, and all other persons involved in furnishing health care within the scope of their duties or courses of study in connection with the University of Louisville. Employed physicians and dentists are agents of the university and within the scope of their duties when rendering professional services in emergencies and other special circumstances so long as such services do not constitute private practice outside the university hospital upon patients not involved in teaching or research and for which the physician or dentist derives income. </section><section prefix="4">"University" means the University of Louisville. </section><section prefix="5">"Excess coverage fund" means the funds that may be made available through appropriations made by the General Assembly to pay judgments hereunder upon exhaustion of the basic coverage compensation fund. </section></text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4475</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>