<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>362.2-961</section_number><catch_line>Liability of general partner after conversion or merger. </catch_line><order_by>2-961</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A conversion or merger under KRS 362.2-951 to 362.2-963 does not discharge any liability under KRS 362.2-404 and 362.2-607 of a person that was a general partner in or dissociated as a general partner from a converting or constituent limited partnership, but: <section prefix="a">The provisions of this subchapter pertaining to the collection or discharge of that liability continue to apply to that liability; </section><section prefix="b">For the purposes of applying those provisions, the converted or surviving organization is deemed to be the converting or constituent limited partnership; and </section><section prefix="c">If a person is required to pay any amount under this subsection, then: <section prefix="1">The person has a right of contribution from each other person that was liable as a general partner under KRS 362.2-404 when the obligation was incurred and has not been released from that obligation under KRS 362.2-607; and </section><section prefix="2">The contribution due from each of those persons is in proportion to the right to receive distributions in the capacity of general partner in effect for each of those persons when the obligation was incurred. </section></section></section><section prefix="2">In addition to any other liability provided by law: <section prefix="a">A person who immediately before a conversion or merger became effective was a general partner in a converting or constituent limited partnership that was not a limited liability limited partnership is personally liable for each obligation of the converted or surviving organization arising from a transaction with a third party after the conversion or merger becomes effective if, at the time the third party enters into the transaction, the third party; <section prefix="1">Does not have notice of the conversion or merger; and </section><section prefix="2">Reasonably believes that: <section prefix="a">The converted or surviving business is the converting or constituent limited partnership; </section><section prefix="b">The converting or constituent limited partnership is not a limited liability limited partnership; and </section><section prefix="c">The person is a general partner in the converting or constituent limited partnership; and </section></section></section><section prefix="b">A person who was dissociated as a general partner from a converting or constituent limited partnership before the conversion or merger became effective is personally liable for each obligation of the converted or surviving organization arising from a transaction with a third party after the conversion or merger becomes effective if: <section prefix="1">Immediately before the conversion or merger became effective, the converting or surviving limited partnership was a not a limited liability limited partnership; and </section><section prefix="2">At the time the third party enters into the transaction, less than two (2) years have passed since the person dissociated as a general partner and the third party: <section prefix="a">Does not have notice of the dissociation; </section><section prefix="b">Does not have notice of the conversion or merger; and </section><section prefix="c">Reasonably believes that the converted or surviving organization is the converting or constituent limited partnership, the converting or constituent limited partnership is not a limited liability limited partnership, and the person is a general partner in the converting or constituent limited partnership. </section></section></section></section></text><history> Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 186, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><former-codification>KRS 362.2-1111. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41528</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>