<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXVIII" order_by="38">WITNESSES, EVIDENCE, NOTARIES, COMMISSIONERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="423" order_by="423">NOTARIES PUBLIC AND COMMISSIONERS OF FOREIGN DEEDS </unit></structure><section_number>423.150</section_number><catch_line>Certificate of acknowledgment. </catch_line><order_by>150</order_by><text>The words "acknowledged before me" mean: <section prefix="1">That the person acknowledging appeared before the person taking the acknowledgment; </section><section prefix="2">That he acknowledged he executed the instrument; </section><section prefix="3">That, in the case of: <section prefix="a">A natural person, he executed the instrument for the purposes therein stated; </section><section prefix="b">A corporation, the officer or agent acknowledged he held the position or title set forth in the instrument and certificate, he signed the instrument on behalf of the corporation by proper authority, and the instrument was the act of the corporation for the purpose therein stated; </section><section prefix="c">A partnership, the partner or agent acknowledged he signed the instrument on behalf of the partnership by proper authority and he executed the instrument as the act of the partnership for the purpose therein stated; </section><section prefix="d">A person acknowledging as principal by an attorney in fact, he executed the instrument by proper authority as the act of the principal for the purposes therein stated; </section><section prefix="e">A person acknowledging as a public officer, trustee, administrator, guardian, or other representative, he signed the instrument by proper authority and he executed the instrument in the capacity and for the purposes therein stated; and </section></section><section prefix="4">That the person taking the acknowledgment either knew or had satisfactory evidence that the person acknowledging was the person named in the instrument or certificate. </section></text><history>Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 131, sec. 5, effective July 1, 1970. </history><metadata><effective>July 1, 1970</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=18236</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>