<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="351" order_by="351">DEPARTMENT FOR NATURAL RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>351.107</section_number><catch_line>Requirements for certification as shotfirer. </catch_line><order_by>107</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person desiring to obtain experience as a shotfirer may not charge or detonate explosives in an underground mine unless he or she is under the direction and within sight and sound of a certified shotfirer. No person shall charge or detonate explosives within an underground mine unless that person has successfully completed a training program and passed a test administered by the department. The test shall include at a minimum a determination of the person's ability to test for mine gases and to safely handle and detonate explosives in an underground coal mine. </section><section prefix="2">The commissioner shall issue a shotfirer's certificate to the person upon successfully passing the test. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 8, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 308, sec. 9, effective April 9, 1996. -- Created 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 8, sec. 7. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><lrc-note> (4/9/96).  The action taken with respect to this statute by 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 308 was to have become effective April 8, 1996, under Section 51 of that Act. The Act, however, did not become effective until April 9, 1996, when the Governor's signed copy of the Act was filed with the Secretary of State. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32910</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>