<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.375</section_number><catch_line>Conditions governing use of title "Doctor" or "Dr." -- Penalty. </catch_line><order_by>375</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall, in connection with the practice of medicine, surgery, osteopathy, optometry, dentistry, podiatry, pharmacy, chiropractic, psychology or psychiatry, nursing, anesthesiology, physio or physical therapy, or any other profession or business having for its purpose the diagnosis, treatment, correction or cure of any human ailment, condition, disease, injury or infirmity, hold himself or herself out as a doctor or employ or use in any manner the title "Doctor" or "Dr.," unless he or she actually has graduated and holds a doctor degree from a school, college, university or institution authorized by its governing body to confer such degree. </section><section prefix="2">No person who holds a doctor degree, as provided in subsection (1) of this section, shall use or employ the title "Doctor" or "Dr." in or upon any letter, statement, card, prescription, sign, listing or other writing held out to the public without affixing suitable words or letters designating the particular doctor degree held by such person. </section><section prefix="3">The written material or designation in connection with advertising, billboards, signs, or professional notices shall be in letters, type, or illumination, or give display and legibility, of at least three-fourths (3/4) that of the title "Doctor" or "Dr." </section><section prefix="4">Any person who violates this section and is found by a trier of fact to have committed the violation with the intent to deceive the public shall have his or her health provider license revoked for not less than six (6) months or more than one (1) year. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 145. -- Created 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 198, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30491</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>