<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.520</section_number><catch_line>Duplicate license. </catch_line><order_by>520</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person whose license has been legitimately lost or destroyed, shall apply to the circuit clerk in the county in which the most recent permanent license was obtained in order to make application for a duplicate license. He shall furnish satisfactory proof by affidavit substantiating the loss or destruction when applying for a duplicate license. </section><section prefix="2">A person whose chauffeur's license has been legitimately lost or destroyed shall apply to the circuit clerk in the county in which the most recent permanent license was obtained in order to make application for a duplicate license. He shall furnish satisfactory proof by affidavit substantiating the loss or destruction when applying for a duplicate license. The fee for a duplicate license shall be according to the schedule set forth in KRS 186.531, and fifty cents ($0.50) shall be submitted to the Transportation Cabinet in compliance with KRS 186.400 through 186.490. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 267, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 173, sec. 1. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 135, sec. 1. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 60, sec. 6, effective March 27, 1958. -- Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 138, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739m-45. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6071</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>