<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="227" order_by="227">FIRE PREVENTION AND PROTECTION -- ELECTRICIANS </unit></structure><section_number>227.332</section_number><catch_line>Notice of hearings. </catch_line><order_by>332</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The state fire marshal shall give written notice of a hearing as required by KRS Chapter 13B. In addition to all parties to the hearing, the state fire marshal shall give this notice to all persons whose pecuniary interests, to the state fire marshal's knowledge or belief, are to be directly and immediately affected by the hearing. </section><section prefix="2">If any hearing is to be held for consideration of administrative regulations of the commissioner, or of other matters which, under subsection (1) of this section, would otherwise require separate notice to more than thirty (30) persons, in lieu of other notice the commissioner may give notice of the hearing by publication pursuant to KRS Chapter 424; but the commissioner shall mail the notice to all persons who had requested the same in writing in advance and have paid to the commissioner the reasonable amount fixed by him or her to cover the cost thereof. </section><section prefix="3">All notices, other than notices provided for in subsection (2) of this section, shall be given as provided in KRS Chapter 13B. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 399, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 142, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 305, sec. 18, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10650</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>