<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="138" order_by="138">EXCISE TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>138.510</section_number><catch_line>Taxes on pari-mutuel wagering on live racing and telephone account, intertrack, and interstate wagering -- Exemptions -- Uses of tax revenue -- Two-day international horse racing event.   </catch_line><order_by>510</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">Except as provided in paragraph (d) of this subsection and subsection (3) of this section, an excise tax is imposed on all tracks conducting pari-mutuel wagering on live racing under the jurisdiction of the commission as follows: <section prefix="1">For each track with a daily average live handle of one million two hundred thousand dollars ($1,200,000) or above, the tax shall be in the amount of three and one-half percent (3.5%) of all money wagered on live races at the track during the fiscal year; and </section><section prefix="2">For each track with a daily average live handle under one million two hundred thousand dollars ($1,200,000), the tax shall be one and one-half percent (1.5%) of all money wagered on live races at the track during the fiscal year. </section></section><section prefix="b">Beginning on April 1, 2014, an excise tax is imposed on all tracks conducting pari-mutuel wagering on historical horse races under the jurisdiction of the commission at a rate of one and one-half percent (1.5%) of all money wagered on historical horse races at the track during the fiscal year. </section><section prefix="c">Money shall be deducted from the tax paid under paragraphs (a) and (b) of this subsection and deposited as follows: <section prefix="1">An amount equal to three-quarters of one percent (0.75%) of all money wagered on live races and historical horse races at the track for Thoroughbred racing shall be deposited in the Thoroughbred development fund established in KRS 230.400; </section><section prefix="2">An amount equal to one percent (1%) of all money wagered on live races and historical horse races at the track for harness racing shall be deposited in the Kentucky standardbred development fund established in KRS 230.770; </section><section prefix="3">An amount equal to one percent (1%) of all money wagered on live races and historical horse races at the track for quarter horse, paint horse, Appaloosa, and Arabian horse racing shall be deposited in the Kentucky quarter horse, paint horse, Appaloosa, and Arabian development fund established by KRS 230.445; </section><section prefix="4">An amount equal to two-tenths of one percent (0.2%) of all money wagered on live races and historical horse races at the track shall be deposited in the equine industry program trust and revolving fund established by KRS 230.550 to support the Equine Industry Program at the University of Louisville, except that the amount deposited from money wagered on historical horse races in any fiscal year shall not exceed six hundred fifty thousand dollars ($650,000); </section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">An amount equal to one-tenth of one percent (0.1%) of all money wagered on live races and historical horse races at the track shall be deposited in a trust and revolving fund to be used for the construction, expansion, or renovation of facilities or the purchase of equipment for equine programs at state universities, except that the amount deposited from money wagered on historical horse races in any fiscal year shall not exceed three hundred twenty thousand dollars ($320,000). </section><section prefix="b">These funds shall not be used for salaries or for operating funds for teaching, research, or administration. Funds allocated under this subparagraph shall not replace other funds for capital purposes or operation of equine programs at state universities. </section><section prefix="c">The Kentucky Council on Postsecondary Education shall serve as the administrative agent and shall establish an advisory committee of interested parties, including all universities with established equine programs, to evaluate proposals and make recommendations for the awarding of funds. </section><section prefix="d">The Kentucky Council on Postsecondary Education may promulgate administrative regulations to establish procedures for administering the program and criteria for evaluating and awarding grants; and </section></section><section prefix="6">An amount equal to one-tenth of one percent (0.1%) of all money wagered on live races and historical horse races shall be distributed to the commission to support equine drug testing as provided in KRS 230.265(3), except that the amount deposited from money wagered on historical horse races in any fiscal year shall not exceed three hundred twenty thousand dollars ($320,000). </section></section><section prefix="d">The excise tax imposed by paragraph (a) of this subsection shall not apply to pari-mutuel wagering on live harness racing at a county fair. </section><section prefix="e">The excise tax imposed by paragraph (a) of this subsection, and the distributions provided for in paragraph (c) of this subsection, shall apply to money wagered on historical horse races beginning September 1, 2011, through March 31, 2014, and historical horse races shall be considered live racing for purposes of determining the daily average live handle. Beginning April 1, 2014, the tax imposed by paragraph (b) of this subsection shall apply to money wagered on historical horse races. </section></section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Except as provided in paragraph (c) of this subsection, an excise tax is imposed on: <section prefix="1">All tracks conducting telephone account wagering; </section><section prefix="2">All tracks participating as receiving tracks in intertrack wagering under the jurisdiction of the commission; and </section><section prefix="3">All tracks participating as receiving tracks displaying simulcasts and conducting interstate wagering thereon. </section></section><section prefix="b">The tax shall be three percent (3%) of all money wagered on races as provided in paragraph (a) of this subsection during the fiscal year. </section><section prefix="c">A noncontiguous track facility approved by the commission on or after January 1, 1999, shall be exempt from the tax imposed under this subsection, if the facility is established and operated by a licensed track which has a total annual handle on live racing of two hundred fifty thousand dollars ($250,000) or less. The amount of money exempted under this paragraph shall be retained by the noncontiguous track facility, KRS 230.3771 and 230.378 notwithstanding. </section><section prefix="d">Money shall be deducted from the tax paid under paragraphs (a) and (b) of this subsection as follows: <section prefix="1">An amount equal to two percent (2%) of the amount wagered shall be deposited as follows: <section prefix="a">In the Thoroughbred development fund established in KRS 230.400 if the host track is conducting a Thoroughbred race meeting or the interstate wagering is conducted on a Thoroughbred race meeting; </section><section prefix="b">In the Kentucky standardbred development fund established in KRS 230.770, if the host track is conducting a harness race meeting or the interstate wagering is conducted on a harness race meeting; or </section><section prefix="c">In the Kentucky quarter horse, paint horse, Appaloosa, and Arabian development fund established by KRS 230.445, if the host track is conducting a quarter horse, paint horse, Appaloosa, or Arabian horse race meeting or the interstate wagering is conducted on a quarter horse, paint horse, Appaloosa, or Arabian horse race meeting; </section></section><section prefix="2">An amount equal to one-twentieth of one percent (0.05%) of the amount wagered shall be allocated to the equine industry program trust and revolving fund established by KRS 230.550 to be used to support the Equine Industry Program at the University of Louisville; </section><section prefix="3">An amount equal to one-tenth of one percent (0.1%) of the amount wagered shall be deposited in a trust and revolving fund to be used for the construction, expansion, or renovation of facilities or the purchase of equipment for equine programs at state universities, as detailed in subsection (1)(c)5. of this section; and </section><section prefix="4">An amount equal to one-tenth of one percent (0.1%) of the amount wagered shall be distributed to the commission to support equine drug testing as provided in KRS 230.265(3). </section></section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">The provisions of this subsection shall apply retroactively to January 1, 2015, and shall expire on December 31, 2017. </section><section prefix="b">If a host track in this state is the location for the conduct of a two (2) day international horse racing event that distributes in excess of a total of twenty million dollars ($20,000,000) in purses and awards: <section prefix="1">The excise tax imposed by subsection (1)(a) of this section shall not apply to money wagered at the track on live races conducted at the track during the two (2) day international horse racing event; and </section><section prefix="2">Amounts wagered at the track on live races conducted at the track during the two (2) day international horse racing event shall not be included in calculating the daily average live handle for purposes of subsection (1) of this section. </section></section></section><section prefix="4">The taxes imposed by this section shall be paid, collected, and administered as provided in KRS 138.530. </section></text><history> Amended 2015 Ky Acts ch. 4, sec. 1, effective March 17, 2015; and ch. 47, sec. 5, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 7, effective April 10, 2014. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 106, effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 57, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 107, effective June 26, 2009. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 6, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 48, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 447, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 43, effective May 30, 1997. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994; ch. 272, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 438, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 7, effective March 30, 1992; and ch. 194, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 159, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 376, sec. 5, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 215, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986; and ch. 296, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 240, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 190, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 343, sec. 2. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 258, sec. 1. -- Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 13, sec. 1, effective February 3, 1956. -- Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 76, sec. 1. -- Created 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 35, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><lrc-note>(6/24/2015). This statute was amended by 2015 Ky. Acts chs. 4 and 47, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together.  (4/10/2014).  2014 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 39 provides that the amendments to this statute made in 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 7, shall apply retroactively beginning September 1, 2011.  (7/14/2000).  In codifying the 2000 Regular Session changes to this statute, an existing reference to "subsection (2)" has been changed to "subsection (3)" under KRS 7.136(1). 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 438, sec. 5, broke down the prior subsection (2) into subsections (2) and (3), and the reference to fiscal year remained in the resulting subsection (3), but the necessary adjustment to the reference in subsection (1) was inadvertently overlooked.  (7/14/92).  This section was amended by two 1992 Acts. Where those Acts are not in conflict, they have been compiled together. Where a conflict exists, the Act which was last enacted by the General Assembly prevails, pursuant to KRS 446.250. </lrc-note><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, L, 7, (1) at 661. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:02</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44411</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>