<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.345</section_number><catch_line>Programs for testing public and private water supplies and for educating public about proper siting and drilling of wells. </catch_line><order_by>345</order_by><text>The Department for Public Health in the Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall establish a program for testing, upon request of the owner or user of the water supply, private water supplies for bacterial and chemical contamination, and for educating the public about proper siting and drilling of wells and treatment of wells and other private water supplies. The program shall consist of the following elements: <section prefix="1">The development of policies, in conjunction with the Energy and Environment Cabinet, for testing private water supplies and using relevant information in a groundwater database; </section><section prefix="2">The development of a data collection system, in conjunction with the Energy and Environment Cabinet, which shall contain the results of water sample tests and information on well location sufficient to locate the wells on an official map; </section><section prefix="3">The development of a private water supply user's manual to be made available to the public; and </section><section prefix="4">The development of a technical assistance program for private water supply users. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 309, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 353, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 296, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 108, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8384</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>