<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="99" order_by="99">URBAN RENEWAL AND REDEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>99.240</section_number><catch_line>Kinds of evidence admissible on question of value of condemned property -- Expedition of proceedings -- Condemnation of property devoted to public use. </catch_line><order_by>240</order_by><text>The following provisions shall apply to any proceedings for the assessment of compensation and damages for real property in a development area taken or to be taken by condemnation for a redevelopment corporation:  <section prefix="1">Evidence of the price and other terms upon any bona fide sale, or the rent received or reserved, and other terms upon any bona fide sale, option, lease or tenancy relating to any of the real property taken or to be taken or to any comparable real property in the vicinity when the option, sale, or lease was given, occurred or the tenancy existed, within a reasonable time of the trial, shall be admissible on direct examination.  </section><section prefix="2">Any time during the pendency of such action or proceeding, the redevelopment corporation, the city or any owner may apply to the court for an order directing any owner, the redevelopment corporation, or the city, as the case may be, to show cause why further proceedings should not be expedited, and the court may upon such application make an order requiring that the hearings proceed and that any other steps be taken with all possible expedition.  </section><section prefix="3">For the purposes of KRS 99.010 to 99.310, the award of compensation shall not be increased by reason of any increase in the value of the real property caused by the assembly, clearance or reconstruction, or proposed assembly, clearance or reconstruction for the purposes of KRS 99.010 to 99.310 of the real property in the development area. No allowance shall be made for the improvements begun on real property after notice to the owner of such property of the institution of the proceedings to condemn such property.  </section><section prefix="4">Evidence shall be admissible bearing upon the insanitary, unsafe or substandard condition of the premises, or the illegal use thereof, or the enhancement of rentals from such illegal use, and such evidence may be considered in fixing the compensation to be paid, notwithstanding that no steps to remedy or abate such conditions have been taken by the department or officer having jurisdiction. If a violation order is on file against the premises in any such department, it shall constitute prima facie evidence of the existence of the condition specified in such order.  </section><section prefix="5">If any of the real property in the development area which is to be acquired by condemnation has, prior to such acquisition, been devoted to another public use, it may nevertheless be acquired, Provided, That no real property belonging to the city or to any other governmental body, or agency or instrumentality thereof, corporate or otherwise, may be acquired without its consent.  </section><section prefix="6">Upon the trial, evidence of the price and other terms upon a sale or assignment or of a contract for the sale or assignment of a mortgage, award, proposed award, transfer of a tax lien or lien of a judgment relating to property taken, shall be relevant, material and competent, upon the issue of value or damage and shall be admissible on direct examination.  </section><section prefix="7">Upon the trial, a statement, affidavit, deposition, report, transcript of testimony in an action or proceeding, or appraisal made or given by any owner or prior owner of the premises taken, or by any person on his behalf, to any court, governmental bureau, department or agency respecting the value of the real property for tax purposes, shall be relevant, material and competent upon the issue of value or damage and shall be admissible on direct examination.  </section></text><history>Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 36, sec. 14. </history><metadata><effective>June 2, 1942</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:07</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26524</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>