<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXII" order_by="22">LEVEES, DRAINAGE, AND RECLAMATION OF LANDS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="268" order_by="268">DRAINAGE AND RECLAMATION ACT OF 1918 </unit></structure><section_number>268.610</section_number><catch_line>Hearing on petition to amend plan -- Duties of clerk after judgment -- Compensation -- Order of appraisal -- Costs. </catch_line><order_by>610</order_by><text>Any owner who will be affected by the proposed changes, amendments and corrections enumerated in the petition provided for in KRS 268.600, may file objections to the granting of the prayer of the petition by the date named in the notice. The fiscal court will hear such petition and all objections filed against it in a summary manner and enter its order. The clerk of the court shall within fifteen (15) days after the entering of the order, transmit a certified copy of the order and a copy of the petition to the secretary of the board, who shall transmit a copy to the county clerk of each county in which any property in the district is located. The clerk shall file and preserve these copies in his office, for which he shall receive a fee of one dollar ($1). If the order of the court provides that the plan for reclamation be changed or the boundary lines of the district extended, the board shall direct the appraisers to appraise the property to be taken, assess benefits and damages and estimate the cost of the improvements as in KRS 268.260 and 268.270. The appraisers' report shall be treated in the same manner as is now provided for in the original formation of districts. If the petition is dismissed the party filing it shall pay the costs, but if it is sustained in whole or in part the objectors shall pay the costs. </text><history>Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 419, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 255, effective January 2, 1978. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2380b-47. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12985</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>