<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="162" order_by="162">SCHOOL PROPERTY AND BUILDINGS </unit></structure><section_number>162.360</section_number><catch_line>Revenues from building -- Determination and use. </catch_line><order_by>360</order_by><text>The governing body of a state educational institution erecting a building or buildings and appurtenances under the provisions of KRS 162.340 shall, by resolution, provide that the bonds shall be payable, solely from the revenues of such building or buildings, provided, said governing body may in its discretion, by said resolution, also provide that the bonds shall be payable from the revenues of any other building or buildings theretofore or as may be thereafter erected and used, in connection with the institution for educational purposes provided, further, any such provision for the payment of the bonds from the revenues of such other building or buildings theretofore erected shall be subject to and in all respects in full conformity and compliance with the rights of the holders of any bonds or obligations payable from the revenues of such other building or buildings theretofore issued by the governing body then outstanding. The resolution shall fix the initial minimum rents, tolls, fees, and other charges to be imposed in connection with the services furnished by the building or buildings to be erected and may also provide that the governing body of the institution shall monthly as the service accrues pay from the current funds of the institution or from student fees, or both, into the special fund provided by KRS 162.230, as that section is made applicable by KRS 162.350, a minimum amount representing the reasonable cost and value of any service rendered to the educational institution by such building or buildings in furnishing any educational facilities in the operation of the educational institution. The resolution shall fix the extent of the pledge of revenues from such other building or buildings toward the payment of the bonds and interest thereon and may specify the terms and conditions upon which additional bonds may be thereafter issued and sold ranking on a parity with and payable from the same source as the bonds authorized by such resolution, and such additional parity bonds may thereafter be so issued and sold to pay all or any part of the cost of building or buildings and appurtenances. The resolution shall definitely fix the minimum amount of revenues necessary to be set apart on or before stated intervals and applied to the payment of the principal and interest on the bonds and the balance of the income and revenues shall be set aside as a proper operation and maintenance fund, including a sufficient sum to pay the cost of insuring the building or buildings against loss or damage by fire and windstorm or other calamity as may have been stipulated in the resolution or resolutions authorizing the bonds. The charges for the services from the building or buildings, together with the available revenues of any other building or buildings pledged to the payment of said bonds and interest thereon, shall be sufficient at all times to provide for the payment of such interest and to create a sinking fund to accomplish retirement of such bonds at or before maturity, and to pay the current operation and maintenance expenses of the building or buildings to the extent such expenses are not otherwise provided. The charges shall be revised from time to time so as to produce these amounts. </text><history>Repealed and reenacted 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 577, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 147, sec. 2. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4535m-8. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4063</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>