<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="212" order_by="212">LOCAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>212.360</section_number><catch_line>Transfer of property of former health agencies to city-county or consolidated local government board -- Extension of control of board to other divisions and institutions. </catch_line><order_by>360</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All property, real, personal, and mixed, belonging to such county or city and now being used exclusively and directly by and for the county board of health of such county and the department of public health of such city, in the performance of duties connected with the maintenance of the public health, including but without being limited thereto city or county hospitals, public health clinics, all the equipment in such institutions, and all other property of every character or description now used in public health work in and by said city and county organizations, and all property, real, personal, and mixed, belonging to any board of tuberculosis hospital in such county, is hereby transferred to said board created under KRS 212.350, and said city, county, and board of tuberculosis hospital shall take all necessary and proper steps to effect the legal transfer of title and possession of all such property to said board. All deeds to such property shall be recorded in the county where the property is located. Said board shall assume all existing liabilities of said board of tuberculosis hospital and shall liquidate such liabilities in the same manner and on the same terms as would have been done by said board of tuberculosis hospital. </section><section prefix="2">In the event that it is deemed desirable or advisable by the city, county, and board that any other division of the city or county or any other governmental agency, including any institution, should be taken over and placed under the control and management and supervision of the board, then and in that event, such division, agency, or institution may be taken over under such terms and conditions as to its management, operation, and maintenance as the said city, by ordinance, the said county and the board, by respective resolutions and agreements, may authorize and direct. </section><section prefix="3">Upon the establishment of a consolidated local government in a county having a board of health previously formed by the city and county, all property, real, personal, and mixed, belonging to the board of health shall remain the property of the board of health as renamed under KRS 212.350. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 204, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 41, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8610</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>