<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.20-283</section_number><catch_line>Prohibition against certain qualified investments and financial interests -- Investment fund manager's limitations on holding management positions in small businesses in which investment fund has invested. </catch_line><order_by>20-283</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No qualified investments shall be made in a small business that is the "alter ego" of the investment fund or the investment fund manager. For purposes of this subsection, a business is an "alter ego" of an investment fund or an investment fund manager if any of the following criteria are satisfied: <section prefix="a">Prior to an investment fund making a qualified investment in the small business, the small business is owned in whole or in an amount greater than twenty percent (20%) of the small business by an investor, officer, director, partner, member, manager, trustee or employee of the investment fund or the investment fund manager; or </section><section prefix="b">The small business employs on a full-time or part-time basis an investor. </section></section><section prefix="2">An investment fund manager may occupy any management position in any small business in which that investment fund has made a qualified investment for the purpose of: <section prefix="a">Filling a management position in an effort to remedy problems arising from a lack of profitability of the small business, or from dishonesty of the persons otherwise managing the small business; or </section><section prefix="b">Serving in a management position in the small business in order to add value to the investment fund and the business by his or her experience, skills, or relationships to help a business succeed. </section></section><section prefix="3">No officer, member, or employee of the authority shall have a direct or indirect financial interest in any investment fund or investment fund manager. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 230, sec. 28, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 414, sec. 14, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2716</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>