<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="279" order_by="279">RURAL ELECTRIC AND RURAL TELEPHONE COOPERATIVE CORPORATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>279.340</section_number><catch_line>Name.   </catch_line><order_by>340</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The name of a cooperative shall satisfy the requirements of KRS 14A.3-010 unless, in an affidavit made by its president or vice president, and filed with the Secretary of State, or in an affidavit made by a person signing articles of incorporation, consolidation, merger or conversion, which relate to such cooperative, and filed, together with any such articles, with the Secretary of State, it shall appear that the cooperative desires to do business in another state and is or would be precluded therefrom by reason of the inclusion of such words or either thereof in its name. </section><section prefix="2">This section shall not apply to any corporation which becomes subject to KRS 279.310 to 279.600 by complying with the provisions of KRS 279.470, which does business in this state pursuant to KRS 279.570 and which elects to retain a corporate name which does not comply with this section. </section></text><history> Repealed and reenacted 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 135, effective July 15, 2010; and repealed, reenacted, and amended ch. 151, sec. 85, effective January 1, 2011. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 135, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 136, sec. 2, effective June 16, 1972. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 1. -- Created 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 147, sec. 4, effective March 25, 1950. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2011 </effective><lrc-note> (1/1/2011).  This section was repealed, reenacted, and amended by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 151, and repealed and reenacted by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51. Pursuant to Section 184 of Acts ch. 51, it was the intent of the General Assembly that the repeal and reenactment not serve to void the amendment, and these Acts do not appear to be in conflict, therefore, they have been codified together.  (7/15/2010).  2010 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 183, provides, "The specific textual provisions of Sections 1 to 178 of this Act which reflect amendments made to those sections by 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137 shall be deemed effective as of June 26, 2007, and those provisions are hereby made expressly retroactive to that date, with the remainder of the text of those sections being unaffected by the provisions of this section." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36736</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>