<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="230" order_by="230">HORSE RACING AND SHOWING </unit></structure><section_number>230.375</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Race Track Retirement Plan. </catch_line><order_by>375</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board of directors of the Kentucky Racing Health and Welfare Fund, Inc., may create and fund the Kentucky Race Track Retirement Plan. The board shall use no more than twenty-five percent (25%) of the annual sum paid by the racing commission under KRS 230.361 to 230.373 to fund the plan. </section><section prefix="2">The plan shall be provided for the benefit of Thoroughbred trainers, assistant trainers, exercise riders, grooms, stable attendants, and other stable employees who can demonstrate that they are not otherwise eligible to participate in any other private or public, nonself-funded retirement or pension plan. </section><section prefix="3">The Kentucky Race Track Retirement Plan shall be administered by the board of directors of the Kentucky Racing Health and Welfare Fund, Inc., for the charitable and benevolent purposes set forth in KRS 230.374, and no part of the sums administered by the fund for the plan or any net earnings of the plan shall inure to the benefit of any private individual, director, officer, or member of the fund, or any of the persons who paid sums to the racing commission under the provisions of KRS 230.361 to 230.373. </section><section prefix="4">The board of directors of the Kentucky Racing Health and Welfare Fund, Inc., shall be the trustee of the plan's funds and shall have full power to invest and reinvest funds. Investments shall be diversified to balance the risks associated with various investment options to maintain the long-term solvency of the plan. The board shall have full power to hold, purchase, sell, assign, transfer, or dispose of any of the investments in which any of the plan's funds have been invested, as well as of the proceeds of investments belonging to the plan. The board members or any investment manager shall discharge their duties with respect to the assets of the plan solely in the interest of the plan's members and: <section prefix="a">For the exclusive purposes of providing benefits to plan members and their beneficiaries and defraying reasonable expenses of administering the plan; </section><section prefix="b">With the care, skill, prudence, and diligence under the circumstances that a prudent person acting in a like capacity and familiar with these matters would use in the conduct of an enterprise of a like character and with like aims; and </section><section prefix="c">In accordance with any other laws or instruments governing the administration of the plan's funds. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 474, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 30, effective July 13, 2004. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 447, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10868</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>