<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.17C-090</section_number><catch_line>Payment of claims of dental-only benefits -- Reports -- Interest</catch_line><order_by>17C-090</order_by><text>.The provisions of KRS 304.17A-700 to 304.17A-730, relating to payment of claims, shall apply to limited health service benefit plans for the provision of dental-only benefits, except as follows: <section prefix="1">A limited health service plan for the provision of dental-only benefits, its agent, or designee shall have three (3) business days in which to respond to an original or corrected claim submitted electronically under KRS 304.17A-704(1)(a) or, within three (3) business days, the limited health service benefit plan for the provision of dental-only benefits, its agent, or designee may list the claim and the date it was received on a file that can be accessed electronically by the provider, its agent, or designee. </section><section prefix="2">Limited health service benefit plans for the provision of dental-only benefits shall be required to submit the reports required by KRS 304.17A-722 on an annual basis. </section><section prefix="3">Limited health service benefit plans for the provision of dental-only benefits shall be required to pay interest required under KRS 304.17A-730 for a claim only if the interest calculated on that claim is equal to or greater than five dollars ($5). </section></text><history> Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 169, sec. 1, effective January 1, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:11</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29412</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>