<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.005</section_number><catch_line>Governor's Postsecondary Education Nominating Committee -- Membership -- Terms -- Duties. </catch_line><order_by>005</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is established the Governor's Postsecondary Education Nominating Committee which shall consist of seven (7) members representing each of the Supreme Court districts who shall be appointed by the Governor with the consent of the House of Representatives and the Senate. If the General Assembly is not in session at the time of appointment, the consent of the General Assembly shall be obtained during the time the General Assembly next convenes. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">In order to be eligible to serve on the Governor's Postsecondary Education Nominating Committee, a member at the time of appointment shall have no conflict of interest pursuant to KRS 45A.340. In addition, no member shall have a relative employed by a public postsecondary institution, the Council on Postsecondary Education, the Kentucky Higher Education Assistance Authority, the Kentucky Higher Education Student Loan Corporation, or the Kentucky Authority for Educational Television during his or her tenure on the committee. No more than two (2) persons holding an undergraduate degree from the same institution of higher education shall be members of the committee. </section><section prefix="b">The Governor shall make the appointments so as to reflect, inasmuch as possible, equal representation of the two (2) sexes and no less than proportional representation of the two (2) leading political parties of the Commonwealth based on the state's voter registration and to assure that appointments reflect the minority racial composition of the Commonwealth. In filling vacancies to the committee, the Governor shall act so as to provide, inasmuch as possible, equal representation of the two (2) sexes by appointing a member of the sex that is the lesser represented at the time of the appointment. If the remaining membership already has an equal number of males and females, the Governor may appoint a member of either sex. </section><section prefix="c">In selecting the members of the committee, the Governor shall solicit recommendations from each of the following: <section prefix="1">Advisory Conference of Presidents; </section><section prefix="2">Council on Postsecondary Education Student Advisory Committee; </section><section prefix="3">Associations representing faculty from universities, technical institutions, and community colleges; </section><section prefix="4">Associations representing university, technical institutions, and community college alumni; </section><section prefix="5">Postsecondary education advocacy groups; </section><section prefix="6">The Kentucky Board of Education; </section><section prefix="7">Associations representing business and civic interests; and </section><section prefix="8">Associations representing independent, nonprofit colleges and universities. </section></section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">Members of the committee representing Supreme Court districts shall serve six (6) year terms and until a successor is appointed, except the initial appointments shall be as follows: <section prefix="1">Two (2) members shall serve a two (2) year term; </section><section prefix="2">Two (2) members shall serve a four (4) year term; and </section><section prefix="3">Three (3) members shall serve a six (6) year term. </section></section><section prefix="b">The terms of the original appointees shall expire on April 14 in the year designated for the term, and the terms of each member appointed thereafter shall begin on April 15. Appointments shall be submitted to the Senate and to the House of Representatives for confirmation by February 1 in each year that a regular session of the General Assembly convenes. Each appointment shall be consented to by both chambers in order for the person to be confirmed. At the first regular meeting of the committee each fiscal year, a chairperson shall be selected by the membership. </section></section><section prefix="4">The members of the committee may be reimbursed for actual and necessary expenditures incurred in the performance of their duties. The expenses of the committee shall be paid out of the appropriation for the Governor's office. </section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">The committee shall be responsible for submitting three (3) nominations from which the Governor shall select each gubernatorial appointment to a university or Kentucky Community and Technical College System governing board made pursuant to KRS 164.131, 164.321, and 164.821 and to the Council on Postsecondary Education pursuant to KRS 164.011. The committee shall not make recommendations for alumni, faculty, and staff appointments made pursuant to KRS 164.131 and 164.821 and the student appointments made pursuant to KRS 164.131, 164.321, and 164.821. If more than one (1) equivalent gubernatorial appointment is being made to a governing board or the Council on Postsecondary Education at the same time, the committee shall submit a number of nominees equal to three (3) times the number of vacancies. The committee shall provide to the Governor, inasmuch as possible, an equal number of male and female nominees. If the Governor needs nominees of a particular sex in order to make an appointment, the committee shall only provide nominees of that sex. The Governor shall select the appointees from among the nominees. </section><section prefix="b">The committee shall be responsible for submitting three (3) nominations from which the Governor shall select each gubernatorial appointment to the Kentucky Authority for Educational Television made pursuant to KRS 168.040, the Kentucky Higher Education Assistance Authority pursuant to KRS 164.746, and the Kentucky Higher Education Student Loan Corporation pursuant to KRS 164A.050. If more than one (1) appointment is being made at the same time, the committee shall submit a number of nominees equal to three (3) times the number of vacancies. The Governor shall select the appointees from among the nominees. </section><section prefix="c">Nominations shall be made thirty (30) days prior to the expiration of a term or as soon as practicable following an unforeseen vacancy. The Governor shall make the appointment within sixty (60) days following receipt of the nominations. If the Governor does not make the appointment within sixty (60) days, the committee shall select one (1) of the nominees to serve. </section></section><section prefix="6">In making its nominations, the committee shall consider the needs of the respective institutions, locate potential appointees, review candidates' qualifications and references, conduct interviews, and carry out other search and screening activities as necessary. </section><section prefix="7">The Governor's office staff shall provide support services for the committee. </section></text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 56, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 71, effective May 30, 1997. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 91, sec. 1, effective March 22, 1994; and ch. 447, sec. 3, effective April 11, 1994. – Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 3, effective February 20, 1992, effective February 20, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4160</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>