<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="367" order_by="367">CONSUMER PROTECTION </unit></structure><section_number>367.660</section_number><catch_line>Exempt solicitations. </catch_line><order_by>660</order_by><text>The following solicitations are exempt from the provisions of KRS 367.650 to 367.670: <section prefix="1">Solicitations by an organization of contributions from its members and their families only, if membership is not included in a solicitation to avoid the provisions of KRS 367.650 to 367.670, is not granted upon the basis of contributions alone, and is within the exception of KRS 367.650(3). </section><section prefix="2">Solicitations by a religious organization for funds for religious purposes such as maintenance of a house of worship, conduct of services, and propagation of its faith and tenets as distinguished from other charitable and civic purposes employed by nonreligious organizations. </section><section prefix="3">Solicitations by a publicly-owned or nonprofit privately-endowed educational institution regulated by the Kentucky Board of Education, the Council on Postsecondary Education, or an equivalent public authority of the jurisdiction where the institution is located, from the alumni, faculty members, student body of the institution and their families, and from corporations, for the continuance of an established educational program. </section><section prefix="4">Local solicitations by a student group or parent-teacher association for its campus or group connected activities with the approval of the administration of the educational institution. </section></text><history> Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 148, effective May 30, 1997. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> May 30, 1997 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=35032</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>