<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.46-018</section_number><catch_line>Fee for modification of permit to construct or operate hazardous waste treatment, storage, or disposal facility. </catch_line><order_by>46-018</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An applicant seeking to modify a permit to construct or operate a hazardous waste treatment, storage, or disposal facility shall be subject to a fee by the cabinet of three hundred dollars ($300) if the cabinet determines that the modification is minor. </section><section prefix="2">An applicant seeking to modify a hazardous waste treatment, storage, or disposal facility permit to add one (1) or more waste streams, and a waste stream with the same characteristic is already permitted, shall be subject to a review fee of three hundred dollars ($300) per waste stream proposed to be added. All other applicants to add one (1) or more waste streams shall be subject by the cabinet to a review fee equal to: <section prefix="a">Tank: three thousand four hundred dollars ($3,400); </section><section prefix="b">Surface impoundment: five thousand dollars ($5,000); </section><section prefix="c">Waste pile: four thousand five hundred dollars ($4,500); </section><section prefix="d">Incinerator: six thousand five hundred dollars ($6,500); </section><section prefix="e">Container: two thousand seven hundred dollars ($2,700); </section><section prefix="f">Land treatment: five thousand five hundred dollars ($5,500); and </section><section prefix="g">Landfill: five thousand five hundred dollars ($5,500). </section></section><section prefix="3">An applicant seeking to modify a permit to construct or operate a hazardous waste treatment, storage, or disposal facility shall be subject to a fee by the cabinet in the following amounts, for the addition or substantial modification of a treatment, storage, or disposal unit: <section prefix="a">A tank with a total capacity of seven thousand five hundred (7,500) or more gallons: seven thousand four hundred dollars ($7,400); </section><section prefix="b">A tank with a total capacity less than seven thousand five hundred (7,500) gallons: three thousand seven hundred dollars ($3,700); </section><section prefix="c">A container with a total capacity of five thousand (5,000) or more gallons: six thousand dollars ($6,000); </section><section prefix="d">A container with a total capacity less than five thousand (5,000) gallons: three thousand dollars ($3,000); </section><section prefix="e">Incinerator: nineteen thousand four hundred dollars ($19,400); </section><section prefix="f">Landfill: fifteen thousand dollars ($15,000); </section><section prefix="g">Land treatment: fifteen thousand eight hundred dollars ($15,800); </section><section prefix="h">Waste pile: twelve thousand two hundred dollars ($12,200); and </section><section prefix="i">Surface impoundment: fourteen thousand dollars ($14,000). </section></section><section prefix="4">The incinerator fee provided in subsections (2) and (3) of this section shall apply once for each different type of incinerator unit at the facility. The types of incinerator units shall include: liquid injection, rotary kiln, fluidized bed, and multiple hearth. The tank fee provided in subsections (2) and (3) of this section shall apply once for each different tank design. Tank design criteria shall include: differences in materials of construction, pressure vessels, nonpressure vessels, shape, and ancillary equipment. The container fee provided in subsections (2) and (3) of this section shall apply once for each different container type. Container types shall include: drums, tote bins, bottles, and roll-off boxes. </section><section prefix="5">An applicant seeking to modify a facility investigation or corrective action plan for a solid waste management unit at a hazardous waste treatment, storage, or disposal facility shall be subject to a fee by the cabinet, which shall be equal to the cost of review but shall not exceed the following amounts for the specified instance: <section prefix="a">Facility investigation: fourteen thousand five hundred dollars ($14,500); and </section><section prefix="b">Corrective action: twenty-nine thousand dollars ($29,000). </section></section><section prefix="6">An applicant seeking to modify a detection, compliance or corrective action program at a regulated unit of a hazardous waste treatment, storage, or disposal facility shall be subject to a fee by the cabinet, which shall not exceed the following amounts for each specified instance: <section prefix="a">Change from detection to compliance monitoring: six thousand dollars ($6,000); </section><section prefix="b">Change from compliance to corrective action: eight thousand dollars ($8,000); and </section><section prefix="c">Modification of detection, compliance, or corrective action program: five thousand dollars ($5,000). </section></section></text><history>Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 471, sec. 5, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><former-codification> KRS 224.1165. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10437</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>