<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>272A.16-040</section_number><catch_line>Merger.   </catch_line><order_by>16-040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">One (1) or more limited cooperative associations may merge with one (1) or more other limited cooperative associations, and one (1) or more business corporations or limited liability companies may merge with and into a limited cooperative association pursuant to this subchapter and a plan of merger if: <section prefix="a">The governing statute of each of the other entities authorizes the merger; </section><section prefix="b">The merger is not prohibited by the law of a jurisdiction that enacted any of those governing statutes; and </section><section prefix="c">Each of the other entities complies with its governing statute in effecting the merger. </section></section><section prefix="2">A plan of merger shall be in a record and shall include: <section prefix="a">The name and form of each constituent entity; </section><section prefix="b">The name of the surviving entity, which shall be a limited cooperative association, and, if the surviving entity is to be created by the merger, a statement to that effect; </section><section prefix="c">The terms and conditions of the merger, including the manner and basis for converting the interests in each constituent entity into any combination of money, interests in the surviving entity, and other consideration; </section><section prefix="d">If the surviving entity is to be created by the merger, the surviving entity’s organic rules; </section><section prefix="e">If the surviving entity is not to be created by the merger, any amendments to be made by the merger to the surviving entity’s organic rules; and </section><section prefix="f">If a member of a constituent limited cooperative association will have personal liability with respect to a surviving entity, the identity of the member by descriptive class or other reasonable manner. </section></section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 160, sec. 113, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:18</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41089</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>