<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="149" order_by="149">FORESTRY </unit></structure><section_number>149.280</section_number><catch_line>Forestry management under cooperative agreements -- Payment of cost of services -- Use of proceeds. </catch_line><order_by>280</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The secretary for energy and environment, or his authorized agent, may, upon request, and whenever he deems it essential to the best interests of the people of the Commonwealth, cooperate with counties, cities, corporations, institutions or individuals in preparing plans for the protection, management and replacement of trees, woodlands and timber tracts, under an agreement that the parties obtaining such assistance pay at least the field expenses of the men employed in preparing said plans. Services rendered under this cooperative plan may include the designation of trees for sale or removal, measuring or estimating the commercial volume contained in the trees designated, marketing advice, and general forestry advice concerning the management of the landowner's forest. </section><section prefix="2">When services are rendered under this section, the landowner or his agent, upon presentation of a statement, shall pay to the Energy and Environment Cabinet, within thirty (30) days of receipt of the statement, the amount due. The amounts so collected by the Energy and Environment Cabinet shall be paid into the State Treasury and shall be credited to a special fund for forest management and marketing, and, with such other funds as may be appropriated by the General Assembly, or contributed by the United States or any governmental or private agency for such purposes, shall be used and disbursed by the Energy and Environment Cabinet for such purpose. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 156, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. III, sec. 13(3). -- Created 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 204, secs. 1 and 2. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1870</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>