<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.2-015</section_number><catch_line>Political subdivisions prohibited from enacting or enforcing legislation governing matters preempted by state or federal law -- Exception for civil rights -- State law to be construed as consistent with federal law. </catch_line><order_by>2-015</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All political subdivisions of the Commonwealth shall be prohibited from enacting and from enforcing ordinances, resolutions, and regulations pertaining to the financial or lending activities of persons or entities which: <section prefix="a">Are subject to the jurisdiction of the department or the provisions of this chapter; </section><section prefix="b">Are subject to the jurisdiction or regulatory supervision of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, the Office of Thrift Supervision, the National Credit Union Administration, the Farm Credit Administration, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, or the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development; or </section><section prefix="c">Originate, purchase, sell, assign, securitize, assist, facilitate, or service property interests or obligations created by financial transactions or loans made, executed, or originated by persons or entities referred to in paragraph (a) or (b) of this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="2">The requirements of this section shall apply to all ordinances, resolutions, or regulations pertaining to lending activities, including any ordinances, resolutions, or regulations which limit or disqualify persons or entities from doing business with a political subdivision based upon financial or lending activities or the imposition of additional reporting requirements or other obligations on such persons or entities seeking to do business with a political subdivision. </section><section prefix="3">Any provision of this chapter preempted by federal law with respect to a national bank or federal savings association shall not apply to the same extent to an operating subsidiary of a national bank or federal savings association. </section><section prefix="4">The provisions of this chapter shall be interpreted and applied to the fullest extent practicable in a manner consistent with applicable federal laws and regulations and with applicable policies and orders of federal regulatory agencies and shall not be deemed to constitute an attempt to override federal law. </section><section prefix="5">Nothing in this section shall be interpreted as preventing the enforcement of ordinances, regulations, or resolutions of political subdivisions of the Commonwealth pertaining to civil rights. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 614, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 64, sec. 11, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 287.015. </former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  In accordance with 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, secs. 38 and 39, this statute has been renumbered as a section of the Kentucky Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14512</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>