<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">A AUTOMATED MOTOR VEHICLE REGISTRATION SYSTEM </unit></structure><section_number>186A.072</section_number><catch_line>Titling of custom-built motorcycles. </catch_line><order_by>072</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in KRS 186A.115 and this section, "custom-built motorcycle" means a motorcycle as defined in KRS 186.010(15) that has been built from one hundred percent (100%) new parts to the individual specifications of: <section prefix="a">The individual who built the motorcycle who will personally use the motorcycle; </section><section prefix="b">A specific known prospective owner of the motorcycle who is purchasing the motorcycle at retail; or </section><section prefix="c">A person engaged in the business of building and selling motorcycles who is building the motorcycle for purposes of retail sale to an unknown buyer. </section></section><section prefix="2">A person who has either personally custom-built a motorcycle or who has purchased a custom-built motorcycle shall be issued a first certificate of title after complying with the provisions of this subsection. The person shall, prior to applying for the certificate of title, apply to the Transportation Cabinet for a vehicle identification number under the provisions of KRS 186A.090. When applying for a first certificate of title for a custom-built motorcycle, the person shall apply in the office of the county clerk of the county in which he or she resides and provide the clerk with the following: <section prefix="a">Written documentation authenticating that one hundred percent (100%) of the parts used to assemble the custom-built motorcycle are new parts purchased from either a wholesale or retail supplier that have never been used; </section><section prefix="b">Proof of insurance to comply with the provisions of KRS 304.39-080; and </section><section prefix="c">Other information that may be required by the Transportation Cabinet in an administrative regulation promulgated under KRS Chapter 13A. If the cabinet fails to promulgate an administrative regulation governing custom-built motorcycles, the only documentation a person applying for a first certificate of title for a custom-built motorcycle shall be required to present to the county clerk is the information required under paragraphs (a) and (b) of this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="3">The Transportation Cabinet shall not classify a custom-built motorcycle as a salvage or rebuilt vehicle and shall not subject a custom-built motorcycle to the provisions of this chapter governing salvage or rebuilt vehicles. </section></text><history> Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 97, sec. 2, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6145</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>