<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXII" order_by="22">LEVEES, DRAINAGE, AND RECLAMATION OF LANDS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="266" order_by="266">LEVEES </unit></structure><section_number>266.120</section_number><catch_line>Duties of board -- Power to enforce aid. </catch_line><order_by>120</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board of levee commissioners shall superintend the construction, care and protection of the levee, and see that convenient crossings of the levee are made at the intersection of all public roads and at such private crossings as the commissioners may establish. </section><section prefix="2">At any time the commissioners deem the levee in danger of being damaged, after being built, by wind or high water, they shall, after giving six (6) hours' notice to all persons between the ages of eighteen (18) and fifty (50) residing within the territory protected by the levee, require them to assemble at a point designated by the commissioners, and aid in the repair and protection of the levee, for which they shall be paid by the commissioners at the rate of one dollar and fifty cents ($1.50) per day. </section><section prefix="3">No person liable to work under this section shall fail to do so after being notified. </section><section prefix="4">All boards shall comply with the provisions of KRS 65A.010 to 65A.090. </section></text><history>Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 75, effective March 21, 2013. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 386, sec. 52. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2417c-8, 2417c-9. </history><metadata><effective>March 21, 2013</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41755</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>