<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="173" order_by="173">CITY, COUNTY, AND REGIONAL LIBRARIES </unit></structure><section_number>173.520</section_number><catch_line>Duties, powers of board -- Approval by department. </catch_line><order_by>520</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall establish, equip and maintain libraries or contract with existing libraries for the furnishing of library service for the district and do all things necessary to provide efficient library service. The board may also enter an agreement pursuant to KRS 65.210 to 65.300 for the provision of additional library service. No district shall establish a library unless the plans for the establishment, equipment, and maintenance have been approved by the Department for Libraries and Archives. No contract shall be made unless the libraries contracting to furnish service are libraries approved by the Department for Libraries and Archives for this purpose. </section><section prefix="2">The district, as a body corporate, by and through the board may: <section prefix="a">Sue and be sued, complain and defend, purchase, or lease grounds, purchase, lease, occupy or erect appropriate buildings for the use of the district libraries and their branches, sell and convey real and personal property for and on behalf of the district, receive gifts of real and personal property for the use and benefit of the district, the same when accepted to be held and controlled by the board according to the terms of the deed, gift, devise or bequest of such property; </section><section prefix="b">Borrow money on the credit of the board in anticipation of the revenue to be derived from taxes levied by the district for the fiscal year in which the money is borrowed, and to pledge the taxes levied for the district for the payment of the principal and interest of the loan. The principal shall not exceed fifty percent (50%) of the anticipated revenue for the fiscal year in which the money is borrowed; </section><section prefix="c">Establish bylaws it deems necessary and expedient to define the duties of officers or employees and make all necessary policies governing libraries, library service and personnel within the district. </section></section><section prefix="3">The board in exercise of its powers shall be guided by the regulations and requirements of the Department for Libraries and Archives. </section><section prefix="4">The powers set forth in this section shall not be construed to limit, restrict or modify any powers or authority granted by any other part of KRS 173.450 to 173.650 or any other law not in conflict with the provisions of this section. </section></text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 58, sec. 6, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 245, sec. 12, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 241, sec. 6. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 8, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4955</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>