<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.7921</section_number><catch_line>Technology initiative trust fund. </catch_line><order_by>7921</order_by><text><section prefix="1"><section prefix="a">The technology initiative trust fund created by KRS 164.7911 is intended to support investments in electronic technology for postsecondary education throughout the Commonwealth to improve student learning. </section><section prefix="b">The Council on Postsecondary Education may establish separate subsidiary programs and related accounts to provide financial assistance to the postsecondary education system in acquiring the infrastructure necessary to acquire and develop electronic technology capacity; to encourage shared program delivery among libraries, institutions, systems, agencies, and programs; to provide funding for the Commonwealth Virtual University under KRS 164.800; and other programs consistent with the purposes of postsecondary education, the adopted strategic agenda, and the biennial budget process. </section></section><section prefix="2">The council shall develop the criteria and process for submission of an application under this section. Any university and the Kentucky Community and Technical College System may apply to the council for financial assistance from the technology initiative trust fund. The council shall determine the matching funds or internal reallocation requirements for the applicants to qualify for funding. Financial assistance that may be awarded by the council shall be consistent with the adopted strategic agenda, the biennial budget process, and the availability of any resources to the technology initiative trust fund. </section></text><history> Created 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 12, effective May 30, 1997. </history><metadata><effective> May 30, 1997 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, K, 1, (2) at 655. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4460</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>