<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">A STATEWIDE EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>39A.350</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 39A.350 to 39A.366. </catch_line><order_by>350</order_by><text>As used in KRS 39A.350 to 39A.366: <section prefix="1">"Disaster relief organization" means an entity that provides emergency or disaster relief services that include health services provided by volunteer health practitioners and that: <section prefix="a">Is designated or recognized as a provider of those services pursuant to a disaster response and recovery plan adopted by an agency of the federal government or the Kentucky Division of Emergency Management; or </section><section prefix="b">Regularly plans and conducts its activities in coordination with an agency of the federal government or the Kentucky Division of Emergency Management; </section></section><section prefix="2">"Emergency" has the same meaning as used in KRS 39A.020; </section><section prefix="3">"Emergency declaration" has the same meaning as "declared emergency" as used in KRS 39A.020; </section><section prefix="4">"Emergency Management Assistance Compact" means the interstate compact established under KRS 39A.950; </section><section prefix="5">"Health facility" has the same meaning as used in KRS 216B.015; </section><section prefix="6">"Health practitioner" means an individual licensed under the laws of this or another state to provide health services; </section><section prefix="7">"Health services" means: <section prefix="a">The provision of treatment, care, advice or guidance, other services, or supplies related to the health or death of individuals or human populations, to the extent necessary to respond to an emergency, including: <section prefix="1">The following, concerning the physical or mental condition or functional status of an individual or affecting the structure or function of the body: <section prefix="a">Preventive, diagnostic, therapeutic, rehabilitative, maintenance, or palliative care; and </section><section prefix="b">Counseling, assessment, procedures, or other services; </section></section><section prefix="2">Sale or dispensing of a drug, a device, equipment, or another item to an individual in accordance with a prescription; and </section><section prefix="3">Funeral, cremation, cemetery, or other mortuary services; or </section></section><section prefix="b">The provision of treatment, care, advice or guidance, other services, or supplies related to the health or death of an animal or to animal populations, to the extent necessary to respond to an emergency, including: <section prefix="1">Diagnosis, treatment, or prevention of an animal disease, injury, or other physical or mental condition by the prescription, administration, or dispensing of vaccine, medicine, surgery, or therapy; </section><section prefix="2">Use of a procedure for reproductive management; and </section><section prefix="3">Monitoring and treatment of animal populations for diseases that have spread or demonstrate the potential to spread to humans; </section></section></section><section prefix="8">"Host entity" means an entity operating in this state which uses volunteer health practitioners to respond to an emergency; </section><section prefix="9">"License" means authorization by a state to engage in health services that are unlawful without the authorization. The term includes authorization under the laws of this state to an individual to provide health services based upon a national certification issued by a public or private entity; </section><section prefix="10">"Scope of practice" means the extent of the authorization to provide health services granted to a health practitioner by a license issued to the practitioner in the state in which the principal part of the practitioner’s services are rendered, including any conditions imposed by the licensing authority; and </section><section prefix="11">"Voluntary health practitioner" means a health practitioner who provides health services, whether or not the practitioner receives compensation for those services. The term does not include a practitioner who receives compensation pursuant to a preexisting employment relationship with a host entity or affiliate which requires the practitioner to provide health services in this state, unless the practitioner is not a resident of this state and is employed by a disaster relief organization providing services in this state while an emergency declaration is in effect. </section></text><history> Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 96, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><lrc-note>  (6/26/2007) 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 96 (2007 House Bill 287) "established" KRS Chapter 39G and created new sections thereof. However, at the time that House Bill 287 was enacted another KRS Chapter 39G was already in existence. The Reviser of Statutes determined that the newly created sections would be more appropriately placed in KRS Chapter 39A and has placed Sections 1 to 9 of Acts ch. 96 within KRS Chapter 39A, under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(a). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=21728</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>