<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="260" order_by="260">MARKETING OF AGRICULTURAL PRODUCTS </unit></structure><section_number>260.821</section_number><catch_line>Inspection fee -- Statements and records -- Penalties for late fees. </catch_line><order_by>821</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For the financing of the producers' share of this program, all handlers who issue payments to Kentucky permitted producers shall deduct an inspection fee at the rate of one-half cent ($0.005) per hundredweight from the producer's payment and shall transfer these funds to the director. <section prefix="a">The deduction shall be identified as "Inspection Fee." </section><section prefix="b">Each handler shall file on forms approved by the director, not later than the last day of January, April, July, and October of each year, a quarterly statement, setting forth the pounds of milk on which payment was issued to permitted producers during the preceding calendar quarter, and upon filing the statement shall transfer the inspection fee payment. </section><section prefix="c">Each handler shall keep the records required by the director to accurately indicate the amount of milk for which payments were issued to permitted producers. </section></section><section prefix="2">For the financing of the processors’ share of this program, handlers shall pay to the director an inspection fee at the rate of one-half cent ($0.005) per hundredweight on all milk received by processor locations in Kentucky. <section prefix="a">Each handler shall file on forms approved by the director, not later than the last day of January, April, July, and October of each year, a quarterly statement, setting forth the pounds of all milk received by processor locations in Kentucky during the preceding calendar quarter, and upon filing the statement shall make the inspection fee payment. </section><section prefix="b">Each handler shall keep the records required by the director to accurately indicate the amount of milk delivered to or received by processor locations in Kentucky. </section><section prefix="c">This fee shall not in any way be passed back to producers. If the fee is found to have been passed back to producers, violators may be penalized as set forth in KRS 260.992, along with other actions that may be taken by the director under KRS 260.775 to 260.845. </section></section><section prefix="3">Inspection fees that are due and have not been remitted to the director within fifteen (15) days following the due date shall be assessed a penalty fee as set forth in KRS 260.992. Assessment of this penalty fee shall not prevent the director from taking other actions under KRS 260.775 to 260.845. </section><section prefix="4">Fees collected shall be used to help pay for a portion of the costs of inspection, analysis, and other expenses necessary for the administration of KRS 260.775 to 260.845. </section></text><history> Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 229, sec. 17, effective January 1, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12651</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>