<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.852</section_number><catch_line>Prerequisites to approval of nuclear waste disposal facility -- Procedure -- Exception. </catch_line><order_by>852</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The location of a nuclear waste disposal facility in the Commonwealth of Kentucky shall require prior approval by a majority of the members of the Kentucky House of Representatives, a majority of the members of the Kentucky Senate, and the approval of the Governor of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="2">Before an application to locate a nuclear waste disposal facility in Kentucky can be submitted for approval to the Kentucky General Assembly, it must first receive the approval of the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services and the secretary of the Energy and Environment Cabinet. It shall be the responsibility of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services and the Energy and Environment Cabinet to ensure that a comprehensive environmental impact statement is submitted and that public hearings are held in the county in which it is proposed to locate a nuclear waste disposal facility. </section><section prefix="3">This section shall not apply to nuclear waste disposal facilities in existence prior to June 17, 1978. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 313, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 379, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 320, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 279, sec. 8, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8492</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>