<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="40" order_by="40">VETERANS </unit></structure><section_number>40.310</section_number><catch_line>Duties of Department of Veterans' Affairs.   </catch_line><order_by>310</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department of Veterans' Affairs shall collect all necessary data and information regarding facilities and services available to veterans, their families, and dependents, and shall cooperate with all information or service agencies throughout the state in informing such persons regarding the existence or availability of all educational, training, and retraining facilities; health, medical, rehabilitation, and housing services and facilities; employment and reemployment services; provisions of federal, state, and local laws affording rights, privileges, and benefits to said persons, their families, and dependents, and all other matters of similar related or appropriate nature. It shall likewise be the duty of the department to assist veterans and their families and dependents in the presentation, proof, and establishment of all claims, privileges, rights, and other benefits which they may have under federal, state, or local laws, and to cooperate with all national, state, and local government and private agencies securing services or any benefits to veterans, their families, and dependents. </section><section prefix="2">The commissioner of the Department of Veterans' Affairs shall prepare and submit to the Governor and each member of the board an annual report with reference to claims presented on behalf of veterans and to otherwise report the activities and accomplishments of the department. </section><section prefix="3">The Department of Veterans' Affairs shall be authorized to apply for and accept gifts, grants, and other contributions from the federal government, or from any other governmental unit which funds shall be administered by the department through use of trust and agency accounts. </section><section prefix="4">Veterans, as used in KRS 40.305 to 40.310 include any individual who served on active duty during peace or war in the Armed Forces of the United States, and who has received an honorable discharge from such service. </section><section prefix="5">The Department of Veterans' Affairs shall maintain full, adequate, and complete copies of all records pertaining to claims of veterans who file said claims for benefits through the department. </section><section prefix="6">The commissioner of the Department of Veterans' Affairs may purchase liability insurance for the protection of employees of the Department of Veterans' Affairs to protect them from liability for acts, omissions, and claims arising in the course and scope of their employment or service to the department. </section><section prefix="7">The Department of Veterans' Affairs shall manage the veterans' program trust fund established by KRS 40.460 by hosting all board meetings, providing logistical support, recording the minutes of each meeting, and authorizing expenditures once the board has approved a request for funds. </section></text><history> Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2013. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 147, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 244, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 313, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992.-- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 34. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 222, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><former-codification> KRS 36.330. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42399</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>