<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="45" order_by="45">A KENTUCKY MODEL PROCUREMENT CODE </unit></structure><section_number>45A.551</section_number><catch_line>Procedures for state agency privatization contracts. </catch_line><order_by>551</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Upon approval of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, a state agency may enter into a privatization contract. </section><section prefix="2">Before a state agency recommends to the Finance and Administration Cabinet that it enter into a privatization contract, the state agency shall determine and set forth in writing: <section prefix="a">The necessity for the service and the intended goals of the service; </section><section prefix="b">Problems and inefficiencies existing with the current governmental operation of the service; and </section><section prefix="c">Whether the service can efficiently be provided by the agency. </section></section><section prefix="3">If the state agency determines that the service cannot efficiently be provided by the agency, the state agency shall be permitted to continue the normal contracting process for the service. However, if the state agency determines that the service can efficiently be provided by the agency and the state agency chooses to proceed with privatization, it shall set forth in writing to the Finance and Administration Cabinet: <section prefix="a">The tangible benefits of privatizing the service; </section><section prefix="b">Any state or federal legal restraints that may limit or prevent privatization of the government service; </section><section prefix="c">The availability of multiple qualified and competitive private vendors; </section><section prefix="d"><section prefix="1">A cost-benefit analysis comparison that shall include, but not be limited to, collection and analysis of the total assessible fixed and variable, direct and indirect, costs of: <section prefix="a">The current governmental operation; and </section><section prefix="b">The private vendor contract. </section></section><section prefix="2">The costs shall include, but not be limited to: <section prefix="a">Facility and equipment maintenance; </section><section prefix="b">Inflation-adjusted costs, where comparison to past years is being conducted; </section><section prefix="c">Transition costs associated with shifting the service delivery from the government agency to a private vendor; </section><section prefix="d">Costs of monitoring, evaluating, and enforcing the contract; </section><section prefix="e">Personnel costs such as those providing for benefits, early retirements, retraining, and relocation in another position; and </section><section prefix="f">A plan for resuming government operation of the service if the privatization effort fails. </section></section></section><section prefix="e">A plan of assistance for all state employees who will be adversely affected by privatizing the service. The plan shall include at least: <section prefix="1">Efforts to place affected employees in vacant positions in another state agency and to retrain employees for another position in state government; </section><section prefix="2">Provisions in the contract, if feasible, for the hiring by the contractor of displaced employees at wages and benefits comparable to the wages and benefits paid to the state employees, subject to the provisions of KRS 11A.130; and </section><section prefix="3">Prior notification to affected state employees the day the contract is signed, or three (3) months before the day the adverse effect will occur, whichever is earlier. </section></section><section prefix="f">A process for monitoring, evaluating, and enforcing a contract with a private vendor which shall include, but not be limited to: <section prefix="1">Development of a method for ongoing, comprehensive performance evaluation of the private vendor; and </section><section prefix="2">Establishment of performance criteria and standards to evaluate the private vendor. </section></section></section><section prefix="4">All information required by subsections (2) and (3) of this section shall be submitted to the Finance and Administration Cabinet for its review and approval prior to proceeding with the contracting provisions of KRS Chapter 45A. </section><section prefix="5">The state agency shall retain responsibility for ensuring the quality and reliability of the services. </section><section prefix="6">All records in the possession of a state agency in conjunction with the approval, evaluation, or enforcement of a privatization contract unless exempt under another statute shall be public records, access to which shall be governed by KRS 61.870 to 61.884. </section><section prefix="7">Any other statute to the contrary notwithstanding, all records prepared, owned, used, in the possession of, or retained by a state agency in conjunction with the approval, evaluation, or enforcement of a privatization contract shall be public records, access to which shall be governed by KRS 61.870 to 61.884. </section></text><history> Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 492, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22446</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>