<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="76" order_by="76">CITY-COUNTY METROPOLITAN SEWER, SEWER CONSTRUCTION, AND SANITATION DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>76.060</section_number><catch_line>Officers and employees -- Legal services -- Effect of compact. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall, in July of each year, elect from its members a chairman and a vice chairman, who shall be of different political party affiliation. It shall employ a secretary-treasurer and a chief engineer, neither of whom is a member of the board. The secretary-treasurer and the chief engineer may be removed by the board for cause, after hearing by it and after at least ten (10) days' notice in writing has been given to the secretary-treasurer or chief engineer, as the case may be, which notice shall embrace the charges preferred against him or her. At the hearing he or she may be represented by counsel. The finding of the board is final. The secretary-treasurer and the chief engineer shall each devote his or her entire time and attention exclusively to the services of the board. The board may employ, and remove at pleasure, professional and technical advisers, experts, and other employees, skilled or unskilled, as it deems requisite for the performance of its duties. </section><section prefix="2">The board shall require the secretary-treasurer and the chief engineer each to execute a bond and may exact from such of its other officers and employees bonds as it deems expedient. All bonds shall be payable to the district in the sums as the board may fix, with approved corporate surety, and premiums therefor shall be paid by the district. The bonds shall obligate the makers thereof to faithfully perform the duties of their respective offices and positions and to fully account for and pay over all money, property, or other thing of value of the district, which may come to their hands, respectively. The board shall fix the salaries and compensation of the officers and employees it engages, which salaries and compensation, however, shall be in line with that paid by the city and county for similar services. </section><section prefix="3">Notwithstanding other provisions of this section, when a city of the first class and a county containing such city have in effect a compact under KRS 79.310 to 79.330, the executive director, secretary-treasurer, and chief engineer shall be appointed by and serve at the joint pleasure of the mayor, and the county judge/executive with the approval of the fiscal court pursuant to KRS 67.040. Upon the establishment of a consolidated local government in a county where a city of the first class and a county containing such city have had in effect a cooperative compact pursuant to KRS 79.310 to 79.330, the executive director, secretary-treasurer, and chief engineer shall be appointed by and serve at the pleasure of the mayor. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 78, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1968 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 51. --Amended 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 180, sec. 1. -- Created 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 4. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:12</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=24478</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>