<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="241" order_by="241">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- ADMINISTRATION AND CONTROL </unit></structure><section_number>241.060</section_number><catch_line>Functions of board. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text>The board shall have the following functions, powers, and duties: <section prefix="1">To promulgate reasonable administrative regulations governing procedures relative to the applications for and revocations of licenses, the supervision and control of the use, manufacture, sale, transportation, storage, advertising, and trafficking of alcoholic beverages, and all other matters over which the board has jurisdiction. Administrative regulations need not be uniform in their application but may vary in accordance with reasonable classifications; </section><section prefix="2">To limit in its sound discretion the number of licenses of each kind or class to be issued in this state or any political subdivision, and restrict the locations of licensed premises. To this end, the board may make reasonable division and subdivision of the state or any political subdivision into districts. Administrative regulations relating to the granting, refusal, and revocation of licenses may be different within the several divisions or subdivisions; </section><section prefix="3">To hold hearings in accordance with the provisions of KRS Chapter 13B. The department may pay witnesses the per diem and mileage provided in KRS 421.015; </section><section prefix="4">To conduct hearings and appeals under KRS 241.150, 241.200, 243.470, and 243.520 and render final orders upon the subjects of the hearings and appeals; </section><section prefix="5">To destroy evidence in the department's possession after all administrative and judicial proceedings are conducted; </section><section prefix="6">To suspend, revoke, or cancel for cause, after a hearing in accordance with KRS Chapter 13B, any license issued under KRS 243.020 to 243.670; </section><section prefix="7">To prohibit the issuance of a license for the premises until the expiration of two (2) years from the time the offense was committed if a violation of KRS Chapter 241, KRS 243.020 to 243.670, or KRS Chapter 244 has taken place on the premises which the owner knew of or should have known of, or was committed or permitted in or on the premises owned by the licensee; and </section><section prefix="8">To suspend a license for any cause for which the board is authorized to exercise its discretion as to revoking a license. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 553, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 33, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 522, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 318, sec. 159, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 225, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 7, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 212. -- Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2554b-103, 2554e-10. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11218</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>