<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="278" order_by="278">PUBLIC SERVICE COMMISSION </unit></structure><section_number>278.508</section_number><catch_line>Exemption of sale of natural gas used as a motor vehicle fuel from regulation -- Regulation of transportation, distribution, or delivery of natural gas used as a motor vehicle fuel. </catch_line><order_by>508</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Notwithstanding any other provisions of this chapter, the rates, terms, and conditions of service for the sale of natural gas to a compressed natural gas fuel station, retailer, or to any end-user for use as a motor vehicle fuel, shall not be subject to regulation by the Kentucky Public Service Commission. Any utility provider of such a nonregulated service shall keep separate records and books of account adequate to allow the commission to allocate costs and revenues and to perform other acts that will assist the commission in enforcing this section. </section><section prefix="2">The transportation, distribution, or delivery of natural gas to any compressed natural gas fuel station, retailer, or any end-user for use as a motor vehicle fuel, shall continue to be subject to regulation by the Kentucky Public Service Commission. Upon request by the utility, the commission shall set flexible rates which provide a fair opportunity to compete with other motor fuels. Price adjustment pursuant to these flexible rates are not rate changes for purposes of this chapter. </section><section prefix="3">The sales or transportation transactions described in this section shall not adversely affect the regulated utility's cost or costs, or the availability of natural gas to its utility sales customers. </section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 273, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14138</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>