<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.496</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky trauma care system fund -- Uses. </catch_line><order_by>496</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky trauma care system fund is created as a restricted account that shall consist of state general fund appropriations and other grants, contributions, donations, or other moneys made available for the purposes of KRS 211.490 to 211.496. Moneys in the fund are hereby appropriated for the purposes set forth in KRS 211.490 to 211.496. </section><section prefix="2">The trauma care system fund shall be used to support: <section prefix="a">Administrative costs of the Department for Public Health, the statewide trauma care director, and the advisory committee that relate to the statewide trauma care system, including public awareness and information efforts; </section><section prefix="b">The implementation of the statewide trauma care system; </section><section prefix="c">Expenses related to hospital trauma center verification; </section><section prefix="d">Continuing education for trauma care providers; and </section><section prefix="e">Support for uncompensated care provided by hospitals, physicians, emergency medical services, or other trauma care providers who provide services in a verified trauma center. Verified trauma centers shall have the authority to contract with state government for receipt of funds under this paragraph. </section></section><section prefix="3">Notwithstanding KRS 45.229, any moneys remaining in the fund at the close of a fiscal year shall not lapse but shall be carried forward into the succeeding next fiscal year to be used for the purposes set forth in KRS 211.490 to 211.496. </section><section prefix="4">Any interest earned on moneys in the account shall accrue to the fund and shall be used for the purposes set forth in KRS 211.490 to 211.496. </section></text><history> Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 25, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8424</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>