<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="200" order_by="200">ASSISTANCE TO CHILDREN </unit></structure><section_number>200.470</section_number><catch_line>Conditions of acceptance for children -- Payment for care. </catch_line><order_by>470</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No child shall be accepted for care or treatment by the Commission for Children with Special Health Care Needs if his parents or legal guardian are able to pay for such treatment except where the child resides in an area of the state where adequate care and treatment are not otherwise available, in which event referral must be made by the doctor caring for the child and the parents or guardian shall reimburse the Commission for Children with Special Health Care Needs for all cost expended by the commission for treatment. </section><section prefix="2">In the event the Commission for Children with Special Health Care Needs determines that the parents or legal guardian of a child with a disability can pay only a portion of the cost of treatment through their own resources or through resources available to them, such parents or guardian shall pay such sums as they are able to pay and the funds thus received shall be turned over to the Commission for Children with Special Health Care Needs and applied to the cost of treatment and care of the child. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 405, sec. 55, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 234, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(24). -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 33, sec. 8, effective July 1, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7299</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>