<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="154" order_by="154">A STATE LOTTERY </unit></structure><section_number>154A.020</section_number><catch_line>State lottery created -- Administration by corporation -- Management -- Intent of General Assembly -- Senate confirmation required for corporation existence. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created and established a state lottery which shall be administered by an independent, de jure municipal corporation and political subdivision of the Commonwealth of Kentucky which shall be a public body corporate and politic to be known as the Kentucky Lottery Corporation. The corporation shall be deemed a public agency within the meaning of KRS 61.805 and 61.870. This corporation shall be managed in such a manner that enables the people of the Commonwealth to benefit from its profits and to enjoy the best possible lottery games. The General Assembly hereby recognizes that the operations of a lottery are unique activities for state government and that a corporate structure will best enable the lottery to be managed in an entrepreneurial and business-like manner. It is the intent of the General Assembly that the Kentucky Lottery Corporation shall be accountable to the Governor, the General Assembly and the people of the Commonwealth through a system of audits, reports and thorough financial disclosure as required by this chapter. </section><section prefix="2">The existence of the corporation shall begin only upon confirmation of the members of the board by the Senate as provided in KRS 154A.030. Until the time of such confirmation, no business shall be conducted on behalf of the lottery. </section><section prefix="3">Notwithstanding any other provision of law to the contrary, no official action of any form shall be taken by the board at any time unless a majority of the members of the board shall have been confirmed by the Senate as provided in KRS 154A.030. Any action taken on behalf of the lottery when less than a majority of the members of the board shall have been confirmed shall be of no effect. </section></text><history>Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 33, effective July 15, 2014. -- Created 1988 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 2, effective December 15, 1988. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43426</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>