<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="405" order_by="405">PARENT AND CHILD </unit></structure><section_number>405.411</section_number><catch_line>Newspaper publication of names of persons with child support arrearages or who fail to appear in child support cases.   </catch_line><order_by>411</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services' designee under KRS 205.712(6) for the administration of child support may compile a list of the names of persons under its jurisdiction who have a child support arrearage that equals or exceeds six (6) months without payment, or fail, after receiving appropriate notice, to comply with subpoenas or warrants relating to paternity or child support proceedings as provided by 42 U.S.C. sec. 666(a)(16). The cabinet may furnish this list to the newspaper of general circulation in that county for publication. </section><section prefix="2">The Department for Income Support, Child Support Enforcement, in the Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall determine uniform standards for publication. The cabinet is authorized to promulgate the necessary administrative regulations under KRS Chapter 13A to implement the provisions of this section. </section><section prefix="3">For purposes of this section, "newspaper of general circulation" means a publication bearing a title or name, regularly issued at least as frequently as once a week for a definite price, having a second-class mailing privilege, being not less than four (4) pages, published continuously during the immediately preceding one (1) year period, which is published for the dissemination of news of general interest, and is circulated generally in the political subdivision in which it is published and in which notice is to be given. In any county where a publication fully complying with this definition does not exist, the Cabinet for Health and Family Services may publish this list in the publication utilized by the Circuit Court Clerk of the county for publication of other legal notices in the county. A newspaper that is not engaged in the distribution of news of general interest to the public, but that is primarily engaged in the distribution of news of interest to a particular group of citizens, is not a newspaper of general circulation. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 158, sec. 70, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 630, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 430, sec. 11, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40963</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>