<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="532" order_by="532">CLASSIFICATION AND DESIGNATION OF OFFENSES -- AUTHORIZED DISPOSITION </unit></structure><section_number>532.043</section_number><catch_line>Requirement of postincarceration supervision for certain felonies. </catch_line><order_by>043</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In addition to the penalties authorized by law, any person convicted of, pleading guilty to, or entering an Alford plea to a felony offense under KRS Chapter 510, 529.100 involving commercial sexual activity, 530.020, 530.064(1)(a), 531.310, or 531.320 shall be subject to a period of postincarceration supervision following release from: <section prefix="a">Incarceration upon expiration of sentence; or </section><section prefix="b">Completion of parole. </section></section><section prefix="2">The period of postincarceration supervision shall be five (5) years. </section><section prefix="3">During the period of postincarceration supervision, the defendant shall: <section prefix="a">Be subject to all orders specified by the Department of Corrections; and </section><section prefix="b">Comply with all education, treatment, testing, or combination thereof required by the Department of Corrections. </section></section><section prefix="4">Persons under postincarceration supervision pursuant to this section shall be subject to the supervision of the Division of Probation and Parole and under the authority of the Parole Board. </section><section prefix="5">If a person violates a provision specified in subsection (3) of this section, the violation shall be reported in writing by the Division of Probation and Parole. Notice of the violation shall be sent to the Parole Board to determine whether probable cause exists to revoke the defendant's postincarceration supervision and reincarcerate the defendant as set forth in KRS 532.060. </section><section prefix="6">The provisions of this section shall apply only to persons convicted, pleading guilty, or entering an Alford plea after July 15, 1998. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch.2, sec.91, effective March 3, 2011. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 19, sec. 15, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 42, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 345, sec. 9, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 606, sec. 25, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> March 3, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39479</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>