<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">B MEDICAL IMAGING, RADIATION THERAPY, AND RELATED OCCUPATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>311B.180</section_number><catch_line>Civil Penalties.   </catch_line><order_by>180</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall assess civil penalties authorized by KRS 311B.190 against an individual or licensee who performs diagnostic or therapeutic procedures without a valid license. </section><section prefix="2">Prior to assessing civil penalties, the board shall confirm the violation of the requirements by any of the following: <section prefix="a">Observing the violation; </section><section prefix="b">Obtaining records, documents, or other physical evidence; </section><section prefix="c">Obtaining statements from either the employer or the employee that confirm the existence of the violation; or </section><section prefix="d">Obtaining statements from third parties, such as patients or coworkers, that corroborate the allegation that a violation has occurred. </section></section><section prefix="3">Civil penalties shall be assessed against individuals who perform diagnostic or therapeutic procedures without a valid license as follows: <section prefix="a">Failure to apply for an initial license by an individual who is fully qualified for licensure at the time the violation is discovered shall be assessed a civil penalty plus the license application fee; </section><section prefix="b">Failure to apply for renewal by an individual who would be eligible for renewal of a license but would not currently qualify due to insufficient continuing education at the time the violation is discovered shall be assessed a civil penalty plus the license renewal fee; </section><section prefix="c">Performance of a diagnostic or therapeutic procedure requiring licensure by an individual who is not qualified for a license at the time the violation is discovered shall be assessed a civil penalty; and </section><section prefix="d">Civil penalties for repeating the above offenses shall be doubled. Each day the violation occurs shall count as a separate repeat offense. </section></section><section prefix="4">Civil penalties, double the amount assessed against the licensee, shall also be assessed against the employer of the individual without a valid license pursuant to subsection (3) of this section. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 50, sec. 18, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40212</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>