<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="42" order_by="42">FINANCE AND ADMINISTRATION CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>42.032</section_number><catch_line>Web site to provide public access to expenditure records of executive branch -- Monthly and weekly updates -- Cabinet is sole custodian of information and records -- Branches to share software and applications. </catch_line><order_by>032</order_by><text><section prefix="1">By January 1, 2012, the Finance and Administration Cabinet shall provide public access to records relating to expenditures of the executive branch of state government through display of the records on a Web site. The Web site shall provide: <section prefix="a">Financial information of expenditures not exempt under the provisions of state or federal law, including: <section prefix="1">The payee name; </section><section prefix="2">The category or type of the expenditure; </section><section prefix="3">A description of the reason for the expenditure, if available; </section><section prefix="4">The expenditure amount; and </section><section prefix="5">A link to the financial document, if the document is electronically available; </section></section><section prefix="b">A searchable format; </section><section prefix="c">Access to the current enacted Executive Branch Budget; and </section><section prefix="d">A link to the public access Web site displays of the legislative and judicial branches of state government, and of the public institutions of higher education. </section></section><section prefix="2">Information on the Web site shall be updated at least on a monthly basis. However, information on the Web site which is part of, or contained in, an electronic accounting system utilized by all branches of state government, such as the Enhanced Management Administrative Reporting System (EMARS), shall be updated on a weekly basis. </section><section prefix="3">The cabinet shall maintain exclusive control and be considered the sole custodian of all information and records generated by and through activity of the executive branch of government, notwithstanding the situs of the information and the records in another branch of government, and disclosure thereof shall only be by the cabinet in accordance with applicable law. </section><section prefix="4">In order to reduce Web site development costs and enhance public access and use of records viewed through Web sites as provided by this section and KRS 7.505 and 26A.260, each branch of state government shall freely share with the other branches of state government the software, software developments, and all applications, data, and information within its control used for Web site design, appearance, content, and operation in compliance with, or in furtherance of, the purposes contemplated by this section and KRS 7.505 and 26A.260. </section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch.105, sec.3, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39926</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>