<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="439" order_by="439">PROBATION AND PAROLE </unit></structure><section_number>439.500</section_number><catch_line>Prohibited activities of probation and parole officers. </catch_line><order_by>500</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No probation or parole officer of the department shall: <section prefix="a">Use his office to influence elections, or to influence the political action of any person; </section><section prefix="b">Serve as a member of the campaign committee of any political party; </section><section prefix="c">Interfere with or participate in the preparation for any election, or the conduct thereof at the polling place, or with the election officers while they are performing their duties; </section><section prefix="d">Be in any manner concerned in demanding, soliciting, or receiving any assessments, subscriptions, or contributions, whether voluntary or involuntary, for any political party or candidate. </section></section><section prefix="2">It shall be unlawful for any person to be in any way concerned with demanding or soliciting assessments, subscriptions, or contributions for any political party or candidate from any member or employee of the Department of Corrections. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 98, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 344, sec. 49, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. V, sec. 24(16). -- Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 26, effective May 18, 1956. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19200</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>