<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="35" order_by="35">MILITARY JUSTICE </unit></structure><section_number>35.195</section_number><catch_line>Sessions.   </catch_line><order_by>195</order_by><text><section prefix="1">At any time after the service of charges which have been referred for trial to a court-martial composed of a military judge and members, the military judge may, subject to KRS 35.175, call the court into session without the presence of the members for the purpose of: <section prefix="a">Hearing and determining motions raising defenses or objections which are capable of determination without trial of the issues raised by a plea of not guilty; </section><section prefix="b">Hearing and ruling upon any matter which may be ruled upon by the military judge under this code whether or not the matter is appropriate for later consideration or decision by the members of the court; </section><section prefix="c">Holding the arraignment and receiving the pleas of the accused; and </section><section prefix="d">Performing any other procedural function which does not require the presence of the members of the court under this code. These proceedings shall be conducted in the presence of the accused, defense counsel, and trial counsel and shall be made part of the record. </section></section> These proceedings may be conducted notwithstanding the number of court members and without regard to KRS 35.145. <section prefix="2">When the members of a court-martial deliberate or vote, only the members may be present. All other proceedings, including any consultation of the members of the court with counsel or the military judge shall be made part of the record and shall be in the presence of the accused, the defense counsel, the trial counsel, and the military judge. </section></text><history>Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 32, sec. 40, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 56, sec. 25. -- Created 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 38, effective July 1, 1954. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=41914</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>