<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>224.43-730</section_number><catch_line>Applications for assistance. </catch_line><order_by>43-730</order_by><text>Financial and technical assistance will be provided to reimburse counties, cities, waste management districts, or any combination thereof preparing area solid waste management plans or portions thereof, preparing engineering design and geotechnical studies for disposal sites, conducting materials recovery or energy recovery feasibility and assessment studies, and conducting special solid waste management studies. <section prefix="1">Area solid waste management plans. Applicants may be cities, counties, waste management districts, or any combination thereof. Assistance may be requested in order to prepare an area solid waste management plan or a portion thereof as outlined by KRS 224.43-345. </section><section prefix="2">Disposal site engineering and geotechnical studies. Applicants may be cities, counties, waste management districts, or any combination thereof, preparing disposal site engineering plans or conducting geotechnical studies required by KRS 224.40-310. Applicants shall have an approved area solid waste management plan, and any proposed disposal site must be consistent with that plan. Prior to receiving any financial assistance, the applicant shall own, or have a legal interest at any proposed site sufficient to allow completion of the detailed study and operation of a waste disposal facility. </section><section prefix="3">Materials or energy recovery study. Applicants may be cities, counties, waste management districts, or any combination thereof, investigating the feasibility of developing a materials or energy recovery facility or operation. Studies may include technological, engineering design, legal, economic, environmental, administrative, and institutional considerations. Applicants shall have an approved area solid waste management plan, and the proposed materials or energy recovery project shall be consistent with that plan. </section><section prefix="4">Relevant solid waste management study. Applicants may be cities, counties, waste management districts, or a combination thereof, proposing to conduct: studies in order to implement a solid waste collection, transportation, processing, treatment, or disposal system; a resource conservation or public education program, site feasibility studies; or analyses of ordinances needed to assure that an adequate management system is provided. Applicants shall have an approved area solid waste management plan, and the proposed study must be consistent with that plan. </section></text><history> Amended 1991 (1st Extra. Sess.), Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 9, effective February 26, 1991. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 398, sec. 8, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> February 26, 1991 </effective><former-codification> KRS 224.894. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:33</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10431</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>