<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.886</section_number><catch_line>Reimbursement for collecting and reporting. </catch_line><order_by>886</order_by><text>To reimburse himself for the cost of collecting and reporting the tax, each person required to pay and report the tax levied by KRS 243.884 shall deduct on each report one percent (1%) of the tax due, provided the amount due is not delinquent at the time of payment. </text><history>Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 390, sec. 7, effective June 1, 1982.</history><metadata><effective>June 1, 1982</effective><lrc-note> (11/5/90).  The text of this section originated in Senate Committee Substitute No. 2 for 1982 House Bill 571, see 1982 Senate Journal 2026. In this substitute, Section 4 had two subsections. Floor Amendment No. 4 to this substitute deleted subsection (1) of Section 4 and removed (2) from the remainder of the text. See 1982 Senate Journal 2207-08. The Senate adopted these two items in its treatment of House Bill 571, see 1982 Senate Journal 2212, and the Free Conference Committee Report on House Bill 571 subsequently also incorporated this language, see 1982 Senate Journal 2415, 1982 House Journal 3258-3259. It was in this form that House Bill 571 passed both Houses. See 1982 Senate Journal 2425, 1982 House Journal 3259. For this reason, the words "subsection (2) of" that appeared before KRS 243.884 were retained in this section by a manifest clerical error in failing to make the necessary conforming amendment. These words have been deleted by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to KRS 7.136. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11422</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>