<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="323" order_by="323">A LANDSCAPE ARCHITECTURE </unit></structure><section_number>323A.110</section_number><catch_line>Grounds for placement on probation, reprimand, refusal to issue or renew, revocation, or suspension of license. </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text>The board may refuse to issue or renew a license, or may place on probation, reprimand, suspend, or revoke the license of any landscape architect to practice landscape architecture in the Commonwealth of Kentucky, and may impose a fine of not less than one hundred dollars ($100) nor more than ten thousand dollars ($10,000) per violation, for any of the following reasons: <section prefix="1">Incompetence or negligence in the practice of landscape architecture, as determined by the board; </section><section prefix="2">Unprofessional conduct, or conduct tending to bring the profession into disrepute, as determined by the board; </section><section prefix="3">Conviction of a felony, including all instances in which a plea of nolo contendere or no contest is the basis of the conviction; </section><section prefix="4">Fraudulent or dishonest landscape architectural practice; </section><section prefix="5">Use of false evidence or misrepresentations in an application for license; </section><section prefix="6">Signing or affixing his or her seal to any plans, prints, specifications, or reports which have not been prepared by the landscape architect personally or under his or her immediate supervision; </section><section prefix="7">Failure to meet the continuing education requirements established by administrative regulation of the board; </section><section prefix="8">Impairment due to drugs, alcohol, or mental disability to an extent that continued practice may be dangerous to clients or to public safety; </section><section prefix="9">Failure to comply with an order issued by the board; and </section><section prefix="10">Violation of any state statute or administrative regulation governing the practice of landscape architecture. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 90, sec. 8, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 291, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 287, sec. 11. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43360</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>