<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="438" order_by="438">OFFENSES AGAINST PUBLIC HEALTH AND SAFETY </unit></structure><section_number>438.337</section_number><catch_line>Responsibilities of Department of Alcoholic Beverage Control in enforcement of KRS 438.305 to 438.340 -- Disposition of revenue and fines collected under KRS 138.140 and KRS 438.305 to 438.340. </catch_line><order_by>337</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except for violations of the provisions of KRS 438.311, 438.313, and 438.315 by a juvenile, which shall be under the jurisdiction of the juvenile session of the District Court, the Department of Alcoholic Beverage Control shall carry out the enforcement provisions of KRS 438.305 to 438.340. </section><section prefix="2">The Department of Alcoholic Beverage Control shall be entitled to the revenue produced by one-twentieth of one cent ($0.0005) of the three-cent ($0.03) per pack revenue collected by the Finance and Administration Cabinet from the state excise tax on the sale of cigarettes as imposed by KRS 138.140 to be deposited in a trust and agency account created in the State Treasury, and to keep fifty percent (50%) of any fines collected under KRS 438.305 to 438.340 to offset the costs of enforcement of KRS 438.305 to 438.340. </section><section prefix="3">The Department of Alcoholic Beverage Control shall be responsible for maintaining statistics for compilation of required reports to be submitted to the United States Department of Health and Human Services. </section><section prefix="4">The Department of Alcoholic Beverage Control shall devise a plan and time frame for enforcement to determine by random inspection if the percentage of retailers or distributors making illegal sales to minors does or does not exceed federal guidelines preventing tobacco sales to minors. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1933, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 423, sec. 9, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19115</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>