<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.0234</section_number><catch_line>Adult education learning system -- Services -- Duties and responsibilities of the Kentucky Adult Education Program.   </catch_line><order_by>0234</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Adult Education Program shall promulgate necessary administrative regulations and administer a statewide adult education and literacy system throughout the state. The adult education and literacy system shall include diverse educational services provided by credentialed professionals, based on the learners' current needs and a commitment to lifelong learning. <section prefix="a">Services shall be provided at multiple sites appropriate for adult learning, including vocational and technical colleges, community colleges, comprehensive universities, adult education centers, public schools, libraries, family resource centers, adult correctional facilities, other institutions, and through the Kentucky Commonwealth Virtual University. Services shall be targeted to communities with the greatest need based on the number of adults at literacy levels I and II as defined by the 1997 Kentucky Adult Literacy Survey and other indicators of need. </section><section prefix="b">Access and referral services shall be initiated at multiple points including businesses, educational institutions, labor organizations, employment offices, and government offices. </section><section prefix="c">Multiple funding sources, program support, and partnerships to administer the adult education and literacy system may include student scholarship and grants; fees for services rendered; and other general, agency, local, state, federal, and private funds. </section></section><section prefix="2">Services included as part of the adult education and literacy system shall include but not be limited to functionally-contexted workplace essential skills training based on employers' needs, leading to a competency-based certificate indicating proficiency in critical thinking, computating, reading, writing, communicating, problem-solving, team-building, and use of technology at various worksites regarding basic skills. </section><section prefix="3">In administering an adult education and literacy system, the Kentucky Adult Education Program shall: <section prefix="a">Assist providers with the development of quality job-specific and workplace essential skills instruction for workers in business and industry, literacy and adult basic education, adult secondary education, including high school equivalency diploma preparation, the external diploma program, English as a second language, and family literacy programs, in cooperation with local business, labor, economic development, educational, employment, and service support entities; </section><section prefix="b">Provide assessments of each student's skill and competency level allowing assessments to be shared with other educational and employment entities when necessary for providing additional educational programs, taking into consideration student confidentiality; </section><section prefix="c">Assist adult educators to meet professional standards; </section><section prefix="d">Create an awareness program in cooperation with the Administrative Office of the Courts to ensure that District and Circuit Court Judges are aware of the provisions of KRS 533.200 and the methods to access adult education and literacy programs for persons sentenced under the statute; </section><section prefix="e">Develop administrative regulations including those for business and industry service participation and mechanisms for service funding through all appropriate federal, state, local, and private resources; </section><section prefix="f">Require and monitor compliance with the program's administrative regulations and policies; and </section><section prefix="g">Develop and implement performance measures and benchmarks. </section></section></text><history> Repealed, reenacted, and renumbered 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 35, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 55, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 526, sec. 10, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 54, effective May 30, 1997. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 143, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 487, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><former-codification>KRS 151B.410. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42215</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>