<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="319" order_by="319">C APPLIED BEHAVIOR ANALYSTS </unit></structure><section_number>319C.060</section_number><catch_line>Board's powers to regulate practice of applied behavior analysis -- Administrative regulations -- Fees. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall have the right to regulate the practice of applied behavior analysis in the state including behavior analysts, assistant behavior analysts, and temporary licensees, including licensure, limitations of activities, supervision, and educational qualifications and continuing education requirements for behavior analysts, assistant behavior analysts, temporary licensees and supervisees. The board shall administer and enforce the provisions of this chapter and shall have the responsibility of evaluating the qualifications of applicants for licensure. </section><section prefix="2">The board shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A relating to the licensure and regulation of behavior analysts, assistant behavior analysts, and temporary licensees including: <section prefix="a">Establishing standards for licensure, temporary licensure, limitations of activities, supervision, and compliance with the educational qualifications as required by KRS 319C.080 for behavior analysts, assistant behavior analysts, and temporary licensees; </section><section prefix="b">Establishing the number of persons a licensed behavior analyst may supervise at one (1) time, including temporary licensees and supervisees; </section><section prefix="c">Adopting a code of ethical standards and standards of practice for all licensed behavior analysts, assistant behavior analysts, and temporary licensees; </section><section prefix="d">Establishing a measure of continued competency as a condition of license renewal and standards for suspension, revocation, or refusal to issue or renew a license of a behavior analyst, assistant behavior analyst, or temporary licensee; </section><section prefix="e">Governing the physical and mental examination of behavior analysts, assistant behavior analysts, and temporary licensees who may be impaired by reason of a mental, physical, or other condition that impedes their ability to practice competently. For purposes of enforcing this section, the board shall have the power to order an immediate temporary suspension in accordance with KRS 13B.125 if there is a reasonable cause to believe that a behavior analyst, assistant behavior analyst, temporary licensee, or applicant may be impaired by reason of a mental, physical, or other condition that impedes his or her ability to practice competently; and </section><section prefix="f">Establishing reasonable fees for the licensure and license renewal of behavior analysts, assistant behavior analysts, and temporary licensees. </section></section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 6, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31297</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>