<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="329" order_by="329">A PRIVATE INVESTIGATORS </unit></structure><section_number>329A.060</section_number><catch_line>Investigation of licensee wrongdoing -- Hearing -- Admonishment. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board may investigate allegations of licensee wrongdoing upon complaint or upon its own volition. The board shall promulgate administrative regulations regarding the receiving and investigating of complaints. </section><section prefix="2">If the board's investigation reveals evidence supporting the complaint, the board shall set the matter for hearing pursuant to the provisions of KRS Chapter 13B before suspending, revoking, imposing probationary or supervisory conditions or an administrative fine, issuing a written reprimand, or any other combination of actions regarding any license under the provisions of KRS 329A.010 to 329A.090. </section><section prefix="3">If, after an investigation that includes an opportunity for the licensee to respond, the board determines that a violation took place but was not of a serious nature, it may issue a written admonishment to the licensee. A copy of the admonishment shall be placed in the board's permanent licensure file. The licensee shall have the right to file a response to the admonishment within thirty (30) days of its receipt and to have that response placed in the board's permanent licensure file. The licensee may, within thirty (30) days of receipt, file a request for hearing with the board. Upon receipt of this request the board shall set aside the written admonishment and set the matter for hearing under the provisions of KRS Chapter 13B. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 269, sec. 11, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31768</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>