<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="95" order_by="95">CITY POLICE AND FIRE DEPARTMENTS </unit></structure><section_number>95.520</section_number><catch_line>Pension fund -- Board of trustees -- Coverage provided in County Employees Retirement System after August 1, 1988.     </catch_line><order_by>520</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In cities meeting the criteria set out in KRS 95.518, there shall be a policemen's and firefighters' pension fund, and a board of trustees for that fund unless the policemen and firefighters are included in the membership of the County Employees Retirement System. </section><section prefix="2">The board of trustees is the trustee of the pension fund, and has exclusive control and management of the pension fund and of all moneys donated or paid for the relief or pensioning of members of the police and fire departments. It may do all things necessary to protect the fund. </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">After August 1, 1988, no new locally administered pension fund shall be created pursuant to this section, and cities which were covered by this section on or prior to August 1, 1988, shall participate in the County Employees Retirement System effective August 1, 1988. </section><section prefix="b">Cities which were covered by this section on or prior to August 1, 1988, shall provide for the retirement of police or firefighters rehired after August 1, 1988, by placing such employees in the County Employees Retirement System. </section><section prefix="c">Cities which were covered by this section on or prior to August 1, 1988, shall place police or firefighters newly hired after August 1, 1988, in the County Employees Retirement System. </section><section prefix="d">Cities which were covered by this section on or prior to August 1, 1988, shall offer employees hired on or prior to August 1, 1988, membership in the County Employees Retirement System under the alternate participation plan as described in KRS 78.530(3), but such employees may elect to retain coverage under this section. </section><section prefix="e">The city shall certify that all police and firefighters placed in the County Employees Retirement System, and not covered by Social Security for their employment with the city, are employed in hazardous positions. If the police and firefighters are covered by Social Security for their employment with the city, the city may certify that they are employed in hazardous positions. </section></section></text><history>Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 28, sec. 13, effective June 24, 2015. -- Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 121, effective January 1, 2015. -- June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective>June 24, 2015</effective><lrc-note>.  Acts 1988, ch. 11, รยง 19, provides: "In order that city employees with a choice can make an informed decision on whether or not to join the county employees retirement system, Kentucky retirement systems shall conduct briefings for each affected pension system on the provisions of this Act. Each employee shall receive a written summary of the retirement benefits which the county employees retirement system offers, and each employee shall be given the opportunity to attend an oral presentation. All such presentations shall be completed by October 15, 1988, and each affected employee shall make his decision by November 1, 1988. Failure of an employee subject to the provisions of this Act to receive a written summary or to attend an oral briefing shall in no way invalidate any of the provisions of this Act." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:09</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44285</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>