<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="13" order_by="13">A ADMINISTRATIVE REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>13A.338</section_number><catch_line>Legislative finding -- Certain administrative regulations void -- Prohibition against promulgating substantially similar regulations within specified time. </catch_line><order_by>338</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The General Assembly finds that certain administrative regulations as evidenced by the records of the Legislative Research Commission, including but not limited to the Kentucky Administrative Regulations Service and the Administrative Register of Kentucky, were found deficient but became effective notwithstanding the finding of deficiency, pursuant to KRS 13A.330(5)(a)2. or 13A.331(5)(a)2., on or after March 27, 2002, and before March 16, 2004. </section><section prefix="2">Contrary provisions of any section of the Kentucky Revised Statutes notwithstanding, each administrative regulation referenced in subsection (1) of this section shall be null, void, and unenforceable as of March 16, 2004. </section><section prefix="3">Contrary provisions of any section of the Kentucky Revised Statutes notwithstanding, the administrative body shall be prohibited from promulgating an administrative regulation that is identical to, or substantially the same as, any of the administrative regulations referenced in subsection (1) of this section for a period beginning on March 16, 2004, and concluding on June 1, 2005. </section><section prefix="4">A list of the administrative regulations referenced in subsection (1) of this section shall be available to the public, in the office of the Legislative Research Commission's regulations compiler. </section></text><history> Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 1, effective March 16, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> March 16, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=778</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>