<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="235" order_by="235">BOATS AND BOATING </unit></structure><section_number>235.030</section_number><catch_line>Title and administration of chapter. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text>This chapter shall be known as the State Boating Act and shall be administered by the Department of Fish and Wildlife Resources in the Tourism, Arts and Heritage Cabinet, except the Transportation Cabinet shall be responsible for administering the boat numbering, registration, and titling requirements. </text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 61, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 46, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 48, sec. 19, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 118, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 391, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 404, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 446, sec. 3, effective April 12, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 295, sec. 74, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 292, sec. 3. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 68, Art. VIII, sec. 2, effective March 17, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/98).  This section was amended by 1998 Ky. Acts chs. 23 and 48. Where these Acts are not in conflict, they have been codified together. Where a conflict exists, Acts ch. 48, which was last enacted by the General Assembly, prevails under KRS 446.250. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11043</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>