<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="150" order_by="150">FISH AND WILDLIFE RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>150.680</section_number><catch_line>Concurrent criminal jurisdiction of portions of Trigg and Lyon Counties within boundaries of Land Between the Lakes ceded to United States. </catch_line><order_by>680</order_by><text>Kentucky cedes to the United States criminal jurisdiction concurrent with that of Kentucky, solely for the purposes of Section 13 of Title 18 of the United States Code and enforcement proceedings pursuant thereto, over those portions of Trigg and Lyon Counties that lie within the boundaries of the Kentucky portion of Land Between the Lakes and are more specifically described as follows: <section prefix="1">Beginning at a point in the Tennessee River at Tennessee River mile 49.2, such being the point of separation between the Kentucky-Tennessee state line and the Trigg County-Calloway County line; thence with the Trigg County-Calloway County line as it meanders northward with the river for a distance of approximately 5.5 miles to a point where the Marshall County-Calloway County line intersects the Trigg County line; thence with the Trigg County-Marshall County line and the river as they meander northward approximately 9 miles to a point where the Trigg County-Lyon County line intersects the Marshall County line; thence with the Lyon County-Marshall County line in a northerly direction to a point in said county line opposite Tennessee River mile 25.7; thence leaving the Lyon County-Marshall County line and running N. 53 deg. 30 min. E. approximately 3,795 feet to U.S. TVA Monument 2CN-6 in the 378-foot contour on the east shore of Kentucky Lake; thence with the 378-foot contour as it meanders northerly to the southwest end of the canal connecting Kentucky Lake and Lake Barkley; thence continuing with the 378-foot contour as it meanders along the southeast shore of the canal in a northeasterly direction to the northeast end of the canal; thence continuing with the 378-foot contour as it meanders eastward and southward to a point where the 378-foot contour intersects the Kentucky-Tennessee state line, said point being located on the west shore of Lake Barkley opposite Cumberland River mile 74.6; thence with the Kentucky-Tennessee state line in a westerly direction for a distance of approximately 8.6 miles to the point of beginning. The combined distance of the calls in the foregoing description that follow the meandering of the 378-foot contour from U.S. TVA Monument 2CN-6 to the Kentucky-Tennessee state line on the west shore of Lake Barkley is approximately 260 miles. </section><section prefix="2">Nothing in this section shall be construed as ceding to the United States any existing legislative or other regulatory jurisdiction of the Commonwealth of Kentucky. </section></text><history>Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 43, sec. 1. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:58</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2057</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>