<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="520" order_by="520">ESCAPE AND OTHER OFFENSES RELATING TO CUSTODY </unit></structure><section_number>520.100</section_number><catch_line>Fleeing or evading police in the second degree. </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of fleeing or evading police in the second degree when: <section prefix="a">As a pedestrian, and with intent to elude or flee, the person knowingly or wantonly disobeys a direction to stop, given by a person recognized to be a peace officer who has an articulable reasonable suspicion that a crime has been committed by the person fleeing, and in fleeing or eluding the person is the cause of, or creates a substantial risk of, physical injury to any person; or </section><section prefix="b">While operating a motor vehicle with intent to elude or flee, the person knowingly or wantonly disobeys a recognized direction to stop his vehicle, given by a person recognized to be a peace officer. </section></section><section prefix="2">No offense is committed under this section when the conduct involved constitutes a failure to comply with a directive of a traffic control officer. </section><section prefix="3">Fleeing or evading police in the second degree is a Class A misdemeanor. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 350, sec. 8, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 606, sec. 162, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 178, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19877</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>