<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="342" order_by="342">WORKERS' COMPENSATION </unit></structure><section_number>342.335</section_number><catch_line>Fraud and misrepresentation in filing or delaying the filing of claims and in receiving or providing services or benefits -- Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>335</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall knowingly file, or permit to be filed, any false or fraudulent claim on his or her behalf to compensation or other benefits under this chapter, or by fraud, deceit, or misrepresentation procure or cause to be made or receive any payments of compensation or other benefits under this chapter to which the recipient is not lawfully entitled, or conspire with, aid, or abet another so to do. No person shall by deceit or misrepresentation or with intent to defraud cause or procure or conspire with, aid or abet another in so causing or procuring any person entitled to compensation or other benefits under this chapter to delay or omit to claim title thereto or to accept the payment of a less sum than that to which he or she may be lawfully entitled thereunder. </section><section prefix="2">Any person, as that term is defined in KRS 342.0011, who knowingly, as defined in KRS 501.020, makes any false representation, including misrepresentations of hazards, classifications, payrolls, or other facts by an employer or its agent that are designed to cause a reduction in the employer's premium, for the purpose of or in the course of receiving or providing any service or benefit available under this chapter, shall be subject to the civil fines imposed pursuant to KRS 342.990 for a violation of this subsection. In addition, if a person who violates the provisions of this subsection is also dependent upon a professional license to provide any service or benefit under this chapter, the commissioner shall refer the matter to the appropriate licensing body and recommend revocation of that person's license to work at his or her profession in the Commonwealth of Kentucky. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1819, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1996 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 19, effective December 12, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 181, Part 13, sec. 63, effective April 4, 1994. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4945. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32479</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>