<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="198" order_by="198">B HOUSING, BUILDINGS, AND CONSTRUCTION - BUILDING CODE </unit></structure><section_number>198B.565</section_number><catch_line>Preparation of designs of system. </catch_line><order_by>565</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The design for any fire protection sprinkler system for buildings and structures shall be prepared by a licensed professional engineer or, if the licensed, professional engineer chooses not to prepare the design, a licensed fire protection sprinkler contractor whose certificate holder is a certified engineering technician, NICET Level III or Level IV, may prepare the design. </section><section prefix="2">When a fire protection sprinkler system is designed by a professional engineer in accordance with subsection (1) of this section, the licensed fire protection sprinkler contractor shall submit to the professional engineer, for his approval, technical drawings and, when required, hydraulic calculations for the installation of the fire protection sprinkler system. Such technical drawings, after approved by the professional engineer, shall be submitted by the professional engineer to the Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction, the insurance authority having jurisdiction, if any, and other authority when required by Kentucky law. </section><section prefix="3">When a fire protection sprinkler system is designed by a licensed fire protection sprinkler contractor in accordance with subsection (1) of this section, the licensed fire protection sprinkler contractor shall submit such design and detailed plans to the Department of Housing, Buildings and Construction, the insurance authority having jurisdiction, if any, and other authority when required by Kentucky law. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 275, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 383, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7027</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>