<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.9105</section_number><catch_line>Powers and responsibilities of Radon Program Advisory Committee. </catch_line><order_by>9105</order_by><text>The committee shall: <section prefix="1">Advise the cabinet with the review, development, and maintenance of standard operating procedures for radon measurement, radon mitigation, laboratory analysis, and quality control; </section><section prefix="2">Advise the cabinet with preparing an annual budget for the use of moneys received by the cabinet from the collection of fees and fines, receipt of grants, and all other radon-related activities; </section><section prefix="3">Review and comment on relevant administrative regulations that are promulgated pursuant to KRS 211.9101 to 211.9135 and make recommendations to and otherwise advise the cabinet on these matters; </section><section prefix="4">Keep minutes of committee meetings and a record of all proceedings; </section><section prefix="5">Make recommendations to the cabinet provided that the final determination rests with the cabinet; </section><section prefix="6">Hold the first meeting of the committee no later than October 1, 2011, to be convened by the commissioner; and </section><section prefix="7">Perform any other duties and responsibilities relating to the topic of radon that may be assigned by the cabinet. </section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 74, sec. 3, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39798</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>