<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.7894</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Coal County College Completion Program. </catch_line><order_by>7894</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The General Assembly recognizes that the bachelor degree attainment rate in the coal-producing counties of Kentucky is lower than the state average. It is the intent of the General Assembly to establish the Kentucky Coal County College Completion Program to assist residents of coal-producing counties who are attending postsecondary education institutions located in coal-producing counties by providing: <section prefix="a">Scholarships to: <section prefix="1">Decrease the financial barriers to bachelor's degree completion; and </section><section prefix="2">Encourage students to remain in the area; and </section></section><section prefix="b">Grants to community colleges located in coal-producing counties to enhance the extent and quality of student support services and program offerings necessary to increase student success and degree production in the area. </section></section><section prefix="2">For purposes of this section: <section prefix="a">"District" means the Kentucky Coal County District consisting of coal-producing counties as defined in KRS 42.4592(1)(c); </section><section prefix="b">"High school" means a Kentucky public high school or a private, parochial, or church school located in Kentucky that has been certified by the Kentucky Board of Education as voluntarily complying with curriculum, certification, and textbook standards established by the Kentucky Board of Education under KRS 156.160; </section><section prefix="c">"Kentucky Coal County College Completion scholarship" or "KCCCC scholarship" means a scholarship described in subsection (1)(a) of this section; </section><section prefix="d">"Kentucky Coal County College Completion student services grant" or "KCCCC student services grant" means a grant described in subsection (1)(b) of this section; and </section><section prefix="e">"Tuition" means the in-state tuition and mandatory fees charged to all students as a condition of enrollment in an undergraduate program. </section></section><section prefix="3">A participating institution shall: <section prefix="a">Be physically located in the district; </section><section prefix="b">Offer bachelor's degree programs; and be: </section><section prefix="c"><section prefix="1">A regionally accredited, independent nonprofit Kentucky college or university licensed by the Council on Postsecondary Education whose main campus is based in the district, including a work-college as determined by the Kentucky Higher Education Assistance Authority; </section><section prefix="2">A four (4) year public university extension campus; or </section><section prefix="3">A regional postsecondary education center, including the University Center of the Mountains. </section></section></section><section prefix="4">A participating institution may establish extension campuses within the district to offer bachelor degree programs for purposes of this section. </section><section prefix="5">A nonparticipating institution shall: <section prefix="a">Have its main campus located in Kentucky but not in the district; </section><section prefix="b">Offer a bachelor's degree program not offered at any participating institution; </section><section prefix="c">Be accredited by the Southern Association of Colleges and Schools; and </section><section prefix="d">Be a public or independent, nonprofit college or university that is licensed by the Council on Postsecondary Education. </section></section><section prefix="6">The Kentucky Higher Education Assistance Authority shall administer the Kentucky Coal County College Completion Program and shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A as may be needed for the administration of the program. </section><section prefix="7">The authority may award a KCCCC scholarship under this section, to the extent funds are available for that purpose, to any person who: <section prefix="a">Is considered a permanent resident of the district for at least one (1) year immediately preceding July 1 of the academic year in which the scholarship is made; </section><section prefix="b">Is a United States citizen; </section><section prefix="c">Is a Kentucky resident as determined by the institution in accordance with criteria established by the Council on Postsecondary Education for the purposes of admission and tuition assessment; </section><section prefix="d">Completes and submits the Free Application for Federal Student Aid for the academic year in which the grant is made; </section><section prefix="e">Has earned at least sixty (60) credits or the equivalent of completed coursework toward a bachelor's degree; </section><section prefix="f">Is enrolled at least half-time at a participating institution, or a nonparticipating institution in accordance with subsection (8) of this section, in upper division courses in a program of study that leads to a bachelor's degree; </section><section prefix="g">Is in good academic standing in accordance with the institution's policy; and </section><section prefix="h">Is not in default on any obligation to the authority under any program administered by the authority under KRS 164.740 to 164.785, except that ineligibility for this reason may be waived by the authority for cause. </section></section><section prefix="8">A student otherwise eligible for the KCCCC scholarship who is enrolled in a nonparticipating institution shall be eligible to receive the KCCCC scholarship if he or she is enrolled in a bachelor's degree program in a field of study that is not offered at any participating institution. A program shall be clearly unlike any degree program offered by a participating institution to be eligible. The authority shall promulgate administrative regulations to establish procedures to designate the approved programs of study at nonparticipating institutions for which an eligible student can receive the KCCCC scholarship, which shall include a program review process that requires fifty percent (50%) or more of the courses offered in a program to be different from courses available in a program offered by a participating institution. The maximum annual total of KCCCC scholarships expended for this purpose, to the extent funds are available, shall not exceed five percent (5%) of the amount appropriated for KCCCC scholarships. </section><section prefix="9"><section prefix="a">The KCCCC scholarship amount provided to a student may be applied to the student's cost of attendance and shall be forty percent (40%), up to the maximum amount defined in subsections (10) and (11) of this section, of the amount remaining after subtracting the student's federal and state grants and scholarships from the institution's published tuition and mandatory fees amount that is used for purposes of packaging federal student aid. Work study and student loan funds shall not be included in the calculation. </section><section prefix="b">For purposes of this subsection, the tuition amount for a work-college, as described in subsection (3)(c)1. of this section, shall be the average tuition and mandatory fees amount of the participating institutions that are described in subsection (3)(c)1. of this section and are not work-colleges. </section><section prefix="c">Students attending less than full-time shall receive a pro rata amount as determined by the authority. </section></section><section prefix="10">The maximum KCCCC scholarship award amount for the 2014-2015 academic year shall not exceed: <section prefix="a">Six thousand eight hundred dollars ($6,800) per academic year for a student attending a participating institution that is a nonprofit, independent college or university; </section><section prefix="b">Two thousand three hundred dollars ($2,300) per academic year for a student attending a participating institution that is a public university extension campus or a regional postsecondary education center; or </section><section prefix="c">Three thousand four hundred dollars ($3,400) per academic year for a student attending a nonparticipating institution as prescribed in subsection (8) of this section. </section></section><section prefix="11">The authority shall calculate the average annual percentage increase in tuition for the six (6) comprehensive universities as defined in KRS 164.001. The maximum KCCCC scholarship amounts in subsection (10) of this section shall be increased for each subsequent academic year by the total average percentage increase since the 2014-2015 academic year. </section><section prefix="12">The authority shall award KCCCC scholarships chronologically based on when applicants submit the Free Application for Federal Student Aid until funds are exhausted, except prior recipients shall be awarded before any new KCCCC scholarship recipients. Applicants who received a KCCCC scholarship in the immediately preceding academic semester and apply by the deadline established by the authority shall be awarded first. </section><section prefix="13">A student may receive a KCCCC scholarship for a maximum of five (5) full-time fall or spring academic semesters, or their equivalent under a trimester or quarter system, or until the completion of a first bachelor's degree, whichever occurs first. The authority shall determine the equivalent usage of academic semester eligibility for students enrolled less than full-time. </section><section prefix="14">The authority may award KCCCC student services grants under this section, to the extent funds are available for that purpose, to a Kentucky Community and Technical College System institution that is physically located in the district. </section><section prefix="15">The maximum annual KCCCC student services grant shall be one hundred fifty thousand dollars ($150,000) per institution. </section><section prefix="16">KCCCC student services grants shall be used for the following purposes: <section prefix="a">To expand outreach services in high schools, in coordination with outreach services provided by the authority, to advise students of the advantages and importance of seeking a bachelor's degree and the opportunities to attain a bachelor's degree within the district; </section><section prefix="b">To expand advising resources to encourage completion of associate degree programs and transfer into bachelor's degree programs; </section><section prefix="c">To expand career advising resources to better link baccalaureate academic pursuits to career opportunities, especially within the district; and </section><section prefix="d">To provide multifaceted retention and student transfer initiatives to encourage associate degree completion leading to bachelor's degree programs. </section></section><section prefix="17">Beginning November 1, 2015, and each year thereafter, the authority shall make an annual report to the Interim Joint Committee on Education on the status of the Kentucky Coal County College Completion Program. </section><section prefix="18">Every four (4) years after implementation of the Kentucky Coal County College Completion Program, the authority shall evaluate the program to ensure the policy objectives are being realized and to suggest adjustments to maximize the increase in bachelor's degree completion rates. </section><section prefix="19">Each participating institution, nonparticipating institution, and recipient of a KCCCC student services grant shall make data available to the authority for the report and evaluation described in subsections (17) and (18) of this section. </section><section prefix="20">If any participating institution, nonparticipating institution, or recipient of a KCCCC student services grant does not demonstrate improved performance in student performance metrics, including but not limited to graduation and transfer rates, the authority may revoke the institution's eligibility for participation in the KCCCC scholarship or KCCCC student services grant.  </section><section prefix="21"><section prefix="a">The coal county college completion scholarship fund is hereby created as a trust fund in the State Treasury to be administered by the Kentucky Higher Education Assistance Authority for the purpose of providing scholarships described in subsection (1)(a) of this section. </section><section prefix="b">The trust fund shall consist of amounts appropriated annually from coal severance tax receipts to the extent that the enacted biennial budget of the Commonwealth includes such appropriations. The trust fund may also receive gifts and grants from public and private sources and federal funds. No general fund moneys shall be appropriated for this purpose. </section><section prefix="c">Any unallotted or unencumbered balances in the trust fund shall be invested as provided in KRS 42.500(9). Income earned from the investments shall be credited to the trust fund. </section><section prefix="d">Notwithstanding KRS 45.229, any fund balance at the close of the fiscal year shall not lapse but shall be carried forward to the next fiscal year and continuously appropriated only for the purposes specified in this section. </section></section><section prefix="22"><section prefix="a">The coal county college completion student services grant fund is hereby created as a trust fund in the State Treasury to be administered by the Kentucky Higher Education Assistance Authority for the purpose of providing grants described in subsection (1)(b) of this section. </section><section prefix="b">The trust fund shall consist of amounts appropriated annually from coal severance tax receipts to the extent that the enacted biennial budget of the Commonwealth includes such appropriations. The trust fund may also receive gifts and grants from public and private sources and federal funds. No general fund moneys shall be appropriated for this purpose. </section><section prefix="c">Any unallotted or unencumbered balances in the trust fund shall be invested as provided in KRS 42.500(9). Income earned from the investments shall be credited to the trust fund. </section><section prefix="d">Notwithstanding KRS 45.229, any fund balance at the close of the fiscal year shall not lapse but shall be carried forward to the next fiscal year and continuously appropriated only for the purposes specified in this section. </section></section></text><history> Created 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 133, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43513</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>