<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXII" order_by="22">LEVEES, DRAINAGE, AND RECLAMATION OF LANDS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="266" order_by="266">LEVEES </unit></structure><section_number>266.100</section_number><catch_line>Board of levee commissioners -- Appointment -- Terms -- Removal of members. </catch_line><order_by>100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The county judge/executive shall, upon the creation of a levee district as provided in KRS 65.182 and 266.010 and every four (4) years thereafter, appoint five (5) resident landowners of the vicinity of the levee to be known as the board of levee commissioners. The commissioners shall serve for a term of four (4) years and until their successors are appointed. The county judge/executive shall fill any vacancies in the board. All appointments to the board shall be subject to the approval of the fiscal court. </section><section prefix="2">Members of the board of levee commissioners may be removed from office as provided by KRS 65.007. </section><section prefix="3">When a multicounty levee district is established the board shall be appointed by the county judges/executive of the counties involved. Appointments shall be apportioned among the counties in ratio to the portion of the levee to be constructed within each county. </section><section prefix="4">The board of levee commissioners is a body politic, with the status of a corporation, and in its corporate name may do everything authorized by law with reference to public levees. </section></text><history>Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 26, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 18, sec. 24, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 394, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 4. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2417c-8, 2417c-14. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12852</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>