<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="167" order_by="167">EDUCATION OF THE PHYSICALLY HANDICAPPED </unit></structure><section_number>167.015</section_number><catch_line>Management for Kentucky School for the Blind and School for the Deaf -- Extramural services and programs. </catch_line><order_by>015</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky School for the Blind at Louisville, Kentucky, and the Kentucky School for the Deaf at Danville, Kentucky, shall be managed and controlled by the Kentucky Board of Education. The board shall have possession and the responsibility and authority for preservation, repair, and control of the buildings and grounds belonging to the state and dedicated to the schools. The board may, except as provided in KRS 45A.045, sell any property held for the use and benefit of the schools, and purchase other property deemed by the board to be suitably and conveniently located, and erect buildings necessary for carrying out the purposes of the schools. The board may promulgate administrative regulations to carry into effect its powers with respect to the schools, and may require from the superintendent of the schools any reports and information it desires as to the condition of the schools. </section><section prefix="2">In addition to being recognized as a school providing quality, full-time educational services to students who are deaf and hard of hearing or who are blind or visually impaired, the Kentucky School for the Deaf and the Kentucky School for the Blind shall also serve as the Statewide Educational Resource Center on Deafness and as the Statewide Educational Resource Center on Blindness, respectively. They shall provide technical assistance and resource services to local school districts, parents, and other agencies or organizations serving children and youth who are deaf and hard of hearing or who are blind or visually impaired. Depending on the availability of funding, services may include, but not be limited to, assessments; consultations on curriculum; language and communication; orientation and mobility; classroom devices, including telecommunication devices for the deaf and hard of hearing and Braille for the blind and visually impaired; assistive technology; professional development; and program development and implementation. The Kentucky School for the Deaf and the Kentucky School for the Blind may enter into collaborative agreements with local school districts and other public and private agencies to provide for regional or satellite programs for children and youth who are deaf and hard of hearing or who are blind or visually impaired. </section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 219, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 598, effective July 13, 1990; and ch. 496, sec. 52, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 286, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 82, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 154. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 68, Art. IV, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><lrc-note> (7/13/90).  The Act amending this section prevails over the repeal and reenactment in House Bill 940, Acts Ch. 476, pursuant to Section 653(1) of Acts Ch. 476. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4696</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>