<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="194" order_by="194">A CABINET FOR HEALTH AND FAMILY SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>194A.550</section_number><catch_line>Training requirements for staff of agencies providing shelter services for victims. </catch_line><order_by>550</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The secretary for health and family services shall promulgate administrative regulations under KRS Chapter 13A setting forth the requirements for initial training courses and continuing education courses for staff of agencies providing protective shelter services for victims of domestic violence. The components of the training shall include the dynamics of domestic violence, effects of domestic violence on adult and child victims, legal remedies for protection, lethality and risk issues, model protocols for addressing domestic violence, available community resources and victims services, and reporting requirements. The training shall be developed in consultation with legal, victim services, victim advocacy, and mental health professionals with an expertise in domestic violence. </section><section prefix="2">Each agency providing protective shelter services for victims of domestic violence shall develop and provide initial training courses and, at least once every two (2) years, continuing education courses which comply with the requirements developed pursuant to subsection (1) of this section, for staff of the agency. </section></text><history> Repealed, reenacted, and amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 36, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 54, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><former-codification>KRS 194B.535. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6681</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>