<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="V" order_by="5">MILITARY AFFAIRS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="39" order_by="39">B LOCAL EMERGENCY MANAGEMENT PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>39B.060</section_number><catch_line>Emergency operations plan. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The city or county, joint county when counties are acting jointly under KRS 39B.010, or city/county emergency operations plan developed pursuant to the provisions of KRS Chapters 39A to 39F shall include adequate provisions or procedures to assess, mitigate, prepare for, respond to, and recover from all disaster or emergency incidents contemplated by KRS 39A.010, 39A.020, or 39A.030 and shall provide for all functions contemplated by these sections. </section><section prefix="2">The local emergency operations plan shall be submitted by the local director to the county judge/executive, or chief executive officers of each participating county when counties are acting jointly under KRS 39B.010, mayor, or chief executive of other local governments immediately following each regular election for these offices, for approval and adoption by the local chief executives through issuance of an executive order pursuant to the provisions of KRS Chapters 39A to 39F. </section><section prefix="3">In the event of a conflict between a city emergency operations plan and a county emergency operations plan and decisions made thereunder: <section prefix="a">The decision made pursuant to the county plan shall prevail if the incident, its consequences, or the threat thereof, extend beyond the boundaries of the city; </section><section prefix="b">The decision made pursuant to the city plan shall prevail if the incident, its consequences, or the threat of the incident, do not extend beyond the boundaries of the city; and </section><section prefix="c">The same precedence shall govern plans of urban-counties and charter counties. </section></section><section prefix="4">The joint plan established by counties acting jointly pursuant to KRS 39B.010 shall incorporate a joint decision-making process whereby the chief executive officers, or their designees, use the integrated emergency management system and the unified incident command system set out in KRS 39A.230 to deal with any incident. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 7, effective July 15, 2014. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 226, sec. 34, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43394</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>