<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="275" order_by="275">LIMITED LIABILITY COMPANIES </unit></structure><section_number>275.337</section_number><catch_line>Derivative actions.   </catch_line><order_by>337</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A member may maintain a direct action against a limited liability company, another member, or a manager to redress an injury sustained by, or to enforce a duty owed to, the member if the member can prevail without showing an injury or breach of duty to the company. </section><section prefix="2">A member may maintain a derivative action to redress an injury sustained by or enforce a duty owed to a limited liability company if: <section prefix="a">The member shall first make a demand on the other members and, if the company is manager-managed, the managers, requesting that they cause the company to bring an action to redress the injury or enforce the right, and they do not bring the action within a reasonable time; or </section><section prefix="b">A demand would be futile. </section></section><section prefix="3">A derivative action on behalf of a limited liability company shall be maintained only by a person that is a member at the time the action is commenced and who: <section prefix="a">Was a member when the conduct giving rise to the action occurred; or </section><section prefix="b">Acquired the status as a member by operation of law or pursuant to the terms of the operating agreement from a person that was a member at the time of the conduct giving rise to the action occurred. </section></section><section prefix="4">In a derivative action on behalf of the limited liability company, the complaint shall state with particularity: <section prefix="a">The date and content of the member’s demand and the response to the demand; or </section><section prefix="b">The reason the demand should be excused as futile. </section></section><section prefix="5">Except as otherwise provided in subsection (8) of this section: <section prefix="a">Any proceeds or other benefits of a derivative action on behalf of a limited liability company, whether by judgment, compromise, or settlement, are the property of the company and not of the plaintiff; and </section><section prefix="b">If the plaintiff receives any proceeds or other benefits, the plaintiff shall immediately remit them to the company. </section></section><section prefix="6">A derivative action on behalf of a limited liability company may not be voluntarily dismissed or settled without the court’s approval. </section><section prefix="7">The proper venue for a direct action under subsection (1) of this section or a derivative action shall be the Circuit Court for the county in which the company maintains its registered office and agent. </section><section prefix="8">On termination of the proceeding brought pursuant to this section, the court may: <section prefix="a">Require the plaintiff member to pay any defendant’s reasonable expenses, including counsel fees, incurred in defending the proceeding to the extent it finds that the proceeding or any portion thereof was commenced without reasonable cause or for an improper purpose; and </section><section prefix="b">Require the limited liability company to pay the plaintiff member’s reasonable expenses, including counsel fees, incurred in the proceeding to the extent it finds that the proceeding has resulted in a substantial benefit to the company. </section></section></text><history> Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 34, sec. 50, effective June 24, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44363</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>