<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.826</section_number><catch_line>Employment status.   </catch_line><order_by>826</order_by><text><section prefix="1">All certified and equivalent employees shall serve a one (1) year probationary period for renewal of limited status. An employee may be separated from the position or reduced in class during this initial probationary period and shall not have a right to appeal except as provided in KRS 156.820. If the employee is separated from the position, notice in writing shall be received at least ten (10) working days prior to separation. A copy of the notification shall be forwarded to the commissioner. Unless the commissioner notifies the employee of separation prior to the end of the initial probationary period, the employee shall be eligible for renewable limited status. Limited status employees are subject to reemployment on an annual basis. Limited status employees may be dismissed without cause before the annual anniversary date. </section><section prefix="2">After completion of the initial probationary period, the individual shall be considered on limited status until successful completion of the fourth year, at which time the employee may be placed on continuing status. </section><section prefix="3">An employee who has been assigned continuing status may not be demoted, disciplined, or dismissed without cause except as provided by provisions in KRS 156.800 to 156.860. </section><section prefix="4">An employee with continuing status who has been promoted shall serve a probationary period of one (1) year in the new position. During the period of promotional probation, the employee shall retain the rights and privileges granted by the provisions of KRS 156.800 to 156.860 to continuing status employees. </section><section prefix="5">During the promotional probationary period, the employee with continuing status may be reverted at the discretion of the appointing authority to a position in the class formerly held. </section><section prefix="6">A continuing status employee who has been laid-off may return to a position with continuing status if an appropriate position is available. </section></text><history> Repealed, reenacted, renumbered, and amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 16, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 526, sec. 23, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 417, sec. 7, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 470, sec. 12, effective July 1, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2013 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, C, 3, (17) at 631. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><former-codification>KRS 151B.070. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=42177</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>