<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="148" order_by="148">PARKS AND TOURISM </unit></structure><section_number>148.650</section_number><catch_line>Establishment and designation of trails. </catch_line><order_by>650</order_by><text><section prefix="1">State scenic trails shall be established and designated by the department on lands administered by the department and on lands under the jurisdiction of a state department, political subdivision, or private lands providing:  <section prefix="a">Such trails are not located in nor traverse any state-owned wildlife management area; and  </section><section prefix="b">Such trails meet the criteria established in KRS 148.610 to 148.780 and supplementary criteria as may be prescribed by the department.  </section></section><section prefix="2">The department may establish and designate state recreation trails on lands administered by the department and on lands under the jurisdiction of a state department, political subdivision, or private lands providing:  <section prefix="a">Such trails are not located in nor traverse any state-owned wildlife management area;  </section><section prefix="b">Such trails are reasonably accessible to urban areas;  </section><section prefix="c">Such trails meet the criteria established in KRS 148.610 to 148.780 and supplementary criteria as may be prescribed by the department; and  </section><section prefix="d">Fee simple, scenic easements, or other rights are obtained from private landowners through which a state recreation trail may pass. The department may establish and designate state recreation trails on lands under the jurisdiction of a federal agency, when in the opinion of the federal agency and the commissioner such lands may be so developed under the provisions of federal law and the provisions of paragraphs (b) and (c) of this subsection.  </section></section><section prefix="3">As provided in this section, trails within park, forest, recreation areas, state natural areas, or any other public area excluding state-owned wildlife management areas may be established and designated state recreation trails by the department.  </section><section prefix="4">Connecting or side trails within park, forest, recreation areas, or natural areas may be established, designated, and marked as components of a state recreation or state scenic trail. </section></text><history>Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 288, sec. 6. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1779</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>