<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="194" order_by="194">A CABINET FOR HEALTH AND FAMILY SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>194A.707</section_number><catch_line>Certification -- Administrative regulations -- Accreditation by other organizations -- Fees -- Compliance. </catch_line><order_by>707</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall establish by the promulgation of administrative regulation under KRS Chapter 13A, an initial and annual certification review process for assisted-living communities. This administrative regulation shall establish procedures related to applying for, reviewing, and approving, denying, or revoking certification, as well as the conduct of hearings upon appeals as governed by KRS Chapter 13B. </section><section prefix="2">An on-site visit of an assisted-living community shall be conducted by the cabinet: <section prefix="a">As part of the initial certification review process; </section><section prefix="b">On a biennial basis as part of the certification review process if during or since the previous certification review an assisted-living community has not received: <section prefix="1">Any statement of danger, unless withdrawn by the cabinet; or </section><section prefix="2">A finding substantiated by the cabinet that the assisted-living community delivered a health service; and </section></section><section prefix="c">Within one (1) year of the date of the previous certification review if during or since the last certification review an assisted-living community has received: <section prefix="1">Any statement of danger that was not withdrawn by the cabinet; or </section><section prefix="2">A finding substantiated by the cabinet that the assisted-living community delivered a health service. </section></section></section><section prefix="3">No business shall market its service as an assisted-living community unless it has: <section prefix="a">Filed a current application for the business to be certified by the department as an assisted-living community; or </section><section prefix="b">Received certification by the department as an assisted-living community. </section></section><section prefix="4">No business that has been denied or had its certification revoked shall operate or market its service as an assisted-living community unless it has: <section prefix="a">Filed a current application for the business to be certified by the department as an assisted-living community; and </section><section prefix="b">Received certification as an assisted-living community from the department. Revocation of certification may be grounds for the department to not reissue certification for one (1) year if ownership remains substantially the same. </section></section><section prefix="5">No business shall operate as an assisted-living community unless its owner or manager has: <section prefix="a">Filed a current application for the business to be certified as an assisted-living community by the department; and </section><section prefix="b">Received certification as an assisted-living community from the department. </section></section><section prefix="6">The department shall determine the feasibility of recognizing accreditation by other organizations in lieu of certification from the department. </section><section prefix="7">Individuals designated by the department to conduct certification reviews shall have the skills, training, experience, and ongoing education to perform certification reviews. </section><section prefix="8">Upon receipt of an application for certification, the department shall assess an assisted-living community certification fee in the amount of twenty dollars ($20) per living unit that in the aggregate for each assisted-living community is no less than three hundred dollars ($300) and no more than one thousand six hundred dollars ($1,600). The department shall submit to the Legislative Research Commission, by June 30 of each year, a breakdown of fees assessed and costs incurred for conducting certification reviews. </section><section prefix="9">The department shall submit to the Legislative Research Commission and make available to any interested person at no charge, by June 30 of each year, in summary format, all findings from certification reviews conducted during the prior twelve (12) months. </section><section prefix="10">Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, the department may request any additional information from an assisted-living community or conduct additional on-site visits to ensure compliance with the provisions of KRS 194A.700 to 194A.729. </section><section prefix="11">Failure to follow an assisted-living community's policies, practices, and procedures shall not result in a finding of noncompliance unless the assisted-living community is out of compliance with a related requirement under KRS 194A.700 to 194A.729. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 36, sec. 4, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 9, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 163, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 4, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (6/20/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 95, 97, 98, 99, 123, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6699</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>