<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.7621</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 65.7621 to 65.7643. </catch_line><order_by>7621</order_by><text>As used in KRS 65.7621 to 65.7643, unless the context requires otherwise: <section prefix="1">"Administrator" means the state administrator of CMRS emergency telecommunications under KRS 65.7625; </section><section prefix="2">"Automatic location identification", or "ALI" means an enhanced 911 service capability that enables the automatic display of information defining the approximate geographic location of the wireless telephone used to place a 911 call and includes the term "pseudo-automatic number identification;" </section><section prefix="3">"Automatic number identification", or "ANI" means an enhanced 911 service capability that enables the automatic display on an ALI screen of the ten-digit, or equivalent, wireless telephone number used to place a 911 call; </section><section prefix="4">"CMRS" means commercial mobile radio service under Sections 3(27) and 332(d) of the Federal Telecommunications Act of 1996, 47 U.S.C. secs. 151 et seq., and the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1993, as it existed on August 10, 1993. The term includes the term "wireless" and service provided by any wireless real time two-way voice communication device, including radio-telephone communications used in cellular telephone service, personal communications service, and the functional or competitive equivalent of a radio-telephone communications line used in cellular telephone service, a personal communications service, or a network radio access line; </section><section prefix="5">"CMRS Board" or "board" means the Commercial Mobile Radio Service Emergency Telecommunications Board of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="6">"CMRS connection" means a mobile handset telephone number assigned to a CMRS customer; </section><section prefix="7">"CMRS customer" means an end user to whom a mobile handset telephone number is assigned and to whom CMRS is provided in return for compensation; </section><section prefix="8">"CMRS Fund" means the commercial mobile radio service emergency telecommunications fund; </section><section prefix="9">"CMRS provider" means a person or entity who provides CMRS to an end user. The term includes both facilities-based resellers and nonfacilities-based resellers; </section><section prefix="10">"CMRS service charge" means the CMRS emergency telephone service charge levied under KRS 65.7629(3) and collected under KRS 65.7635; </section><section prefix="11">"FCC order" means the Order of the Federal Communications Commission, FCC Docket No. 94-102, adopted effective October 1, 1996, including any subsequent amendments or modifications thereof; </section><section prefix="12">"Local exchange carrier" or "LEC" means any person or entity who is authorized to provide telephone exchange service or exchange access in the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="13">"Local government" means any city, county, charter county, or urban-county government of the Commonwealth, or any other governmental entity maintaining a PSAP; </section><section prefix="14">"Mobile telephone handset telephone number" means the ten (10) digit number assigned to a CMRS connection; </section><section prefix="15">"Proprietary information" means information held as private property, including customer lists and other related information, technology descriptions, technical information, or trade secrets; </section><section prefix="16">"Pseudo-automatic number identification" means a wireless enhanced 911 service capability that enables the automatic display of the number of the cell site or cell face; </section><section prefix="17">"Public safety answering point" or "PSAP" means a communications facility that is assigned the responsibility to receive 911 calls originating in a given area and, as appropriate, to dispatch public safety services or to extend, transfer, or relay 911 calls to appropriate public safety agencies; </section><section prefix="18">"Service supplier" means a person or entity who provides local exchange telephone service to a telephone subscriber; </section><section prefix="19">"Wireless enhanced 911 system," "wireless E911 system," "wireless enhanced 911 service," or "wireless E911 service" means an emergency telephone system that provides the end user of the CMRS connection with wireless 911 service and, in addition, directs 911 calls to appropriate public safety answering points based on the geographical location from which the call originated and provides the capability for automatic number identification and automatic location identification features in accordance with the requirements of the FCC order; and </section><section prefix="20">"Tier III CMRS provider" means a non-nationwide Commercial Mobile Radio Service provider with no more than five hundred thousand (500,000) subscribers as of December 31, 2001. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 33, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 219, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 92, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 535, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><lrc-note> (6/25/2009). This statute, as amended by 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 12, sec. 33, contained a reference in subsection (1) to "Section 4 of this Act," a statute codified at KRS 42.724. After consultation with the drafter and examination of the materials in the bill folder, the reference has been replaced with "KRS 65.7625" (Section 34 of that Act) by the Reviser of Statutes during codification to correct a manifest clerical or typographical error. This correction has been made under the authority of KRS 7.136(1).  (7/12/2006).  2006 Ky. Acts ch. 193, sec. 14, instructs the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in the Act, as it confirms reorganization within the executive branch and establishes the Kentucky Office of Homeland Security. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23500</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>