<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions.   </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text><section prefix="1">"Cabinet," as used in KRS 186.400 to 186.640, means the Transportation Cabinet; except as specifically designated, "cabinet," as used in KRS 186.020 to 186.270, means the Transportation Cabinet only with respect to motor vehicles, other than commercial vehicles; "cabinet," as used in KRS 186.020 to 186.270, means the Department of Vehicle Regulation when used with respect to commercial vehicles. </section><section prefix="2">"Highway" means every way or place of whatever nature when any part of it is open to the use of the public, as a matter of right, license, or privilege, for the purpose of vehicular traffic. </section><section prefix="3">"Manufacturer" means any person engaged in manufacturing motor vehicles who will, under normal conditions during the year, manufacture or assemble at least ten (10) new motor vehicles. </section><section prefix="4">"Motor vehicle" means in KRS 186.020 to 186.260, all vehicles, as defined in paragraph (a) of subsection (8) of this section, which are propelled otherwise than by muscular power. As used in KRS 186.400 to 186.640, it means all vehicles, as defined in paragraph (b) of subsection (8) of this section, which are self-propelled. "Motor vehicle" shall not include a moped as defined in this section, but shall include low-speed vehicles as defined in this section. </section><section prefix="5">"Moped" means either a motorized bicycle whose frame design may include one (1) or more horizontal crossbars supporting a fuel tank so long as it also has pedals, or a motorized bicycle with a step-through type frame which may or may not have pedals rated no more than two (2) brake horsepower, a cylinder capacity not exceeding fifty (50) cubic centimeters, an automatic transmission not requiring clutching or shifting by the operator after the drive system is engaged, and capable of a maximum speed of not more than thirty (30) miles per hour. </section><section prefix="6">"Operator" means any person in actual control of a motor vehicle upon a highway. </section><section prefix="7"><section prefix="a">"Owner" means a person who holds the legal title of a vehicle or a person who pursuant to a bona fide sale has received physical possession of the vehicle subject to any applicable security interest. </section><section prefix="b">A vehicle is the subject of an agreement for the conditional sale or lease, with the vendee or lessee entitled to possession of the vehicle, upon performance of the contract terms, for a period of three hundred sixty-five (365) days or more and with the right of purchase upon performance of the conditions stated in the agreement and with an immediate right of possession vested in the conditional vendee or lessee, or if a mortgagor of a vehicle is entitled to possession, the conditional vendee or lessee or mortgagor shall be deemed the owner. </section><section prefix="c">A licensed motor vehicle dealer who transfers physical possession of a motor vehicle to a purchaser pursuant to a bona fide sale, and complies with the requirements of KRS 186A.220, shall not be deemed the owner of that motor vehicle solely due to an assignment to his dealership or a certificate of title in the dealership's name. Rather, under these circumstances, ownership shall transfer upon delivery of the vehicle to the purchaser, subject to any applicable security interest. </section></section><section prefix="8"><section prefix="a">"Vehicle," as used in KRS 186.020 to 186.260, includes all agencies for the transportation of persons or property over or upon the public highways of this Commonwealth and all vehicles passing over or upon said highways, excepting road rollers, road graders, farm tractors, vehicles on which power shovels are mounted, such other construction equipment customarily used only on the site of construction and which is not practical for the transportation of persons or property upon the highways, such vehicles as travel exclusively upon rails, and such vehicles as are propelled by electric power obtained from overhead wires while being operated within any municipality or where said vehicles do not travel more than five (5) miles beyond the city limit of any municipality. </section><section prefix="b">As used in KRS 186.400 to 186.640, "vehicle" means every device in, upon or by which any person or property is or may be transported or drawn upon a public highway, excepting devices moved by human and animal power or used exclusively upon stationary rails or tracks, or which derives its power from overhead wires. </section></section><section prefix="9">KRS 186.020 to 186.270 apply to motor vehicle licenses. KRS 186.400 to 186.640 apply to operator's licenses. </section><section prefix="10">"Dealer" means any person engaging in the business of buying or selling motor vehicles. </section><section prefix="11">"Commercial vehicles" means all motor vehicles that are required to be registered under the terms of KRS 186.050, but not including vehicles primarily designed for carrying passengers and having provisions for not more than nine (9) passengers (including driver), motorcycles, sidecar attachments, pickup trucks and passenger vans which are not being used for commercial or business purposes, and motor vehicles registered under KRS 186.060. </section><section prefix="12">"Resident" means any person who has established Kentucky as his or her state of domicile. Proof of residency shall include but not be limited to a deed or property tax bill, utility agreement or utility bill, or rental housing agreement. The possession by an operator of a vehicle of a valid Kentucky operator's license shall be prima-facie evidence that the operator is a resident of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="13">"Special status individual" means: <section prefix="a">"Asylee" means any person lawfully present in the United States who possesses an I-94 card issued by the United States Department of Justice, Immigration and Naturalization Service, on which it states "asylum status granted indefinitely pursuant to Section 208 of the Immigration &amp; Nationality Act"; </section><section prefix="b">"K-1 status" means the status of any person lawfully present in the United States who has been granted permission by the United States Department of Justice, Immigration and Naturalization Service to enter the United States for the purpose of marrying a United States citizen within ninety (90) days from the date of that entry; </section><section prefix="c">"Refugee" means any person lawfully present in the United States who possesses an I-94 card issued by the United States Department of Justice, Immigration and Naturalization Service, on which it states "admitted as a refugee pursuant to Section 207 of the Immigration &amp; Nationality Act"; and </section><section prefix="d">"Paroled in the Public Interest" means any person lawfully present in the United States who possesses an I-94 card issued by the United States Department of Justice, Immigration and Naturalization Service, on which it states "paroled pursuant to Section 212 of the Immigration &amp; Nationality Act for an indefinite period of time." </section></section><section prefix="14">"Instruction permit" includes both motor vehicle instruction permits and motorcycle instruction permits. </section><section prefix="15">"Motorcycle" means any motor driven vehicle having a seat or saddle for the use of the operator and designed to travel on not more than three (3) wheels in contact with the ground, including vehicles on which the operator and passengers ride in an enclosed cab. "Motorcycle" shall include an alternative-speed motorcycle as defined in this section, but shall not include a tractor or a moped as defined in this section. </section><section prefix="16">"Low-speed vehicle" means a motor vehicle that: <section prefix="a">Is self-propelled using an electric motor, combustion-driven motor, or a combination thereof; </section><section prefix="b">Is four (4) wheeled; and </section><section prefix="c">Is designed to operate at a speed not to exceed twenty-five (25) miles per hour as certified by the manufacturer. </section></section><section prefix="17">"Alternative-speed motorcycle" means a motorcycle that: <section prefix="a">Is self-propelled using an electric motor, combustion-driven motor, or a combination thereof; </section><section prefix="b">Is three (3) wheeled; </section><section prefix="c">Has a fully enclosed cab and includes at least one (1) door for entry; and </section><section prefix="d">Is designed to operate at a speed not to exceed forty (40) miles per hour as certified by the manufacturer. </section></section><section prefix="18">"Multiple-vehicle driving range" means an enclosed area that is not part of a highway or otherwise open to the public on which a number of motor vehicles may be used simultaneously to provide driver training under the supervision of one (1) or more driver training instructors. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 16, sec. 2, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 103, sec. 1, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 264, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 43, sec. 2, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 51, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 287, sec. 1, effective January 1, 1989. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 431, sec. 7, effective January 1, 1987. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 349, sec. 2, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. IX, sec. 20(2), (7), (9). -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 139, sec. 2, effective January 1, 1967. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 1, effective January 1, 1963. -- Amended 1956 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 7, Art. X, sec. 10, effective September 1, 1956. -- Amended 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 190, secs. 1 and 2, effective June 15, 1950. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2739g-1, 2739m-33. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40123</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>