<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="I" order_by="1">SOVEREIGNTY AND JURISDICTION OF THE COMMONWEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="1" order_by="1">BOUNDARIES </unit></structure><section_number>1.400</section_number><catch_line>Boundary with Tennessee. </catch_line><order_by>400</order_by><text> The boundary with Tennessee begins at a point in the middle of the Mississippi River near Compromise, Kentucky, in latitude 36 deg. 29 min. 57 sec. .7, and runs S. 89 deg. 15 min. 18 sec. E.--passing a large set rock at station 0+456, and passing a small set rock at station 12+840, to station 13+215--the west bank of the Mississippi River. Beginning on the east bank of the Mississippi River, at station 35+363, in latitude 36 deg. 30 min. 00 sec. .29, and running S. 89 deg. 35 min. 15 sec. E., passing a set rock at station 35+877, to a second set rock at station 40+055; thence N. 83 deg. 40 min. 19 sec. E., passing stone No. 1 at station 52+80, to station 66+750, a mulberry post; thence S. 83 deg. 35 min. E., to stone No. 2, at station 79+550; thence S. 88 deg. 57 min. 40 sec. E., to station 90+723; thence S. 88 deg. 5 min. E., to station 95+860; thence S. 88 deg. 10 min. E., to station 101+304; thence S. 87 deg. 17 min. E., to stone No. 3, station 105+600; thence as follows, same course continued, to station 106+586; thence S. 88 deg. 25 min. E., to station 111+568; thence S. 88 deg. 5 min. E., to station 117+226; thence S. 89 deg. 16 min. E., to station 125+059; thence S. 89 deg. 46 min. E., to station 125+667; thence S. 87 deg. 57 min. E., to station 128+307; thence S. 88 deg. 33 min. E., to station 131+035; thence S. 88 deg. 33 min., passing stone No. 4, at 132,000 feet, to station 133+720; thence S. 88 deg. 07 min. E., to station 136+360; thence S. 89 deg. 42 min. E., to station 139+007; thence S. 89 deg. 28 min. E., to station 141+770; thence S. 88 deg. 15 min. E., to station 144+575; thence S. 88 deg. 16 min. E., to station 147+230; thence S. 88 deg. 32 min. E., to station 149+855; thence S. 89 deg. 02 min. E., to station 152+586; thence S. 89 deg. 21 min. E., to station 154+864; thence S. 87 deg. 30 min. E., to station 157+439; thence S. 87 deg. 43 min., passing stone No. 5, to station 160+657; thence S. 89 deg. 12 min. E., to station 163+384; thence S. 89 deg. 15 min. E., to station 168+770; thence S. 89 deg. 31 min. E., to station 171+356; thence S. 89 deg. 51 min. E., to station 174+225; thence N. 89 deg. 18 min. E., to station 176+637; thence N. 89 deg. 28 min. E., to station 179+543; thence N. 89 deg. 57 min. E., to station 182+187; thence N. 89 deg. 59 min. E., to station 184+800, at stone No. 6; thence N. 89 deg. 25 min. E., to station 187+531; thence N. 89 deg. 10 min. E., to station 190+226; thence N. 89 deg. 41 min. E., to station 192+830; thence N. 89 deg. 57 min. E., to station 195+490; thence N. 89 deg. 04 min. E., to station 198+358; thence N. 89 deg. 19 min. E., to station 200+833; thence S. 89 deg. 51 min. E., to station 203+504; thence N. 89 deg. 37 min. E., to station 206+169; thence N. 89 deg. 22 min. E., to station 208+784; thence N. 89 deg. 52 min. E., passing stone No. 7, to station 211+619; thence S. 89 deg. 49 min. E., to station 214+210; thence N. 89 deg. 34 min. E., to station 216+908; thence N. 89 deg. 17 min. E., to station 219+611; thence N. 89 deg. 20 min. E., to station 222+296; thence S. 89 deg. 35 min. E., to station 224+970; thence N. 89 deg. 53 min. E., to station 227+620; thence S. 89 deg. 52 min. E., to station 230+286; thence S. 89 deg. 52 min. E., to station 232+921; thence S. 89 deg. 40 min. E., to station 235+628; thence S. 89 deg. 00 min. E., passing stone No. 8, to station 238+337; thence S. 89 deg. 35 min. E., to station 241+116; thence S. 88 deg. 37 min. E., to station 243+774; thence N. 89 deg. 38 min. E., to station 246+290; thence N. 89 deg. 23 min. E., to station 248+956; thence S. 89 deg. 39 min. E., to station 251+591; thence S. 88 deg. 22 min. E., to station 254+268; thence N. 89 deg. 54 min. E., to station 256+950; thence S. 87 deg. 58 min. E., to station 259+320; thence N. 80 deg. 30 min. E., to station 261+960; thence N. 89 deg. 33 min. E., passing stone No. 9, which is 17 feet north of the line, to station 264+900; thence S. 89 deg. 22 min. E., to station 267+551; thence N. 89 deg. 11 min. E., to station 270+106; thence N. 89 deg. 48 min. E., to station 272+872; thence N. 89 deg. 27 min. E., to station 274+980; thence N. 89 deg. 02 min. E., to station 277+917; thence N. 86 deg. 56 min. E., to station 280+883; thence N. 87 deg. 40 min. E., to station 283+578; thence N. 88 deg. 32 min. E., to station 285+960; thence N. 87 deg. 50 min. E., to station 288+669; thence N. 88 deg. 37 min. E., passing stone No. 10, to station 291+376; thence N. 89 deg. 35 min. E., to station 293+993; thence N. 88 deg. 59 min. E., to station 296+679; thence N. 88 deg. 54 min. E., to station 299+333; thence S. 88 deg. 36 min. E., to station 301+989; thence S. 88 deg. 32 min. E., to station 304+650; thence S. 89 deg. 34 min. E., to station 307+523; thence N. 89 deg. 45 min. E., to station 309+998; thence S. 88 deg. 28 min. E., to station 312+975; thence S. 89 deg. 54 min. E., to station 315+642; thence S. 89 deg. 34 min. E., passing stone No. 11, to station 317+908; thence S. 89 deg. 53 min. E., to station 320+560; thence S. 86 deg. 37 min. E., to station 323+200; thence S. 89 deg. 13 min. E., to station 325+682; thence S. 89 deg. 19 min. E., to station 328+412; thence S. 89 deg. 13 min. E., to station 331+075; thence S. 89 deg. 09 min. E., to station 334+188; thence S. 88 deg. 51 min. E., to station 336+386; thence S. 89 deg. 42 min. E., to station 339+458; thence S. 89 deg. 34 min. E., to station 342+446; thence N. 89 deg. 33 min. E., passing stone No. 12, to station 344+756; thence S. 89 deg. 58 min. E., to station 347+391; thence S. 89 deg. 50 min. E., to station 350+022; thence S. 89 deg. 32 min. E., to station 352+614; thence S. 89 deg. 47 min. E., to station 355+378; thence east, to station 357+910; thence S. 89 deg. 33 min. E., to station 360+636; thence S. 89 deg. 45 min. E., to station 363+332; thence S. 89 deg. 16 min. E., to station 365+627; thence S. 89 deg. 29 min. E., to station 368+161; thence S. 89 deg. 25 min. E., passing stone No. 13, to station 371+107; thence S. 89 deg. 18 min. E., to station 373+770; thence S. 88 deg. 40 min. E., to station 376+410; thence N. 88 deg. 58 min. E., to station 378+602; thence N. 89 deg. 53 min. E., to station 381+722; thence S. 89 deg. 51 min. E., to station 384+050; thence S. 89 deg. 28 min. E., to station 386+683; thence S. 89 deg. 21 min. E., to station 388+861; thence N. 89 deg. 07 min. E., to station 391+577; thence S. 89 deg. 36 min. E., to station 394+175; thence N. 89 deg. 23 min. E., passing stone No. 14, to station 396+994; thence N. 88 deg. 56 min. E., to station 399+578; thence S. 88 deg. 42 min. E., to station 402+690; thence S. 85 deg. 45 min. E., to station 405+210; thence east to station 407+833; thence S. 89 deg. 39 min. E., to station 409+587; thence S. 89 deg. 01 min. E., to station 413+050; thence S. 88 deg. 10 min. E., to station 415+686; thence S. 88 deg. 23 min. E., to station 418+469; thence S. 89 deg. 18 min. E., passing stone No. 15, to station 423+918; thence S. 88 deg. 16 min. E., to station 425+975; thence S. 87 deg. 45 min. E., to station 428+195; thence S. 88 deg. 41 min. E., to station 431+829, a small stone on the west bank of the Tennessee River; thence with and down said River to a small stone on the east bank of the Tennessee River, at station 427+721, the river being the common boundary between the two states and subject to their common use and concurrent jurisdiction; thence N. 86 deg. 41 min. E., to station 440+167; thence S. 83 deg. 28 min. E., to station 446+563; thence S. 83 deg. 8 min. E., passing stone No. 16, to station 449+541; thence S. 82 deg. 45 min. E., to station 451+754; thence S. 82 deg. 8 min. E., to station 455+898; thence S. 83 deg. 11 min. E., to station 459+780; thence S. 83 deg. 33 min. E., to station 462+499; thence S. 82 deg. 57 min. E., to station 466+944; thence S. 85 deg. 37 min. E., to station 470+719; thence S. 84 deg. 44 min. E., to station 475+666, at stone No. 17, on the west bank of the Cumberland River; thence S. 85 deg. 29 min. E., passing a small stone on the east bank of Cumberland River, to station 491+313, a small rock at hickory and gum; thence S. 5 deg. 12 min. W. 11,149 feet, to small stone at three black oaks, station 490+302; thence N. 87 deg. 44 min. E., passing stones Nos. 18 and 19, to station 536+512; thence N. 88 deg. 20 min. E., to stone No. 20, at station 550+302; thence N. 88 deg. 30 min. E., to station 552+882; thence N. 89 deg. 21 min. E., to station 567+247; thence N. 89 deg. 16 min. E., to station 577+472, passing stone No. 21; thence N. 88 deg. 44 min. E., to station 585+897; thence N. 89 deg. 31 min. E., to station 591+713; thence N. 87 deg. 15 min. E., to station 598+581; thence N. 89 deg. 41 min. E., to station 600+818; thence N. 89 deg. 28 min. E., to station 602+469, stone No. 22; thence N. 89 deg. 31 min. E., to station 606+144; thence N. 89 deg. 29 min. E., to station 617+818; thence N. 89 deg. 06 min. E., to station 623+595; thence N. 88 deg. 33 min. E., to station 626+027; thence N. 89 deg. 05 min. E., to stone No. 23, at station 628+867; thence N. 89 deg. 08 min. E., to station 634+910; thence N. 88 deg. 47 min. E., to station 637+370; thence N. 89 deg. 54 min. E., to station 645+031; thence N. 89 deg. 24 min. E., to station 650+332; thence N. 89 deg. 58 min. E., passing stone No. 24, to station 655+925; thence N. 89 deg. 25 min. E., to station 661+974; thence N. 89 deg. 43 min. E., to station 668+012; thence S. 89 deg. 46 min. E., to station 676+269; thence N. 88 deg. 33 min. E., to station 678+759; thence N. 88 deg. 50 min. E., passing stone No. 25, to station 685+682; thence N. 89 deg. 27 min. E., to station 690+207; thence N. 89 deg. 31 min. E., to station 698+455; thence N. 89 deg. E., to station 703+451; thence N. 89 deg. 27 min. E., to station 704+913; thence N. 89 deg. 26 min. E., passing stone No. 26, to station 707+827; thence N. 89 deg. 28 min. E., to station 709+759; thence N. 88 deg. 46 min. E., to station 720+694; thence N. 89 deg. 03 min. E., to station 723+591; thence N. 88 deg. 42 min. E., to station 727+474; thence N. 89 deg. 13 min. E., to station 729+870; thence N. 87 deg. 52 min. E., passing stone No. 27, to station 735+796; thence N. 89 deg. E., to station 739+227; thence N. 88 deg. 34 min. E., to station 744+100; thence N. 88 deg. 39 min. E., to station 746+259; thence N. 88 deg. 26 min. E., to station 749+202; thence N. 88 deg. 44 min. E., to station 753+994; thence N. 88 deg. 32 min. E., to station 757+601; thence N. 87 deg. 28 min. E., to station 761+760, at stone No. 28; thence N. 98 deg. 44 min. E., to station 766+453; thence S. 89 deg. 11 min. E., to station 769+468; thence N. 87 deg. 59 min. E., to station 773+549; thence N. 89 deg. 18 min. E., to station 779+196; thence N. 88 deg. 53 min. E., passing stone No. 29, to station 791+286; thence N. 88 deg. 33 min. E., to station 798+393; thence N. 88 deg. 24 min. E., to station 805+863; thence S. 89 deg. 58 min. E., passing stone No. 30, to station 813+522; thence N. 86 deg. 37 min. E., to station 827+196; thence N. 87 deg. 59 min. E., to station 831+967; thence N. 88 deg. 12 min. E., passing stone No. 31, to station 846+533; thence N. 88 deg. 53 min. E., to stone No. 32, at station 856+572; thence S. 47 deg. 53 min. E., to station 866+860, large stone at black-jack; thence N. 68 deg. 1 min. E., to station 870+893, the first corner of the Middleton offset; thence N. 7 deg. 30 min. E., 2484 feet, to second corner; thence S. 82 deg. 30 min. E., 1927 feet, to third corner; thence S. 7 deg. 30 min. W., 1256 feet, to fourth corner, and station 873+125; thence N. 68 deg. 01 min. E., to stone N. 33, at station 884+596, (beech); thence S. 88 deg. 19 min. E., to station 892+213; thence S. 88 deg. 2 min. E., to station 897+903; thence S. 89 deg. 40 min. E., to station 901+559; thence S. 89 deg. 8 min. E., to station 905+502; thence S. 87 deg. 39 min. E., to station 910+483; thence S. 88 deg. 5 min. E., to station 918+635, passing stone No. 34; thence S. 88 deg. 13 min. E., to station 927+928; thence S. 88 deg. 31 min. E., to station 929+288; thence S. 87 deg. 18 min. E., to station 935+811; thence S. 83 deg. 5 min. E., to station 942+387; thence S. 84 deg. 14 min. E., passing stone No. 35, to station 947+111; thence S. 86 deg. 8 min. E., to station 954+019; thence S. 84 deg. 56 min. E., passing large stone on Nashville and Glasgow turnpike, to station 958+582; thence S. 85 deg. 17 min. E., to station 964+088; thence S. 86 deg. 13 min. E., to station 967+751; thence S. 85 deg. 37 min. E., to station 971+804; thence S. 85 deg. 40 min. E., passing stone No. 36, to station 975+039; thence S. 86 deg. 39 min. E., to station 978+405; thence S. 85 deg. 9 min. E., to station 984+655; thence S. 88 deg. 27 min. E., to station 986+152; thence S. 86 deg. 20 min. E., to station 997+314; thence S. 87 deg. 6 min. E., to station 998+807, at stone No. 37; thence S. 87 deg. 3 min. E., to station 1008+852; thence S. 85 deg. 3 min. E., to station 1012+618; thence S. 86 deg. 2 min. E., to station 1014+427; thence S. 82 deg. 8 min. E., to station 1018+104; thence S. 87 deg. 14 min. E., passing stone No. 38, to station 1027+678; thence S. 88 deg. 8 min. E., to station 1033+997; thence N. 89 deg. 27 min. E., to station 1036+143; thence S. 87 deg. 51 min. E., to station 1050+395; thence S. 87 deg. 9 min. E., to station 1053+164, passing stone No. 39; thence S. 87 deg. 24 min. E., passing stone No. 40, to station 1081+944; thence N. 88 deg. 36 min. E., to station 1092+355; thence S. 89 deg. 17 min. E., to station 1100+366; thence S. 88 deg. 29 min. E., passing stone No. 41, to station 1108+262; thence N. 86 deg. 41 min. E., to station 1109+955; thence S. 88 deg. 29 min. E., to station 1129+562; thence S. 87 deg. 52 min. E., passing stone No. 42, to station 1130+985; same course continued, passing stone No. 43, to station 1159+044; thence S. 89 deg. 23 min. E., to station 1165+889; thence N. 89 deg. 12 min. E., to station 1177+670; thence S. 79 deg. 53 min. E., passing small stone at station 1179+907, on the west bank of Cumberland River, to stone No. 44, at station 1180+535; thence N. 87 deg. 19 min. E., to station 1203+306; thence N. 79 deg. 21 min. E., to stone No. 45, at station 1206+988; thence N. 87 deg. 21 min. E., to station 122+383; thence N. 89 deg. 21 min. E., to station 1223+758; thence N. 87 deg. 21 min. E., to station 1228+654; thence N. 80 deg. 21 min. E., to station 1232+088; thence S. 89 deg. 09 min. E., to station 1239+104; thence N. 70 deg. 36 min. E., to station 1241+124; thence S. 88 deg. 39 min. E., to stone No. 46, at station 1246+318; thence S. 88 deg. 24 min. E., to station 1248+594; thence S. 87 deg. 59 min. E., to station 1251+723, passing stone No. 47, to station 1272+688; thence S. 87 deg. 18 min. E., to station 1275+958; thence S. 88 deg. 30 min. E., to station 1277+938; thence S. 88 deg. E., to station 1285+750; thence S. 87 deg. 45 min. E., to station 1291+058; thence S. 87 deg. E., passing stone No. 48, to station 1297+045; thence S. 88 deg. E., to station 1307+584; thence S. 87 deg. 45 min. E., passing stone No. 49, to station 1328+850; thence S. 85 deg. 30 min. E., to station 1342+320; thence S. 87 deg. 30 min. E., passing stone No. 50, to station 1353+385; thence S. 86 deg. 30 min. E., to station 1356+650; thence S. 87 deg. 30 min. E., passing stone No. 51, to station 1401+600, at stone No. 52; thence S. 87 deg. 30 min. E., to station 1424+100, at stone No. 53; same course continued to station 1453+500, at stone No. 54; thence S. 89 deg. 5 min. E., to station 1474+000; thence S. 87 deg. 40 min. E., to station 1480+570, at stone No. 55; thence S. 86 deg. 40 min. E., to station 1505+400, at stone No. 56; thence S. 89 deg. 10 min. E., to station 1521+100; thence S. 85 deg. 10 min. E., to station 1527+200; thence S. 86 deg. 40 min. E., to station 1531+061, stone No. 57; thence S. 87 deg. 40 min. E., passing stone No. 58, to station 1545+530; thence S. 88 deg. 10 min. E., to station 1557+186; thence S. 87 deg. 15 min. E., to station 1562+732; thence S. 88 E., to station 1567+150; thence S. 88 deg. 15 min. E., passing stone No. 59, to station 1588+290; thence N. 89 deg. 15 min. E., to station 1590+696; thence S. 88 deg. 15 min. E., passing stone No. 60, to station 1605+398; thence S. 88 deg. 45 min. E., to station 1610+550; thence S. 88 deg. 15 min. E., to station 1617+934; thence S. 88 deg. E., to station 1625+094; thence S. 86 deg. 50 min. E., passing stone No. 61, to station 1641+682, at stone No. 62; thence S. 88 deg. 50 min. E., to station 1670+466, at stone No. 63; same course continued to station 1696+578, at stone at seven pines and two black oaks, Tennessee and Kentucky corner; thence N. 33 deg. 16 min. E., 8309 feet, to Tennessee and Virginia corner, at stone at chestnut-oak, latitude 36 deg. 36 min. 00 sec. .94. The line of boundary from the stone at seven pines to the stone at the Tennessee and Virginia corner, follows the backbone of Cumberland mountain.  From the stone in Cumberland Gap, latitude 36 deg. 36 min. 11 sec. .74, to Virginia and Tennessee corner, is S. 28 deg. 11 min. W. 1200 feet.  From same stone to seven pines, is S. 32 deg. 44 min. W. 9510 feet.  From stone John G. Newlee's sulphur spring, in latitude 36 deg. 35 min. 49 sec. .01, to Virginia and Tennessee corner, is N. 55 deg. 35 min. W.  From same stone to stone at seven pines, Tennessee and Kentucky corner, S. 48 deg. 14 min. W.  Any island or islands in that part of the River Tennessee, which forms the common boundary between the two states, shall be within the exclusive jurisdiction of Kentucky; but any appropriations thereof by individuals made under the laws of North Carolina or Tennessee before February 11, 1820, shall be valid. </text><history>Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 188 to 198 and from General Statutes, ch. 8, pp. 170, 171 -- Boundary approved 1860 Ky. Acts ch. 816, sec. 1 -- Boundary approved 1820 Ky. Acts ch. 546, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> October 1, 1942 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=6</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>