<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.488</section_number><catch_line>Department to communicate core content and career-readiness standards, assist in identifying students who are academically behind or have high absentee rates or discipline problems, and develop enhanced courses to be offered. </catch_line><order_by>488</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Prior to January 1, 2013, the Kentucky Department of Education shall communicate to all local school districts the minimum core content standards for postsecondary education introductory courses and career-readiness standards required under KRS 158.6453. </section><section prefix="2">Prior to the beginning of the 2013-2014 school year, the department shall assist districts in the analyses of assessment data to identify students who are academically behind, who have higher than normal absentee rates, or who have a record of discipline problems at the end of grade six (6), grade eight (8), grade nine (9), grade ten (10), and grade eleven (11). </section><section prefix="3">The department shall develop enhanced courses in English, reading, and mathematics to be offered to students in grade six (6), grade nine (9), grade ten (10), grade eleven (11), and grade twelve (12) who are academically behind to help them meet the college and career-readiness standards. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 3, effective April 19, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> April 19, 2012 </effective><lrc-note> (4/19/2012). 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 10, provides that the Act, which included the creation of this statute, shall be known as the "Career Pathways Act of 2012." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40072</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>