<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="132" order_by="132">LEVY AND ASSESSMENT OF PROPERTY TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>132.130</section_number><catch_line>Distilled spirits in bonded warehouses to be reported by proprietor or custodian. </catch_line><order_by>130</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Effective January 1, 1967, every owner, proprietor, or custodian of a bonded warehouse or of premises under the control and supervision of the United States Internal Revenue Service, in which distilled spirits are stored shall between January 1 and February 1 of each year file with the Department of Revenue a report sworn to by him showing the quantity and kind of distilled spirits in the bonded warehouse or premises as of January 1 of that year; the quantity and kind of spirits on which the federal tax has been paid or is due; what distilled spirits have been removed from the bonded warehouse or premises for transfer in bond out of this state during the preceding twelve (12) months; the county, city, and taxing district in which such distilled spirits were certified for taxation; the fair cash value of the distilled spirits estimated at a price it would bring at a fair voluntary sale; and such other facts pertaining to the distilled spirits as the department may require. </section><section prefix="2">On January 1, May 1, and September 1, after the federal tax has been paid or becomes due, or after any of the distilled spirits are removed from the bonded warehouse or premises for transfer in bond out of this state, every owner, proprietor, or custodian of a bonded warehouse or premises in which distilled spirits are stored upon which taxes have accrued on assessments prior to January 1, 1967, shall file with the Department of Revenue and the county clerk, in which county the distilled spirits were at the time of the assessment, a statement, sworn to by him, showing the quantity of the distilled spirits on which the federal tax has been paid or is due; what distilled spirits have been removed from the bonded warehouse or premises or transferred in bond out of this state during the preceding four (4) months; the years in which such distilled spirits were assessed for taxation; and the county, city, or taxing district in which the distilled spirits were stored at the time of the assessment. At the same time, all taxes and interest on such distilled spirits due the state, county, or other taxing district shall be paid to the officers entitled to receive them. The report required by this section shall be made whether or not any distilled spirits are stored in the bonded warehouse or premises at the time the report is due. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 178, effective June 20, 2005. -- Repealed and reenacted 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 316, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 258, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 254, sec. 1. -- Amended 1949 (1st Extra Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 4 1/2. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4105. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:00</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28226</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>