<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">DEPARTMENT OF LAW </unit></structure><section_number>15.3977</section_number><catch_line>Certification categories for court security officers. </catch_line><order_by>3977</order_by><text>The following certification categories shall exist for certified court security officers: <section prefix="1">"Precertification status" means that the certified court security officer is currently employed or appointed by an agency and meets or exceeds all those minimum qualifications set forth in KRS 15.3971, but has not successfully completed the training course provided in KRS 15.3975(1). Upon the council's verification that the minimum qualifications have been met, the officer shall have court security officer powers as authorized under the statute under which he or she was appointed or employed. If an officer fails to successfully complete the training course provided in KRS 15.3975(1) within one (1) year of employment, his or her court security powers shall automatically terminate; </section><section prefix="2">"Certification status" means that unless the certification is in revoked status or inactive status, the certified court security officer is currently employed or appointed by an agency and has met all training requirements. The officer shall have court security officer powers as authorized under the statute under which he or she was appointed or employed; </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">"Inactive status" means that unless the certification is in revoked status: <section prefix="1">The person has been separated on or after December 1, 1998, from the agency by which he or she was employed or appointed and has no peace officer or court security officer powers; or </section><section prefix="2">The person is on military active duty for a period exceeding three hundred sixty-five (365) days. </section></section><section prefix="b">The person may remain on inactive status. A person who is on inactive status and who returns to a court security officer position shall have certification status restored if he or she has successfully completed the training course under KRS 15.3975(1), has not committed an act for which his or her certified status may be revoked pursuant to KRS 15.3973, and successfully completes an in-service training course as prescribed in an administrative regulation promulgated by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council. </section><section prefix="c">A person returning from inactive to active certification as a court security officer after June 26, 2007, under KRS 15.380 to 15.404 shall meet the following minimum qualifications: <section prefix="1">Be a citizen of the United States; </section><section prefix="2">Possess a valid license to operate a motor vehicle; </section><section prefix="3">Be fingerprinted for a criminal background check; </section><section prefix="4">Not have been convicted of any felony; </section><section prefix="5">Not be prohibited by federal or state law from possessing a firearm; </section><section prefix="6">Have received and read the Kentucky Law Enforcement Officers Code of Ethics as established by the council; </section><section prefix="7">Have not received a dishonorable discharge, bad conduct discharge, or general discharge under other than honorable conditions, if having served in any branch of the Armed Forces of the United States; </section><section prefix="8">Have been interviewed by the employing agency; and </section><section prefix="9">Not have had certification as a peace officer permanently revoked in another state; </section></section></section><section prefix="4">"Training deficiency status" means that unless the certification is in revoked status or inactive status, the certified court security officer is currently employed or appointed by an agency and has failed to meet all in-service training requirements. The officer's court security powers shall automatically terminate, and he or she shall not exercise court security officer powers in the Commonwealth until he or she has corrected the in-service training deficiency; </section><section prefix="5">"Revoked status" means that the court security officer has no court security powers and his or her certification has been revoked by the Kentucky Law Enforcement Council for any one (1) of the following reasons: <section prefix="a">Failure to meet or maintain training requirements; </section><section prefix="b">Willful falsification of information to obtain or maintain certified status; </section><section prefix="c">Certification was the result of an administrative error; </section><section prefix="d">Plea of guilty to, conviction of, or entering of an Alford plea to any felony; </section><section prefix="e">Prohibition by federal or state law from possessing a firearm; or </section><section prefix="f">Receipt of a dishonorable discharge, a bad conduct discharge, or general discharge under other than honorable conditions from any branch of the Armed Forces of the United States; and </section></section><section prefix="6">"Denied status" means that a person does not meet the requirements to achieve precertification status or certification status as a court security officer. </section>The design of a certificate may be changed periodically. When a new certificate is produced, it shall be distributed free of charge to each currently certified court security officer. </text><history> Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 54, sec. 4, effective June 26, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=947</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>