<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IV" order_by="4">JUDICIAL BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="24" order_by="24">A DISTRICT COURT </unit></structure><section_number>24A.110</section_number><catch_line>Criminal jurisdiction. </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The District Court shall have exclusive jurisdiction to make final disposition of all criminal matters, including violations of county, urban-county, or city ordinances or codes, except: <section prefix="a">Offenses denominated by statute as felonies or capital offenses; and </section><section prefix="b">Offenses punishable by death or imprisonment in the penitentiary. </section></section><section prefix="2">The District Court has exclusive jurisdiction to make a final disposition of any charge or a public offense denominated as a misdemeanor or violation, except where the charge is joined with an indictment for a felony, and all violations of county, urban-county, or city ordinances and, prior to trial, to commit the defendant to jail or hold him to bail or other form of pretrial release. </section><section prefix="3">The District Court has, concurrent with Circuit Court, jurisdiction to examine any charge of a public offense denominated as a felony or capital offense or which may be punished by death or imprisonment in the penitentiary and to commit the defendant to jail or hold him to bail or other form of pretrial release. </section><section prefix="4">The District Court may, upon motion and for good cause shown, reduce a charge of a felony to a misdemeanor in accordance with the Rules of Criminal Procedure. </section></text><history>Created 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 2; and ch. 28, sec. 10. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20690</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>