<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXIV" order_by="34">DESCENT, WILLS, AND ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="393" order_by="393">ESCHEATS </unit></structure><section_number>393.062</section_number><catch_line>Presumption of abandonment of unclaimed funds held by life insurance corporation. </catch_line><order_by>062</order_by><text><section prefix="1">"Unclaimed funds," as used in this section, means all moneys held and owing by any life insurance corporation unclaimed and unpaid for more than three (3) years after the moneys became due and payable as established from the records of the corporation under any contract which has matured or terminated. A life insurance policy not matured by actual proof of the death of the insured is deemed to be matured and the proceeds thereof are deemed to be due and payable if such policy was in force when the insured attained the limiting age under the mortality table on which the reserve is based, unless the person appearing entitled thereto has within the preceding three (3) years, (a) assigned, readjusted, or paid premiums on the policy, or subjected the policy to loan, or (b) corresponded in writing with the life insurance corporation concerning the policy. Moneys otherwise payable according to the records of the corporation are deemed due and payable although the policy or contract has not been surrendered as required. </section><section prefix="2">Unclaimed funds, as defined in this section, held and owing by a life insurance corporation shall be presumed abandoned if the last known address, according to the records of the corporation, of the person entitled to the funds is within this state. If a person other than the insured or annuitant is entitled to the funds and no address of such person is known to the corporation or if it is not definite and certain from the records of the corporation what person is entitled to the funds, it is presumed that the last known address of the person entitled to the funds is the same as the last known address of the insured or annuitant according to the records of corporation. </section></text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 95, sec. 8, effective June 24, 2003. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 142, sec. 2, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:35</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36196</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>