<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="48" order_by="48">BUDGET </unit></structure><section_number>48.960</section_number><catch_line>Conflicting provisions superseded -- Electronic imprint data as additional data -- Ownership of data. </catch_line><order_by>960</order_by><text><section prefix="1">KRS 48.950 and 48.955 shall supersede all other provisions in law which may be in conflict, including but not limited to KRS Chapters 6, 7, 11, 12, 15, 18 and 18A, 27A, 42, 43, 44, 45, 46, 47, 48, 56, 58, 131, 152, 157, 164, 171, 174, and 177. </section><section prefix="2">Data and records in electronic or print form which are authorized under KRS 48.950 and 48.955 shall be in addition to all other data, records and forms which may be provided by law, including but not limited to, KRS 42.005 to 42.990, 45.001 to 45.991, and 48.010 to 48.800. </section><section prefix="3">The General Assembly declares that: <section prefix="a">All data collected by or in the custody of any budget unit resulting from the expenditure of appropriated funds and which is not confidential under law shall be deemed to be the property right of the Commonwealth; and </section><section prefix="b">No property right or privilege of confidentiality may be asserted or maintained by such custodial budget unit for the production of public records not exempted pursuant to KRS Chapter 61 which may be created and required pursuant to KRS 48.950 and 48.955. </section></section></text><history>Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 3, sec. 3, effective February 10, 1988. </history><metadata><effective>February 10, 1988 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22583</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>