<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="227" order_by="227">A ELECTRICIANS AND ELECTRICAL CONTRACTORS </unit></structure><section_number>227A.040</section_number><catch_line>Powers and duties of department. </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The department, with assistance from the Electrical Advisory Committee, shall administer and enforce the provisions of KRS 227A.010 to 227A.140 and shall evaluate the qualifications of applicants for licensure. </section><section prefix="2">The department may issue subpoenas, examine witnesses, pay appropriate witness fees, administer oaths, and investigate allegations of practices violating the provisions of KRS 227A.010 to 227A.140 or the administrative regulations promulgated under KRS 227A.010 to 227A.140 and KRS Chapter 13A. </section><section prefix="3">The department shall conduct hearings under KRS Chapter 13B and keep records and minutes necessary to carry out the functions of KRS 227A.010 to 227A.140. </section><section prefix="4">The department, with assistance from the Electrical Advisory Committee, shall evaluate the qualifications of applicants and issue licenses to qualified candidates. </section><section prefix="5">The department shall renew licenses. </section><section prefix="6">The department may: <section prefix="a">Refuse to issue or renew a license; </section><section prefix="b">Suspend or revoke a license; </section><section prefix="c">Impose supervisory or probationary conditions upon a licensee; </section><section prefix="d">Impose administrative disciplinary fines; </section><section prefix="e">Issue written reprimands or admonishments; and </section><section prefix="f">Take any combination of the actions permitted in this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="7">The department may seek injunctive relief in the Circuit Court of Franklin County, in the county in which the violation occurred, or in the county where the business of the accused is located to stop any unlawful practice in KRS 227A.010 to 227A.140 and administrative regulations promulgated thereunder. The department may also seek injunctive relief for unlicensed persons who inappropriately use the title "electrical contractor," "electrician," or "master electrician." </section><section prefix="8">The department, with comments and advice from the Electrical Advisory Committee if required by KRS 198B.030(8) and (9), may promulgate administrative regulations to create a code of ethics and procedures governing the licensure of electrical contractors, electricians, and master electricians. </section><section prefix="9">The department may enter into reciprocal agreements with other states having licensure, certification, or registration qualifications and requirements substantially equal to those of this state. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 100, sec. 18, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 431, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 256, sec. 7, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 119, sec. 4, effective June 24, 2003. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:31</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39913</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>