<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="218" order_by="218">A CONTROLLED SUBSTANCES </unit></structure><section_number>218A.1447Restrictions</section_number><catch_line>on possession of dextromethorphan and sale of products containing dextromethorphan.   </catch_line><order_by>1447Restrictions</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person, other than a medical facility, medical practitioner, pharmacist, pharmacy intern, pharmacy technician, pharmacy licensed or registered under KRS Chapter 315, or registrant under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act, 21 U.S.C. secs. 301 et seq., shall not possess one (1) gram or more of: <section prefix="a">Pure dextromethorphan; or </section><section prefix="b">Dextromethorphan extracted from solid or liquid dose forms, as defined by United States Pharmacopeia reference standards. </section></section><section prefix="2">A person shall not sell any products containing dextromethorphan to individuals under eighteen (18) years of age, except that in any prosecution for selling a product containing dextromethorphan to an individual under eighteen (18) years of age it shall be an affirmative defense that the sale was induced by the use of false, fraudulent, or altered identification papers or other documents and that the appearance and character of the purchaser were such that his or her age could not have been ascertained by any other means and that the purchaser's appearance and character indicated strongly that he or she was of legal age to purchase products containing dextromethorphan. This evidence may be introduced either in mitigation of the charge or as a defense to the charge itself. </section><section prefix="3">Any person who sells any product containing dextromethorphan shall limit access to these products by requiring proof of age from a prospective buyer by showing a government-issued photo identification card that displays his or her date of birth if the person has reason to believe that the prospective buyer is under the age of eighteen (18) years. </section></text><history> Created 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 1, effective June 24, 2015. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2015 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44260</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>