<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="403" order_by="403">DISSOLUTION OF MARRIAGE -- CHILD CUSTODY </unit></structure><section_number>403.740</section_number><catch_line>Domestic violence order -- Restrictions -- Temporary child support --Expiration and reissuance.  </catch_line><order_by>740</order_by><text>(1)Following a hearing ordered under KRS 403.730, if a court finds by apreponderance of the evidence that domestic violence and abuse has occurredand may again occur, the court may issue a domestic violence order:(a)Restraining the adverse party from:1.Committing further acts of domestic violence and abuse;2.Any unauthorized contact or communication with the petitioner orother person specified by the court;3.Approaching the petitioner or other person specified by the courtwithin a distance specified in the order, not to exceed five hundred(500) feet;4.Going to or within a specified distance of a specifically describedresidence, school, or place of employment or area where such aplace is located; and5.Disposing of or damaging any of the property of the parties;(b)Directing or prohibiting any other actions that the court believes will be ofassistance in eliminating future acts of domestic violence and abuse,except that the court shall not order the petitioner to take any affirmativeaction;(c)Directing that either or both of the parties receive counseling servicesavailable in the community in domestic violence and abuse cases; and(d)Additionally, if applicable:1.Directing the adverse party to vacate a residence shared by theparties to the action;2.Utilizing the criteria set forth in KRS 403.270, 403.320, and 403.822,grant temporary custody; and3.Utilizing the criteria set forth in KRS 403.211, 403.212, and 403.213,award temporary child support.(2)In imposing a location restriction described in subsection (1)(a)4. of thissection, the court shall:(a)Afford the petitioner and respondent, if present, an opportunity to testifyon the issue of the locations and areas from which the respondent shouldor should not be excluded;(b)Only impose a location restriction where there is a specific, demonstrabledanger to the petitioner or other person protected by the order;(c)Specifically describe in the order the locations or areas prohibited to therespondent; and(d)Consider structuring a restriction so as to allow the respondent transitthrough an area if the respondent does not interrupt his or her travel toharass, harm, or attempt to harass or harm the petitioner.(3)When temporary child support is granted under this section, the court shallenter an order detailing how the child support is to be paid and collected. Childsupport ordered under this section may be enforced utilizing the sameprocedures as any other child support order.(4)A domestic violence order shall be effective for a period of time fixed by thecourt, not to exceed three (3) years, and may be reissued upon expiration forsubsequent periods of up to three (3) years each. The fact that an order hasnot been violated since its issuance may be considered by a court in hearing arequest for a reissuance of the order.</text><history>Repealed and reenacted 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 6, effective January1, 2016. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 170, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2010. --Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 133, sec. 44, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended1996 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 16, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky.Acts ch. 172, sec. 6, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 152,sec. 6, effective July 13, 1984.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:32</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44754</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>