<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.450</section_number><catch_line>Instruction permits for motor vehicle and motorcycle -- Application -- Age requirements -- Restrictions on driving with permit.   </catch_line><order_by>450</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person who is at least sixteen (16) years of age may apply for an instruction permit to operate a motor vehicle. A person who possesses a valid intermediate motor vehicle operator's license issued under KRS 186.452 or a person who is at least eighteen (18) years of age may apply for an instruction permit to operate a motorcycle. A holder of either a motor vehicle or motorcycle instruction permit may also operate a moped under that permit. A person applying for an instruction permit under this section shall make application in the office of the circuit clerk in the county where the person lives. A person applying for an instruction permit shall be required to comply with the following: <section prefix="a">If the person is under the age of eighteen (18), the instruction permit application shall be signed by the applicant's parent or legal guardian. If the person does not have a living parent or does not have a legal guardian, the instruction permit application shall be signed by a person willing to assume responsibility for the applicant pursuant to KRS 186.590; and </section><section prefix="b">All applicants for an instruction permit shall comply with the examinations required by KRS 186.480. </section></section><section prefix="2">If an applicant successfully passes the examinations required by KRS 186.480, the applicant shall be issued an instruction permit upon payment of a six dollar ($6) fee pursuant to KRS 186.531. </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">An instruction permit to operate a motor vehicle shall be valid for three (3) years and may be renewed. An instruction permit to operate a motorcycle shall be valid for one (1) year and may be renewed one (1) time. </section><section prefix="b">Except as provided in KRS 186.415, a person who has attained the age of sixteen (16) years and is under the age of eighteen (18) years shall have the instruction permit a minimum of one hundred eighty (180) days before applying for an intermediate license and shall have an intermediate license for a minimum of one hundred eighty (180) days before applying for an operator's license. </section><section prefix="c">A person who was under eighteen (18) years of age at the time of application for an instruction permit and is eighteen (18) years of age or older shall have the instruction permit a minimum of one hundred eighty (180) days and complete a driver training program under KRS 186.410(4) before applying for an operator's license. </section><section prefix="d">A person who is at least eighteen (18) years of age and is under the age of twenty-one (21) years at the time of application for an instruction permit shall have the instruction permit a minimum of one hundred eighty (180) days before applying for an operator's license. </section><section prefix="e">A person who is at least twenty-one (21) years of age at the time of application for an instruction permit shall have the instruction permit a minimum of thirty (30) days before applying for an operator's license. </section><section prefix="f">In accordance with KRS 15A.352(5), a person whose motorcycle instruction permit has expired may apply to the circuit clerk to receive a motorcycle operator's license or endorsement if the person presents proof of successful completion of a motorcycle safety education course approved by the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet under KRS 15A.350 to 15A.366. </section></section><section prefix="4"><section prefix="a">A person shall have the instruction permit in his possession at all times when operating a motor vehicle, motorcycle, or moped upon the highway. </section><section prefix="b">When operating a motor vehicle, a motor vehicle instruction permit holder shall be accompanied by a person with a valid operator's license who is at least twenty-one (21) years of age occupying the seat beside the operator at all times. </section><section prefix="c">The requirements of paragraph (b) of this subsection shall not apply to a motor vehicle instruction permit holder being supervised on a multiple-vehicle driving range by a driver training instructor affiliated with a driver training school licensed under KRS Chapter 332 or a public or nonpublic secondary school. </section></section><section prefix="5">A person with an instruction permit who is under the age of eighteen (18) shall not operate a motor vehicle, motorcycle, or moped between the hours of 12 midnight and 6 a.m. unless the person can demonstrate good cause for driving, including but not limited to emergencies, involvement in school-related activities, or involvement in work-related activities. </section><section prefix="6">Except when accompanied by a driver training instructor affiliated with a driver training school licensed under KRS Chapter 332 or a public or nonpublic secondary school, a person with an instruction permit who is under the age of eighteen (18) years shall not operate a motor vehicle at any time when accompanied by more than one (1) unrelated person who is under the age of twenty (20) years. A peace officer shall not stop or seize a person nor issue a uniform citation for a violation of this subsection if the officer has no other cause to stop or seize the person other than a violation of this subsection. This subsection shall not apply to any operator of a vehicle registered under the provisions of KRS 186.050(4) who is engaged in agricultural activities. </section><section prefix="7">A violation under subsection (4), (5), or (6) of this section, a conviction for a moving violation under KRS Chapter 189 for which points are assessed by the cabinet, or a conviction for a violation of KRS 189A.010(1) shall add an additional minimum of one hundred eighty (180) days from the date of the violation before a person who is under the age of eighteen (18) years may apply for an intermediate license to operate a motor vehicle, motorcycle, or moped. </section><section prefix="8">A person under the age of eighteen (18) who accumulates more than six (6) points against his driving privilege may have the driving privilege suspended pursuant to KRS Chapter 186 or probated by the court. </section><section prefix="9">An applicant for relicensing after revocation shall pay the clerk a fee of twenty-five dollars ($25). The twenty-five dollar ($25) fee shall not apply to any person whose license was suspended for failure to meet the conditions described in KRS 186.411 when, within one (1) year of suspension, the driving privileges of such individuals are reinstated and persons reinstated pursuant to KRS 159.051. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 16. sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012; and ch. 79, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 46, sec. 3, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 43, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 52, sec. 2, effective March 16, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 198, sec. 2, effective October 1, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 503, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 234, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 266, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 349, sec. 5, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 3. -- Amended 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 60, sec. 4. -- Amended 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 127, sec. 3. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2739m-39. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note> (7/12/2012). This statute was amended by 2012 Ky. Acts chs. 16 and 79, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together.  (7/12/2006).  2006 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec, 9, provides: "The amendments to Section 1 of this Act (this statute) shall apply to any person who obtains an original or renewal instruction permit pursuant to KRS 186.450 on or after October 1, 2006." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40341</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>