<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>154.10-125</section_number><catch_line>Content and effect of strategic economic development plan. </catch_line><order_by>10-125</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The strategic economic development plan shall include, but not be limited to: <section prefix="a">A review with reconfirmation or modification of stated goals; </section><section prefix="b">An analysis of the current world economy and its impact on the economy of Kentucky and the nature of the competitive environment within which Kentucky's workforce and businesses must compete; </section><section prefix="c">An analysis of broad trends of economic change; </section><section prefix="d">The identification of the position of Kentucky's workforce, businesses, and communities relative to the external economic environment; </section><section prefix="e">A statewide and regional assessment of Kentucky's economic strengths and weaknesses; </section><section prefix="f">An analysis of the sustainability of Kentucky's economy over time; and </section><section prefix="g">Identification of strategies, objectives, and actions to be taken to improve Kentucky's competitive position with focus given to human and natural resources development, infrastructure, capital, technology, entrepreneurship, modernization, quality of life, and institutional development. </section></section><section prefix="2">Under each strategy, a discussion shall be provided of the objectives to be established within a set time frame, including: <section prefix="a">Programs to be established and administered; </section><section prefix="b">Funding required; and </section><section prefix="c">Public policies to be pursued. </section></section><section prefix="3">In the development of the initial strategic economic development plan, the board shall be guided by, but not limited to, the following principles: <section prefix="a">Economic development shall be a partnership of government, private business, local communities, and education; </section><section prefix="b">Growth of jobs and incomes shall come from new business creation in Kentucky, existing Kentucky businesses, and attraction of new business to Kentucky; </section><section prefix="c">Economic development and environmental protection are compatible objectives; </section><section prefix="d">Strategies for economic development shall focus on: <section prefix="1">Systems, not programs; </section><section prefix="2">Regions and sectors, not individual businesses; </section><section prefix="3">Decentralization; </section><section prefix="4">Participation by users; </section><section prefix="5">Helping communities to help themselves; </section><section prefix="6">Activities that will make Kentucky products globally competitive; </section><section prefix="7">Education and assistance, as well as financing; </section><section prefix="8">Financing as an investment; </section><section prefix="9">Retaining and growing Kentucky businesses; </section><section prefix="10">Creating high value job opportunities to all who have prepared themselves; and </section><section prefix="11">Encouragement of private sector investment. </section></section><section prefix="e">Economic development strategies approved by the board shall remain flexible to keep Kentucky competitive in a rapidly changing environment. </section></section></text><history>Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 105, sec. 13, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2610</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>