<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="67" order_by="67">A URBAN-COUNTY GOVERNMENT </unit></structure><section_number>67A.025</section_number><catch_line>Chief administrative officer -- Appointment -- Duties -- Compensation -- Removal. </catch_line><order_by>025</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In order to provide professional assistance in the administration of urban-county governments, a chief administrative officer may be employed to serve on the staff of the chief executive officer. The chief administrative officer shall possess demonstrable education and/or professional experience in the art and science of governmental management. The chief administrative officer may be a nonresident of Kentucky and/or the urban-county, but must become a resident of the urban-county within six (6) months of appointment and shall maintain such residence during the tenure of his or her office. </section><section prefix="2">The chief administrative officer shall be appointed by the chief executive officer subject to confirmation by a vote of three-fifths (3/5) of the legislative body. </section><section prefix="3">The chief administrative officer of any urban-county government created before December 31, 1987, may be removed, with or without cause, by: (a) executive order of the chief executive officer; or (b) three-fifths (3/5) vote of the entire legislative body. </section> Upon removal, the chief administrative officer shall not be entitled to severance pay or notice of intention to remove him or her. The chief administrative officer of any urban-county government created after December 31, 1987, may be removed by three-fifths (3/5) vote of the entire legislative body. </text><history>Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 379, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 166. sec. 3, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1988 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23841</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>