<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="15" order_by="15">A JUSTICE AND PUBLIC SAFETY CABINET </unit></structure><section_number>15A.063</section_number><catch_line>Juvenile Justice Oversight Council -- Purpose -- Membership -- Duties. </catch_line><order_by>063</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Juvenile Justice Oversight Council is created for the purpose of providing independent review of the state juvenile justice system and providing recommendations to the General Assembly. The council is to actively engage in the implementation of the juvenile justice reforms in 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 132, collect and review performance measurement data, and continue to review the juvenile justice system for changes that improve public safety, hold youth accountable, provide better outcomes for children and families, and control juvenile justice costs. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">The membership of the council shall include the following: <section prefix="1">The secretary of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, ex officio; </section><section prefix="2">The commissioner of the Department for Behavioral Health, Developmental and Intellectual Disabilities, ex officio; </section><section prefix="3">The commissioner of the Department for Community Based Services, ex officio; </section><section prefix="4">The commissioner of the Department of Juvenile Justice, ex officio; </section><section prefix="5">The commissioner of the Department of Education, ex officio; </section><section prefix="6">The director of the Administrative Office of the Courts, ex officio; </section><section prefix="7">The Public Advocate, ex officio; </section><section prefix="8">The Senate chair of the Committee on Judiciary, nonvoting ex officio; </section><section prefix="9">The House chair of the Committee on Judiciary, nonvoting ex officio; and </section><section prefix="10">Five (5) at-large members appointed by the Governor, as follows: <section prefix="a">One (1) member representing public schools or an education group or organization; </section><section prefix="b">One (1) District Judge nominated by the Chief Justice of the Kentucky Supreme Court; </section><section prefix="c">One (1) member representing law enforcement; </section><section prefix="d">One (1) member of the County Attorneys' Association nominated by the Attorney General; and </section><section prefix="e">One (1) member representing community-based organizations, whether for-profit or nonprofit, with experience in programs for juveniles, including substance abuse prevention and treatment, case management, mental health, or counseling. </section></section></section><section prefix="b">The chairs of the House and Senate Judiciary Committees shall serve as co-chairs. </section><section prefix="c">At-large members shall be appointed by August 1, 2014, and shall serve a term of two (2) years, and may be reappointed. </section><section prefix="d">Each ex officio member, except for legislative members, may designate a proxy by written notice to the council prior to call of order of each meeting, and the proxy shall be entitled to participate as a full voting member. </section><section prefix="e">Except as otherwise provided by law, members shall not be compensated for being members of the council but shall be reimbursed for ordinary travel expenses, including meals and lodging, incurred while performing council business. </section><section prefix="f">The council shall meet at least quarterly. A quorum, consisting of a majority of the membership of the council, shall be required for the transaction of business. Meetings shall be held at the call of the chair, or upon the written request of two (2) members to the chair. </section></section><section prefix="3">The council shall: <section prefix="a">Oversee the implementation of the reforms contained in 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 132, including: <section prefix="1">Review of the performance measures to be adopted and recommend modifications; </section><section prefix="2">Ensure all policies are implemented in accordance with the time frames established; </section><section prefix="3">Ensure the fiscal incentive program established pursuant to KRS 15A.062 is implemented and continue to review the program; and </section><section prefix="4">Review the Department of Juvenile Justice facilities plan submitted following a reduction of population and make recommendations to the General Assembly as to the plan and any changes to the reinvestment of savings achieved from the closure of any facilities; </section></section><section prefix="b">Collect and review performance data and recommend any additional performance measures needed to identify outcomes in the juvenile justice system; </section><section prefix="c">Review the information received from the Department of Education pursuant to KRS 156.095, and determine whether any action is necessary, including additional performance measures, funding, or legislation; </section><section prefix="d">Continue review of juvenile justice areas determined appropriate by the council, including: <section prefix="1">Status offense reform; </section><section prefix="2">Necessary training for school resource officers and school security officers, as defined in KRS 158.441, in juvenile justice best practices, research and impacts on recidivism and long-term outcomes; </section><section prefix="3">Graduated sanctions protocols in public schools, including their current use and their development statewide; </section><section prefix="4">A minimum age of criminal responsibility; </section><section prefix="5">Competency;  </section><section prefix="6">Reforms to the family resource and youth service centers in the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="7">Population levels in Department of Juvenile Justice facilities, and the potential for closure of facilities while maintaining staffing ratios necessary to comply with applicable accreditation standards; and  </section><section prefix="8">Whether juvenile court hearings should be open to the public; and </section></section><section prefix="e">Report by November 2014, and by November of each year thereafter, to the Interim Joint Committee on Judiciary and the Governor and make recommendations to the General Assembly for any additional legislative changes the council determines appropriate. </section></section><section prefix="4">The council shall be attached to the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet for administrative purposes. </section><section prefix="5">The council shall terminate on July 1, 2022, unless the General Assembly extends the term of the council. </section></text><history> Created 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2014. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43481</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>