<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="257" order_by="257">LIVESTOCK AND POULTRY DISEASE CONTROL </unit></structure><section_number>257.472</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Equine Health and Welfare Council -- Duties -- Members -- Meetings -- Construction of KRS 257.472 to 257.476. </catch_line><order_by>472</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Equine Health and Welfare Council is hereby established and shall be attached to the Kentucky Department of Agriculture for administrative purposes only. The council shall: <section prefix="a">Assist, advise, and consult with the commission created by KRS 257.192 on equine health and welfare issues; </section><section prefix="b">Act to maintain the health, welfare, and safety of equines in the Commonwealth; and </section><section prefix="c">Carry out the duties assigned to the council in KRS 257.474. </section></section><section prefix="2">The council shall be composed of thirteen (13) voting members and two (2) nonvoting ex officio members as follows: <section prefix="a">The Commissioner of Agriculture or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="b">The state veterinarian or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="c">One (1) representative of the University of Kentucky College of Agriculture Equine Initiative to be designated by the dean of the University of Kentucky College of Agriculture; </section><section prefix="d">One (1) representative of the University of Louisville Equine Industry Program to be designated by the dean of the College of Business; </section><section prefix="e">One (1) representative of equine education programs chosen by Morehead State University, Murray State University, or Western Kentucky University on a rotating basis at the pleasure of the university to serve a one (1) year term; </section><section prefix="f">The executive director of the University of Kentucky Livestock Disease Diagnostic Center, or his or her designee, or the executive director of the Murray State University Breathitt Veterinary Center, or his or her designee, who shall serve one (1) year terms on a rotating basis; </section><section prefix="g">One (1) representative of the Kentucky Farm Bureau Federation with an interest in equine issues; </section><section prefix="h">One (1) veterinarian representing the Kentucky Equine Health and Welfare Alliance Inc.; </section><section prefix="i">One (1) member representing the Kentucky Veterinary Medical Association; </section><section prefix="j">One (1) member to be appointed by the Governor from a list of three (3) nominees submitted by the Kentucky Horse Council; </section><section prefix="k">One (1) member representing organized horse rescue entities to be selected by the Governor from a listing of those who apply for membership on the council; </section><section prefix="l">Two (2) members at large who live in diverse regions of the state to be appointed by the Governor. Each member at large shall primarily represent one (1) of the following: <section prefix="1">Equine breeders and owners; and </section><section prefix="2">Agricultural interests; </section></section><section prefix="m">The chair of the Senate Standing Committee on Agriculture, who shall serve as a nonvoting ex officio member; and </section><section prefix="n">The chair of the House Standing Committee on Agriculture and Small Business, who shall serve as a nonvoting ex officio member. </section></section><section prefix="3">Initial terms of members serving under subsection (2)(c), (d), and (g) to (l) of this section shall be staggered by the Governor. Thereafter, terms shall be for four (4) years or until their successors are duly appointed and qualified. Vacancies on the council shall be filled for the remainder of the unexpired term in the same manner as the original appointment. </section><section prefix="4">Consideration shall be given to racial and gender equity in the appointment of council members. </section><section prefix="5">The council shall elect one (1) of its members to serve as chair for a term of two (2) years. </section><section prefix="6">The council shall meet quarterly or upon the call of the chair. The first meeting of the council shall occur at the beginning of the quarter following appointments to the council. </section><section prefix="7">A quorum of the council shall consist of seven (7) voting members. A majority of the voting members present may act upon matters before the council. </section><section prefix="8">Members of the council shall serve without compensation. </section><section prefix="9">Nothing in KRS 257.472 to 257.476 shall be construed to infringe upon the regulatory authority of: <section prefix="a">The Kentucky Horse Racing Commission to inspect, investigate, and supervise horses and other participants in horse racing and breeders incentive funds as provided by KRS Chapter 230, administrative regulations promulgated under KRS Chapter 230, or any other law applicable to the regulation of horse racing in the Commonwealth; </section><section prefix="b">The Kentucky Board of Veterinary Examiners to license and certify veterinarians as provided by KRS Chapter 321, administrative regulations promulgated under KRS Chapter 321, or any other law applicable to the regulation of veterinarians in the Commonwealth; or </section><section prefix="c">The Kentucky Livestock Care Standards Commission to make recommendations to the Board of Agriculture to establish, maintain, or revise standards governing the care and well-being of on-farm livestock and poultry, or any other authority of the commission authorized under this chapter. </section></section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  A reference to the "Kentucky Horse Racing Authority" in subsection (9) of this section, as created by 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 1, has been changed in codification to the "Kentucky Horse Racing Commission" to reflect the reorganization of certain parts of the Executive Branch, as set forth in Executive Order 2009-535 and confirmed by the General Assembly in 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24. This change was made by the Reviser of Statutes pursuant to 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1938.  (7/15/2010).  The proposed Senate Committee Substitute to House Bill 398, which became 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 106, attached the text of Senate Bill 105/HCS to HB 398 and made several changes to the existing provisions, including the addition of paragraph (c) to subsection (9) of this statute. As drafted, paragraph (c) contained the phrase, "commission authorized under this Act." After examination of the materials in the bill folder and consultation with the drafter, "this Act" was changed to "this chapter" during codification, as all sections of 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 106 are located in KRS Chapter 257. This substitution was made by the Reviser of Statutes under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(f). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:27</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=12394</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>