<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="205" order_by="205">PUBLIC ASSISTANCE AND MEDICAL ASSISTANCE </unit></structure><section_number>205.6489</section_number><catch_line>Administration -- Outreach -- Data collection. </catch_line><order_by>6489</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Children's Health Insurance Program shall be administered by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services in terms of conducting eligibility determination and providing oversight over enrollment and claims payment. </section><section prefix="2">The program shall include a system of outreach and referral for children who may be eligible for the Kentucky Children's Health Insurance Program. The program shall work with the Department for Medicaid Services, the Department for Community Based Services, schools, pediatricians, public health departments, and other entities interested in the health of children in developing the system of outreach and referral. </section><section prefix="3">The cabinet shall promulgate administrative regulations in accordance with KRS Chapter 13A to establish a structure for quality assurance and utilization review under KRS 205.6481 to 205.6495 and KRS 304.17A-340. </section><section prefix="4">The Kentucky Children's Health Insurance Program shall collect, analyze, and publicly disseminate comprehensive data on the number of children enrolled in the program, services received through the program, and the effect on health outcomes of children served by the program including the special health needs of minority children. The information collected by the program shall be subject to KRS 216.2927(1). The program shall have access to all data collected by the cabinet under KRS 216.2920 to 216.2929 and shall coordinate program data collection efforts with the data collection efforts of the cabinet under KRS 216.2920 to 216.2929. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 263, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 36, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 253, sec. 5, effective April 2, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7788</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>