<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6">THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY </unit></structure><section_number>6.190</section_number><catch_line>Compensation -- Travel expenses. </catch_line><order_by>190</order_by><text>Beginning as of January 1, 1984, the members of the General Assembly, other than the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the President of the Senate, the Speaker Pro Tempore of the House of Representatives, President Pro Tempore of the Senate, and the majority and minority leadership of each house of the General Assembly, shall each receive as compensation one hundred dollars ($100) per day, the President of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives shall each receive as compensation one hundred twenty-five dollars ($125) per day, the majority and minority floor leaders of each house of the General Assembly shall each receive as compensation one hundred twenty dollars ($120) per day, and the President Pro Tempore of the Senate, the Speaker Pro Tempore, and the majority and minority caucus chairmen and whips of each house of the General Assembly shall each receive as compensation one hundred fifteen dollars ($115) per day, during the session of the General Assembly. In addition to his compensation as a member of the General Assembly, each chairman of a standing committee of the House of Representatives or the Senate shall receive compensation of ten dollars ($10) for each regularly scheduled meeting of the standing committee which he chairs during sessions of the General Assembly. Beginning as of July 1, 1980, each member of the General Assembly shall receive mileage and reimbursement of road tolls for one (1) round trip for each week of the session between his home and the State Capitol during regular sessions and extraordinary sessions of the General Assembly and the necessary travel in going to and returning from the sessions of their respective houses. The mileage allowance under this section shall be equal to the maximum mileage allowance permitted by the federal government, to be increased as federal mileage allowance is increased. </text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 486, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 331, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 407, sec. 5, effective July 1, 1980 -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 437, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 83, sec. 8, effective March 29, 1976. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 3. -- Created 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><former-history>Repealed 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 29. -- Amended 1944 Ky. Acts ch. 56, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 2005-1, 2005-2. </former-history><former-history-former-name>KRS 6.190:  </former-history-former-name><budget-ref> See Legislative Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 123, Pt. I, 1, (1) at 782. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=273</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>