<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="18" order_by="18">A STATE PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>18A.190</section_number><catch_line>Holidays for state personnel -- Military spouses to receive paid deployment and return days off. </catch_line><order_by>190</order_by><text><section prefix="1">State offices shall be closed and state employees shall be given a holiday on the following days: <section prefix="a">The first day of January plus one (1) extra day; </section><section prefix="b">The third Monday in January; </section><section prefix="c">Good Friday, one-half (1/2) day; </section><section prefix="d">The last Monday in May; </section><section prefix="e">The fourth day of July; </section><section prefix="f">The first Monday in September; </section><section prefix="g">The eleventh day of November; </section><section prefix="h">Presidential election day as required under KRS 2.190; </section><section prefix="i">The fourth Thursday in November plus one (1) extra day; and </section><section prefix="j">The twenty-fifth day of December plus one (1) extra day. </section></section><section prefix="2">When any of the days enumerated in subsection (1) falls on a Saturday, the preceding Friday shall be observed as the holiday, and when any of the days enumerated in subsection (1) falls on a Sunday, the following Monday shall be observed as the holiday. When one (1) extra day is mentioned in paragraphs (a), (i) and (j) of subsection (1), the Governor shall designate the extra day. </section><section prefix="3">Any state employee who is the spouse of a member of the United States Armed Forces, including a member of a state National Guard or a Reserve component on federal active duty, shall receive, at the discretion of the state employee, one (1) day off, with pay, from work when the member is deployed and one (1) day off, with pay, from work when the member returns from deployment. </section><section prefix="4">The holidays set out in this section are in addition to vacation leave and other benefits of state employees. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 252, Pt. XXVIII, sec. 8, effective April 25, 2006. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 576, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 25, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended as KRS 18A.190, 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 448, sec. 38, effective July 15, 1982. -- Created 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 289, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> April 25, 2006 </effective><budget-ref> See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, C, 2, (2) at 628.  See State/Executive Branch Budget, 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 117, Pt. I, D, 10, (1) at 636. </budget-ref><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><budget-ref-start-year>2014</budget-ref-start-year><budget-ref-end-year>2016</budget-ref-end-year><former-codification> KRS 18.350. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=1386</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>