<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.812</section_number><catch_line>Legislative intent, findings, and declarations. </catch_line><order_by>812</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It is the intent of the General Assembly to provide rigorous academic and career and technical education programs that are relevant for all students and that encourage at-risk students to graduate from high school prepared to enter postsecondary education institutions or the workforce with needed skills. </section><section prefix="2">The purposes of elementary and secondary education programs of career and technical education are to: <section prefix="a">Provide students opportunities to understand the relevance of and master academic skills in mathematics, science, English, reading, and communications as well as technical literacy in broad-based career fields; </section><section prefix="b">Provide students a variety of opportunities to master the usage of technology; </section><section prefix="c">Prepare individuals with specialized, transferable academic skills and technical skills for gainful employment in broad-based career fields; and </section><section prefix="d">Assist individuals in making successful transitions from school to work, to postsecondary education, to the military, or from one (1) career to another. </section></section><section prefix="3">The General Assembly acknowledges that: <section prefix="a">Rigorous, relevant, and high-quality career and technical education offers students an opportunity to develop skills in mathematics, science, English, reading, communication, problem-solving, and technology, and in career and technical areas that are essential to meet the goals for Kentucky education as described in KRS 158.6451 and that help students achieve the capacities required of all students as defined in KRS 158.645; </section><section prefix="b">Students need access to career pathway programs that meet high standards, connect technical skills with core academic requirements for high school students, and align with postsecondary education requirements and business and industry needs; </section><section prefix="c">Students can accelerate their overall scholastic achievement when given an opportunity to learn in an integrated school- and work-based environment; </section><section prefix="d">Students are less likely to drop out of school when they are making academic progress and see relevance in the program of study to their future potential for success; and </section><section prefix="e">The General Assembly has a responsibility to provide the resources that recognize the increased costs for offering high-quality, relevant career and technical education programs. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 1, effective April 19, 2012. -- Created 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 2, effective June 21, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> April 19, 2012 </effective><lrc-note> (4/19/2012). 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 10, provides that the Act, which included an amendment to this statute, shall be known as the "Career Pathways Act of 2012." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40070</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>