<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="317" order_by="317">A COSMETOLOGISTS </unit></structure><section_number>317A.130</section_number><catch_line>Sanitation requirements and prohibited practices.   </catch_line><order_by>130</order_by><text>No instructor, student, cosmetologist, apprentice, or nail technician shall: <section prefix="1">Fail to provide the head rest of each chair with a relaundered towel or a sheet of clean paper for each person; </section><section prefix="2">Fail to place around the patron's neck a strip of cotton, towel, or neck strip so that the haircloth does not come in contact with the patron's skin; </section><section prefix="3">Use on one (1) patron a towel that has been used upon another patron, unless the towel has been relaundered; </section><section prefix="4">Use on any patron any razor, scissors, tweezers, comb, bowl, recirculating pipes, rubber disc, or part of vibrator or other similar equipment or appliance that comes into contact with the head, face, hands, feet, or neck of a patron, until the equipment or appliance has been immersed in boiling water for ten (10) minutes or in a sterilizing solution and placed in a wet or dry sterilizer until again used. Only those methods of sterilization that are bacteriologically effective and approved by the Department for Public Health shall be used; or </section><section prefix="5">Use on any patron a liquid nail enhancement product containing monomeric methyl methacrylate, also known as dental acrylic monomer, for the purpose of creating artificial nail enhancements in the practice of cosmetology and nail technology. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 152, sec. 12, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 437, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 82, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 354, sec. 13. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 675, instructs the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in the Act, as it confirms the establishment of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40889</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>