<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IV" order_by="4">JUDICIAL BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="27" order_by="27">A JUDICIAL SUPPORT AGENCIES AND PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>27A.420</section_number><catch_line>Sentencing level relating to plea bargaining. </catch_line><order_by>420</order_by><text>The sentencing level of the system shall consist of at least the following information in regard to plea bargaining: <section prefix="1">Did the defendant plead guilty to any offense in exchange for a lesser penalty or in exchange for dropping other charges against him; </section><section prefix="2">If the answer to subsection (1) of this section is yes: <section prefix="a">What offenses and levels of offense was a guilty plea accepted to; list each separately; and </section><section prefix="b">What offenses and levels of offense were dismissed in exchange for a plea of guilty; list each separately; </section></section><section prefix="3">What punishment was imposed for each offense for which a plea of guilty was accepted in exchange for a lesser penalty or in exchange for dropping charges: <section prefix="a">Imprisonment; list offense and term of imprisonment for each offense separately; and </section><section prefix="b">Fine; list offense, and amount of fine for each offense separately; </section></section><section prefix="4">Was probation, suspended sentence or any other nonimposition of sentence imposed for any offense where a plea of guilty was made in exchange for a lesser penalty or in exchange for dropping other charges: <section prefix="a">Describe each separately; and </section><section prefix="b">Describe any conditions placed upon each; list separately. </section></section></text><history>Created 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 389, sec. 18, effective July 15, 1986. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20962</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>