<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.9-990</section_number><catch_line>Penalty for violation of this subtitle. </catch_line><order_by>9-990</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person who intentionally violates any provision of this subtitle, or violates any administrative regulation promulgated hereunder, or violates any order of the commissioner, shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. Each transaction in violation of this subtitle and each day that a violation continues shall constitute a separate offense. </section><section prefix="2">This section shall not be deemed to limit the power of the commissioner to enforce any of the administrative penalties found in this subtitle. </section><section prefix="3">For purposes of this section, "payment instrument" also includes debit authorization, electronic funds transfer, and any other form of electronic transmission of money. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 820, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 98, sec. 24, effective January 1, 2010. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 213, sec. 13, effective July 14, 1992; and ch. 341, sec. 13, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 368.990. </former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  In accordance with 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, secs. 38 and 39, this statute has been renumbered as a section of the Kentucky Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286, and KRS references within this statute have been adjusted to conform with the 2006 renumbering of that code. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:13</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14923</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>