<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="95" order_by="95">A FIRE PROTECTION PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>95A.060</section_number><catch_line>Responsibility of Kentucky Community and Technical College System for education programs approved by the commission -- Commission to ratify certain personnel decisions -- Procedure for budget administration. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Community and Technical College System shall conduct or contract for the delivery of all certificate, diploma, or associate degree programs approved by the commission. </section><section prefix="2">The Kentucky Community and Technical College System shall provide the fiscal and administrative support requested by the commission, through the chancellor's Office of Technical Education and Workforce Development. </section><section prefix="3">The commission shall ratify all personnel decisions necessary to perform the functions required by the commission, subject to budget appropriation limits. </section><section prefix="4">The commission shall establish the proposed budget for all administrative, fire rescue training functions, and other activities in which the commission is authorized to engage, including, but not limited to, salaries, equipment, maintenance, utilities, insurance, and other matters. The commission shall submit the budget to the Kentucky Community and Technical College System, which shall submit the budget, through appropriate channels, for inclusion in the executive branch budget. The Kentucky Community and Technical College System shall not change the proposed budget which is submitted to it but may comment thereon in writing, with copies sent to the commission and to all agencies who receive the proposed budget during the budget process. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 77, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 270, sec. 8, effective July 14, 2000. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><lrc-note> (6/20/2005).  2005 Ky. Acts chs. 11, 85, 95, 97, 98, 99, 123, and 181 instruct the Reviser of Statutes to correct statutory references to agencies and officers whose names have been changed in 2005 legislation confirming the reorganization of the executive branch. Such a correction has been made in this section. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:08</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26135</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>