<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="151" order_by="151">B WORKFORCE EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>151B.185</section_number><catch_line>Office of Vocational Rehabilitation -- Divisions. </catch_line><order_by>185</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Office of Vocational Rehabilitation is hereby created within the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet, Department of Workforce Investment. The office shall consist of an executive director and those administrative bodies and employees provided or appointed pursuant to law. The office shall be composed of the Division of Program Services and the Division of the Carl D. Perkins Vocational Training Center. Each division shall be headed by a director appointed by the secretary of the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet under the provisions of KRS 12.050, and shall be composed of organizational entities as deemed appropriate by the secretary of the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet. </section><section prefix="2">The Office of Vocational Rehabilitation shall have such powers and duties as contained in KRS 151B.180 to 151B.210 and such other functions as may be established by administrative regulation. </section><section prefix="3">The office shall be the sole state agency for the purpose of developing and approving state plans required by state or federal laws and regulations as prerequisites to receiving federal funds for vocational rehabilitation. </section><section prefix="4">The chief executive officer of the office shall be the executive director of the Office of Vocational Rehabilitation. The executive director shall be appointed by the secretary of the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet under the provisions of KRS 12.050. The executive director shall have experience in vocational rehabilitation and supervision and shall have general supervision and direction over all functions of the office and its employees, and shall be responsible for carrying out the programs and policies of the office. </section><section prefix="5">Except as otherwise provided, the office shall be the state agency responsible for all rehabilitation services and for other services as deemed necessary. The office shall be the agency authorized to expend all state and federal funds designated for rehabilitation services. The Office of the Secretary of the Education and Workforce Development Cabinet is authorized as the state agency to receive all state and federal funds and gifts and bequests for the benefit of rehabilitation services. </section><section prefix="6">Employees under the jurisdiction of the Office of Vocational Rehabilitation who are members of a state retirement system as of June 30, 1990, shall remain in their respective retirement systems. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 11, sec. 21, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 45, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 44, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 469, sec. 27, effective July 15, 1994. -- Repealed, reenacted, and amended as KRS 151B.185 by 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 470, sec. 36, effective July 1, 1990, which prevailed over an amendment to KRS 163.120 by 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, sec. 270, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 361, sec. 15, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 316, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 121, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 83, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><former-codification> KRS 163.120. </former-codification><lrc-note> (7/13/90).  The subsequent repeal, with reenactment and amendment, of this section prevails over its amendment by a prior Act of the 1990 Regular Session pursuant to KRS 446.260. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2217</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>