<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIV" order_by="14">LIBRARIES AND ARCHIVES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="171" order_by="171">STATE LIBRARIES -- LIBRARIANS -- STATE ARCHIVES AND RECORDS </unit></structure><section_number>171.410</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 171.420 to 171.740. </catch_line><order_by>410</order_by><text>As used in KRS 171.420 to 171.740: <section prefix="1">"Public record or record" means all books, papers, maps, photographs, cards, tapes, disks, diskettes, recordings, and other documentary materials, regardless of physical form or characteristics, which are prepared, owned, used, in the possession of or retained by a public agency. "Public record" shall not include any records owned by a private person or corporation that are not related to functions, activities, programs or operations funded by state or local authority; </section><section prefix="2">"Department" means the Department for Libraries and Archives; </section><section prefix="3">"Commission" means the State Archives and Records Commission; and </section><section prefix="4">"Public agency" means every state or local office, state department, division, bureau, board, commission and authority; every legislative board, commission, committee and officer; every county and city governing body, council, school district board, special district board, municipal corporation, and any board, department, commission, committee, subcommittee, ad hoc committee, council or agency thereof; and any other body which is created by state or local authority and which derives at least twenty-five percent (25%) of its funds from state or local authority. </section></text><history>Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 150, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 245, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VIII, B, sec. 2. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 92, sec. 32. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 159. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 106, Art. V, sec. 2. -- Created 1958 Ky. Acts ch. 49, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1986 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4819</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>