<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="48" order_by="48">BUDGET </unit></structure><section_number>48.500</section_number><catch_line>Interpretation of branch budget bills -- Legislative review. </catch_line><order_by>500</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Subject to the provisions of this section, when the General Assembly is not in session, all questions that arise as to the meaning of items in a branch budget bill shall be decided by the Finance and Administration Cabinet for the executive branch budget bill and the Transportation Cabinet budget bill, and by the Chief Justice and the Legislative Research Commission for their respective branches of government. </section><section prefix="2">The secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, the Chief Justice, and the Legislative Research Commission shall transmit decisions made under subsection (1) of this section to the Interim Joint Committee on Appropriations and Revenue of the Legislative Research Commission and shall include, in detail, the reasons for such decisions. </section><section prefix="3">If the Interim Joint Committee on Appropriations and Revenue disapproves a decision made under this section, the decision shall not be implemented unless it is: <section prefix="a">Revised to comply with the objections of the committee; or </section><section prefix="b">The committee is informed, in writing, in detail, within thirty (30) days of the committee's disapproval, that a determination has been made not to comply with the objections of the committee. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 73, sec. 11, effective June 8, 2011. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 13, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 507, sec. 15, effective July 13, 1990. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 450, sec. 24, effective July 1, 1983. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39791</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>