<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="510" order_by="510">SEXUAL OFFENSES </unit></structure><section_number>510.110</section_number><catch_line>Sexual abuse in the first degree. </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of sexual abuse in the first degree when: <section prefix="a">He or she subjects another person to sexual contact by forcible compulsion; or </section><section prefix="b">He or she subjects another person to sexual contact who is incapable of consent because he or she: <section prefix="1">Is physically helpless; </section><section prefix="2">Is less than twelve (12) years old; or </section><section prefix="3">Is mentally incapacitated; or </section></section><section prefix="c">Being twenty-one (21) years old or more, he or she: <section prefix="1">Subjects another person who is less than sixteen (16) years old to sexual contact; </section><section prefix="2">Engages in masturbation in the presence of another person who is less than sixteen (16) years old and knows or has reason to know the other person is present; or </section><section prefix="3">Engages in masturbation while using the Internet, telephone, or other electronic communication device while communicating with a minor who the person knows is less than sixteen (16) years old, and the minor can see or hear the person masturbate; or </section></section><section prefix="d">Being a person in a position of authority or position of special trust, as defined in KRS 532.045, he or she, regardless of his or her age, subjects a minor who is less than eighteen (18) years old, with whom he or she comes into contact as a result of that position, to sexual contact or engages in masturbation in the presence of the minor and knows or has reason to know the minor is present or engages in masturbation while using the Internet, telephone, or other electronic communication device while communicating with a minor who the person knows is less than sixteen (16) years old, and the minor can see or hear the person masturbate. </section></section><section prefix="2">Sexual abuse in the first degree is a Class D felony, unless the victim is less than twelve (12) years old, in which case the offense shall be a Class C felony. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 72, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 33, effective July 12, 2006. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 259, sec. 5, effective July 15, 2002. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 91, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19768</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>