<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="213" order_by="213">VITAL STATISTICS </unit></structure><section_number>213.136</section_number><catch_line>Certified copy of a vital record. </catch_line><order_by>136</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The state registrar shall upon receipt of an application issue a certified copy of a vital record in the registrar's custody or a part thereof to any applicant. Each copy issued shall show the date of registration and copies issued from records marked "delayed" or "amended" shall be similarly marked and show the effective date. The documentary evidence used to establish a delayed certificate shall be shown on all copies issued. All forms and procedures used in the issuance of certified copies of vital records in the Commonwealth shall be provided or approved by the state registrar. </section><section prefix="2">A certified copy of a vital record or any part thereof, issued in accordance with subsection (1) of this section, shall be considered for all purposes the same as the original and shall be prima facie evidence of the facts stated therein. The evidentiary value of a certificate or record which has been amended shall be determined by the judicial or administrative body, or official before which the certificate is offered as evidence. </section><section prefix="3">The federal agency responsible for national vital statistics may be furnished copies or data from the system of vital statistics for national statistics, if the federal agency shares in the cost of collecting, processing, and transmitting the data, and if the data is not used for other than statistical purposes by the federal agency unless so authorized by the cabinet. </section><section prefix="4">Federal, state, local, and other public or private agencies may, upon request, be furnished copies or data from the system of vital statistics for statistical or administrative purposes upon terms or conditions as may be prescribed by regulation if the copies or data are not used for purposes other than those for which they were requested without prior permission of the cabinet. No information other than statistical data shall be provided for commercial purposes. </section><section prefix="5">The cabinet may, by agreement, transmit copies of records and other reports required by this chapter to offices of vital statistics outside the Commonwealth when the records or other reports relate to residents of those jurisdictions or persons born in those jurisdictions. The agreement shall require that the copies be used for statistical and administrative purposes only and the agreement shall further provide for the retention and disposition of the copies. Copies received by the Vital Statistics Branch from offices of vital statistics in other states shall be handled in the same manner as prescribed in this section. </section><section prefix="6">No person shall prepare or issue any certificate which purports to be an original, certified copy, or copy of a vital record except as authorized in this section or regulation adopted hereunder. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 442, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 369, sec. 26, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8747</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>