<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="186" order_by="186">LICENSING OF MOTOR VEHICLES, OPERATORS, AND TRAILERS </unit></structure><section_number>186.164</section_number><catch_line>Collection and distribution of special license plate fees -- Design,printing, and replacement -- Application process -- Voluntary contributionfor designated group -- Administrative regulations -- Audit of speciallicense plate funds.  </catch_line><order_by>164</order_by><text>(1)The SF portion of the fee required under KRS 186.162 shall include the fee toreflectorize all license plates under KRS 186.240. All EF fees required underKRS 186.162 shall be collected at the time of an initial or renewal applicationby the county clerk who shall forward the EF fee to the cabinet. The cabinetshall remit EF fees to the group or organization identified in KRS 186.162 on aquarterly basis. The cabinet may retain any investment income earned fromholding EF fees designated to be remitted under this subsection to offsetadministrative costs incurred by the cabinet in the administration of EF fees.(2)A special license plate shall be the color and design selected by the group ororganization identified in subsection (13) of this section, contingent upon theapproval of the Transportation Cabinet. In addition to the design selected for aspecial license plate, the name "Kentucky," an annual renewal decal, and anycombination of letters or numerals required by the cabinet in the design shallalso appear on the plate.(3)Except as provided in KRS 186.162, the total initial fee for a special licenseplate created under this chapter shall be twenty-eight dollars ($28), of whichthe Transportation Cabinet shall receive twenty-five dollars ($25) and thecounty clerk shall receive three dollars ($3), and the total renewal fee shall befifteen dollars ($15), of which the Transportation Cabinet shall receive twelvedollars ($12) and the county clerk shall receive three dollars ($3). Thetwenty-five dollar ($25) initial fee and twelve dollar ($12) renewal fee receivedby the Transportation Cabinet under this subsection shall include an applicant'sregistration fee required under KRS 186.050.(4)An actual metal special license plate shall be issued on the same schedule asregular license plates are issued under KRS 186.240. The cabinet shall havethe discretion to extend the time period that will exist between the date a metalspecial license plate is issued and the date that regular plates are issued underKRS 186.240. A renewal registration decal shall be issued all other yearsduring the owner's or lessee's birth month, except as provided in KRS186.041(2), 186.042(5), and 186.174(2). A person seeking a special licenseplate for a vehicle provided as part of the person's occupation shall conform tothe requirements of KRS 186.050(14).(5)(a)If a special license plate issued under this chapter deteriorates to thepoint that the lettering, numbering, or images on the face of the plate arenot legible, the plate shall be replaced free of charge, if the owner orlessee has not transferred the vehicle to which the plate was issuedduring the current licensing period.(b)If a special license plate issued under this chapter is lost, stolen, ordamaged in an accident, the county clerk shall issue a new plate uponpayment of a three dollar ($3) county clerk fee, if the owner or lessee hasnot transferred the vehicle to which the plate was issued during thecurrent licensing period.(6)Upon the sale, transfer, or termination of a lease of a vehicle with any speciallicense plate issued under this chapter, the owner or lessee shall remove thespecial plate and return it and the certificate of registration to the county clerk.The county clerk shall reissue the owner or lessee a regular license plate and acertificate of registration upon payment of a three dollar ($3) county clerk fee. Ifthe owner or lessee requests, the county clerk shall reissue the special plateupon payment of a three dollar ($3) county clerk fee for use on any othervehicle of the same classification and category owned, leased, or acquired bythe person during the current licensing period. If the owner or lessee has thespecial plate reissued to a vehicle which has been previously registered in thisstate, the regular license plate that is being replaced shall be returned to thecounty clerk who shall forward the plate to the Transportation Cabinet.(7)A special license plate may be issued to the owner or lessee of a motor vehiclethat is required to be registered under KRS 186.050(1), (3)(a), or (4)(a), excepta special license plate shall not be issued to a taxicab, limousine, or U-Drive-Itregistered and licensed under this chapter or KRS Chapter 281. A personapplying for a special license plate shall apply in the office of the county clerk inthe county of the person's residence, except as provided in KRS 186.168(3).All special license plates issued under this chapter may be combined with apersonalized license plate under the provisions of KRS 186.174. The fee tocombine a special license plate with a personalized license plate shall be asestablished in KRS 186.162(3).(8)Within thirty (30) days of termination from election to, appointment to, ormembership with any group or organization, an applicant to whom a speciallicense plate was issued under this chapter shall return the special licenseplate to the county clerk of the county of his or her residence, unless theperson is merely changing his or her status with the group or organization toretired.(9)A group wanting to create a special license plate that is not authorized underthis chapter on June 20, 2005, shall comply with the following conditions beforebeing eligible to apply for a special license plate:(a)The group shall be nonprofit and based, headquartered, or have achapter in Kentucky;(b)The group may be organized for, but shall not be restricted to, social,civic, or entertainment purposes;(c)The group, or the group's lettering, logo, image, or message to be placedon the license plate, if created, shall not discriminate against any race,color, religion, sex, or national origin, and shall not be construed, asdetermined by the cabinet, as an attempt to victimize or intimidate anyperson due to the person's race, color, religion, sex, or national origin;(d)The group shall not be a political party and shall not have been createdprimarily to promote a specific political belief;(e)The group shall not have as its primary purpose the promotion of anyspecific faith, religion, or antireligion;(f)The name of the group shall not be the name of a special product orbrand name, and shall not be construed, as determined by the cabinet, aspromoting a product or brand name; and(g)The group's lettering, logo, image, or message to be placed on thelicense plate, if created, shall not be obscene, as determined by thecabinet.(10)If the cabinet denies to issue a group a special license plate based upon theconditions specified in subsection (9) of this section, the cabinet shall,immediately upon denying to issue a group a special license plate, notify inwriting the chairperson of both the House and Senate standing committees ontransportation of the denial and the reasons upon which the cabinet based thedenial. A person seeking a personalized license plate under KRS 186.174 shallbe subject to the conditions specified in subsection (9)(c) to (g) of this section.(11)If the cabinet approves a request for a special license plate, the cabinet shallbegin designing and printing the plate after the group collects a minimum ofnine hundred (900) applications with each application being accompanied by atwenty-five dollar ($25) state fee. The applications and accompanying fee shallbe submitted to the cabinet at one (1) time as a whole and shall not besubmitted individually or intermittently.(12)An initial applicant for, or an applicant renewing, his or her registration for aspecial license plate may, at the time of application, make a voluntarycontribution that the county clerk shall forward to the cabinet. The entity thatsponsors a special plate established by the process outlined in this sectionmay set a requested donation amount, not to exceed ten dollars ($10), that willautomatically be added to the cost of registration or renewal, unless theindividual registering or renewing the vehicle registration opts out ofcontributing that recommended amount. The cabinet shall, on an annual basis,remit the voluntary contributions to the appropriate group identified to be usedfor the declared purpose stated under subsection (13) of this section. Thecabinet may retain any investment income earned from holding voluntarycontributions designated to be remitted under this subsection to offsetadministrative costs incurred by the cabinet in the administration of thecontributions. Any group or organization that receives a mandatory EF feeunder KRS 186.162 shall submit the information required under subsection(13)(a) and (c) of this section to the Transportation Cabinet within thirty (30)days of June 20, 2005.(13)If a group wants to receive a donation when the group or organization's speciallicense plate is initially purchased or renewed under subsection (12) of thissection, the group shall, at the time the nine hundred (900) applications aresubmitted to the Transportation Cabinet, also submit a notarized affidavit to thecabinet attesting to:(a)The name, address, and telephone number for the group or organization.If the group or organization does not have its headquarters in theCommonwealth, then the name, address, and telephone number for thegroup or organization's Kentucky state chapter shall be required. Thenames of the officers of the group or organization shall also be required. Ifthe entity receiving funds under subsection (12) of this section is not astate governmental agency, a program unit within a state governmentalagency, or is a group or organization that does not have a statewidechapter, then an extra donation for use by the group or organization shallbe prohibited;(b)The amount of the monetary donation the group wants to receive when aperson purchases the group or organization's special license plate; and(c)The purpose for which the donated funds will be used by the group ororganization. Donated funds shall not be limited for use by members ofthe group or organization, and shall not be used for administrative orpersonnel costs of the group or organization.(14)All funds received by a group or organization under subsection (12) of thissection shall be deposited into an account separate from all other accounts thegroup or organization may have, and the account shall be audited yearly at theexpense of the group or organization. The completed audit shall be forwardedto the Transportation Cabinet in Frankfort. One hundred percent (100%) of thefunds received by a group or organization under subsection (12) of this sectionshall be used for the express purpose identified by the group in subsection (13)of this section. Any group or organization that receives a mandatory EF feeunder KRS 186.162 shall comply with the provisions of this subsection.(15)The secretary of the Transportation Cabinet shall promulgate administrativeregulations under KRS Chapter 13A to establish additional rules to implementthe issuance of special license plates issued under this chapter, including butnot limited to:(a)Documentation that will be required to accompany an application for aspecial license plate to provide proof of:1.Election to the United States Congress or the Kentucky GeneralAssembly;2.Election or appointment to the Kentucky Court of Justice;3.Membership in a Masonic Order, Fraternal Order of Police, oremergency management organization;4.Eligibility for membership in the Gold Star Mothers of America;5.Eligibility as a father for associate membership in the Gold StarMothers of America;6.Eligibility for membership in the Gold Star Wives of America;7.Ownership of an amateur radio operator license;8.Receipt of the Silver Star Medal;9.Receipt of the Bronze Star Medal awarded for valor; or10.Eligibility for a Gold Star Siblings license plate for a person whosesibling died while serving the country in the United States ArmedForces. For the purposes of this subparagraph, "sibling" means asibling by blood, a sibling by half-blood, a sibling by adoption, or astepsibling.(b)The time schedule permissible for a group or organization to request adesign change for the special license plate; and(c)The procedures for review of proposed license plates and the standardsby which proposed special license plates are approved or rejected inaccordance with subsection (9) of this section.(16)Any individual, group, or organization that fails to audit any funds receivedunder this chapter, or that intentionally uses any funds received in any wayother than attested to under subsection (13) of this section or for administrativeor personnel costs in violation of subsection (13) of this section, shall be guiltyof a Class D felony and upon conviction shall, in addition to being subject tocriminal penalties, be assessed a mandatory five thousand dollar ($5,000) fine.</text><history>Amended 2015 Ky. Acts ch. 19, sec. 39, effective June 24, 2015; and ch.32, sec. 2, effective January 1, 2016. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 33, sec. 3,effective July 15, 2010, ch. 40, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2010; ch. 72, sec. 2,effective July 15, 2010; and ch. 113, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended2008 Ky. Acts ch. 30, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Actsch. 40, sec. 1, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 2,effective July 12, 2006; and ch. 200, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2006. -- Created2005 Ky. Acts ch. 133, sec. 2, effective June 20, 2005.</history><metadata><effective>January 1, 2016</effective><lrc-note> (1/1/2016). This statute was amended by2015 Ky. Acts chs. 19 and 32, which do not appear to be in conflict and havebeen codified together.</lrc-note><pdf-author></pdf-author><pdf-creation-date></pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=44720</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>