<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="346" order_by="346">COMPENSATION OF CRIME VICTIMS </unit></structure><section_number>346.165</section_number><catch_line>Contracts regarding crime -- Money to be paid to board -- Disposition. </catch_line><order_by>165</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Every person contracting with any person or the representative or assignee of any person accused or convicted of a crime in this state, with respect to the reenactment of such crime, by way of a movie, book, magazine article, radio or television presentation, live entertainment of any kind, or from the expression of such person's thoughts, feelings, opinions, or emotions regarding such crime, shall pay over to the board any moneys which would otherwise, by terms of such contract, be owing to the person so accused or convicted or his representatives. </section><section prefix="2">After deducting all sums paid to the victim by the board, the board shall deposit such moneys in its accounts for the benefit of and payable to any victim of crimes committed by such person, provided that such person is eventually convicted of the crime and provided further that such victim, within five (5) years of the date of the crime, brings a civil action in a court of competent jurisdiction and recovers a money judgment against such person or his representatives. </section><section prefix="3">Upon disposition of charges favorable to any person accused of committing a crime, or upon a showing by such person that five (5) years have elapsed from the board's receipt of such funds and that such person has not been convicted of said crime and further that no actions are pending against such person in connection with the crime or pursuant to this section, the board shall immediately pay over any such moneys to such person. </section><section prefix="4">Notwithstanding any inconsistent provision of the civil practice law and rules with respect to the timely bringing of an action, the five (5) year period provided for in subsection (2) of this section shall not begin to run until the board has received such moneys. </section><section prefix="5">Any action taken by any person convicted of a crime, whether by way of execution of a power of attorney, creation of corporate entities, or otherwise, to defeat the purpose of this section shall be null and void as against the public policy of this state. </section><section prefix="6">The failure of a person to pay moneys to the board in accordance with subsection (1) shall create a debt due and owing to the board from that person and shall constitute a preferential lien to the state which may be collected by the board by civil process. </section></text><history>Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 297, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:47</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32712</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>