<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="199" order_by="199">PROTECTIVE SERVICES FOR CHILDREN - ADOPTION </unit></structure><section_number>199.557</section_number><catch_line>Federal Title IV-E adoption assistance. </catch_line><order_by>557</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For the purpose of this section, unless the context requires otherwise, "Federal Title IV-E adoption assistance" means a monthly payment to assist in the integration of the child into the adoptive family and the payment of nonrecurring adoption expenses which include reasonable and necessary adoption fees, court costs, attorney fees, and other expenses which are directly related to legal adoption of a special-needs child and which are not incurred in violation of state or federal law. </section><section prefix="2">Federal Title IV-E adoption assistance shall be paid to the adoptive parent or parents after conclusion of the adoption if the child meets the eligibility criteria established at 42 U.S.C. sec. 673. </section><section prefix="3">Agreements for Federal Title IV-E adoption assistance under this section shall be made prior to the adoption of the child. </section><section prefix="4">Payment shall be out of funds appropriated to the cabinet and Federal Title IV-E funds of the Social Security Act as amended (42 U.S.C. secs. 673 et seq.). All payments shall be in accordance with administrative regulations promulgated by the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. Payments shall not exceed the amount which would be paid for foster care for the child. Nonrecurring adoption expenses shall only be reimbursed up to the limit established by the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services or his designated representative in accordance with 42 U.S.C. secs. 673 et seq. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 48, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 181, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 144, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 247, sec. 4, effective July 13, 1990. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=7189</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>