<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">B MEDICAL IMAGING, RADIATION THERAPY, AND RELATED OCCUPATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>311B.090</section_number><catch_line>Restrictions on unlicensed persons -- Application of chapter.   </catch_line><order_by>090</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall engage or attempt to engage in the operation of radiation-producing equipment or the administration of ionizing radiation for the purpose of medical imaging or radiation therapy in Kentucky unless licensed in accordance with the provisions of this chapter. </section><section prefix="2">This chapter shall not apply to any individual licensed in the Commonwealth of Kentucky as a licensed practitioner of the healing arts, any student enrolled in an approved educational program in medical imaging technology or radiation therapy, or any employee of the federal government engaged in the performance of official duties within the state. </section><section prefix="3">Misuse of regulated credentials shall result in disciplinary action by the board in addition to possible action by the credentialing agency. </section><section prefix="4">Nothing in this chapter or in the administrative regulations promulgated by the board pursuant to this chapter shall be interpreted to limit or restrict a licensed health care practitioner or provider from engaging in the full scope of practice authorized by the license for that person's profession, training, or services. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 50, sec. 9, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40203</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>