<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XX" order_by="20">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="243" order_by="243">ALCOHOLIC BEVERAGES -- LICENSES AND TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>243.120</section_number><catch_line>Business authorized by distiller's, rectifier's, or winery license -- Class A and Class B distiller's licenses. </catch_line><order_by>120</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A distiller's, rectifier's, or winery license shall authorize the licensee to engage in the business of distiller, rectifier, or winery at the premises specifically designated in the license, to maintain aging warehouses, and to transport for himself or herself only any alcoholic beverage which he or she is authorized under the license to manufacture or sell. The licensee shall transport alcoholic beverages only by a vehicle operated by himself or herself, which has affixed to its sides at all times a sign of form and size prescribed by the state board, containing among other things the name and license number of the licensee. No distilled spirits or wine shall be transported on the same truck or vehicle with malt beverages, except by a common carrier, unless the owner of the truck or vehicle holds a distributor's license. </section><section prefix="2"><section prefix="a">Distillers that produce more than fifty thousand (50,000) gallons of distilled spirits per calendar year at the premises shall obtain a distiller's license, Class A. </section><section prefix="b">Distillers that produce fifty thousand (50,000) gallons or less of distilled spirits per calendar year at the premises shall obtain a distiller's license, Class B (craft distillery). </section></section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 12, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 2013 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 59, effective June 25, 2013. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 289, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1950 Ky. Acts ch. 176, sec. 8. -- Amended 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 168, secs. 1 and 10. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2554b-118. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43034</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>