<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="132" order_by="132">LEVY AND ASSESSMENT OF PROPERTY TAXES </unit></structure><section_number>132.260</section_number><catch_line>Rental space for parking mobile homes and recreational vehicles -- Report -- Right to inspect. </catch_line><order_by>260</order_by><text>Every person providing rental space for the parking of mobile homes and recreational vehicles shall by February 1 of each year report the name of the owner and type and size of all mobile homes and recreational vehicles not registered in this state under KRS 186.655 on his premises on the prior January 1 to the property valuation administrator of the county in which the property is located. The report shall be made in accordance with forms prescribed by the Department of Revenue and shall be signed and verified by the chief officer or person in charge of the business. The property valuation administrator may make a personal inspection and investigation of the premises on which mobile homes and recreational vehicles are located, for the purpose of identifying and assessing such property. No person in charge of such premises shall refuse to permit the inspection and investigation. </text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 185, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 317, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Repealed and reenacted 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. V, sec. 327, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 395, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 262, sec. 3. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 186, Art. I, sec. 6. -- Amended 1949 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 8. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 4777a-1, 4777a-2, 4777a-3, 4777a-5. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:00</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28250</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>