<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.481</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Cardiovascular Disease Initiative -- Goals -- KCDI board. </catch_line><order_by>481</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Cardiovascular Disease Initiative (KCDI) is hereby created with the program goals that include but are not limited to: <section prefix="a">Preventing and reducing the prevalence of cardiovascular disease in Kentucky through early detection and education; </section><section prefix="b">Reducing the incidence of deaths from cardiovascular disease in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="c">Measurably reducing health-care costs associated with cardiovascular disease in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="d">Conducting research and developing new intellectual property and ancillary health businesses that create new knowledge-based businesses in Kentucky; </section><section prefix="e">Improving access to best practices and protocols for cardiovascular disease for all Kentuckians through an e-health network; and </section><section prefix="f">Assisting in securing state, federal, and private funding to stimulate health information capacities. </section></section><section prefix="2">The KCDI shall be governed by a board that shall be appointed by the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, except as provided in paragraphs (q) to (s) of this subsection, no later than August 1, 2007, and composed of: <section prefix="a">One (1) member shall be appointed by the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services who shall serve as chair of the KCDI during the first year, and this individual shall remain as a board member for two (2) additional years. The board shall elect its chair after the first year and may reelect the current chair; </section><section prefix="b">The president of the University of Louisville, or a designee; </section><section prefix="c">The president of the University of Kentucky, or a designee; </section><section prefix="d">The secretary or designee of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="e">The commissioner or designee of the Department of Commercialization and Innovation; </section><section prefix="f">The commissioner or designee of the Department for Public Health; </section><section prefix="g">The commissioner or designee of the Department of Insurance; </section><section prefix="h">The chair of the Kentucky e-Health Network Board, or a designee; </section><section prefix="i">One (1) representative of a Kentucky comprehensive university and one (1) representative of the Kentucky Community and Technical College System; </section><section prefix="j">Two (2) physicians with experience in research and treatment of cardiovascular disease, one (1) recommended by the dean of the medical school at the University of Louisville and one (1) recommended by the dean of the medical school at the University of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="k">The executive director of the Kentucky Primary Care Association; </section><section prefix="l">The president of the Kentucky Academy of Family Physicians; </section><section prefix="m">One (1) member of a Kentucky chapter of the American Heart Association; </section><section prefix="n">Four (4) members representing the business community, from a list of eight (8) persons recommended by the Kentucky Chamber of Commerce; </section><section prefix="o">Four (4) members representing private sector hospitals that treat the greatest number of cardiology patients as measured by the number of MDC 5 discharges and as reported by COMPdata or its successor; </section><section prefix="p">One (1) representative from a freestanding pediatric teaching hospital; </section><section prefix="q">One (1) at-large member appointed by the Governor; </section><section prefix="r">Two (2) members of the Senate, one (1) representing each major political party, appointed by the President of the Senate; and </section><section prefix="s">Two (2) members of the House of Representatives, one (1) representing each major political party appointed by the Speaker of the House. </section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">Members serving under paragraphs (b) to (h), (k), and (l) of subsection (2) of this section shall serve by virtue of their positions and shall not be subject to term limits. </section><section prefix="b">Members appointed under paragraphs (i) and (j) of subsection (2) of this section shall serve three (3) year terms and may be reappointed to no more than two (2) consecutive terms. Members shall continue to serve until a successor is appointed. </section><section prefix="c">Members appointed under paragraphs (m) to (p) of subsection (2) of this section shall serve staggered terms that shall not exceed three (3) year terms. Members shall continue to serve until a successor is appointed. </section><section prefix="d">Members appointed under paragraphs (q), (r), and (s) of subsection (2) of this section shall serve three (3) year terms. </section></section><section prefix="4">The KCDI board shall meet at least quarterly or upon the call of the chair. All members may receive reimbursement for expenses related to attendance at meetings and official functions of the board in accordance with state administrative regulations relating to travel reimbursement but shall not be otherwise compensated for duties associated with the board. </section><section prefix="5">The KCDI board may appoint committees, subcommittees, advisory councils, or other groups to assist in the furtherance of the goals of the KCDI. Members appointed under this subsection need not be members of the KCDI board and may receive reimbursement for expenses related to attendance at meetings and official functions of the board in accordance with state administrative regulations relating to travel reimbursement but shall not be otherwise compensated for duties associated with the board. </section><section prefix="6">No member of the board shall be subject to personal liability for a loss sustained or damage suffered as a result of board action or inaction. </section><section prefix="7">The KCDI board shall be attached to the Cabinet for Health and Family Services for administrative purposes. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 312, effective July 15, 2010. -- Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 2, effective June 26, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8418</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>