<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="158" order_by="158">CONDUCT OF SCHOOLS -- SPECIAL PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>158.060</section_number><catch_line>School month and school day -- Duty-free lunch period -- Nonteaching time for teachers. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Twenty (20) school days, or days in which teachers are actually employed in the schoolroom, shall constitute a school month in the common schools. </section><section prefix="2">Each full-time teacher shall be provided with a duty-free lunch period each day during the regularly scheduled student lunch period. The duty-free lunch period shall be not less than the length of the lunch period specified in the school calendar approved by the chief state school officer. A full-time teacher may be assigned to lunch room duty during the regularly scheduled student lunch period only for an amount of time equal to the noninstructional time in excess of fifty-five (55) minutes included in the teacher's daily schedule. The calculation of noninstructional time shall not include the teacher's duty-free lunch period, the time teachers are required to be at school prior to the start of the student's instructional day, or the time teachers are required to remain at school after the students are dismissed. </section><section prefix="3">Except for children with disabilities and children attending the primary school program who may attend a program of less than six (6) hours per day under policy adopted by the local school district board of education and approved by the commissioner of education and children attending a school district where the local board has approved a schedule that provides at least the equivalent of six (6) hours of daily instruction during the school year, a minimum of six (6) hours of actual school work shall constitute a school day. Kindergarten programs may be operated for less than six (6) hours without state board approval. The Kentucky Board of Education, upon recommendation of the chief state school officer, shall develop and approve regulations governing make up by school districts of whole days missed due to emergencies, or partial days missed as a result of shortening regularly scheduled school days due to emergencies. </section><section prefix="4">Teachers shall be provided additional time for nonteaching activities. The nonteaching time shall be used to provide teachers opportunities for professional development activities as provided in KRS 156.095, instructional planning, school-based decision making as provided in KRS 160.345, curriculum development, and outreach activities involving their students' families and the community. </section><section prefix="5">Character education programs and activities shall be considered valuable and legitimate components of the actual school work constituting a school day under subsection (3) of this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 162, sec. 5, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 261, sec. 3, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 20, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996; ch. 195, sec. 24, effective July 15, 1996; and ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 6, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1994; ch. 394, sec. 21, effective July 15, 1994; and ch. 405, sec. 26, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. I, sec. 26, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 40, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1985 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 12, effective October 18, 1985. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 359, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 306, sec. 1, effective March 30, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 345, sec. 1. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 271, sec. 1. -- Amended 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 244, Art. VII, sec. 1. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 4363-6. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><lrc-note> (7/14/2000).  This section was amended by 2000 Ky. Acts chs. 162 and 261, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3430</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>