<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="344" order_by="344">CIVIL RIGHTS </unit></structure><section_number>344.090</section_number><catch_line>Religion or national origin, employment discrimination not unlawful in certain cases. </catch_line><order_by>090</order_by><text>Notwithstanding any other provisions of KRS 344.030 to 344.110, it is not an unlawful practice for: <section prefix="1">An employer to hire and employ employees, or an employment agency to classify, or refer for employment an individual, for a labor organization to classify its membership or to classify or refer for employment an individual, or for an employer, labor organization, or joint labor-management committee controlling apprenticeship or other training or retraining programs to admit or employ an individual in any such program, on the basis of his religion or national origin in those certain instances where religion or national origin is a bona fide occupational qualification reasonably necessary to the normal operation of that particular business or enterprise. </section><section prefix="2">A religious corporation, association, or society to employ an individual on the basis of his religion to perform work connected with the carrying on by such corporation, association, or society of its religious activity. </section><section prefix="3">A school, college, university, or other educational institution to hire and employ employees of a particular religion if the school, college, university, or other educational institution is, in whole or substantial part, owned, supported, controlled, or managed by a particular religion or by a particular religious corporation, association, or society, or if the curriculum of the school, college, university, or other educational institution is directed toward the propagation of a particular religion and the choice of employees is calculated by such organization to promote the religious principles for which it is established or maintained. </section></text><history>Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 2, Art. 3, sec. 308. </history><metadata><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32611</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>