<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>286.4-440</section_number><catch_line>Application and license fees. </catch_line><order_by>4-440</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each applicant at the time of making application shall pay two hundred fifty dollars ($250) to the commissioner as a fee for investigating the application for the initial location in Kentucky, or a fee of one hundred fifty dollars ($150) for additional locations, and the additional sum of four hundred dollars ($400) as an annual license fee for each location for the period terminating on the last day of the current calendar year. If the application is filed after June 30 in any year, the payment shall be two hundred dollars ($200) as a license fee in addition to the fee for investigation. </section><section prefix="2">If any person regulated by the department desires to purchase an existing licensed location or locations, the person shall submit an application to the commissioner containing the information as the commissioner may prescribe. The fee for this application shall be one hundred dollars ($100) per location not to exceed one thousand dollars ($1,000). </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 659, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 157, sec. 1, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 198, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 204, sec. 4, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification> KRS 288.440. </former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2006).  In accordance with 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 247, secs. 38 and 39, this statute has been renumbered as a section of the Kentucky Financial Services Code, KRS Chapter 286. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14633</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>