<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIX" order_by="19">PUBLIC SAFETY AND MORALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="230" order_by="230">HORSE RACING AND SHOWING </unit></structure><section_number>230.290</section_number><catch_line>Provisions applicable to all licenses. </catch_line><order_by>290</order_by><text>All licenses granted under this chapter: <section prefix="1">Shall be in writing; </section><section prefix="2">Shall be subject to all administrative regulations and conditions as may from time to time be prescribed by the racing commission; </section><section prefix="3">Shall contain conditions as may be considered necessary or desirable by the racing commission for purposes of this chapter; and </section><section prefix="4">No license shall extend beyond the end of the calendar year for which it was issued, unless the license expires on the last date of the birth month of the licensee, in which case it may expire on that date. The racing commission may renew any license and any renewal shall not be construed to be a waiver or condonement of any violation which occurred prior to renewal and shall not prevent subsequent proceedings against the licensee therefor. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 454, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 5, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 10, effective July 13, 2004. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 109, sec. 19, effective March 30, 1992. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 156, sec. 4. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 184, sec. 9, effective June 16, 1960. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:30</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=10841</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>