<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="100" order_by="100">PLANNING AND ZONING </unit></structure><section_number>100.187</section_number><catch_line>Contents of comprehensive plan. </catch_line><order_by>187</order_by><text>The comprehensive plan shall contain, as a minimum, the following elements: <section prefix="1">A statement of goals and objectives, which shall serve as a guide for the physical development and economic and social well-being of the planning unit; </section><section prefix="2">A land use plan element, which shall show proposals for the most appropriate, economic, desirable, and feasible patterns for the general location, character, extent, and interrelationship of the manner in which the community should use its public and private land at specified times as far into the future as is reasonable to foresee. Such land uses may cover, without being limited to, public and private, residential, commercial, industrial, agricultural, and recreational land uses; </section><section prefix="3">A transportation plan element, which shall show proposals for the most desirable, appropriate, economic, and feasible pattern for the general location, character, and extent of the channels, routes, and terminals for transportation facilities for the circulation of persons and goods for specified times as far into the future as is reasonable to foresee. The channels, routes, and terminals may include, without being limited to, all classes of highways or streets, railways, airways, waterways; routings for mass transit trucks, etc.; and terminals for people, goods, or vehicles related to highways, airways, waterways, and railways; </section><section prefix="4">A community facilities plan element which shall show proposals for the most desirable, appropriate, economic, and feasible pattern for the general location, character, and the extent of public and semipublic buildings, land, and facilities for specified times as far into the future as is reasonable to foresee. The facilities may include, without being limited to, parks and recreation, schools and other educational or cultural facilities, libraries, churches, hospitals, social welfare and medical facilities, utilities, fire stations, police stations, jails, or other public office or administrative facilities; </section><section prefix="5"><section prefix="a">Provisions for the accommodation of all military installations greater than or equal in area to three hundred (300) acres that are: <section prefix="1">Contained wholly or partially within the planning unit's boundaries; </section><section prefix="2">Abutting the planning unit's boundaries; or </section><section prefix="3">Contained within or abutting any county that contains a planning unit. </section></section><section prefix="b">The goal of providing for the accommodation of these military installations shall be to minimize conflicts between the relevant military installations and the planning unit's residential population. These provisions shall be made after consultation with the relevant installation's command authorities to determine the needs of the relevant military installation. These consultations shall include but not be limited to questions of installation expansion, environmental impact, issues of installation safety, and issues relating to air space usage, to include noise pollution, air pollution, and air safety concerns; and </section></section><section prefix="6">The comprehensive plan may include any additional elements such as, without being limited to, community renewal, housing, flood control, pollution, conservation, natural resources, regional impact, historic preservation, and other programs which in the judgment of the planning commission will further serve the purposes of the comprehensive plan. </section></text><history> Amended 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 167, sec. 10, effective June 24, 2003. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1986. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 25. </history><metadata><effective> June 24, 2003 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:11</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26711</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>