<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="11" order_by="11">A EXECUTIVE BRANCH CODE OF ETHICS </unit></structure><section_number>11A.990</section_number><catch_line>Penalties -- Time limitation on prosecution for violation of KRS 11A.040. </catch_line><order_by>990</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person who violates KRS 11A.040 shall be guilty of a Class D felony. In addition: <section prefix="a">The judgment of conviction for a violation of KRS 11A.040(2) shall recite that the offender is disqualified to hold office thereafter; and </section><section prefix="b">Any person who violates KRS 11A.040(1) to (5) shall be judged to have forfeited any employment, or constitutional or statutory office he holds, provisions of KRS Chapter 18A to the contrary notwithstanding. </section></section><section prefix="2">Any officer, public servant, or candidate required to file a statement of financial disclosure under KRS 11A.050 who does not file the statement by a date specified in that section shall have his salary withheld from the first day of noncompliance until he shall have completed the action required by law. The amount withheld shall be deducted from his overall pay and allowances and shall be recoverable upon the filing of the statement of financial disclosure. The commission may grant a reasonable extension of time for filing a statement of financial disclosure for good cause shown. </section><section prefix="3">Any person who maliciously files with the commission a false charge of misconduct on the part of any public servant or other person shall be fined not to exceed five thousand dollars ($5,000), or imprisoned in a county jail for a term not to exceed one (1) year, or both. </section><section prefix="4">Prosecution for violation of any provision of KRS 11A.040 shall not be commenced after four (4) years have elapsed from the date of the violation. Any executive agency lobbyist, employer, or real party in interest who violates any provision in KRS 11A.206 shall for the first violation be subject to a civil penalty not to exceed five thousand dollars ($5,000). For the second and each subsequent violation, he shall be guilty of a Class D felony. </section><section prefix="5">Any executive agency lobbyist, employer, or real party in interest who fails to file the initial registration statement or updated registration statement required by KRS 11A.211 or 11A.216, or who fails to remedy a deficiency in any filing in a timely manner, may be fined by the commission an amount not to exceed one hundred dollars ($100) per day, up to a maximum total fine of one thousand dollars ($1,000). </section><section prefix="6">Any executive agency lobbyist, employer, or real party in interest who intentionally fails to register, or who intentionally files an initial registration statement or updated registration statement required by KRS 11A.211 or 11A.216 which he knows to contain false information or to omit required information shall be guilty of a Class D felony. </section><section prefix="7">An executive agency lobbyist, employer, or real party in interest who files a false statement of expenditures or details of a financial transaction under KRS 11A.221 or 11A.226 is liable in a civil action to any official or employee who sustains damage as a result of the filing or publication of the statement. </section><section prefix="8">Violation of KRS 11A.236 is a Class D felony. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 475, sec. 8, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 602, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1998; and ch. 603, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1993 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 55, effective September 16, 1993. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 287, sec. 15, effective July 14, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:15</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=617</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>