<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="508" order_by="508">ASSAULT AND RELATED OFFENSES </unit></structure><section_number>508.075</section_number><catch_line>Terroristic threatening in the first degree. </catch_line><order_by>075</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person is guilty of terroristic threatening in the first degree when he or she: <section prefix="a">Intentionally makes false statements that he or she or another person has placed a weapon of mass destruction on: <section prefix="1">The real property or any building of any public or private elementary or secondary school, vocational school, or institution of postsecondary education; </section><section prefix="2">A school bus or other vehicle owned, operated, or leased by a school; </section><section prefix="3">The real property or any building public or private that is the site of an official school-sanctioned function; or </section><section prefix="4">The real property or any building owned or leased by a government agency; or </section></section><section prefix="b">Intentionally and without lawful authority, places a counterfeit weapon of mass destruction at any location or on any object specified in paragraph (a) of this subsection. </section></section><section prefix="2">A counterfeit weapon of mass destruction is placed with lawful authority if it is placed, with the written permission of the chief officer of the school or other institution, as a part of an official training exercise and is placed by a public servant, as defined in KRS 522.010. </section><section prefix="3">A person is not guilty of commission of an offense under this section if he or she, innocently and believing the information to be true, communicates a threat made by another person to school personnel, a peace officer, a law enforcement agency, a public agency involved in emergency response, or a public safety answering point and identifies the person from whom the threat was communicated, if known. </section><section prefix="4">Terroristic threatening in the first degree is a Class C felony. </section></text><history> Created 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001. </history><metadata><effective> June 21, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:21</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19736</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>