<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.6929</section_number><catch_line>Right of action of educational institution for damages caused by violation of KRS 164.6901 to 164.6935. </catch_line><order_by>6929</order_by><text><section prefix="1">An educational institution has a right of action against an athlete agent or a former student-athlete for damages caused by a violation of KRS 164.6901 to 164.6935. In an action under this section, the court may award to the prevailing party costs and reasonable attorney's fees. </section><section prefix="2">Damages of an educational institution under subsection (1) of this section include losses and expenses incurred because, as a result of the conduct of an athlete agent or former student-athlete, the educational institution was injured by a violation of KRS 164.6901 to 164.6935 or was penalized, disqualified, or suspended from participation in athletics by a national association for the promotion and regulation of athletics, by an athletic conference, or by reasonable self-imposed disciplinary action taken to mitigate sanctions likely to be imposed by such an organization. </section><section prefix="3">A right of action under this section does not accrue until the educational institution discovers or by the exercise of reasonable diligence would have discovered the violation by the athlete agent or former student-athlete. </section><section prefix="4">Any liability of the athlete agent or the former student-athlete under this section is several and not joint. </section><section prefix="5">The office may assess a civil penalty against an athlete agent not to exceed twenty-five thousand dollars ($25,000) for a violation of KRS 164.6901 to 164.6935. </section><section prefix="6">KRS 164.6901 to 164.6935 does not restrict rights, remedies, or defenses of any person under law or equity. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 221, effective July 15, 2010. -- Repealed and reenacted 2003 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 15, effective June 24, 2003. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 259, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><former-codification>KRS 164.686. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:49</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4401</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>