<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="156" order_by="156">DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION </unit></structure><section_number>156.476</section_number><catch_line>Textbooks for children with impaired vision -- Requirement that publisher of adopted textbook furnish American Printing House for the Blind with text in electronic format. </catch_line><order_by>476</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Board of Education, upon the recommendation of the chief state school officer, shall select suitable textbooks and programs in an appropriate format, which include braille textbooks, and other materials available in clear type of eighteen (18) to twenty-four (24) points in the different subject areas for children with impaired vision who are attending the public schools of the Commonwealth of Kentucky in grades kindergarten through twelve (12). These books and materials shall not be subject to the official bids, filing fees, sampling, and the stipulated list prices, lowest wholesale prices, and the standards and specifications required for the books and materials approved and listed by the State Textbook Commission for regular use by the pupils attending the public schools of the State of Kentucky. The Kentucky Board of Education, upon the recommendation of the chief state school officer, may promulgate an administrative regulation determining the pupils eligible for the books and materials, the number of books and types of materials to be purchased, and the general administration of the program. The chief state school officer, subject to the approval of the Kentucky Board of Education, may purchase these books and materials and distribute them without cost to the pupils with impaired vision attending the public schools of the state. All books and programs purchased under this section for the pupils with impaired vision are the property of the state. </section><section prefix="2">The Department of Education shall require any publisher of a textbook or program adopted for use in the public schools of the Commonwealth to furnish the American Printing House for the Blind with computer diskettes or tapes of those print materials either in the American Standard Code for Information Interchange, (ASCII), or in any other format, either electronic or print, which can be readily translated into braille or large print. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 419, sec. 13, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 362, sec. 6, effective July 15, 1996.. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 382, sec. 4, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 476, Pt. IV, sec. 165, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 463, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 9, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 82, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 71, sec. 13, effective March 13, 1974. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 3. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:52</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3199</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>