<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="365" order_by="365">TRADE PRACTICES </unit></structure><section_number>365.430</section_number><catch_line>Issuance of license -- Scope of authorization. </catch_line><order_by>430</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The clerk, upon receipt of an application giving fully and completely the information under oath as required by KRS 365.420 and upon receipt of the fee provided for in KRS 365.445, shall issue a license to the applicant, authorizing the applicant to advertise, represent, and sell the particular goods so inventoried at the time and place stated in the application and in true accordance with the provisions of KRS 365.410 to 365.480 and 365.992. The license shall be issued in duplicate and shall bear a number and date of its expiration. A license issued under KRS 365.410 to 365.480 and 365.992 shall be granted and valid only for the sale of the inventoried goods which are the property of the licensee. The license shall apply only to the premises specified in the application, and it may not be transferred or assigned. If a licensee under KRS 365.410 to 365.480 and 365.992 is engaged in business in other locations, advertising or offering of goods on behalf of the other locations shall not represent or imply any participation in or cooperation with the sale on the premises specified in the license, nor shall any advertising or other offering of goods on behalf of the premises where the licensed sale is being conducted represent or imply any participation in or cooperation with the sale at other locations. No license under KRS 365.410 to 365.480 and 365.992 shall be issued to any person: <section prefix="a">To conduct a sale in the trade name or style of a person in whose goods the applicant for the license has acquired a right or title thereto within twelve (12) months prior to the time of making application for the license. </section><section prefix="b">To continue a sale in the name of a licensee under KRS 365.410 to 365.480 and 365.992 whose goods the applicant acquired a right or title while the sale is in progress. </section></section><section prefix="2">Paragraphs (a) and (b) of subsection (1) shall not apply to any person who has acquired a right, title, or interest in goods as an heir, devisee, or legatee or pursuant to an order or process of a court of competent jurisdiction. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 305, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1994. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 60, sec. 4. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:42</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=34782</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>