<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="217" order_by="217">FOODS, DRUGS, AND POISONS </unit></structure><section_number>217.600</section_number><catch_line>When penalties not applicable. </catch_line><order_by>600</order_by><text>The penalties provided for violations of KRS 217.542 to 217.630 shall not apply to:  <section prefix="1">Any carrier while lawfully engaged in transporting a pesticide within this state, if such carrier shall, upon request, permit the department or its designated agent to copy all records showing the transactions in and movements of the pesticides or devices;  </section><section prefix="2">Public officials of this state and of the federal government while engaged in the performance of their official duties in administering state or federal laws or regulations, or while engaged in pesticide research;  </section><section prefix="3">The manufacturer or shipper of a pesticide for experimental use only by or under the supervision of an agency of this state or of the federal government authorized by law to conduct research in the field of pesticides; provided, that such manufacturer or shipper hold a valid experimental permit as provided for in KRS 217.542 to 217.630 or by EPA;  </section><section prefix="4">Any person who ships a substance or mixture of substances being put through tests in which the purpose is only to determine its value for pesticide purposes or to determine its toxicity or other properties and from which the user does not expect to receive any benefit in pest control from its use.  </section></text><history>Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 295, sec. 56, effective July 15, 1980. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 200, sec. 10. -- Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 218, sec. 8, effective July 1, 1956. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1980</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:37</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9393</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>