<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IV" order_by="4">JUDICIAL BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="27" order_by="27">A JUDICIAL SUPPORT AGENCIES AND PERSONNEL </unit></structure><section_number>27A.080</section_number><catch_line>Juvenile court records to be deposited with Administrative Office of the Courts -- Availability of records. </catch_line><order_by>080</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Administrative Office of the Courts shall be the primary repository of court records of juveniles charged with, arrested for, and against whom complaints have been filed, involving status offenses, public offenses, and youthful offender proceedings, together with all court records of the handling and disposition of those cases, and shall keep and maintain these records. </section><section prefix="2">The Administrative Office of the Courts shall make juvenile records available to the agencies and persons specified by law. </section><section prefix="3">All courts, law enforcement agencies, prosecutors, the Department of Juvenile Justice, the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet, except the Department for Public Advocacy, and other agencies holding records coming within the purview of subsection (1) of this section shall make them available to the Administrative Office of the Courts in the manner and at the times specified by the Administrative Office of the Courts. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 110, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 99, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 79, effective July 15, 1998. -- Created 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 358, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1996. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><lrc-note> (6/26/2007). Although 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 110, contains references to the "Department of Public Advocacy," the entity created by 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, secs. 7 and 40, and Executive Order 2006-805 is the "Department for Public Advocacy." In accordance with 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 335, and KRS 7.136, the erroneous references in this section have been corrected in codification. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20939</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>