<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="III" order_by="3">EXECUTIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="11" order_by="11">THE GOVERNOR </unit></structure><section_number>11.040</section_number><catch_line>Personnel for Governor's office -- Office of Secretary of the Governor's Executive Cabinet. </catch_line><order_by>040</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Governor may appoint such persons as he deems necessary for the proper operation of his office to perform such duties as the Governor may require of them. The persons so appointed shall hold office at the pleasure of the Governor. None of the provisions of KRS 64.640 shall be applicable to persons appointed under this subsection. </section><section prefix="2">There is hereby created an agency of the state government to be known as the Office of the Secretary to the Governor's Executive Cabinet.  The Office of the Secretary to the Governor's Executive Cabinet shall not be part of the Office of the Governor, but shall constitute a separate agency of state government.  The secretary so appointed shall have such rights, duties and responsibilities as may be assigned by the Governor. </section><section prefix="3">The position of secretary to the Governor's Executive Cabinet shall be filled by appointment of the Governor and shall serve at the pleasure of the Governor.  The secretary shall be responsible for implementing all policies of the Governor, coordinating all activities of the Governor's Executive Cabinet, and advising and consulting with the Governor on all policy matters affecting the state. </section><section prefix="4">The Office of the Secretary to the Governor's Executive Cabinet shall include such principal assistants, appointed by the secretary of the cabinet pursuant to KRS 12.050, as may be necessary to execute the functions of the office. </section></text><history>Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 393, sec.1, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 27, sec. 2, effective May 18, 1956. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 3942f-1 to 3942f-3. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1982</effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=530</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>