<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XI" order_by="11">REVENUE AND TAXATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="131" order_by="131">DEPARTMENT OF REVENUE </unit></structure><section_number>131.250</section_number><catch_line>Returns, reports, and statements to be filed electronically -- Waiver. </catch_line><order_by>250</order_by><text><section prefix="1">For the purpose of facilitating the administration of the taxes it administers, the department may require any tax return, report, or statement to be electronically filed. </section><section prefix="2">The following reports, returns, or statements shall be electronically filed: <section prefix="a">The return required by KRS 136.620; </section><section prefix="b">For tax periods beginning on or after January 1, 2007, the report required by KRS 138.240; </section><section prefix="c">For tax periods beginning on or after August 1, 2010, the report required by KRS 138.260; </section><section prefix="d">For taxable years beginning on or after January 1, 2010, the return filed by a specified tax return preparer reporting the annual tax imposed by KRS 141.020, if the specified tax return preparer is required to electronically file the return for federal income tax purposes; </section><section prefix="e">The annual withholding statement required by KRS 141.335, if the employer issues one hundred (100) or more statements annually; and </section><section prefix="f">For tax periods beginning on or after July 1, 2005, the return required by KRS 160.615. </section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">A person required to electronically file a return, report, or statement may apply for a waiver from the requirement by submitting the request on a form prescribed by the department. </section><section prefix="b">The request shall indicate the lack of one (1) or more of the following: <section prefix="1">Compatible computer hardware; </section><section prefix="2">Internet access; or </section><section prefix="3">Other technological capabilities determined relevant by the department. </section></section></section></text><history> Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 147, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2010).  Following the enactment of 2010 House Bill 319, which became 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 147, the drafter informed the Reviser of Statutes that the date, August 1, 2010, in subsection (2)(c) of this statute should have been January 1, 2007. Following an examination of the materials in the bill folder, the Reviser determined that the statutory authority necessary to make this adjustment was lacking, and the date has not been altered. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:01</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=28131</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>