<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.0053</section_number><catch_line>Prohibited appointments -- Ineligibility to serve on council or governing board -- Conflicts of interest. </catch_line><order_by>0053</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No appointing authority shall appoint himself or his spouse, or the Governor or his spouse, to a governing board of a postsecondary institution created pursuant to KRS 164.131, 164.321, or 164.821, or to the Council on Postsecondary Education created pursuant to KRS 164.011. </section><section prefix="2">No full-time employee of a public institution of postsecondary education shall be eligible to serve on the Council on Postsecondary Education or on the governing board of another institution of postsecondary education, except the community and technical college faculty and nonteaching personnel serving on the board of regents for the Kentucky Community and Technical College System, and except the faculty member appointed under KRS 164.011(3). </section><section prefix="3">No postsecondary institution shall award an honorary degree to a sitting governor.  </section><section prefix="4">All governing board members created pursuant to KRS 164.131, 164.321, and 164.821 and the members of the Council on Postsecondary Education shall have no conflict of interest pursuant to KRS 45A.340, except for compensation paid to faculty, staff, or student members. </section></text><history> Amended 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 72, effective May 30, 1997. -- Created 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 10, sec. 8, July 1, 1992. </history><metadata><effective> May 30, 1997 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4161</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>