<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="196" order_by="196">CORRECTIONS </unit></structure><section_number>196.732</section_number><catch_line>Community corrections funds -- Deposit of state funds saved via pilot projects -- Purposes of appropriated funds. </catch_line><order_by>732</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Beginning in the fiscal year after a pilot project has been implemented pursuant to KRS 196.731, fifty percent (50%) of any state expenditures that are avoided as calculated in KRS 196.731 shall be deposited by the department in the community corrections fund, which shall be a separate, interest-bearing account within the State Treasury. The remaining fifty percent (50%) shall be deposited in the general fund. Amounts deposited in the community corrections fund, including interest, are hereby appropriated to the commission for the following purposes: <section prefix="a">Fifty percent (50%) to the community corrections program responsible for those savings; and </section><section prefix="b">Fifty percent (50%) to the Division of Probation and Parole. </section></section><section prefix="2">Notwithstanding KRS 45.229, any moneys remaining in the community corrections fund at the close of the fiscal year shall not lapse but shall carry forward into the next fiscal year to be used for the purposes outlined in this subsection. </section><section prefix="3">None of the calculated savings shall be appropriated to the commission for distribution if: <section prefix="a">In a pilot project developed pursuant to KRS 196.731(1)(a), there is an increase in the percentage of targeted offenders on probation who are convicted of a new felony offense and sentenced to a term of imprisonment; or </section><section prefix="b">In a pilot project developed pursuant to KRS 196.731(1)(b), there is an increase in the percentage of supervised individuals who are convicted of a new felony offense. </section></section><section prefix="4">The moneys appropriated pursuant to this section shall be used to supplement, not supplant, any other state or county appropriations for probation, parole or other post-prison supervision services, or community corrections programs. </section><section prefix="5">Moneys received through appropriations pursuant to this section and KRS 196.731 shall be used for the following purposes: <section prefix="a">Implementing evidence-based practices; </section><section prefix="b">Creating, increasing, or improving the availability of risk reduction and treatment programs and interventions, including substance abuse treatment programs, for supervised individuals; </section><section prefix="c">Paying the costs of global positioning monitoring system for offenders of at least medium risk; and </section><section prefix="d">Increasing the number of probation and parole staff, including equipment and office space the officers and staff may need. </section></section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch.2, sec.72, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:45</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39587</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>