<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="212" order_by="212">LOCAL HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>212.430</section_number><catch_line>Compensation of employees -- Civil service. </catch_line><order_by>430</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall fix the compensation of all agents and employees of the board, and such compensation shall be as nearly comparable as practicable with the compensations paid and received by corresponding or comparable civil employees of such city or county. </section><section prefix="2">The agents and employees of the board shall be employed and governed, as provided in this subsection, in accordance with the merit system. For the purpose of governing the employment, appointment, suspension, lay-off, and dismissal of employees by the board, and personnel matters relating thereto, any law or laws, or amendments thereof, and any rules and regulations issued pursuant thereto, authorizing, creating, and governing any city board or commission empowered to administer and enforce civil service laws, rules, and regulations in and for such city are hereby made applicable to the personnel and personnel matters of the board to the extent of and with respect to corresponding and comparable offices, positions, and places of employment of and under the board. Such city board or commission is hereby authorized and directed to perform, without compensation from the board, all things necessary to be done to accomplish the aforesaid purpose, including the creation and putting into effect of, and maintaining, a "classified service," in accordance with which the board will be governed in the employment of agents and employees and in the performance of its duties under this section. The director of health of the board shall function as appointing authority in and with respect to said personnel matters of the board. Provided, however, regulations of such city board or commission as may administer the civil service laws, rules, and regulations in such city, as applied to employees of the board, shall be not less stringent than those of the merit system of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services of Kentucky. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 410, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 361, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. VI, sec. 107(3). -- Created 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 41, sec. 7. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8623</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>