<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="194" order_by="194">A CABINET FOR HEALTH AND FAMILY SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>194A.622</section_number><catch_line>Kentucky Commission on Autism Spectrum Disorders -- Membership -- Administrative support -- Meetings -- Comprehensive state plan on training, treatments, and services -- Advisory and monitoring functions.   </catch_line><order_by>622</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created the Kentucky Commission on Autism Spectrum Disorders, which shall consist of the following twenty-two (22) members who shall be initially appointed by July 1, 2005: <section prefix="a">The secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="b">The commissioner of the Department for Medicaid Services or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="c">The director of the Kentucky Early Intervention System, Department for Public Health, or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="d">The commissioner of the Department for Behavioral Health, Developmental and Intellectual Disabilities or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="e">The commissioner of the Department for Aging and Independent Living or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="f">The chair of the Council on Postsecondary Education or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="g">The director of the Division of Exceptional Children Services or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="h">The commissioner of the Department of Vocational Rehabilitation or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="i">The commissioner of the Department of Insurance or his or her designee; </section><section prefix="j">Two (2) nonvoting ex officio members from the House of Representatives, one (1) representing the majority party and one (1) representing the minority party, who shall be appointed by and serve at the pleasure of the Speaker of the House; </section><section prefix="k">Two (2) nonvoting ex officio members from the Senate, one (1) representing the majority party and one (1) representing the minority party, who shall be appointed by and serve at the pleasure of the President of the Senate; </section><section prefix="l">Four (4) professional ASD treatment providers, including at least one (1) mental health provider, one (1) physical health provider, and one (1) complex needs consultant from a special education cooperative, to be appointed by the Governor; and </section><section prefix="m">Five (5) parents, including three (3) who, at the time of their appointment to the commission, have a child with an ASD who is under eighteen (18) years of age and two (2) who, at the time of their appointment to the commission, have a child with an ASD who is eighteen (18) years of age or older, to be appointed by the Governor. </section></section><section prefix="2">In making appointments to the commission, the Governor shall ensure broad representation of Kentucky's citizens who are concerned with the health and quality of life of individuals with an ASD, may appoint individuals who are also members of the Commonwealth Council on Developmental Disabilities, and shall consider candidates recommended by the Autism Spectrum Disorders Advisory Consortium of Kentucky. </section><section prefix="3">Members shall serve without compensation but shall be reimbursed for their actual expenses incurred in the performance of commission duties in accordance with KRS 45.101 and administrative regulations promulgated thereunder. Members of the commission shall serve until the commission ceases to exist, a successor has been appointed, or until removed for good cause. </section><section prefix="4">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services shall provide staff and administrative support for the commission. </section><section prefix="5">The chair of the commission shall be designated by the Governor and may be a member in addition to those listed in subsection (1) of this section. The chair of the commission shall establish procedures for the commission's internal procedures. </section><section prefix="6">The commission shall meet at least three (3) times per year. The commission shall also meet as often as necessary to accomplish its purpose upon the call of the chair, the request of four (4) or more members, or the request of the Governor. </section><section prefix="7">The commission shall develop a comprehensive state plan for creating an integrated system of training, treatments, and services for individuals of all ages with an ASD. The commission shall utilize relevant data and research and consult with appropriate professionals, agencies, institutions, and organizations representing the private and public sectors, including the Kentucky Autism Training Center, to develop the state plan. The state plan shall include the following: <section prefix="a">An assessment of the diverse needs for services and supports for individuals with an ASD; </section><section prefix="b">Identification of state, federal, private, and any other appropriate funding sources; </section><section prefix="c">Development of a comprehensive training plan, which shall include the Kentucky Autism Training Center, to meet training needs; </section><section prefix="d">An analysis of standards for provider training and qualifications, best practice standards for services, and the need for additional service providers; </section><section prefix="e">An evaluation of health benefit plans and insurance coverage for the treatment of ASD; </section><section prefix="f">A plan for the identification of individuals of all ages with an ASD and for the creation of a statewide ASD registry; </section><section prefix="g">An analysis of program and service eligibility criteria; </section><section prefix="h">An assessment of the need for coordinated, enhanced, and targeted special education and treatment programs for children with an ASD; and </section><section prefix="i">A timeline for implementing and monitoring the recommendations of the plan statewide. The timeline shall include input from the following: <section prefix="1">The Cabinet for Health and Family Services; </section><section prefix="2">The Department for Medicaid Services; </section><section prefix="3">The Department for Public Health; </section><section prefix="4">The Department for Behavioral Health, Developmental and Intellectual Disabilities; </section><section prefix="5">The Kentucky Early Intervention System; </section><section prefix="6">The Division of Exceptional Children Services; </section><section prefix="7">The Department of Vocational Rehabilitation; </section><section prefix="8">The Department of Insurance; </section><section prefix="9">The Department of Education; </section><section prefix="10">The Council on Postsecondary Education; and </section><section prefix="11">Other appropriate agencies, professionals, institutions, and organizations representing the public and private sectors, including the Kentucky Autism Training Center. </section></section></section><section prefix="8">Based upon the comprehensive state plan for an integrated system of training, treatment, and services for individuals of all ages with an ASD, the commission shall make recommendations regarding legislation, administrative regulations, and policies to the Governor and the General Assembly on the following: <section prefix="a">Needs for services and supports for individuals who have an ASD; </section><section prefix="b">Funding needs and sources, including state, federal, private, and any other appropriate funding sources; </section><section prefix="c">Training needs and a plan to implement a comprehensive training system, which shall include the Kentucky Autism Training Center; </section><section prefix="d">Standards for provider training and qualifications, best practice standards for services, and the need for additional providers; </section><section prefix="e">Goals for developing health benefit plans that provide insurance coverage for the treatment of ASD; </section><section prefix="f">A plan for the identification of individuals of all ages with an ASD and for the creation of a statewide ASD registry; </section><section prefix="g">Consistent program and service eligibility criteria; </section><section prefix="h">The need for coordinated, enhanced, and targeted special education and treatment programs for individuals with an ASD; and </section><section prefix="i">Strategies and timelines for establishing an accountable, cost-efficient, and cooperative system of services that integrates and builds upon existing public and private agencies, programs, and resources. </section></section><section prefix="9">The commission shall submit the comprehensive state plan and recommendations to the Governor, the Commonwealth Council on Developmental Disabilities, and the Legislative Research Commission by October 1, 2006, at which time the commission shall cease to exist unless reauthorized by the General Assembly. </section><section prefix="10">The Commonwealth Council on Developmental Disabilities shall appoint a subcommittee, which shall include members of the commission, to monitor the implementation of the state plan as developed by the commission beginning October 1, 2006. The subcommittee shall prepare, and the council shall submit, a report to the Governor and Legislative Research Commission that assesses progress in the implementation of the state plan and that makes recommendations on the need for modifications to the state plan as developed by the Kentucky Commission on Autism Spectrum Disorders. The subcommittee shall prepare, and the council shall submit, the report as it deems appropriate, but no less than biennially, until October 1, 2015. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 24, effective July 12, 2012; and ch. 158, sec. 20, effective July 12, 2012. -- Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 242, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 6, effective June 26, 2007. -- Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 138, sec. 2, effective June 20, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><lrc-note>(7/12/2012). This statute was amended by 2012 Ky. Acts chs. 146 and 158, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together.  (6/20/2005). 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 138, sec. 2, creates the Kentucky Commission on Autism Spectrum Disorders and provides that it shall consist of 23 members, including the secretaries of the Cabinet for Health Services and the Cabinet for Families and Children. The reorganization of these cabinets into a single Cabinet for Health and Family Services under Executive Orders 2004-444 and 2004-726 was confirmed by the General Assembly, and the membership of Kentucky Commission on Autism Spectrum Disorders has been changed from 23 to 22 in codification pursuant to 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 675. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40942</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>