<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="217" order_by="217">B FERTILIZER AND PESTICIDE USE AND APPLICATION </unit></structure><section_number>217B.105</section_number><catch_line>Registration of pesticide dealers -- Fees -- Branch offices -- Required records. </catch_line><order_by>105</order_by><text><section prefix="1">No person shall act in the capacity of a dealer, or shall engage or offer to engage in the business of, advertise as, or assume to act as a dealer without having registered as a dealer with the department. </section><section prefix="2">Application for a dealer registration shall be in the form and shall contain the information prescribed by the department. Each application shall be accompanied by a fee of fifty dollars ($50). All registrations issued under this section shall expire on December 31 of the year for which they are issued. The registration for a dealer may be renewed annually upon application to the department, accompanied by a fee of fifty dollars ($50) for each registration, on or before the first day of January of the calendar year for which the registration is issued. </section><section prefix="3">No person shall be registered as a dealer without proof of financial responsibility as required by KRS 217B.130. </section><section prefix="4">A dealer shall register each branch office location. </section><section prefix="5">Application for a branch office registration shall be in the form and shall contain the information prescribed by the department. Each application shall be accompanied by a fee of twenty-five dollars ($25). All registrations issued under this section shall expire on December 31. The registration for a branch office may be renewed annually upon application to the department, accompanied by a fee of twenty-five dollars ($25) for each registration, on or before the first of January of the calendar year for which the registration is issued. No branch office registration may be issued unless the applicant is registered as a dealer. </section><section prefix="6">The department shall issue to each applicant who satisfies the requirements of this section a registration which entitles the applicant to conduct the business described in the application for the calendar year for which the registration is issued, unless the registration is sooner revoked or suspended. </section><section prefix="7">The department shall promulgate administrative regulations requiring dealers to maintain records with respect to their operations as it determines are necessary for the effective enforcement of this chapter. The records shall include, but not be limited to, brands and amounts of restricted use pesticides sold, and the buyer's name, address, use of the pesticide, and certification number. Records required under this section shall extend to financial data, sales data, shipment data, and personnel data. The records are to be retained for a period of two (2) years from the time of sale. For the purposes of enforcing the provisions of this chapter, any dealer shall, upon request of the department, furnish or permit the department at all reasonable times to have access to, and to copy, records as required by this section. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 172, sec. 9, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 72, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 148, sec. 24. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9535</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>