<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="329" order_by="329">DETECTION OF DECEPTION EXAMINERS </unit></structure><section_number>329.010</section_number><catch_line>Definitions. </catch_line><order_by>010</order_by><text>As used in this chapter, unless the context otherwise requires: <section prefix="1">"Detection of deception examiner," referred to in this chapter as "examiner," means any person, other than a trainee, who uses any device or instrument to test or question individuals for the purpose of detecting deception. Before a person may be licensed as an examiner, he or she must have at least one (1) year's experience in detection of deception. Before an examiner may supervise a trainee, he or she must have at least two (2) years' experience in detection of deception; </section><section prefix="2">"Trainee" means any person who has successfully completed a polygraph examiner's course at a polygraph examiner's school approved by the cabinet, but who has not been awarded the final certificate of proficiency or graduate certificate from the school, or any person, not a licensed examiner, who administers detection of deception examinations under the direct, personal supervision and control of a licensed examiner who is licensed by this state. No examiner may have more than two (2) trainees under his or her supervision and control at any one (1) time; </section><section prefix="3">"Person" means any natural person, partnership, association, corporation, or trust; </section><section prefix="4">"Cabinet" means the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet of the Commonwealth of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="5">"Secretary" means the secretary of the Justice and Public Safety Cabinet of the Commonwealth of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="6">"Polygraph" means an instrument which records permanently and simultaneously a subject's cardiovascular and respiratory patterns and other physiological changes pertinent to the detection of deception; and </section><section prefix="7">"Polygraph examiner" means the same as detection of deception examiner. </section></text><history> Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 298, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 44, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. V, sec. 24(13). -- Created 1962 Ky. Acts ch. 78, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> June 26, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:50</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31738</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>