<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="319" order_by="319">PSYCHOLOGISTS </unit></structure><section_number>319.020</section_number><catch_line>Board of Examiners of Psychology. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The board shall consist of nine (9) members appointed by the Governor. Six (6) members shall be licensed psychologists. Two (2) members shall be credentialed by the board as certified psychologists, licensed psychological practitioners, or licensed psychological associates. One (1) member shall be a citizen at large who is not associated with or financially interested in the practice or business regulated. </section><section prefix="2">Licensed psychologist members shall be appointed by the Governor from a group consisting of the three (3) nominees receiving the most votes for each position to be filled, the nominees to be selected by all licensed psychologists credentialed under this chapter from a list of eligible candidates prepared by the Kentucky Psychological Association. Candidates shall be solicited from all licensed psychologists credentialed according to the provisions of this chapter and each nominee shall be a licensed psychologist credentialed according to the provisions of this chapter. Each licensed psychologist member shall be a resident of this state and shall have engaged in the practice or teaching of psychology as a licensed psychologist for at least three (3) years in this state. </section><section prefix="3">Certified psychologist, licensed psychological practitioner, or licensed psychological associate members shall be appointed by the Governor from a group consisting of the three (3) nominees receiving the most votes for each position to be filled, the nominees to be selected by all certified psychologists, licensed psychological practitioners, and licensed psychological associates credentialed under this chapter from a list of eligible candidates prepared by the Kentucky Psychological Association. Candidates shall be solicited from all certified psychologists, licensed psychological practitioners, and licensed psychological associates credentialed according to the provisions of this chapter. Each nominee shall be a resident of this state, licensed according to the provisions of this chapter, and shall have engaged in the practice or teaching of psychology as a certified psychologist, licensed psychological practitioner, or licensed psychological associate for at least three (3) years in this state. </section><section prefix="4">The term of each board member shall be four (4) years and until a successor is appointed and qualified. No member shall serve more than two (2) consecutive full terms. The Governor shall fill any vacancy occurring in the board in the manner prescribed in subsection (2) of this section. Upon recommendation by a majority of the board members and after notice and a hearing, the Governor shall remove any member for incompetence, neglect of duty, or malfeasance in office. </section><section prefix="5">Five (5) members of the board shall constitute a quorum. Each member shall receive one hundred dollars ($100) per day for attending each meeting and shall receive his necessary expenses incurred in the performance of the duties required by this chapter. Annually the board shall elect one (1) of its licensed members as chairperson for a term of one (1) year. No person shall serve more than two (2) consecutive full terms as chairperson. The board shall meet at least twice annually and at other times as it determines necessary. Special meetings may be called by the chairperson and shall be called upon the written request of two (2) members. </section></text><history> Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 80, sec. 4, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 104, sec. 3, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 291, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1988. -- Amended 1986 Ky. Acts ch. 128, sec. 4, effective July 15, 1986. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 33, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 206, sec. 13. -- Amended 1964 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 2. -- Created 1948 Ky. Acts ch. 169, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> June 21, 2001 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:54</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31222</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>