<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="506" order_by="506">INCHOATE OFFENSES </unit></structure><section_number>506.120</section_number><catch_line>Engaging in organized crime. </catch_line><order_by>120</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person, with the purpose to establish or maintain a criminal syndicate or to facilitate any of its activities, shall not do any of the following: <section prefix="a">Organize or participate in organizing a criminal syndicate or any of its activities; </section><section prefix="b">Provide material aid to a criminal syndicate or any of its activities, whether such aid is in the form of money or other property, or credit; </section><section prefix="c">Manage, supervise, or direct any of the activities of a criminal syndicate, at any level of responsibility; </section><section prefix="d">Knowingly furnish legal, accounting, or other managerial services to a criminal syndicate; </section><section prefix="e">Commit, or conspire or attempt to commit, or act as an accomplice in the commission of, any offense of a type in which a criminal syndicate engages on a continuing basis; </section><section prefix="f">Commit, or conspire or attempt to commit or act as an accomplice in the commission of, any offense of violence; </section><section prefix="g">Commit, or conspire or attempt to commit, or act as an accomplice in the commission of bribery in violation of KRS Chapters 518 or 521, or KRS 119.205, 121.025, 121.055, 524.070, 156.465, 45A.340, 63.090, 6.080, 18A.145, or 244.600; </section><section prefix="h">Commit, or conspire or attempt to commit, or act as an accomplice in the commission of more than one (1) theft of retail merchandise with the intent to resell the stolen merchandise; or </section><section prefix="i">Acquire stolen retail merchandise for the purpose of reselling it where the person knew or should have known that the merchandise had been stolen. </section></section><section prefix="2">Whoever violates this section is guilty of engaging in organized crime, which shall be a Class B felony, unless the offense involves only the theft or acquisition of retail merchandise for the purpose of reselling it, in which case it shall be a Class C felony. </section><section prefix="3">As used in this section "criminal syndicate" means five (5) or more persons, or, in cases of merchandise theft from a retail store for the purpose of reselling the stolen merchandise, two (2) or more persons, collaborating to promote or engage in any of the following on a continuing basis: <section prefix="a">Extortion or coercion in violation of KRS 514.080 or 521.020; </section><section prefix="b">Engaging in, promoting, or permitting prostitution or human trafficking in violation of KRS Chapter 529; </section><section prefix="c">Any theft offense as defined in KRS Chapter 514; </section><section prefix="d">Any gambling offense as defined in KRS 411.090, KRS Chapter 528, or Section 226 of the Constitution; </section><section prefix="e">Illegal trafficking in controlled substances as prohibited by KRS Chapter 218A, in intoxicating or spirituous liquor as defined in KRS Chapters 242 or 244, or in destructive devices or booby traps as defined in KRS Chapter 237; or </section><section prefix="f">Lending at usurious interest, and enforcing repayment by illegal means in violation of KRS Chapter 360. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 106, sec. 15, effective June 25, 2009. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 19, sec. 3, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 417, sec. 16, effective December 1, 2000. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 121, sec. 37, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 448, sec. 72, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 188, sec. 306, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 321, sec. 1, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> June 25, 2009 </effective><lrc-note> (12/1/2000). The contingency on the effectiveness of this statute set by 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 417, sec. 18, was met, the voters of the Commonwealth having ratified at the general election on November 7, 2000, a constitutional amendment (see 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 399) abolishing the Railroad Commission. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:22</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19712</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>