<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="441" order_by="441">JAILS AND COUNTY PRISONERS </unit></structure><section_number>441.055</section_number><catch_line>Regulation of jails -- Adoption and revision of standards. </catch_line><order_by>055</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Department of Corrections shall for those counties which elect to house state prisoners in their jail: <section prefix="a">Adopt the recommendations of the Jail Standards Commission created pursuant to Executive Order Number 81-1026 and promulgate regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A establishing minimum standards for jails. These standards shall include, but not be limited to, rules governing the following areas: <section prefix="1">Health and safety conditions; </section><section prefix="2">Fire safety; </section><section prefix="3">Jail operations, recordkeeping, and administration; </section><section prefix="4">Curriculum of basic and continuing annual training for jailers and jail personnel; </section><section prefix="5">Custody, care, and treatment of prisoners; </section><section prefix="6">Medical care; and </section><section prefix="7">Jail equipment, renovation, and construction; </section></section><section prefix="b">Develop a jail standards review process, which shall include the participation of persons knowledgeable of jail operations to review and amend the standards as necessary. The jail standards shall be reviewed no later than December 31, 1992, and at least every two (2) years thereafter. Fifty percent (50%) of the participants in the review process shall be appointed from persons representing county interests and fifty percent (50%) shall be appointed from persons representing state interests; and </section><section prefix="c">Provide technical assistance and consultation to local governments in order to facilitate compliance with standards. </section></section><section prefix="2">The department shall, for those counties that elect not to hold state prisoners in their jails, adopt the recommendations of the Jail Standards Commission and promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A to establish minimum standards for those jails. These standards shall be limited to health and life safety. </section><section prefix="3">The department may establish classifications of jails based on the maximum permissible period of incarceration or other criteria and promulgate standards for each class of jail. </section></text><history> Amended 2014 Ky. Acts ch. 132, sec. 21, effective July 15, 2014. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 108, sec. 3, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 114, effective July 14, 1992; and ch. 262, sec. 1, effective July 14, 1992. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 385, sec. 6, effective July 1, 1982. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2014 </effective><former-codification> KRS 441.011.</former-codification><lrc-note> (7/14/92).  This section was amended by two 1992 Acts. Where those Acts are not in conflict, they have been compiled together. Where a conflict exists, the Act which was last enacted by the General Assembly prevails, pursuant to KRS 446.250. (10/5/90, restored 11/12/99).  Pursuant to KRS 7.136(1), "KRS Chapter 13A" was substituted for prior references to "KRS Chapter 13" in this statute. The sections in KRS Chapter 13 were repealed by 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 417, sec. 36, and KRS Chapter 13A was created in that same chapter of the 1984 Ky. Acts. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=43496</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>