<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVIII" order_by="28">MINES AND MINERALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="349" order_by="349">COALBED METHANE DEVELOPMENT </unit></structure><section_number>349.055</section_number><catch_line>Coalbed Methane Well Review Board established -- Board attached to Department of Natural Resources within Energy and Environment Cabinet. </catch_line><order_by>055</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Coalbed Methane Well Review Board is hereby established. The review board shall be composed of five (5) members and shall have the powers and duties specified under this chapter. </section><section prefix="2">The review board shall consist of the commissioner of the Department for Natural Resources or his or her designee within the department, the director of the Division of Mine Reclamation and Enforcement and the director of the Division of Oil and Gas within the Department for Natural Resources, a representative of the oil and gas industry, and a representative of the coal industry. The representatives from the oil and gas industry and the coal industry shall be appointed by the Governor for terms of four (4) years subject to confirmation by the Senate. </section><section prefix="3">The review board shall be, for administrative purposes only, attached to the Energy and Environment Cabinet, Department for Natural Resources. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 1872, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 123, sec. 48, effective June 20, 2005. -- Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 65, sec. 11, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:46</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32734</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>