<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="65" order_by="65">GENERAL PROVISIONS APPLICABLE TO COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS </unit></structure><section_number>65.135</section_number><catch_line>Legislative intention to occupy field regarding violations of KRS 439.3401 and KRS 17.500. </catch_line><order_by>135</order_by><text><section prefix="1">It is the intent of the General Assembly to occupy the entire field of legislation relating to: <section prefix="a">Any person who has committed or is charged with the commission of a violent offense as specified in KRS 439.3401; and </section><section prefix="b">Any person who has committed or is charged with commission of a sex crime as specified in KRS 17.500. </section></section><section prefix="2">No city, county, urban-county, charter county, consolidated local government, or other unit or instrumentality of local government shall enact an ordinance or other rule or regulation relating to the control, management, registration, monitoring, or housing of, or other matter relating to, a person specified in subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="3">The fact that the General Assembly has not regulated a particular subject relating to a person specified in subsection (1) of this section does not grant a city, county, urban-county, charter county, consolidated local government, or other unit or instrumentality of local government the authority to enact an ordinance, rule, or regulation relating to that subject. </section><section prefix="4">Cities, counties, urban-counties, charter counties, consolidated local governments, and units and instrumentalities of local government shall enforce the provisions of state law with regard to persons specified in subsection (1) of this section. </section><section prefix="5">On July 12, 2006, any local ordinance, resolution, or rule relating to any topic specified in this section shall be null, void, and unenforceable. </section></text><history> Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 182, sec. 16, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2006 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=23341</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>