<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="344" order_by="344">CIVIL RIGHTS </unit></structure><section_number>344.510</section_number><catch_line>Commission established -- Members -- Terms -- Executive director. </catch_line><order_by>510</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby established the Kentucky Commission on Women as a separate administrative body of state government within the meaning of KRS Chapter 12. </section><section prefix="2">The membership of the commission shall consist of the Lieutenant Governor and not more than twenty-four (24) members and a chairman who shall be appointed by the Governor. The members of the commission shall serve terms of four (4) years; except that: <section prefix="a">Of the members initially appointed after June 17, 1978, six (6) members shall serve a term of one (1) year, six (6) a term of two (2) years, six (6) a term of three (3) years and six (6) a term of four (4) years; and </section><section prefix="b">Of the members appointed after July 15, 1998, six (6) members appointed to fill the terms expiring June 17, 1999, shall serve until January 17, 2000; six (6) members appointed to fill the terms expiring June 17, 2000, shall serve until January 17, 2001; six (6) members appointed to fill the terms expiring June 17, 2001, shall serve until January 17, 2002; and six (6) members appointed to fill the terms expiring June 17, 2002, shall serve until January 17, 2003; and subsequent appointments shall be for four (4) year terms ending on January 17. The Governor shall appoint a chairman who shall serve at the Governor's will. There shall be an executive director, who shall be appointed by the Governor, and shall be administrative head and chief executive officer of the commission. The Governor, in appointing the commission, shall attempt to insure, insofar as it may be practicable, and with due regard to the several geographic regions and socio-economic groupings of the state, that the membership is broadly representative of the women of the state. The commission shall meet at the call of the chairman, but at least twice during each calendar year; a majority of the members shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of the commission's business. </section></section></text><history> Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 194, sec. 10, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 379, sec. 9, effective April 9, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 155, sec. 157, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 70, sec. 1. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1998 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32650</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>