<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="X" order_by="10">ELECTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="121" order_by="121">CAMPAIGN FINANCE REGULATION </unit></structure><section_number>121.210</section_number><catch_line>Central campaign committee -- Designation -- Duties -- Unauthorized or disavowed campaign committee. </catch_line><order_by>210</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each candidate may designate one (1) central campaign committee. If so designated, the central campaign committee shall receive all reports made by any other campaign committee authorized in writing by the candidate to accept contributions or make expenditures for the purpose of influencing the nomination for election, or election, of the candidate who designated it as his central campaign committee.  </section><section prefix="2">Each statement or report which an authorized committee is required to file with or furnish to the registry shall, if that committee is not a central campaign committee, be furnished instead to the central campaign committee for the candidate on whose behalf that committee is, or is established for the purpose of, accepting contributions or making expenditures.  </section><section prefix="3">Each central campaign committee shall receive all reports and statements filed with or furnished to it by other authorized committees, and shall consolidate and furnish the reports and statements to the registry, together with its own reports and statements as prescribed by KRS 121.180.  </section><section prefix="4">Campaign committees not authorized by, or which have been disavowed by the candidate, shall not include the name of the candidate as part of the committee's name and shall file the reports and statements with the registry as prescribed in KRS 121.180. </section></text><history>Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 292, sec. 9, effective July 15, 1980. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 253, sec. 7. </history><metadata><effective>July 15, 1980 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:04</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=27872</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>