<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXV" order_by="35">DOMESTIC RELATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="403" order_by="403">DISSOLUTION OF MARRIAGE -- CHILD CUSTODY </unit></structure><section_number>403.840</section_number><catch_line>Appearance of parties and child. </catch_line><order_by>840</order_by><text><section prefix="1">In a child custody proceeding in this state, the court may order a party to the proceeding who is in this state to appear before the court in person with or without the child. The court may order any person who is in this state and who has physical custody or control of the child to appear in person with the child. </section><section prefix="2">If a party to a child custody proceeding whose presence is desired by the court is outside this state, the court may order that a notice given pursuant to KRS 403.812 include a statement directing the party to appear in person with or without the child and informing the party that failure to appear may result in a decision adverse to the party. </section><section prefix="3">The court may enter any order necessary to ensure the safety of the child and of any person ordered to appear under this section. </section><section prefix="4">If a party to a child custody proceeding who is outside this state is directed to appear under subsection (2) of this section or desires to appear personally before the court with or without the child, the court may require another party to pay reasonable and necessary travel and other expenses of the party so appearing and of the child. </section></text><history> Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 133, sec. 21, effective July 13, 2004. </history><metadata><effective> July 13, 2004 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:32</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17514</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>