<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.482</section_number><catch_line>Business plans and benchmark measures -- Presentation of plans to Interim Joint Committees -- Updates to be provided -- Public-private collaboration. </catch_line><order_by>482</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The KCDI board shall establish goals and business plans for one (1), three (3), five (5), and ten (10) year time periods that include but are not limited to benchmark measures on: <section prefix="a">Outreach, including identification of Kentuckians who are at high risk for cardiovascular disease utilizing allied health programs in postsecondary institutions, the resources of community-based physicians, and local health departments; </section><section prefix="b">Education on lifestyle modifications to prevent cardiovascular disease; </section><section prefix="c">Early identification, including identification of target populations for hypertension, cholesterol, diabetes, and other at-risk histories utilizing a statewide data repository; </section><section prefix="d">Education, including the development and implementation of educational curricula and public awareness materials that address different target populations, such as age groups, gender, and identified occupational groups, and include distinctions for rural and urban populations; </section><section prefix="e">Follow-up strategies for identified at-risk Kentuckians, including disease management protocols utilizing a statewide data repository and the allied health programs in postsecondary institutions, the resources of community-based physicians, and local health departments; </section><section prefix="f">Improving access to health care for at-risk and identified patient population and improving access to best practices for health-care providers, including utilization of an Internet-based e-health system; </section><section prefix="g">Basic, clinical, and translational research on cardiovascular disease and its treatment; </section><section prefix="h">Commercialization of intellectual property to create profitable new businesses, as well as the development of an Internet-based data repository and e-health program established at Kentucky Innovation and Commercialization Centers affiliated with comprehensive universities, in accordance with KRS 154.12-300 to 154.12-310, on cardiovascular and other diseases that can be accessed by health-care providers working with patients; and </section><section prefix="i">Patient privacy protection as required by federal and state law. </section></section><section prefix="2">The board shall present business plans that include specific budget items developed pursuant to subsection (1) of this section to the Interim Joint Committee on Appropriations and Revenue and the Interim Joint Committee on Health and Welfare of the General Assembly prior to initial expenditure of any funds relating to implementation of the business plans and shall provide updates annually or upon request of the General Assembly. The board shall make business plans available to any interested party upon request. </section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">The board may create a public or nonprofit corporation to facilitate public-private collaboration in development and implementation of the KCDI. </section><section prefix="b">A public or nonprofit organization may receive and expend funds appropriated by the General Assembly and may solicit, apply for, and receive any funds, grants, contracts, contributions, property, or services from any person, governmental agency, or other organization to carry out the responsibilities given to it by the KCDI Board. </section><section prefix="c">Funds appropriated to a public or nonprofit corporation shall not lapse at the end of a state fiscal year and shall be used solely for the purposes for which the funds were appropriated. </section><section prefix="d">A public or nonprofit corporation created under this subsection shall: <section prefix="1">Follow standard accounting practices; </section><section prefix="2">Submit to an annual financial audit by an independent auditor; </section><section prefix="3">Submit a quarterly report of receipts and expenditures to the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services and the KCDI board no later than sixty (60) days after the end of a quarter; and </section><section prefix="4">Submit an annual financial and progress report to the Governor, the secretary of the Finance and Administration Cabinet, and the Interim Joint Committees on Appropriations and Revenue and Health and Welfare by September 30 following the end of each state fiscal year. The annual report shall include a report of receipts and expenditures, the financial audit, and a report on the status and progress of the corporation's initiatives. </section></section></section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 98, sec. 12, effective July 15, 2008; and ch. 113, sec. 15, effective July 15, 2008. -- Created 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 126, sec. 3, effective June 26, 2007. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2008).  This section was amended by 2008 Ky. Acts chs. 98 and 113, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:39</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=8419</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>