<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXI" order_by="21">AGRICULTURE AND ANIMALS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="247" order_by="247">PROMOTION OF AGRICULTURE AND HORTICULTURE </unit></structure><section_number>247.417</section_number><catch_line>Members of council -- Officers -- Compensation -- Meetings -- Quorum. </catch_line><order_by>417</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The membership of the council shall consist of the Lieutenant Governor, the Commissioner of Agriculture, the secretary of the Cabinet for Economic Development, and eighteen (18) citizen members, a majority of whom shall be full-time farmers, appointed by the Commissioner of Agriculture. Two (2) members shall be appointed from each Supreme Court district and four (4) from the state at large. All members shall serve at the Commissioner's will during his incumbency, and until each member's successor is appointed. </section><section prefix="2">The Commissioner of Agriculture shall serve as chairman of the council. The council may elect by majority vote a vice chairman and such officers of the council as may be deemed necessary. </section><section prefix="3">Citizen members of the council shall receive a compensation of fifty dollars ($50) per day for each day of attendance at meetings of the council, and shall be reimbursed by the Commissioner's Office for necessary and actual expenses in accordance with the provisions of KRS Chapters 44 and 45. </section><section prefix="4">The council shall meet at the call of the chairman, but not less often than four (4) times during each calendar year. A majority of the members appointed to the council shall constitute a quorum. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 235, sec. 7, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 404, sec. 36, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 396, sec. 52, effective July 15, 1982; and ch. 447, sec. 18, effective April 12, 1982. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 154, sec. 29, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 299, sec. 52. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 53, sec. 3. -- Created 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 87, sec. 4(3). </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 1992 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=11646</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>