<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="153" order_by="153">THE ARTS -- STATE ZOO </unit></structure><section_number>153.430</section_number><catch_line>Executive director -- Staff -- Use of revenues -- Audit. </catch_line><order_by>430</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The Kentucky Center for the Arts Corporation shall appoint an executive director, who shall hold office at its pleasure, and shall serve in a full-time capacity. The executive director shall be the chief administrative officer of the corporation and shall provide the staff direction and coordination in implementing the program and discharging the duties of the corporation. The executive director is authorized to act under direction of the corporation in employing necessary staff to perform its duties and exercise its powers as assigned by KRS 153.420. </section><section prefix="2">The staff shall keep all minutes, records and orders of the corporation, and shall be responsible for preservation of all such documents, which are public records subject to KRS 61.870 to 61.884. The staff shall also perform any other duties assigned by the executive director, with approval of the corporation. </section><section prefix="3">All revenues derived by the corporation from the use of the Kentucky Center for the Arts, or contributions to the Kentucky Center for the Arts from any other source as authorized in KRS 153.420, shall be solely used to defray the expenses of the Kentucky Center for the Arts, including payment on debt, the cost of management and operation of its facilities, the creation of an adequate reserve for repair, replacement, debt service and capital improvements, and the procurance of insurance and promotional activities. Any additional revenues in excess of amounts necessary to defray the actual costs and expenses properly related to the conduct of any activity authorized in KRS 153.420 derived by the corporation from any other source, or as a result of any other activity authorized in KRS 153.420, shall similarly be used solely for the purposes enumerated in this section. An annual audit of all funds of the corporation and its affiliated entities shall be made by the State Auditor of Public Accounts, and reported to the Governor. </section></text><history>Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 3, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 382, sec. 4, effective April 9, 1980. -- Created 1980 Ky. Acts ch. 295, sec. 39, effective July 15, 1980. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1990 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:56</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=2483</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>