<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXII" order_by="32">OWNERSHIP AND CONVEYANCE OF PROPERTY</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="381" order_by="381">TITLE TO PROPERTY AND RESTRICTIONS ON USE, OWNERSHIP, AND ALIENATION </unit></structure><section_number>381.9201</section_number><catch_line>Applicability of KRS 381.9201, 381.9205, and 381.9207 -- Modification or waiver by agreement -- Certificate not required in certain cases. </catch_line><order_by>9201</order_by><text><section prefix="1">This section and KRS 381.9205 and 381.9207 apply to all units subject to KRS 381.9101 to 381.9207, except as provided in subsection (2) of this section or as modified or waived by agreement of purchasers of units in a condominium in which all units are restricted to nonresidential use. </section><section prefix="2">The certificate referred to in KRS 381.9203 shall not be required in the case of: <section prefix="a">A gratuitous disposition of a unit; </section><section prefix="b">A disposition pursuant to court order; </section><section prefix="c">A disposition by a government or governmental agency; </section><section prefix="d">A disposition by foreclosure or deed in lieu of foreclosure; </section><section prefix="e">A disposition to a person in the business of selling real estate who intends to offer those units to purchasers, and where the purchaser has modified or waived the requirements of KRS 381.9203 by agreement; or </section><section prefix="f">A disposition that may be canceled at any time and for any reason by the purchaser without penalty. </section></section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 9, effective April 11, 2012. -- Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 97, sec. 51, effective January 1, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> April 11, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:38</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40016</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>