<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXVII" order_by="37">SPECIAL PROCEEDINGS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="417" order_by="417">ARBITRATION AND AWARD </unit></structure><section_number>417.060</section_number><catch_line>Proceedings to compel or stay arbitration. </catch_line><order_by>060</order_by><text><section prefix="1">On application of a party showing an agreement described in KRS 417.050, and the opposing party's refusal to arbitrate, the court shall order the parties to proceed with arbitration.  If the opposing party denies the existence of the agreement to arbitrate, the court shall proceed summarily to the determination of the issue so raised.  The court shall order arbitration if found for the moving party; otherwise, the application shall be denied.  </section><section prefix="2">On application, the court may stay an arbitration proceeding commenced or threatened on a showing that there is no agreement to arbitrate.  Such an issue, when in substantial and bona fide dispute, shall be forthwith and summarily tried and the stay ordered if found for the moving party.  If found for the opposing party, the court shall order the parties to proceed to arbitration.  </section><section prefix="3">If an issue referable to arbitration under the alleged agreement is involved in an action or proceeding pending in a court having jurisdiction to hear applications under subsection (1) of this section, the application shall be made therein.  Otherwise and subject to KRS 417.210, the application may be made in any court of competent jurisdiction.  </section><section prefix="4">Any action or proceeding involving an issue subject to arbitration shall be stayed if an order for arbitration or an application therefor has been made under this section; or if the issue is severable, the stay may be with respect thereto only.  When the application is made in such action or proceeding, the order for arbitration shall include such stay.  </section><section prefix="5">An order for arbitration shall not be refused on the ground that the claim in issue lacks merit or bona fides or because any fault or grounds for the claim sought to be arbitrated have not been shown.  </section></text><history>Created 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 278, sec. 2, effective July 13, 1984. </history><metadata><effective>July 13, 1984 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:29</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=17991</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>