<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="217" order_by="217">B FERTILIZER AND PESTICIDE USE AND APPLICATION </unit></structure><section_number>217B.565</section_number><catch_line>Identification of vehicles -- Employee identification cards. </catch_line><order_by>565</order_by><text>Each business establishment or business entity shall at all times have its vehicles, which are actively and regularly engaged in service work marked for easy identification with at least the letters "L.P.C.O." two (2) inches high, and the company name thereon, followed by the license number of the business establishment or business entity.  Identification of vehicles may be permanent or removable; however, signs shall accompany the vehicle at all times for purpose of identification.  Each licensed business establishment or business entity shall furnish each employee performing work or soliciting business an identification card to be secured from the department and said identification card shall be carried on his or her person at all times for the purpose of identification of the employee to the department or to the person or persons for whom such work is being performed.  It is the responsibility of every business establishment or business entity issuing identification cards to collect any and all cards, or produce proof that a reasonable effort was made to collect same, from employees whose employment has terminated with that company.  Identification cards collected in this manner shall be mailed to the department. </text><history>Created 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 81, sec. 14, effective June 17, 1978. </history><metadata><effective>June 17, 1978 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:36</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=9574</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>