<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="L" order_by="50">KENTUCKY PENAL CODE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="534" order_by="534">FINES </unit></structure><section_number>534.030</section_number><catch_line>Fines for felonies. </catch_line><order_by>030</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Except as otherwise provided for an offense defined outside this code, a person who has been convicted of any felony shall, in addition to any other punishment imposed upon him, be sentenced to pay a fine in an amount not less than one thousand dollars ($1,000) and not greater than ten thousand dollars ($10,000) or double his gain from commission of the offense, whichever is the greater. </section><section prefix="2">In determining the amount and method of paying a fine for commission of a felony, the court shall consider, among others, the following factors: <section prefix="a">The defendant's ability to pay the amount of the fine; </section><section prefix="b">The hardship likely to be imposed on the defendant's dependents by the amount of the fine and the time and method of paying it; </section><section prefix="c">The impact the amount of the fine will have on the defendant's ability to make reparation or restitution to the victim; and </section><section prefix="d">The amount of the defendant's gain, if any, derived from the commission of the offense. </section></section><section prefix="3">When a defendant is convicted of two (2) or more felonies committed through a single act and is sentenced to fines pursuant to subsection (1), the aggregate amount of the fines shall not exceed ten thousand dollars ($10,000) or double the amount of the defendant's gain from commission of the offenses, whichever is the greater. </section><section prefix="4">Fines required by this section shall not be imposed upon any person determined by the court to be indigent pursuant to KRS Chapter 31. </section><section prefix="5">This section shall not apply to a corporation. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 403, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 497, sec. 6, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 7, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 406, sec. 292, effective January 1, 1975. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:19</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=20097</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>