<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="44" order_by="44">CLAIMS UPON THE TREASURY </unit></structure><section_number>44.020</section_number><catch_line>Claims allowed by courts -- Contest. </catch_line><order_by>020</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Within three (3) working days after the first and fifteenth of each month, the sheriff, or any other public official with a claim payable from the State Treasury for duties performed in any court of the Court of Justice, shall make out the claim and have it certified by the judge of the court as allowable for payment, and transmit the list to the Department for Local Government. The claim approved by the judge of the court shall serve as an order of allowance notwithstanding any statutory provision to the contrary. The Department for Local Government shall keep a separate record of all claims allowed in each county, noting the number and amount of each warrant issued for the payment of the claims. </section><section prefix="2">The order of any court authorized by law to approve and allow fee bills, settlements, credits, charges, and other claims against the State Treasury shall not be treated as a judgment, or made conclusive against the state, but shall only be regarded as prima facie evidence of the correctness and legality of the fee bill, settlement, credit, charge, or claim. The Department for Local Government, if it believes the fee bill, settlement, credit, charge, or claim to be fraudulent, erroneous, or illegal, may, upon the advice of the Attorney General, refuse to pay and may contest the claim in the Franklin Circuit Court, which shall have exclusive jurisdiction of all actions against the Department for Local Government to compel the payment of claims against the State Treasury. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 117, sec. 32, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 47, sec. 26, effective June 26, 2007. -- Amended 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 69, sec. 15, effective July 15, 1998. -- Amended 1990 Ky. Acts ch. 136, sec. 1, effective July 13, 1990. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 123, effective June 17, 1978. -- Amended 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 13. -- Amended 1976 Ky. Acts ch. 62, sec. 51. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. II, sec. 9(1). -- Amended 1954 Ky. Acts ch. 191. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 340a-1, 359. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:20</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22126</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>