<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="439" order_by="439">PROBATION AND PAROLE </unit></structure><section_number>439.990</section_number><catch_line>Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>990</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any warden or other officer of any prison or any peace officer who willfully fails or refuses to execute or obey the orders of the department, one (1) of its divisions, or the board, under any provision of KRS 439.250 to 439.560, shall be fined not less than twenty-five dollars ($25) nor more than two hundred dollars ($200). </section><section prefix="2">Any Commonwealth's attorney who willfully violates KRS 439.370 shall be fined one hundred dollars ($100). </section><section prefix="3">Any person who willfully violates any of the provisions of KRS 439.500 or 439.510 shall be guilty of a misdemeanor, and upon conviction thereof shall be punished by a fine not exceeding five hundred dollars ($500) or imprisonment not exceeding one (1) year, or both. It shall be the duty of the commissioner to dismiss from office or employment any officer or other employee of the department convicted for violating any of the provisions of KRS 439.500. </section></text><history>Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 107, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 344, sec. 59, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. V, sec. 24(14). -- Created 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 101, secs. 33 and 34, effective May 18, 1956. </history><metadata><effective>July 14, 1992 </effective><former-history>Repealed 1956 Ky. Acts ch. 101, sec. 34. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. secs. 1142b-3, 3838-9. </former-history><former-history-former-name>KRS 439.990: </former-history-former-name><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:26</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19220</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>