<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="315" order_by="315">PHARMACISTS AND PHARMACIES </unit></structure><section_number>315.110</section_number><catch_line>License expiration date -- Renewal fee -- Application and requirements -- Certificate -- Display -- Pocket certificate. </catch_line><order_by>110</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Each license to practice pharmacy, unless sooner suspended or revoked, shall expire on February 28 following its date of issuance. Every pharmacist who desires to continue to practice pharmacy shall pay to the executive director of the board a reasonable renewal fee to be set by administrative regulation of the board, but not to exceed one hundred seventy-five dollars ($175) annually or increase more than twenty-five dollars ($25) per year, and shall file with the board an application in such form and containing such data as the board may require for renewal of the license. A delinquent renewal penalty fee not to exceed the renewal fee may be assessed and set by administrative regulation for each renewal period the licensee fails to renew the license after expiration. </section><section prefix="2">Every pharmacist shall keep his current certificate conspicuously displayed in his primary place of practice. </section><section prefix="3">In addition to a current renewal certificate, each pharmacist shall be issued upon renewal a pocket certificate which shall be in the licensee's possession at all times when the licensee is engaged in the practice of pharmacy and which shall be exhibited by the licensee upon request from any member, inspector or agent of the board. </section></text><history> Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 61, sec. 2, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 257, sec. 11, effective July 15, 1996. --Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 191, sec. 8, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 310, sec. 3. -- Amended 1970 Ky. Acts ch. 221, sec. 7. -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 260, sec. 2. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 234, sec. 2. -- Recodified 1942 Ky. Acts ch. 208, sec. 1, effective October 1, 1942, from Ky. Stat. sec. 2627. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:55</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=31004</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>