<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XL" order_by="40">CRIMES AND PUNISHMENTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="441" order_by="441">JAILS AND COUNTY PRISONERS </unit></structure><section_number>441.510</section_number><catch_line>Transporting to and from detention facility. </catch_line><order_by>510</order_by><text><section prefix="1">If an inmate is confined in a detention facility, he shall be transported as necessary in accordance with the following provisions: <section prefix="a">If he is lodged in an urban-county facility in the county where the trial is to be held, the jailer shall carry out this duty; and </section><section prefix="b">In all other cases, the sheriff of the county where the prisoner is incarcerated shall carry out this duty as provided in subsection (3) of this section. </section></section><section prefix="2">The transportation of any inmate housed in a county detention center whose court appearance is necessary in any other county shall be transported by the sheriff of the county where the trial or court proceedings are to be held. </section><section prefix="3">If an accused is sentenced to confinement, the sheriff shall deliver him to the proper detention facility, with the exception that in the case of a sentence to an urban-county detention facility, the jailer shall carry out this duty. </section><section prefix="4">In each county where there is no jail, the fiscal court or the legislative body of a charter county government, as appropriate, shall adopt a transportation plan which establishes the party responsible for transporting prisoners as necessary: <section prefix="a">The fiscal court or the legislative body of a charter county government, as appropriate, may require the jailer to serve as transportation officer to be responsible for transporting prisoners as necessary; or </section><section prefix="b">The fiscal court or the legislative body of a charter county government, as appropriate, may require the sheriff to serve as transportation officer to be responsible for transporting prisoners as necessary; or </section><section prefix="c">The fiscal court or the legislative body of a charter county government, as appropriate, may adopt any reasonable transportation plan so long as the party responsible for transporting prisoners is specified. </section></section><section prefix="5">Upon the recommendation of the jailer, the fiscal court shall employ a female transportation officer for purposes of assisting the jailer during the transportation of female prisoners, when deemed necessary by the jailer. </section><section prefix="6">In any county where there is no jail and the jailer does not transport prisoners, the jailer shall serve as a bailiff to the Circuit and District Courts of the county as provided for in KRS 71.050. </section><section prefix="7">Nothing in this section shall prohibit the jailer from transporting the prisoners as he or she deems necessary. </section></text><history> Amended 2001 Ky. Acts ch. 97, sec. 1, effective June 21, 2001. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1996 Ky. Acts ch. 84, sec. 1, effective July 15, 1996. -- Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 89, sec. 2, effective July 14, 1992. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 10, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 385, sec. 47, effective July 1, 1982. -- Created 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 22, sec. 55, effective January 2, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> June 21, 2001 </effective><former-codification> KRS 441.500. </former-codification><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=19356</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>