<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>304.20-100</section_number><catch_line>Loss run statement to be provided upon request -- Duties of insurer and insurer's agent.   </catch_line><order_by>20-100</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Commercial property and casualty" means any kind of property and casualty insurance relating to commercial risks that is not insurance for personal risks as defined in KRS 304.13-011; </section><section prefix="b">"Loss run statement" means a report relating to commercial property and casualty risks maintained by an insurer containing the history of claims occurring within a policy term; and </section><section prefix="c">"Provide" means to mail, personally deliver, or electronically send a document, or to allow access through an electronic portal to view or generate a document. </section></section><section prefix="2">An insurer shall provide a loss run statement to an insured or an insurer's agent within twenty (20) calendar days of receipt of a written request submitted by the insured or the insurer's agent. </section><section prefix="3">An insurer's agent that receives a loss run statement pursuant to subsection (2) of this section shall provide a copy of the loss run statement to the insured within five (5) calendar days of receipt by the agent. </section><section prefix="4">The loss run statement provided pursuant to subsection (2) of this section shall be a five (5) year loss run history for the prior five (5) years or a complete loss run history with the insurer if the history is less than five (5) years. </section><section prefix="5">An insurer's agent that receives a loss run statement pursuant to subsection (2) of this section shall not divulge consumer information to any third party, except in accordance with applicable laws governing the privacy of consumer financial information, health information, or other information that is otherwise required by law to be held as confidential. </section><section prefix="6">An insurer shall not charge any fees to prepare and provide one (1) loss run statement in accordance with subsection (2) of this section. </section></text><history> Created 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 64, sec. 1, effective July 12, 2012. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:04</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40249</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>