<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVIII" order_by="18">PUBLIC HEALTH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="211" order_by="211">STATE HEALTH PROGRAMS </unit></structure><section_number>211.752</section_number><catch_line>Annual reports to Legislative Research Commission. </catch_line><order_by>752</order_by><text>The Department for Medicaid Services, the Department for Public Health, the Office of Health Policy, and the Personnel Cabinet shall submit a report to the Legislative Research Commission by January 10 of each odd-numbered year on the following: <section prefix="1">The financial impact and reach diabetes of all types is having on the entity, the Commonwealth, and localities. Items included in this assessment shall include the number of lives with diabetes impacted or covered by the entity, the number of lives with diabetes and family members impacted by prevention and diabetes control programs implemented by the entity, the financial toll or impact diabetes and its complications places on the program, and the financial toll or impact diabetes and its complications places on the program in comparison to other chronic diseases and conditions; </section><section prefix="2">An assessment of the benefits of implemented programs and activities aimed at controlling diabetes and preventing the disease. This assessment shall also document the amount and source for any funding directed to the agency or entity from the Kentucky General Assembly for programs and activities aimed at reaching those with diabetes; </section><section prefix="3">A description of the level of coordination existing between the entities on activities, programmatic activities, and messaging on managing, treating, or preventing all forms of diabetes and its complications; </section><section prefix="4">The development or revision of detailed action plans for battling diabetes with a range of actionable items for consideration by the General Assembly. The plans shall identify proposed action steps to reduce the impact of diabetes, prediabetes, and related diabetes complications. The plan shall also identify expected outcomes of the action steps proposed in the following biennium while also establishing benchmarks for controlling and preventing relevant forms of diabetes; and </section><section prefix="5">The development of a detailed budget blueprint identifying needs, costs, and resources required to implement the plan identified in subsection (4) of this section. This blueprint shall include a budget range for all options presented in the plan identified in subsection (4) of this section for consideration by the General Assembly. </section></text><history> Created 2011 Ky. Acts ch.83, sec.2, effective June 8, 2011. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:40</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39837</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>