<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="IX" order_by="9">COUNTIES, CITIES, AND OTHER LOCAL UNITS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="98" order_by="98">HEALTH AND WELFARE IN CITIES OF THE FIRST CLASS AND IN COUNTIES CONTAINING SUCH CITIES </unit></structure><section_number>98.013</section_number><catch_line>City to have lien upon real property of general assistance recipient -- Notice -- Filing, recording and indexing -- Filing fee -- Enforceability of lien -- Waiver -- Precipitation. </catch_line><order_by>013</order_by><text><section prefix="1">On and after July 1, 1952 a city of the first class shall have a lien upon all real estate and rights to real estate belonging to or thereafter acquired by any recipient of general assistance through said city's department of public welfare. The lien shall become effective upon the first payment of assistance to the recipient after June 19, 1952, and shall be cumulative and shall include all amounts paid to the recipient. The lien shall continue until it is satisfied, or becomes unenforceable. </section><section prefix="2">The lien shall not be effectual as against any mortgage, purchaser, or judgment creditor without actual notice until notice thereof has been filed by the director of public welfare of the city in the office of the county clerk of the county in which the property is located. Such notice, from the date of the filing thereof, shall constitute notice of all payments of assistance, whether paid prior or subsequent to the date of the filing of the notice. Such notice shall be filed by the director of public welfare in those cases in which it is discovered that the recipient has sufficient real estate to justify the filing of such a notice. </section><section prefix="3">The director of public welfare shall file an adequate notice of the existence of the lien provided for by this section which notice shall not specify the amount of assistance paid but the director of public welfare shall furnish to any authorized person upon proper request the total amount of the lien as of the date of the inquiry. </section><section prefix="4">The county clerk shall file, record and index such notices as other liens on real estate are required by law to be filed, recorded and indexed but shall index said lien only in the name of the recipient. The lien shall be designated "City's Lien." </section><section prefix="5">The clerk shall be entitled to a fee pursuant to KRS 64.012 for filing and indexing the lien. The department of public welfare of the city shall pay the fee but the fee shall become a part of the lien as an added cost to the recipient to be recovered at the time a lien is satisfied. </section><section prefix="6">The lien shall not be enforceable while the real estate is occupied by the surviving spouse or until she remarries, or is occupied by a dependent child, provided, no other action is brought to settle the estate. </section><section prefix="7">In any case in which it appears that it would be to the best interest of the recipient to sell his real estate and reinvest the proceeds in other real estate, the department of public welfare of the city may grant permission and waive the lien to the extent necessary for the purpose of effecting the transfer but such lien shall attach to the reinvested property. </section><section prefix="8">Any claim under KRS 98.011 to 98.014 may be precipitated and the lien provided by this section may be enforceable during the lifetime of any person who has received general assistance in order to recover any amount obtained as a result of such person knowingly making a false statement or representation or knowingly failing to disclose a fact to procure, increase, or continue any material benefit for himself. </section></text><history> Amended 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 255, sec. 13, effective January 1, 2007. -- Amended 1978 Ky. Acts ch. 384, sec. 227, effective June 17, 1978. -- Created 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 211, sec. 3, effective June 19, 1952. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2007 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:08</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=26461</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>