<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIX" order_by="29">COMMERCE AND TRADE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>362.2-206</section_number><catch_line>Delivery to and filing of records by the Secretary of State.   </catch_line><order_by>2-206</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Unless the Secretary of State determines that a record fails to comply with the filing requirements of this subchapter, and if all filing fees have been paid, then the Secretary of State shall file the record and: <section prefix="a">For a statement of dissociation, send: <section prefix="1">A copy of the filed statement to the person which the statement indicates has dissociated as a general partner; and </section><section prefix="2">A copy of the filed statement to the limited partnership; </section></section><section prefix="b">For a statement of withdrawal, send: <section prefix="1">A copy of the filed statement to the person on whose behalf the record was filed; and </section><section prefix="2">If the statement refers to an existing limited partnership, a copy of the filed statement to the limited partnership; and </section></section><section prefix="c">For all other records, send a copy of the filed record to the person, or the duly authorized representative thereof, on whose behalf the record was filed. </section></section><section prefix="2">Upon request and payment of a fee, the Secretary of State shall send to the requester a certified copy of the requested record. </section><section prefix="3">Except as otherwise provided in KRS 14A.2-090 and 14A.4-030, a record delivered to the Secretary of State for filing under this subchapter may specify an effective time and a delayed effective date. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 151, sec. 149, effective January 1, 2011. -- Created 2006 Ky. Acts ch. 149, sec. 110, effective July 12, 2006. </history><metadata><effective> January 1, 2011. </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:41</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=36811</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>