<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XII" order_by="12">CONSERVATION AND STATE DEVELOPMENT</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="146" order_by="146">NATURAL RESOURCES </unit></structure><section_number>146.090</section_number><catch_line>Soil and Water Conservation Commission. </catch_line><order_by>090</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The secretary for energy and environment, with the approval of the Soil and Water Conservation Commission shall divide the state into nine (9) soil and water conservation areas which shall contain as nearly as practicable, an equal number of soil and water conservation districts; </section><section prefix="2">The Soil and Water Conservation Commission shall consist of nine (9) members, not more than five (5) of whom shall be of the same political party, to be appointed by the secretary for energy and environment with the approval of the Governor; </section><section prefix="3">One (1) member shall be appointed from each of the areas from a list of two (2) names submitted from each such area by the supervisors of the soil and water conservation districts that have their principal offices therein. All members shall be supervisors of soil and water conservation districts; </section><section prefix="4">The term of office of each such member shall be four (4) years; provided that, whenever a member of the commission ceases to hold the office of district supervisor by virtue of which he is serving on the commission, his term of office as a member of the commission shall be terminated. In the case of any vacancy other than the one (1) caused by the expiration of a term, the secretary for energy and environment, with the approval of the Governor, shall appoint the successor from a list of two (2) names submitted by the supervisors of the soil and water conservation area which was represented by the former member. The successor shall also be a supervisor of a soil and water conservation district; </section><section prefix="5">The members of the commission shall designate a chairman from among their members and may from time to time change such designation. The commission shall keep a record of its official actions. A majority of the commission shall constitute a quorum. The commission may call upon the Attorney General for such legal services as it may require. It may delegate to its chairman, any of its members, the director of the division, or any officer, employee, or agent, such powers and duties as it deems proper. Members of the commission shall receive no compensation for their services, but shall be entitled to expenses, including traveling expenses, necessarily incurred in discharging their duties; </section><section prefix="6">The following persons are advisory members of the commission by virtue of their offices: the secretary for energy and environment, the Commissioner of Agriculture, the director of the agricultural experiment station, the director of vocational education, and the state conservationist of the United States Department of Agriculture. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 118, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1984 Ky. Acts ch. 111, sec. 80, effective July 13, 1984. -- Amended 1974 Ky. Acts ch. 74, Art. III, sec. 13(1). -- Amended 1966 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 56. -- Amended 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 68, Art. XIV, sec. 1. -- Amended 1956 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 7, Art. VII, sec. 13. -- Amended 1952 Ky. Acts ch. 202, sec. 1. -- Created 1946 Ky. Acts ch. 52, sec. 2. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:59</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=29289</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>