<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="164" order_by="164">STATE UNIVERSITIES AND COLLEGES -- REGIONAL EDUCATION -- ARCHAEOLOGY </unit></structure><section_number>164.003</section_number><catch_line>Legislative findings and goals for achievement by 2020. </catch_line><order_by>003</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The General Assembly hereby finds that: <section prefix="a">The general welfare and material well-being of citizens of the Commonwealth depend in large measure upon the development of a well-educated and highly trained workforce; </section><section prefix="b">The education and training of the current and future workforce of the Commonwealth can provide its businesses and industries with the competitive edge critical to their success in the global economy and must be improved to provide its citizens the opportunity to achieve a standard of living in excess of the national average; and </section><section prefix="c">The positive advancement of the welfare of the citizens of the Commonwealth through the transmission of knowledge can only be achieved by the incorporation of ethical standards, the historic American moral principles promoted by the nation's Founding Fathers, into Kentucky public instruction, state educational training, and personal development of its teachers, students, and people, and affirms President George Washington's statement in his September 19, 1796, farewell address: "Of all the dispositions and habits which lead to political prosperity, Religion and morality are indispensable." </section></section><section prefix="2">The General Assembly declares on behalf of the people of the Commonwealth the following goals to be achieved by the year 2020: <section prefix="a">A seamless, integrated system of postsecondary education strategically planned and adequately funded to enhance economic development and quality of life; </section><section prefix="b">A major comprehensive research institution ranked nationally in the top twenty (20) public universities at the University of Kentucky; </section><section prefix="c">A premier, nationally recognized metropolitan research university at the University of Louisville; </section><section prefix="d">Comprehensive universities, with at least one (1) nationally recognized program of distinction or one (1) nationally recognized applied research program, working cooperatively with other postsecondary institutions to assure statewide access to baccalaureate and master's degrees of a quality at or above the national average; </section><section prefix="e">A comprehensive community and technical college system with a mission that assures, in conjunction with other postsecondary institutions, access throughout the Commonwealth to a two (2) year course of general studies designed for transfer to a baccalaureate program, the training necessary to develop a workforce with the skills to meet the needs of new and existing industries, and remedial and continuing education to improve the employability of citizens; and </section><section prefix="f">An efficient, responsive, and coordinated system of providers that delivers educational services to all adult citizens in quantities and of a quality that is comparable to the national average or above and significantly elevates the level of education of the adults of the Commonwealth. </section></section><section prefix="3">The achievement of these goals will lead to the development of a society with a standard of living and quality of life that meets or exceeds the national average. </section><section prefix="4">The achievement of these goals will only be accomplished through increased educational attainment at all levels, and contributions to the quality of elementary and secondary education shall be a central responsibility of Kentucky's postsecondary institutions. </section><section prefix="5">The furtherance of these goals is a lawful public purpose that can best be accomplished by a comprehensive system of postsecondary education with single points of accountability that ensure the coordination of programs and efficient use of resources. </section><section prefix="6">The Commonwealth further recognizes that Kentucky's independent institutions offer rich and diverse postsecondary education choices throughout the state. Kentucky's people are best served by a broad array of postsecondary education providers. This vital component of the system will be a full partner in the greater system of postsecondary education. </section></text><history> Amended 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 113, sec. 9, effective July 15, 2008. -- Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 37, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2002. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 526, sec. 2, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1997 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 1, sec. 2, effective May 30, 1997. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:48</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=4158</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>