<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIII" order_by="23">PRIVATE CORPORATIONS AND ASSOCIATIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="" order_by=""></unit></structure><section_number>271B.6-210</section_number><catch_line>Issuance of shares. </catch_line><order_by>6-210</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The powers granted in this section to the board of directors may be reserved to the shareholders by the articles of incorporation. </section><section prefix="2">The board of directors may authorize shares to be issued for consideration consisting of any tangible or intangible property or benefit to the corporation, including cash, promissory notes, services performed, contracts for services to be performed, or other securities of the corporation. </section><section prefix="3">Before the corporation issues shares, the board of directors shall determine that the consideration received or to be received for shares to be issued is adequate. That determination by the board of directors is conclusive insofar as the adequacy of consideration for the issuance of shares relates to whether the shares are validly issued, fully paid, and nonassessable. </section><section prefix="4">When the corporation receives the consideration for which the board of directors authorized the issuance of shares in accordance with this section, the shares issued therefor are fully paid and nonassessable. When, and to the extent, consideration for the issuance of shares consists of a promissory note or contract for services or other benefits, the shares shall be fully paid and nonassessable at the time the note is issued or the contract is entered into. </section><section prefix="5">The board of directors, or a committee of the board of directors, may authorize one (1) or more officers of the corporation to approve the issuance, sale, or contract for sale of shares or to determine the designation and relative rights, preferences, and limitations of a class or series of shares, all within limits specifically prescribed by the board of directors or the committee. </section></text><history> Amended 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 10, effective November 15, 2002. -- Created 1988 Ky. Acts ch. 23, sec. 38, effective January 1, 1989. </history><metadata><effective> November 15, 2002 </effective><lrc-note>(6/26/2007).  2007 Ky. Acts ch. 137, sec. 179, effective June 26, 2007 provided: The General Assembly finds and declares that the amendment of KRS 271B.6-210, 271B.6-230, 271B.7-040, 271B.7-280, and 271B.8-080, as provided for in 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 102, secs. 10, 11, 15, 18, and 19, respectively, are and were effective as of November 15, 2002.  (11/15/02).  2002 Ky. Acts ch. 102, sec. 22, provides that this section "shall take effect November 15, 2002, if a constitutional amendment proposing to amend Sections 190, 191, 192, 193, 194, 195, 198, 200, 202, 203, 205, 207, and 208 of the Constitution of Kentucky relating to corporations is enacted by the General Assembly and approved by the voters in the November, 2002 general elections. Otherwise, [this section] shall be void."   A constitutional amendment proposing to amend 11 of those 13 sections of the Constitution was enacted by the General Assembly and approved by the voters. During the 2002 Regular Session, the General Assembly enacted 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 341, which proposed to amend Sections 190, 191, 192, 193, 194, 198, 200, 202, 203, 207, and 208 of the Constitution of Kentucky. The voters approved that amendment in the November, 2002 general elections. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:25</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=13341</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>