<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="VI" order_by="6">FINANCIAL ADMINISTRATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="48" order_by="48">BUDGET </unit></structure><section_number>48.180</section_number><catch_line>Financial information submitted as part of executive branch budget request. </catch_line><order_by>180</order_by><text>In addition to the information required by KRS 48.110, the Governor shall submit the following information as a separate part of the branch budget request for the executive branch of government: <section prefix="1">Summary statements of the financial condition of the state, which shall include such detailed schedules of revenues and summary of expenditures by fund as specified by law in addition to those the Governor deems desirable; and summary statements of the estimated fund balances for the current fiscal year and each of the next two (2) fiscal years; and statement of the surplus account for the general fund and the road fund, for the budget reserve trust fund account, and for each special fund. Each surplus account shall show the excess of all current revenues over all current expenditures as of the beginning of each of the two (2) fiscal years last concluded, and all changes in each surplus account during each of such two (2) fiscal years. </section><section prefix="2">A statement as of the close of the last completed fiscal year and as of the close of the current fiscal year, showing for the Commonwealth the total funded debt, the value of sinking fund assets, the net funded debt, the floating liabilities as of the close of the last completed fiscal year and the estimated floating liabilities as of the end of the current fiscal year, and the total debt as of the close of the last completed fiscal year and as of the close of the current fiscal year. </section><section prefix="3">A summary statement for each major fund of the cash resources estimated to be available at the beginning of each of the next two (2) fiscal years, and the estimated cash receipts of the fiscal year. </section><section prefix="4">Such other information as is deemed desirable or is required by law or regulation. </section></text><history> Amended 1995 (3d Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 2, sec. 4, effective November 3, 1995. -- Created 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 450, sec. 9, effective July 1, 1983. </history><metadata><effective> November 3, 1995 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:17:17</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=22553</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>