<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XIII" order_by="13">EDUCATION</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="160" order_by="160">SCHOOL DISTRICTS </unit></structure><section_number>160.6131</section_number><catch_line>Definitions for KRS 160.613 to 160.617. </catch_line><order_by>6131</order_by><text>As used in KRS 160.613 to 160.617: <section prefix="1">"Department" means the Department of Revenue; </section><section prefix="2">"Communications service" means the provision, transmission, conveyance, or routing, for consideration, of voice, data, video, or any other information signals of the purchaser's choosing to a point or between or among points specified by the purchaser, by or through any electronic, radio, light, fiber optic, or similar medium or method now in existence or later devised. <section prefix="a">"Communications service" includes but is not limited to: <section prefix="1">Local and long-distance telephone services; </section><section prefix="2">Telegraph and teletypewriter services; </section><section prefix="3">Postpaid calling services; </section><section prefix="4">Private communications services involving a direct channel specifically dedicated to a customer's use between specific points; </section><section prefix="5">Channel services involving a path of communications between two (2) or more points; </section><section prefix="6">Data transport services involving the movement of encoded information between points by means of any electronic, radio, or other medium or method; </section><section prefix="7">Caller ID services, ring tones, voice mail, and other electronic messaging services; </section><section prefix="8">Mobile wireless telecommunications service and fixed wireless service as defined in KRS 139.195; and </section><section prefix="9">Voice over Internet Protocol (VOIP). </section></section><section prefix="b">"Communications service" does not include any of the following if the charges are separately itemized on the bill provided to the purchaser: <section prefix="1">Information services; </section><section prefix="2">Internet access as defined in 47 U.S.C. sec. 151; </section><section prefix="3">Installation, reinstallation, or maintenance of wiring or equipment on a customer's premises. This exclusion does not apply to any charge attributable to the connection, movement, change, or termination of a communications service; </section><section prefix="4">The sale of directory and other advertising and listing services; </section><section prefix="5">Billing and collection services provided to another communications service provider; </section><section prefix="6">Cable service, satellite broadcast, satellite master antenna television, wireless cable service, including direct-to-home satellite service as defined in Section 602 of the federal Telecommunications Act of 1996, and Internet protocol television provided through wireline facilities without regard to delivery technology; </section><section prefix="7">The sale of communications service to a communications provider that is buying the communications service for sale or incorporation into a communications service for sale, including: <section prefix="a">Carrier access charges, excluding user access fees; </section><section prefix="b">Right of access charges; </section><section prefix="c">Interconnection charges paid by the provider of mobile telecommunications services or other communications providers; </section><section prefix="d">Charges for the sale of unbundled network elements as defined in 47 U.S.C. sec. 153(29) on January 1, 2001, to which access is provided on an unbundled basis in accordance with 47 U.S.C. sec. 251(c)(3); and </section><section prefix="e">Charges for use of facilities for providing or receiving communications service; </section></section><section prefix="8">The sale of communications services provided to the public by means of a pay phone; </section><section prefix="9">Prepaid calling services and prepaid wireless calling service; </section><section prefix="10">Interstate telephone service, if the interstate charge is separately itemized for each call; and </section><section prefix="11">If the interstate calls are not itemized, the portion of telephone charges identified and set out on the customer's bill as interstate as supported by the provider's books and records; </section></section></section><section prefix="3">"Gross cost" means the total cost of utility services including the cost of the tangible personal property and any services associated with obtaining the utility services regardless from whom purchased; </section><section prefix="4">"Gross receipts" means all amounts received in money, credits, property, or other money's worth in any form, as consideration for the furnishing of utility services; </section><section prefix="5">"Utility services" means the furnishing of communications services, electric power, water, and natural, artificial, and mixed gas; </section><section prefix="6">"Cable service" has the same meaning as provided in KRS 136.602; </section><section prefix="7">"Satellite broadcast and wireless cable service" has the same meaning as provided in KRS 136.602; </section><section prefix="8">"Ring tones" has the same meaning as provided in KRS 136.602; and </section><section prefix="9">"Multichannel video programming service" has the same meaning as in KRS 136.602. </section></text><history> Amended 2009 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 3, effective July 1, 2009. -- Amended 2007 Ky. Acts ch. 141, sec. 17, effective July 1, 2007. -- Amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 595, effective June 20, 2005; and ch. 168, sec. 129, effective March 18, 2005. -- Created 2004 Ky. Acts ch. 79, sec. 1, effective July 1, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> July 1, 2009 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:51</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=3785</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>