<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXIV" order_by="24">PUBLIC UTILITIES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="277" order_by="277">RAILROADS -- ORGANIZATION AND OPERATING REGULATIONS </unit></structure><section_number>277.355</section_number><catch_line>Prohibition against damage, disturbance, or disruption of railroads, trains, or tracks -- Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>355</order_by><text><section prefix="1">A person shall not knowingly drop or throw any object at, onto, or in the path of any railroad rail or track, locomotive, engine, railroad car, or other vehicle of a railroad company when it is on a railroad track. </section><section prefix="2">An unauthorized person shall not climb upon or into any locomotive, railroad car, or other vehicle of a railroad company when it is on a railroad track. </section><section prefix="3">An unauthorized person shall not disrupt, delay, or prevent the operation of any train or other vehicle of a railroad company when it is on a railroad track. </section><section prefix="4">A person shall not knowingly deface, damage, obstruct, remove, or otherwise impair the operation of any railroad grade crossing warning signal or other protective device, including but not limited to any gate, bell, light, cross buck, stop sign, yield sign, advance warning sign, or advance pavement marking. </section><section prefix="5">Except as provided in subsection (6) of this section, a person who violates any of the provisions of this section shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor. </section><section prefix="6"><section prefix="a">If a violation of this section causes damage to property in excess of one thousand dollars ($1,000) or creates a substantial risk of serious physical injury to a person, as defined in KRS 500.080, the violator shall be guilty of a Class D felony. </section><section prefix="b">If a violation of this section causes physical injury to a person, as defined in KRS 500.080, the violator shall be guilty of a Class C felony. </section><section prefix="c">If a violation of this section causes serious physical injury to a person, as defined in KRS 500.080, the violator shall be guilty of a Class B felony. </section></section></text><history> Created 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 13, effective June 20, 2005. </history><metadata><effective> June 20, 2005 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:16</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=14028</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>