<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXV" order_by="25">BUSINESS AND FINANCIAL INSTITUTIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="292" order_by="292">SECURITIES (BLUE SKY LAW) </unit></structure><section_number>292.991</section_number><catch_line>Penalties. </catch_line><order_by>991</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person who willfully violates any provision of this chapter except KRS 292.440, or who willfully violates KRS 292.440 knowing the statement made to be false or misleading in any material respect, shall be guilty of a Class D felony. </section><section prefix="2">Any person who willfully violates any rule or order of the commissioner, authorized under this chapter, shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor; but no person may be imprisoned for violation of any rule or order of which that person did not have actual knowledge. </section><section prefix="3">The commissioner may refer such evidence as may be available concerning violations of this chapter or of any rule or order hereunder to the Attorney General or the proper prosecuting authority, who may in his or her discretion, with or without such a reference, institute the appropriate criminal proceedings under this chapter. </section><section prefix="4">Nothing in this chapter limits the power of the state to punish any person for any conduct which constitutes a crime by statute or at common law. </section></text><history> Amended 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 24, sec. 879, effective July 15, 2010. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 165, sec. 22, effective July 15, 1994. -- Amended 1982 Ky. Acts ch. 346, sec. 13, effective July 15, 1982. -- Amended 1972 Ky. Acts ch. 265, sec. 17. -- Created 1960 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 17, effective January 1, 1961. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2010 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:11</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=15593</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>