<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="II" order_by="2">LEGISLATIVE BRANCH</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="6" order_by="6">THE GENERAL ASSEMBLY </unit></structure><section_number>6.793</section_number><catch_line>Time schedule for filing statements of financial interests. </catch_line><order_by>793</order_by><text><section prefix="1">The statement of financial interests required by KRS 6.781 shall be filed with the commission for the preceding calendar year by no later than February 15 of each year, complete through December 31 of the preceding year, except that: <section prefix="a">A candidate for nomination or election to the General Assembly shall file his statement no later than twenty-one (21) days after the filing deadline as set by the law or within ten (10) days of the filing deadline if it is a special election date he became a candidate as defined in KRS 6.611; and </section><section prefix="b">An individual appointed to a position listed in KRS 6.781(3) shall file his initial statement no later than twenty-one (21) days after the date of his appointment. </section></section><section prefix="2">The commission may grant a reasonable extension of time for filing a statement of financial interests for good cause shown. </section></text><history> Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 493, sec. 5, effective July 14, 2000. -- Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 479, sec. 1, effective April 11, 1994. -- Created 1993 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 4, sec. 20, effective September 16, 1993. </history><metadata><effective> July 14, 2000 </effective><lrc-note> (7/14/2000).  The extraneous phrase "date he became a candidate as defined in KRS 6.611" at the end of subsection (1)(a) of this statute could not be removed from the amended version of this statute in codification even though its deletion was specified in the drafter's version for 2000 Ky. Acts. ch. 493 (House Bill 712) because the indicated bracketing and striking through of the phrase was inadvertently overlooked in the preparation and proofing of the bill for introduction. Cf. KRS 446.145(1) and 446.280. </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-01</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:14</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=391</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>