<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXXVIII" order_by="38">WITNESSES, EVIDENCE, NOTARIES, COMMISSIONERS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="421" order_by="421">WITNESSES </unit></structure><section_number>421.360</section_number><catch_line>Uniform Interstate Depositions and Discovery Act. </catch_line><order_by>360</order_by><text><section prefix="1">This section may be cited as the Uniform Interstate Depositions and Discovery Act. </section><section prefix="2">As used in this section: <section prefix="a">"Foreign jurisdiction" means a state other than this state; </section><section prefix="b">"Foreign subpoena" means a subpoena issued under authority of a court of record of a foreign jurisdiction; </section><section prefix="c">"Person" means an individual, corporation, business trust, estate, trust, partnership, limited liability company, association, joint venture, public corporation, government, or governmental subdivision, agency, or instrumentality, or any other legal or commercial entity; </section><section prefix="d">"State" means a state of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, a federally recognized Indian tribe, or any territory or insular possession subject to the jurisdiction of the United States; and </section><section prefix="e">"Subpoena" means a document, however denominated, issued under authority of a court of record requiring a person to: <section prefix="1">Attend and give testimony at a deposition; </section><section prefix="2">Produce and permit inspection and copying of designated books, documents, records, electronically stored information, or tangible things in the possession, custody, or control of the person; or </section><section prefix="3">Permit inspection of premises under the control of the person. </section></section></section><section prefix="3"><section prefix="a">To request issuance of a subpoena under this section, a party shall submit a foreign subpoena to the clerk of the Circuit Court of the county in which discovery is sought to be conducted in this state. A request for the issuance of a subpoena under this section does not constitute an appearance in the courts of this state. </section><section prefix="b">When a party submits a foreign subpoena to a clerk of the Circuit Court in this state, the clerk, in accordance with that court’s procedure, shall promptly issue a subpoena for service upon the person to which the foreign subpoena is directed. </section><section prefix="c">A subpoena under paragraph (b) of this subsection shall: <section prefix="1">Incorporate the terms used in the foreign subpoena; and </section><section prefix="2">Contain or be accompanied by the names, addresses, and telephone numbers of all counsel of record in the proceeding to which the subpoena relates and of any party not represented by counsel. </section></section></section><section prefix="4">A subpoena issued by a clerk of the Circuit Court under subsection (3) of this section shall be served in compliance with any rule of court or statute relating to the service of a subpoena issued in this state. </section><section prefix="5">Rules of court and any provision of the Kentucky Revised Statutes applicable to compliance with subpoenas to attend and give testimony; produce designated books, documents, records, electronically stored information, or tangible things; or permit inspection of premises shall apply to subpoenas issued under subsection (3) of this section. </section><section prefix="6">An application to the court for a protective order or to enforce, quash, or modify a subpoena issued by a clerk of the Circuit Court under subsection (3) of this section shall comply with the rules of court of this state and statutes of this state and be submitted to the Circuit Court in the county in which discovery is to be conducted. </section><section prefix="7">In applying and construing this uniform act, consideration shall be given to the need to promote uniformity of the law with respect to its subject matter among states that enact it. </section><section prefix="8">This section applies to requests for discovery in cases pending on July 15, 2008. </section></text><history> Created 2008 Ky. Acts ch. 114, sec. 1, effective July 15, 2008. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2008 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:28</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=18075</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>