<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVI" order_by="26">OCCUPATIONS AND PROFESSIONS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="311" order_by="311">PHYSICIANS, OSTEOPATHS, PODIATRISTS, AND RELATED MEDICAL PRACTITIONERS </unit></structure><section_number>311.275</section_number><catch_line>Request to expunge minor violations from permanent record -- Administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>275</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any licensee, permit holder, or certificate holder who is disciplined under this chapter for a minor violation may request in writing that the board expunge the minor violation from the licensee's, permit holder's, or certificate holder's permanent record. <section prefix="a">The request for expungement may be filed no sooner than three (3) years after the date on which the licensee, permit holder, or certificate holder has completed disciplinary sanctions imposed and if the licensee, permit holder, or certificate holder has not been disciplined for any subsequent violation of the same nature within this period of time. </section><section prefix="b">No person may have his or her record expunged under this chapter more than once. </section></section><section prefix="2">The board shall promulgate administrative regulations under KRS Chapter 13A to establish violations which are minor violations under this section. A violation shall be deemed a minor violation if it does not demonstrate a serious inability to practice the profession; adversely affect the public health, safety or welfare; or result in economic or physical harm to a person, or create a significant threat of such harm. </section></text><history> Created 2002 Ky. Acts ch. 335, sec. 3, effective July 15, 2002. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 2002 </effective><lrc-note> (7/15/2002).  A manifest clerical or typographical error has been corrected in codification in subsection (1)(a) of this statute as amended by 2002 Ky. Acts ch.335, sec 3, under the authority of KRS 7.136(1)(h), by removing the duplicated words "completed disciplinary sanctions imposed and if the licensee, permit holder, or certificate holder has." </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:57</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=30474</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>