<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVI" order_by="16">MOTOR VEHICLES</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="189" order_by="189">TRAFFIC REGULATIONS -- VEHICLE EQUIPMENT AND STORAGE </unit></structure><section_number>189.292</section_number><catch_line>Use of personal communication device prohibited while operating motor vehicle in motion on traveled portion of roadway -- Exclusions -- Administrative regulations. </catch_line><order_by>292</order_by><text><section prefix="1">As used in this section, "personal communication device" means a device capable of two (2) way audio or text communication that emits an audible signal, vibrates, displays a message, or otherwise summons or delivers communication to the possessor, including but not limited to a paging device and a cellular telephone. </section><section prefix="2">Except as provided in subsection (3) of this section, no person shall, while operating a motor vehicle that is in motion on the traveled portion of a roadway, write, send, or read text-based communication using a personal communication device to manually communicate with any person using text-based communication, including but not limited to communications referred to as a text message, instant message, or electronic mail. </section><section prefix="3">Subsection (2) of this section shall not apply to: <section prefix="a">The use of a global positioning system feature of a personal communication device; </section><section prefix="b">The use of a global positioning or navigation system that is physically or electronically integrated into the motor vehicle; </section><section prefix="c">The reading, selecting, or entering of a telephone number or name in a personal communication device for the purpose of making a phone call; </section><section prefix="d">An operator of an emergency or public safety vehicle, when the use of a personal communication device is an essential function of the operator's official duties; or </section><section prefix="e">The operator of a motor vehicle who writes a text message on a personal communication device to: <section prefix="1">Report illegal activity; </section><section prefix="2">Summon medical help; </section><section prefix="3">Summon a law enforcement or public safety agency; or </section><section prefix="4">Prevent injury to a person or property. </section></section></section><section prefix="4">The secretary of the Transportation Cabinet may promulgate administrative regulations pursuant to KRS Chapter 13A to implement the provisions of this section, including but not limited to updates or advances in the automotive and information technology industries. </section></text><history> Amended 2011 Ky. Acts ch. 59, sec. 3, effective June 8, 2011. -- Created 2010 Ky. Acts ch. 110, sec. 2, effective July 15, 2010. </history><metadata><effective> June 8, 2011 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-03</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:44</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=39750</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>