<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XVII" order_by="17">ECONOMIC SECURITY AND PUBLIC WELFARE</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="194" order_by="194">A CABINET FOR HEALTH AND FAMILY SERVICES </unit></structure><section_number>194A.146</section_number><catch_line>Statewide Strategic Planning Committee for Children in Placement -- Membership -- Plans -- Review -- Information Systems -- Study of changes in child welfare delivery -- Annual report.   </catch_line><order_by>146</order_by><text><section prefix="1">There is hereby created the "Statewide Strategic Planning Committee for Children in Placement" which is administratively attached to the Department for Community Based Services. The committee shall be composed of the following: <section prefix="a">Members who shall serve by virtue of their positions: the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services or the secretary's designee, the commissioner of the Department for Public Health, the commissioner of the Department for Behavioral Health, Developmental and Intellectual Disabilities, the commissioner for the Department for Medicaid Services, the commissioner of the Department for Community Based Services, the commissioner of the Department of Juvenile Justice, the commissioner of the Department of Education, the executive director of the Administrative Office of the Courts, the Senate co-chair of the Interim Joint Committee on Health and Welfare of the General Assembly, the House co-chair of the Interim Joint Committee on Health and Welfare of the General Assembly, or their designees; and </section><section prefix="b">One (1) foster parent selected by the statewide organization for foster parents, one (1) District Judge selected by the Chief Justice of the Kentucky Supreme Court, one (1) parent of a child in placement at the time of appointment to be selected by the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, one (1) youth in placement at the time of the appointment to be selected by the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services, one (1) private child care provider selected by the statewide organization for private child care providers, and one (1) private child-placing provider selected by the secretary of the Cabinet for Health and Family Services. These members shall serve a term of two (2) years, and may be reappointed. </section></section><section prefix="2">The Statewide Strategic Planning Committee for Children in Placement shall, by July 1, 2013, develop a statewide strategic plan for the coordination and delivery of care and services to children in placement and their families. The plan shall be submitted to the Governor, the Chief Justice of the Supreme Court, and the Legislative Research Commission on or before July 1, 2013, and each July 1 thereafter. </section><section prefix="3">The strategic plan shall, at a minimum, include: <section prefix="a">A mission statement; </section><section prefix="b">Measurable goals; </section><section prefix="c">Principles; </section><section prefix="d">Strategies and objectives; and </section><section prefix="e">Benchmarks. </section></section><section prefix="4">The planning horizon shall be three (3) years. The plan shall be updated on an annual basis. Strategic plan updates shall include data and statistical information comparing plan benchmarks to actual services and care provided. </section><section prefix="5">The Statewide Strategic Planning Committee for Children in Placement shall, in consultation with the commissioner and the statewide placement coordinator as provided for in KRS 199.801, establish a statewide facilities and services plan that identifies the location of existing facilities and services for children in placement, identifies unmet needs, and develops strategies to meet the needs. The planning horizon shall be three (3) years. The plan shall be updated on an annual basis. The plan shall be used to guide, direct, and, if necessary, restrict the development of new facilities and services, the expansion of existing facilities and services, and the geographic location of placement alternatives. </section><section prefix="6">The Statewide Strategic Planning Committee for Children in Placement may, through the promulgation of administrative regulations, establish a process that results in the review and approval or denial of the development of new facilities and services, the expansion of existing facilities and services, and the geographic location of any facilities and services for children in placement in accordance with the statewide facilities and services plan. Any process established shall include adequate due process rights for individuals and entities seeking to develop new services, construct new facilities, or expand existing facilities, and shall require the involvement of local communities and other resource providers in those communities. </section><section prefix="7">As a part of the statewide strategic plan, and in consultation with the Commonwealth Office of Technology, the Statewide Strategic Planning Committee for Children in Placement shall plan for the development or integration of information systems that will allow information to be shared across agencies and entities, so that relevant data will follow a child through the system regardless of the entity or agency that is responsible for the child. The data produced shall be used to establish and monitor the benchmarks required by subsection (3) of this section. The data system shall, at a minimum, produce the following information on a monthly basis: <section prefix="a">Number of placements per child; </section><section prefix="b">Reasons for placement disruptions; </section><section prefix="c">Length of time between removal and establishment of permanency; </section><section prefix="d">Reabuse or reoffense rates; </section><section prefix="e">Fatality rates; </section><section prefix="f">Injury and hospitalization rates; </section><section prefix="g">Health care provision rates; </section><section prefix="h">Educational achievement rates; </section><section prefix="i">Multiple placement rates; </section><section prefix="j">Sibling placement rates; </section><section prefix="k">Ethnicity matching rates; </section><section prefix="l">Family maintenance and preservation rate; and </section><section prefix="m">Adoption disruption rates. </section></section><section prefix="8">The Statewide Strategic Planning Committee for Children in Placement shall ensure that a study is conducted to evaluate the extent to which changes in the child welfare delivery model, to include contracting for a continuum of care and shared decision-making with private child-caring and child placing agencies, would enhance the effectiveness and outcomes for children served in the foster care system. The Statewide Strategic Planning Committee shall develop a report of its findings and recommendations which shall be included in the annual report due on or before July 1, 2013. </section><section prefix="9">The Statewide Strategic Planning Committee for Children in Placement shall publish an annual report no later than December 1 of each year that includes, but is not limited to, the information outlined in subsection (7) of this section. The annual report shall be filed with the Governor and the Legislative Research Commission. </section></text><history> Amended 2012 Ky. Acts ch. 146, sec. 23, effective July 12, 2012; and ch. 158, sec. 18, effective July 12, 2012. -- Repealed, reenacted and amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 32, effective June 20, 2005; and amended 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 617, effective June 20, 2005. -- Amended 2000 Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 14, effective July 14, 2000; ch. 506, sec. 24, effective July 14, 2000; and ch. 536, sec. 24, effective July 14, 2000. -- Created 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 395, sec. 2, effective July 15, 1998. </history><metadata><effective> July 12, 2012 </effective><former-codification>KRS 194B.102 </former-codification><lrc-note>(7/12/2012). This statute was amended by 2012 Ky. Acts chs. 146 and 158, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together.(6/20/2005).  This section, originally codified at KRS 194B.102, was repealed, reenacted as a new section of KRS Chapter 194A, and amended by 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 99, sec. 32, and amended by 2005 Ky. Acts ch. 85, sec. 617, which do not appear to be in conflict and have been codified together. (7/15/98).  A reference in this statute to the former Department for Health Services has been changed to the Department for Public Health under 1998 Ky. Acts ch. 426, sec. 629, and KRS 7.136(2). </lrc-note><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:16:43</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=40940</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag><tag>suspect-parse</tag></tags></law>