<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><law><structure><unit label="title" identifier="XXVII" order_by="27">LABOR AND HUMAN RIGHTS</unit><unit label="chapter" identifier="344" order_by="344">CIVIL RIGHTS </unit></structure><section_number>344.500</section_number><catch_line>Appointment of interpreter for deaf, hard-of-hearing, or speech-impaired person -- Compensation of interpreter. </catch_line><order_by>500</order_by><text><section prefix="1">Any person who is deaf, hard of hearing, or speech impaired or who because of a speaking or other impairment has difficulty in communicating with other persons shall be entitled to the assistance and services of a qualified interpreter. </section><section prefix="2">A qualified interpreter shall be appointed in any proceeding before a board, commission, agency, or licensing authority of the state or any of its political subdivisions, when the principal party in interest or a witness is deaf, hard of hearing, or speech impaired. </section><section prefix="3">No person shall be appointed as an interpreter pursuant to this section unless the appointing authority makes a preliminary determination that the interpreter is able to readily communicate with the person who is deaf, hard of hearing, or speech impaired, and is able to accurately repeat and translate the statements of the person, and the appointee is agreed to by the person who is deaf, hard of hearing, or speech impaired. </section><section prefix="4">Upon the request of the appointing authority, the Kentucky Commission on the Deaf and Hard of Hearing, the Kentucky Registry of Interpreters for the Deaf, or the Kentucky Association of the Deaf, shall recommend qualified interpreters to assist a person who is deaf, hard of hearing, or speech impaired. </section><section prefix="5">The appointing authority shall set the compensation for each day the interpreter is in attendance. The compensation, plus any reasonable expenses incurred by the interpreter, shall be paid from the funds of the appointing authority. </section></text><history> Amended 1994 Ky. Acts ch. 452, sec. 7, effective July 15, 1994. – Amended 1992 Ky. Acts ch. 144, sec. 17, effective July 14, 1992. -- .Created 1976 (1st Extra. Sess.) Ky. Acts ch. 14, sec. 277, effective January 2, 1978. </history><metadata><effective> July 15, 1994 </effective><pdf-author>ganesan_m</pdf-author><pdf-creation-date>2015-07-02</pdf-creation-date><pdf-download-date>2016-03-18 12:15:53</pdf-download-date><original-link>http://www.lrc.ky.gov/statutes/statute.aspx?id=32649</original-link></metadata><tags><tag>computer-parsed</tag><tag>unverified</tag></tags></law>